<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Moon: Full, Blue, &amp; Cheesy</title>
		<link>http://forestcat72.wordpress.com/2012/08/25/full-blue-cheesy/</link>
		<comments>http://forestcat72.wordpress.com/2012/08/25/full-blue-cheesy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 13:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>forestcat72</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artemis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Full moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greeks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jules Verne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunar phase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Shakespeare]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forestcat72.wordpress.com/?p=71</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The moon has gone by many names over the centuries. The Romans called it Luna. The Greeks named it Artemis. To us, it&#8217;s just The Moon. But it is such an iconic symbol from our history, culture and everyday life that it cannot be shunted to the side. Mankind&#8217;s history and fascination with the moon [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=71&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 280px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Moon_merged_small.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured " title="The Moon as seen by an observer from Earth. So..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e4/Moon_merged_small.jpg/300px-Moon_merged_small.jpg" alt="" width="270" height="270" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">(Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p>The moon has gone by many names over the centuries. The Romans called it Luna. The Greeks named it Artemis. To us, it&#8217;s just The Moon. But it is such an iconic symbol from our history, culture and everyday life that it cannot be shunted to the side.</p>
<p>Mankind&#8217;s history and fascination with the moon dates back to the beginning of the first humans. Eclipses, both lunar and solar were being predicted as early as 1000 BC. By 600 BC, the Greeks had determined that the moon revolved around the earth, it was spherical in shape and they understood why the moon went through phases. The moon has also been used to measure time for centuries.</p>
<p>Culturally, the moon has featured in poems, stories and songs. The likes of William Shakespeare, Beethoven and even Jules Verne have immortalized the moon in their works. The moon is also the stuff of legend. To explain a lunar eclipse, the Bushmen of Southern Africa say that a lion reaches up and covers the moon with his paw so he can hunt in the dark.</p>
<p><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:William_Shakespeare.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured alignleft" title="William Shakespeare" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/31/William_Shakespeare.jpg/75px-William_Shakespeare.jpg" alt="William Shakespeare" width="75" height="97" /></a><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Beethoven.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured aligncenter" title="Portrait Ludwig van Beethoven when composing t..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6f/Beethoven.jpg/75px-Beethoven.jpg" alt="Portrait Ludwig van Beethoven when composing t..." width="75" height="90" /></a><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Jules_Verne.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured alignright" title="Poe's novel inspired later writers, including ..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/b6/Jules_Verne.jpg/75px-Jules_Verne.jpg" alt="Poe's novel inspired later writers, including ..." width="75" height="105" /></a></p>
<p>The moon, however, has another effect on the human race that has been bandied about between scientists and the public for what seems like forever. Does the full moon create lunacy in humans? There have been scientific studies galore that have shown no correlation between the phases of the moon and aberrant behavior in people. Although the scientific evidence is overwhelming, it cannot explain the number of incidents that occur during the few days leading up to a full moon and the few days after one.</p>
<p>Ask any hospital emergency room attendant, nursing home staffer, teacher or police officer if the full moon affects people, and you&#8217;ll get a completely different story than from the scientific community. Anyone who works in retail will also notice the lack of patience, oddity of questions and bizarre behavior exhibited by an overwhelming number of their customers. It may not be proved with microscopes and rigorous testing, but there is something there.</p>
<p>I have had this conversation with many people &#8211; business owners who share my faith in the idea and skeptics. The skeptics won&#8217;t even entertain the notion that the moon could change a person&#8217;s normal behavior. I remind them that the earth would not have the tides it does without the moon.* If these bodies of water are so affected by the movement of the moon around the earth, then why wouldn&#8217;t humans who are almost 80% water be affected as well?</p>
<p>This theory has been compounded by legends and stories of werewolves, people going missing, strange and unexplained violence. Lines from movies warning travelers to stay off the moors, artist&#8217;s renderings of strange beasts backlit by a full moon, they all lend to the fantastical notion that the moon controls our basest emotions. None of these helps support the possibility that we simply react differently when the pull of the moon is at its strongest.</p>
<p>Some will argue that since we know it is a full moon, we look for the odd and unusual. And this is true for a certain segment of the population. They perceive a problem, and so one is created. However, I find it difficult to believe that everyone knows exactly when the full moon is occurring each month, considering some of these people need to be reminded when election day is held in the U.S. every year. It used to be that I wouldn&#8217;t keep track of when a full moon was occurring, but once I started working a regular retail job, it became a task I didn&#8217;t take lightly. I like being prepared for the inevitable onslaught of the ridiculous and inane. And it does happen. Trust me. Oh, by the way, we&#8217;re having another full moon this month. Keep your eye on Friday!</p>
<p>Of course all of the above would be completely moot if the moon were actually made of cheese. Perhaps a nice Havarti.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*The oceans would still have  a tide caused by the sun, but it would be about one third of what they are with the moon.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=71&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://forestcat72.wordpress.com/2012/08/25/full-blue-cheesy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/84ba1e74a26a90fd9111d6569a41b8be?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">forestcat72</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e4/Moon_merged_small.jpg/300px-Moon_merged_small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Moon as seen by an observer from Earth. So...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/31/William_Shakespeare.jpg/75px-William_Shakespeare.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">William Shakespeare</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6f/Beethoven.jpg/75px-Beethoven.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Portrait Ludwig van Beethoven when composing t...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/b6/Jules_Verne.jpg/75px-Jules_Verne.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Poe&#039;s novel inspired later writers, including ...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheesy</title>
		<link>http://jingsandthings.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/cheesy/</link>
		<comments>http://jingsandthings.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/cheesy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jingsandthings</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jingsandthings.wordpress.com/?p=141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I admit it. I’m a cheese freak, a cheese chomper, a cheese lover. I’m not addicted to its taste and texture, at least I don’t think I am, but meals and life would be bland without cheese. Ever since I can remember cheese has captivated me. When young, it was Scottish Cheddar, occasionally Dunlop. That’s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I admit it. I’m a cheese freak, a cheese chomper, a cheese lover. I’m not addicted to its taste and texture, at least I don’t think I am, but meals and life would be bland without cheese.</p>
<p>Ever since I can remember cheese has captivated me. When young, it was Scottish Cheddar, occasionally Dunlop. That’s all that was available. Traditional Scottish cheeses had disappeared and it took decades for us to rediscover the will and prowess for making fabulous cheese.</p>
<p>Process cheese entered the arena, its slices alluring to those who disliked cutting slices for sandwiches; or the triangles of the spreading variety whose taste hovered somewhere between plastic and sawdust with a consistency that stuck to teeth and roof of mouth like rogue bubble-gum mixed with wood glue.</p>
<div id="attachment_142" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 209px"><a href="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-6747.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-142" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-6747.jpg?w=199&h=300" alt="Cheese store" width="199" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cheese being matured in a small creamery near Ludlow</p></div>
<p>No, for me cheese has to be cheese. The natural and simple process of turning milk into cheese was first revealed to me on a school trip to a farm in Ayrshire. The education department obviously thought children raised in Glasgow didn’t know what a cow looked like, despite most of us having easy access to the countryside. My enduring memory of that visit was the overpowering animal smell. I seem to remember it was the pigs. Of the cheese-making process I remember nothing.</p>
<p>For packed lunches at school and later, a chunk of cheddar and an apple was often my choice. Though when I worked in one place in Glasgow city centre I was able to indulge all my cheesy fantasies. Ferguson’s, I think the place was called, a large upmarket tearoom, near the Central Station, selling wondrous choux pastry concoctions, alongside a delicatessen I’d never seen the like of before but which is now replicated in a constrained and shadowy form in every supermarket.</p>
<div id="attachment_143" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-6743.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-143" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-6743.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="Shelves of cheese" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Round cheeses maturing under a mould.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_151" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-67441.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-151" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-67441.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="Woman inspecting shelves of maturing cheeses." width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cheeses are turned and inspected regularly</p></div>
<p>From the moment hand pushed open door, the aroma of pungent cheese and herby, garlicky or spicy meats enveloped the customer. A counter that swept from door into the dim recesses of the shop was decorated by a myriad of colours and shapes. Cold meats and salamis I never knew existed, and the most tastebud-drooling array of cheeses, soft, hard, medium, cow, ewe, goat. I was in seventh heaven and set out to work my way through them all, buying a sliver of each, five days a week for my lunch. Sadly, I now can’t remember whether I achieved my aim. Perhaps, I found a few I really liked, at a price I could just about afford, and stuck to them.</p>
<p>Over the years I’ve been fascinated by seeing the milk to cheese transformation take place in a number of dairies, large and small, cool and damp, making firm, crumbly and soft cheeses such as crowdie. In one large establishment, saying it was up north keeps it safely vague, husband and I were horrified to discover the smoked cheese we occasionally bought never saw a smokery. Our vision of cheeses carefully smoked over slow burning oak chips was shattered when we saw a bottle of artificial smoked flavour tilted into the vat. We’ve never bought that particular cheese since, and steer well clear of any other food labelled smoked unless we are assured of the authenticity of the process.</p>
<div id="attachment_145" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0209.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-145" title="IMG_0209" src="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0209.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="French cheese shop" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A cheese shop in Montmartre, Paris, open at the front to make it almost impossible to walk past.</p></div>
<p>Cheese remains a favourite food, sometimes cooked, sometimes on a slice of homemade bread, occasionally just a slice or chunk surreptitiously enjoyed on its own while making a meal. Camembert is a favourite, thought best enjoyed in private as the smell can lead guests to wonder what nasties lurk in fridge and kitchen. Pecorino has recently become a staple, replacing Parmesan, as it’s easier to grate and the depth of flavour means it’s economic to use and zings in quiches and on homemade pizzas.</p>
<p>In recent years Scotland has emerged from the dark side of the moon. A look at the Taste of Scotland website lists a wonderful array of cheeses made here. In fact reading through them I’m almost tempted to do what I did all those years ago with the cheeses in Ferguson’s, and work my way steadily through them. Though perhaps I already have!</p>
<div id="attachment_146" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0208.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-146" title="IMG_0208" src="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0208.jpg?w=1024&h=767" alt="French cheese shop" width="1024" height="767" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">La Fromagerie Lepic in Montmartre, Paris. Just the place for a cheese lover.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jingsandthings.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/cheesy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/53404f918bada5efb005a588984864dc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jingsandthings</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-6747.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-6743.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/library-67441.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0209.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0209</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jingsandthings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0208.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0208</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paralympics 2012 &#8211; Opening Ceremony</title>
		<link>http://takingtheshortview.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/paralympics-2012-opening-ceremony/</link>
		<comments>http://takingtheshortview.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/paralympics-2012-opening-ceremony/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 10:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>andrewlewin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paralympics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://takingtheshortview.wordpress.com/?p=1506</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And so for 11 more days the flame burns brightly in the east, with the London Paralympics 2012 open for business after a lengthy opening ceremony so packed with high-brow science and arts that it made Danny Boyle&#8217;s Olympics shindig a month ago look a bit common. Boyle had clearly got all the money and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1506&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And so for 11 more days the flame burns brightly in the east, with the London Paralympics 2012 open for business after a lengthy opening ceremony so packed with high-brow science and arts that it made Danny Boyle&#8217;s Olympics shindig a month ago look a bit common.</p>
<p>Boyle had clearly got all the money and there was a definite sense that this show was made on a fraction of that budget, but in some ways not only was that not a problem, it was an advantage: this ceremony was consequently more human and more intimate, more about individuals and their hopes and dreams than it was about impressive spectacle.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be honest, until the last couple of weeks I had no idea that the concept of the Paralympics had been seeded in a British forerunner, the 1948 International Wheelchair Games at Stoke Mandeville for WW2 veterans with spinal cord injuries. It was held on the same day as the opening of the 1948 London Olympics, and was the revolutionary idea of Sir Ludwig Guttmann (a German doctor who escaped Nazi Germany before the start of the war) which transformed the way that treatment of such patients with disabilities were approached. Instead of viewing his patients as men whose lives were essentially over bar the dying, Guttmann used sport to prove to them that they could still achieve great things whatever their injuries; and from that, not only did the Paralympics proper come into being in 1960, but the whole medical approach and treatment of people with disabilities was transformed for all time. It&#8217;s something that Britain can be very proud of having played such a crucial part.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s also a daunting legacy to live up to. The Olympics opening ceremony had the audacious aim of trying to define what it meant to be British &#8211; not only to overseas audiences, but to the British themselves; the Paralympics opening show, by contrast, could allow itself to be no where near as parochial. Its aim was nothing less than to show what it means to be <i>human</i>, in all its diverse and equally wonderful forms and guises.</p>
<p>The Paralympics ceremony took on <i>The Tempest</i> theme that Boyle had started a month previously, and ran with it. Where Boyle&#8217;s opening credo had been Caliban&#8217;s line &#8220;Be not afeard, the isle is full of noises,&#8221; here the central plank of what followed was from Miranda: </p>
<blockquote><p>How many goodly creatures are there here!<br />
How beauteous mankind is!<br />
O brave new world,<br />
That has such people in it!</p></blockquote>
<p>It was intended as a celebration both of what defines us as a species, but also of our individual uniqueness. Or as Professor Stephen Hawking put it: &#8220;We are all different, there is no such thing as a standard or run-of-the-mill human being, but we share the same human spirit.&#8221;</p>
<p>With such lofty and worthy aspirations, this opening ceremony didn&#8217;t have the freedom to convey the same sense of wicked humour, anarchy and subversiveness that made Boyle&#8217;s Olympics opener so joyously brilliant, but it had its moments: a section on the importance of books and a moment to pause and reflect on reading rooms (a.k.a. libraries) carried the same sort of implied rebuke to current government cost-cutting fervour as had Boyle&#8217;s section on the NHS. And what certain sections of the government backbenches will have made about the prominence of the United Nations’ Universal Declaration of Human Rights there, or the recreated equal rights demonstration that followed, can only be imagined. </p>
<p>Arguably the best bit of subversiveness came spontaneously from the home team ParalympicsGB, a sizeable majority of whom seemed to have pointedly hidden their identification lanyards out of sight so that the sponsorship of Atos &#8211; the company behind the loathed assessments throwing hundreds of thousands of disabled people off employment support allowance &#8211; was resolutely concealed.</p>
<p>But the ceremony did carefully and rather brilliantly seed itself with nods back to its Olympics counterpart a month before, by no means ending with retaining <i>The Tempest</i> theme. The music had something of the same mix of the opening ceremony, with some beautifully moving epic yet human newly composed classical-sounding pieces, Orbital providing the techno in place of Underworld, and David Bowie&#8217;s &#8220;Heroes&#8221; once again blasting out to welcome the arrival of the home team at the end of the parade of athletes. </p>
<p>Where the Olympics had relished the chance to play once-forbidden songs by the Sex Pistols and Frankie Goes to Hollywood, Wednesday night featured a cover version of &#8220;Spasticus Autisticus&#8221;, itself once banned because of the language used about the disabled. That&#8217;s despite having been written by Ian Dury, who suffered a debilitating attack of polio aged seven: the choice was sublimely perfect to show how things had changed (and how in some ways they hadn&#8217;t.) And where the Olympics opening ceremony was opened by Sir Kenneth Branagh, this time we had Sir Ian McKellen; and where we&#8217;d earlier had a brief cameo from Sir Tim Berners-Lee, this time there was Professor Hawking. It was an almost &#8220;whatever you can do, we can match it&#8221; nod at Boyle&#8217;s earlier spectacular; but in this show, McKellen and Hawking got far bigger, more important parts to play than Branagh and Berners-Lee ever had. </p>
<p>McKellen as Prospero had the lead role in the show along with Nicola Miles-Wildin as Miranda, and did a perfect job that only improved still further when he was able to cast off Prospero&#8217;s robes at the end and party down with his co-stars, all of them looking like they were all having the time of their lives. And Hawking was brilliantly used as the intelligence of the show working as the narrator/master of ceremonies, carefully announcing the themes of the show as it progressed.</p>
<p>&#8220;Look at the stars and not down at your feet,&#8221; said Hawking early in proceedings, encapsulating the spirit of what was to come. &#8220;Be curious.&#8221; </p>
<p>The overall message was that if we do indeed look up and dare to dream, then we can all achieve truly astonishing things with our lives no matter our individual circumstances or the issues and obstacles that confront us: whether in science and technology as in Hawking&#8217;s own case, or in the performing arts (some brilliant dancers and singers emphatically proved this point), or in the field of sporting excellence that is after all what the Paralympics is most centrally about.</p>
<p>Downsides to the evening? Well, it did overrun by nearly an hour and some of the Paralympians were starting to look very cold and tired by the end, but that was doubtless due to certain inevitable logistic points such as the pace of the athletes&#8217; parade that couldn&#8217;t be hurried. And one could whinge about a less-than-stellar performance by the Channel 4 broadcasters, who looked as though they were painfully learning how to do this sort of thing on the job. Their deficiencies were only highlighted by the inclusion of experienced hand Clare Balding, fresh from being quite the best thing of the BBC Olympics coverage two weeks before (does she ever sleep?) </p>
<p>But the howls of outrage from viewers that Channel 4 should dare interrupt the ceremony for advertising breaks were misplaced. They are, after all, a commercial broadcaster flying without the aid of the BBC license fee, and this is the reality of the media business. After all, this is how the rest of the world saw London 2012 as a whole. We were just very, very lucky indeed that our own experience in the UK was filtered through the advert-free BBC prism, and rather than being outraged about Channel 4&#8242;s ad breaks it would be more appropriate to take the time to remember how very special a thing the BBC is &#8211; and how it needs to be protected from being broken up by any thoughtless politicians looking for cheap headlines.</p>
<p>The best thing of all about Wednesday&#8217;s ceremony was that it was the perfect salve to heal the memories of the Olympics&#8217; closing ceremony, with its gaudy, superficial vacuousness so inappropriate to the 16 days of achievement and aspiration that had preceded it. The Paralympics ceremony did much to restore that sense of wonder and awe in which we had been basking up to then.</p>
<p>Key to that was the cauldron: in one sense this was the cost-saving re-use of a second-hand prop from the Olympics, and yet it was so much more than that. Seeing it where we had left it a fortnight before &#8211; still splayed open but now cold and dark &#8211; evoked a sense of melancholy even as it linked the two events together. So when Margaret Maughan (the winner of Britain’s first Paralympic gold medal in Rome in 1960) lit the cauldron anew at the end of a near four-hour ceremony, it was a sense of hope and wonder that was being reignited along with it. </p>
<p>Seeing the cauldron burst into light and reassemble itself was the perfect antidote to the downbeat ending of the Olympics: it said that even when things are over, they can be rekindled and reignited and can live again. Dreams never truly die as long as someone, somewhere still carries the torch and keeps it safe.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1506/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1506/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1506&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://takingtheshortview.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/paralympics-2012-opening-ceremony/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/30da04041508a925e45d279490d99c09?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">andrewlewin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Barrio Of Kitsch</title>
		<link>http://theurgetowander.com/2012/08/25/the-barrio-of-kitsch/</link>
		<comments>http://theurgetowander.com/2012/08/25/the-barrio-of-kitsch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 12:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Madhu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buenos Aires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Photo Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benito Quinquela Martín]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caminito]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colourful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graffitti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[La Boca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Street Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tourism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theurgetowander.com/?p=8019</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is edgy, it is seedy and it is touristy. And it probably deserves all the bad press it receives. But there is no denying the sense of drama and theatre in the psychedelic barrio of La Boca. A throwback to its maritime history and the meshing of cultures of early immigrant settlers. The name [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8019&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://theurgetowander.com/2012/08/25/the-barrio-of-kitsch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>91</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/header11.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/header11.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graffiti, La Boca</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/becf26ec7326c58cfbb4c6b9275b882f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mashet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graffiti and local kids. Note shoes on cables above!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graffiti and the ubiquitous shoes :-)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">El Caminito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">El Caminito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Conventillo turned souvenir shop! Note wax model of a lady doing laundry below the stairs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Windows and Balconies of a painted Conventillo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tacky tourist photo op :-)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-111.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street and Tango bar sighnboard</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-6-a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Buildings facing the Vuelta de Rocha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Statue of Benito Quinquela Martín in the Plaza</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Vuelta de Rocha. The Benito Quinquela Martín museum (not seen in this pc) is adjacent to the blue building on the left</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">View of the ferry bridge - Puente Nicolas Avellaneda - painted orange, with the newer bridge of the same name in the foreground. The ferry bridge is the only one of its kind outside Europe.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/martin-mural.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A tile mural reproduction of Quinquela Martín&#039;s &#34;Dia de Trabajo&#34; (Working day) by Ricardo Sanchez</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graffiti celebrating the Bomberos Voluntarios de la Boca/ Volunteer Fire Department of Boca</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-14.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Windows, El Caminito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-15.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Crumbling old mansions in the seedier part of the Barrio</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-13.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">El Caminito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-4.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graffiti 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theurgetowander.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/la-boca-8.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fundacion Proa - an arts center with a library, rooftop cafe and auditorium.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tyranny of Inspiration</title>
		<link>http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/the-tyranny-of-inspiration/</link>
		<comments>http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/the-tyranny-of-inspiration/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 02:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jennifer Lynn Krohn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judgements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poets and Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/?p=430</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This doesn’t happen to me anymore.  But through my latter years of high school and my first few years of college, the one time I was guaranteed to be inspired was when I was driving.  I’d switch lanes and suddenly a line pop into my head.  With one hand, I’d pull a pen from my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=430&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This doesn’t happen to me anymore.  But through my latter years of high school and my first few years of college, the one time I was guaranteed to be inspired was when I was driving.  I’d switch lanes and suddenly a line pop into my head.  With one hand, I’d pull a pen from my purse, and whenever I stopped at a red light I scribbled, as quickly as I could, on my arm, praying that the light would not change.  At those moments, I seemed to catch all the green lights.  When I arrived home, I transcribed the words scrawled across my skin, desperate to find that spark I felt when I was getting off the freeway.  What I was able to save seemed to die on the page, in that rush to catch the muse’s words I missed something and that magic was lost.</p>
<p>As of late, I’ve been hearing and reading a lot about how poets must allow the poem find its own way, to remove their ego from the process.  If they start out with an idea of what the poem should be, they will suffocate it by trying to make it fit that mold.  I think that this is true—poems are about discovering the unknown.  However, I often felt that my own process is antithetical to this concept; I start with ideas.  Well, maybe I should say I start with questions that I try to answer.  What if Bluebeard had a wife who hadn’t looked in the bloody chamber?  How did Pygmalion’s statue feel about her transformation?  What is in the bathtub buried in my neighbor’s backyard?  Why did our friendship end?  This process still has room for discovery, yet it seems so constricting when compared to the process of other poets.  After all, from the onset of the poem I imagine that I will find an answer.</p>
<p>I suspect that I don’t really understand the process of the other poets.  One thing that I don’t lack is sense of insecurity. So when someone responds to my statement that “I revise the hell out of my poems” with the fact that they tend to do minimal revisions, I don’t take the take the statement as it was meant—a simple observation in the differences in our process—but as a reprimand.  In the end, I can’t escape the feeling that my work is contrived, lacks inspiration, and that I’m strangling it with revision (apparently, I’m my own worse critic).</p>
<p>Yet, when I’m writing I’m often surprised by what shows up on the page.  In one poem where I’m deal with the fairy tale, “<a title="East of the Sun. West of the Moon" href="http://www.surlalunefairytales.com/eastsunwestmoon/index.html" target="_blank">East of the Sun, West of the Moon</a>,” I found it interesting that the bear the heroine married was considered monstrous, but that his human form that visited each night was welcomed without fear (on the part of the heroine).  I started writing with the question “What if the human half is the real monster?”  A few drafts, in I wrote the lines, “Mother should&#8217;ve told me/to light a lamp,/ warned me/ that it was the devil/ who visited each night.”  The poem had veered away from the fairy tale.  In subsequent revisions, the girl never left home, and I realized that the poem was about incest.  Revision had led me into territory I had not planned to enter that I would probably have never choose to write about.  Like I said, writing is about discovery.</p>
<p>Perhaps the reason that I so doubt my writing process is because it seems to lack that quality of inspiration.  Inspiration—I imagine is when you suddenly feel electrified words burst forth, and they seem to crystallize that very moment.   When I write, I sit down and trudge.  I try to get an idea on the page.  It is usually awful, so I come back the next day and interrogate the thing—I revise.  Sometimes it leads me nowhere—sometimes I write what I (presumptuously) call a poem.  After a good day of writing, I have the same feeling I get after a day of moving or cooking or cleaning.  I’m tired, but I’ve accomplished something.  I don’t feel the elation, the energy of inspiration.</p>
<p>When I go through my old notebooks and look at the car poems—I see ideas that never should have made it to the page.  In that moment of what seemed to be inspiration—when I drove dangerously for what I hoped to be a poem—I’d just gotten an idea, an idea of what I wanted a poem to be.  This so-called inspiration did not allow me to examine each word, to question my assumptions, to let the poem breath and grow with each new draft.  After all, who was I to doubt the muse?  At the time of writing, those words seemed to lack ego, to appear out of the ether.</p>
<p>Looking back, I wonder why I mistook those moments for inspiration, why when I write now I feel that my process is lacking though the writing is leaps and bounds better.  Maybe, it was because those moments of elation were so similar to those moments of coming across a great line or paragraph when reading.  Maybe I subconsciously thought that writing must feel like reading that it should simply flow and that there are moments of epiphany.  But writing is nothing like reading, the same way baking is nothing like eating a slice of cake.  It seems so obvious, but it is hard to resist the elation, to resist what seems to be inspiration.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 438px"><img src="http://www.friendsofart.net/static/images/art2/alphonse-mucha-poetry.jpg" alt="Poetry by Alphonse Mucha " width="428" height="693" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Poetry by Alphonse Mucha</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/430/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/430/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=430&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/the-tyranny-of-inspiration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/01b8403573d4d1673b42c287ec035bb6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jennifer Krohn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.friendsofart.net/static/images/art2/alphonse-mucha-poetry.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Poetry by Alphonse Mucha </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mt. Kalatungan Climb – Day 2</title>
		<link>http://nagbabasangpinoy.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/mt-kalatungan-climb-day-2/</link>
		<comments>http://nagbabasangpinoy.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/mt-kalatungan-climb-day-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 05:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tintin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bukidnon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mountains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mountain climbing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mountaineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mt. Kalatungan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pangantucan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nagbabasangpinoy.wordpress.com/?p=1810</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First part: Mt. Kalatungan Climb – Day 1 It was a cold, gusty morning on the summit of Mt. Kalatungan and our tent was still miraculously upright. Raging winds gave it a serious beating the previous night. There was a puddle of water inside and our sleeping bags were wet, which explained why our asses [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1810&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://nagbabasangpinoy.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/mt-kalatungan-climb-day-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-forest-1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-forest-1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan forest 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7ee7e8a4d48cd7a34b696d292d5f0e1a?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nagbabasang pinoy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-summit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan summit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bangkaso.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bangkaso</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-summit-group-photo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan summit group photo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dwarf-bamboo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dwarf bamboo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/water-source.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">water source</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-bamboo-campsite.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan bamboo campsite</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fern-garden.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fern garden</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lumpanag-peak.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lumpanag Peak</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/manobo-guides.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Manobo guides</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tintins-peak2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tintin&#039;s Peak2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tintins-peak.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tintin&#039;s Peak</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thorny-plant.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thorny plant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-forest-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan forest 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-forest-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan forest 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kalatungan-forest-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kalatungan forest 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/red-mushroom.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">red mushroom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/huge-tree.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">huge tree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nagbabasangpinoy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_9598.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9598</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Standing on the Shoulders of Gnats</title>
		<link>http://airandangelsblog.com/2012/08/29/standing-on-the-shoulders-of-gnats-2/</link>
		<comments>http://airandangelsblog.com/2012/08/29/standing-on-the-shoulders-of-gnats-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 14:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>airandangelsblog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://airandangelsblog.com/?p=81</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m a fully paid-up member of Generation Y &#8211; you know, the one that&#8217;s meant to be incapable of putting away its childish things and properly growing up. So, in between watching classic episodes of Thundercats on Youtube and snogging my Rick Astley posters, I thought I&#8217;d have a go at blogging about some of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=81&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 317px"><a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thundercats-w11.jpg"><img class="wp-image-121 " title="Thundercats-w11" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thundercats-w11.jpg?w=307&h=242" alt="" width="307" height="242" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Gratuitous Thundercats picture</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m a fully paid-up member of Generation Y &#8211; you know, the one that&#8217;s meant to be incapable of putting away its childish things and properly growing up. So, in between watching classic episodes of <em>Thundercats </em>on Youtube and snogging my Rick Astley posters, I thought I&#8217;d have a go at blogging about some of the books I remember from childhood &#8211; the ones that inspired me, informed me and ultimately made me want to write myself. In other words, the &#8216;giants&#8217; of the literary canon.</p>
<div id="attachment_120" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 199px"><a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/penguin-classics-clothbound1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-120" title="penguin-classics-clothbound" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/penguin-classics-clothbound1.jpg?w=189&h=172" alt="" width="189" height="172" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Worthy Stuff</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">I guess this is the bit where I&#8217;m supposed to wax lyrical about my precocious love for the classics &#8211; how I devoured <em>The Secret Garden</em>, sped through <em>Treasure Island</em> and wept over <em>Little Women</em> before moving seamlessly on to meatier stuff like <em>Pride and Prejudice</em> and <em>Wuthering Heights</em>. But that wouldn&#8217;t be entirely true. We&#8217;ve talked a lot on my MA course about what constitutes a &#8216;classic&#8217; children&#8217;s novel, and why some books are admitted to the pantheon of literary greats while others are left out in the cold. A lot of it has to do with snobbery, and the power wielded by adult parents, teachers and authors over what children read. My personal definition of a classic is anything my parents would have deemed &#8216;educational&#8217;. My parents were suckers for anything &#8216;educational&#8217;. Being an observant sort of kid, I worked out early on that I could get pretty much anything I wanted, providing I could come up with some tenuous way that it would further my intellectual development. This might not, in reality, have led to any great enlightenment, but it certainly led to some bumper Christmasses.</p>
<div id="attachment_125" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 232px"><a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pony1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-125 " title="pony" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pony1.jpg?w=222&h=222" alt="" width="222" height="222" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pony Porn</p></div>
<p>And so I had whole shelves of appropriately wholesome and edifying books, many of which I never actually got round to reading. Some of them I genuinely loved &#8211; I thought <em>Heidi</em> was great, and I remember racing through <em>Peter Pan</em> and <em>Alice in Wonderland. </em>But the books I remember most clearly from my formative years aren&#8217;t the ones my parents would have approved of -  and they certainly don&#8217;t belong to any &#8216;canon&#8217;. In fact, in most cases they&#8217;d be considered (whisper it!) rather lowbrow.</p>
<p>During my preteen pony-fetish phase, for instance, when I nearly bankrupted my parents by demanding weekly lessons and all the accompanying kit before abruptly tiring of all things equine, I insisted on reading absolutely anything that had the world &#8216;pony&#8217; in the title. All of these books were pretty much interchangeable: <em>Pony Club Cup</em>, <em>Pony Club Camp</em>, <em>Pony Club Orgy</em> &#8211; you get the idea. Their literary value was secondary to their ability to describe horses in spectacularly florid language, some of which would put <em>Fifty Shades of Grey</em> to shame: <strong>&#8216;<em>He was a magnificent bay stallion, a pure-bred Arab, whose rippling muscles were much in evidence beneath his glossy withers.</em>&#8216;</strong> OK, so I just made that up, but I exaggerate only slightly. I absolutely lapped up this kind of stuff when I was eight.</p>
<p><a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/chalet-school.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-480   alignright" title="chalet school" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/chalet-school.jpg?w=134&h=222" alt="" width="134" height="222" /></a></p>
<p>Then there were the school books &#8211; I was addicted to the Chalet School series, all 58 of which are similarly identical, except that here you replace the word &#8216;pony&#8217; with a 1940s Euro-posh girl&#8217;s name, as in <em>Carola Storms the Chalet School</em>/<em>Lavender Laughs in the Chalet School</em>/<em>Theodora and the Chalet</em> School etc. Indeed, I may have my past obsession with all things Alpine to blame for eventually opting to study German at university, a decision that I&#8217;m still recovering from now.</p>
<p>The Chalet School girls&#8217; exploits segued smoothly into those of Jessica and Elizabeth Wakefield in the <em>Sweet Valley High</em> series, which was in a broadly similar vein except that boys, kissing and fashion replaced the latent sapphic tendencies of the Chalet School girls. Even at 10 or 11 I recognised that these books were appallingly written; every single Sweet Valley book started off with a description of the Wakefield twins&#8217; &#8216;silky blond hair&#8217;, &#8216;perfect size 6 figures&#8217; and &#8216;almond-shaped eyes the blue-green of the Caribbean&#8217;. And they were horribly <a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/playing-with-fire_300.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-155" title="playing-with-fire_300" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/playing-with-fire_300.jpg?w=135&h=225" alt="" width="135" height="225" /></a>all-American &#8211; the boys were all called things like Todd and Bruce and Chad. And yet I loved them still.</p>
<p>The end of primary school marked the end of school stories and the start of my Judy Blume period. (&#8216;Period&#8217; being a highly appropriate word, given that Judy Blume was a tad obsessed with the things.) There was <em>Are You There God?, It&#8217;s Me, Margaret</em>, and <em>Blubber</em> and <em>Tiger Eyes</em>. And then, of course, there was <em>Forever</em>, which made its way around the class in a kind of sacred adolescent ritual, each sweaty-palmed twelve-year-old passing it on silently but knowingly to their successor. At least, the kids who got it at the beginning might have passed it on knowingly &#8211; by the time it got to me it was only about three chapters long, anxious parents long since having removed anything faintly risqué. I had to go and read the rest in the Enfield branch of Ottakar&#8217;s while my dad lurked in the gardening section. <a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/forever-judy-blume1.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-488" title="forever-judy-blume" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/forever-judy-blume1.jpg?w=152&h=215" alt="" width="152" height="215" /></a></p>
<p>Having been duly enlightened by <em>Forever</em>, my next literary passion was Virginia Andrews&#8217; <em>Flowers in the Attic</em> series. These books had <em>everything: </em><strong>Sex!</strong> (And not just any sex, but <em>incest</em>, which was simultaneously horribly wrong and weirdly compelling) <strong>Dwarves!</strong> (Actually twins who had stunted growth because they&#8217;d been kept in a windowless attic for five years). <strong>Wonderfully implausible plotlines!</strong> (Hmm&#8230;a heroine who <a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/flowers-in-the-attic-vc-andrews.jpg"><img class="wp-image-116 alignleft" title="flowers-in-the-attic-vc-andrews" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/flowers-in-the-attic-vc-andrews.jpg?w=136&h=214" alt="" width="136" height="214" /></a>spends her entire adolescence locked in an attic becomes a world-class ballerina on her release? ) Not to mention characters who, way before the Kardashians, had satisfyingly alliterative names: Cathy &#8211; Chris &#8211; Carrie &#8211; Cory &#8211; Corrine. Just brilliant.</p>
<div id="attachment_498" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 153px"><a href="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/stephen-king-it.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-498" title="stephen-king-it" src="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/stephen-king-it.jpg?w=143&h=215" alt="" width="143" height="215" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Never trust a clown.</p></div>
<p>And then there were the horror stories, which I started reading around the time of the inevitable &#8216;Sleepover, Pizza And Scary Video&#8217; phase &#8211; lots of Stephen King, and one book whose title I&#8217;ve forgotten (Witch Spell? Witch Child?) which involved people being decapitated by hockey balls and the main character doing unspeakable things with a crucifix in the bath. That one terrified me so much that I convinced myself the book itself was &#8216;haunted&#8217;, and at one point couldn&#8217;t sleep with it in my room. Overactive imagination, moi?</p>
<p>How does all this literary nostalgia relate to my own writing? Well, it&#8217;s hardly rocket science &#8211; basically, it&#8217;s reminded me that whatever I write should be enjoyable to read. I&#8217;ve always thought of myself as a pretty high-minded kind of girl where books are concerned &#8211; I studied literature-based subjects at university, I&#8217;ve worked for a literary publishing company and I&#8217;ve spent the past five years trying to wean the children I teach off series fiction like <em>Animal Ark</em>, <em>My Secret Unicorn</em> and those ubiquitous <em>Rainbow Fairies.</em> But, don&#8217;t you know, it turns out that, when it comes to sheer emotional engagement with what I read, my tastes are determinedly lowbrow. None of these books are &#8216;classics&#8217; in the usual sense of the word, but I remember most of them much more vividly than all the worthy tomes that were quietly gathering dust on my bookshelf. Well-meaning parents may buy books because they&#8217;re &#8216;classics&#8217; &#8211; but children choose to read them because they&#8217;re fun. And if my readers happen to learn something while they&#8217;re having fun, then that&#8217;s all to the good.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/81/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/81/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=81&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://airandangelsblog.com/2012/08/29/standing-on-the-shoulders-of-gnats-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thundercats-w11.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thundercats-w11.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thundercats-w11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c6e6912ffc82850cf67ccc05dd05a992?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">airandangelsblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thundercats-w11.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thundercats-w11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/penguin-classics-clothbound1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">penguin-classics-clothbound</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pony1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pony</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/chalet-school.jpg?w=181" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chalet school</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/playing-with-fire_300.jpg?w=180" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">playing-with-fire_300</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/forever-judy-blume1.jpg?w=108" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">forever-judy-blume</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/flowers-in-the-attic-vc-andrews.jpg?w=191" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">flowers-in-the-attic-vc-andrews</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://airandangelsblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/stephen-king-it.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stephen-king-it</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tapestry of Poems</title>
		<link>http://unsungpoet.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/tapestry-of-poems/</link>
		<comments>http://unsungpoet.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/tapestry-of-poems/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 23:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Unsungpoet</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astral Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reincarnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spirits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Cosmos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Elements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://unsungpoet.wordpress.com/?p=1427</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our migrations as peoples and as tribes of souls repeat themselves again and again Like strange holograms across the land Footsteps eternal through mysterious time Tracing the passion of all our lives We&#8217;re all connected by these hallowed glowing trails more precious than the Holy Grail Cast my shadows to the wind and move on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1427&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sedona-hwy-copy1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1428" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sedona-hwy-copy1.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="414" /></a></p>
<p>Our migrations as peoples<br />
and as tribes of souls<br />
repeat themselves again and again<br />
Like strange holograms across the land<br />
Footsteps eternal through mysterious time<br />
Tracing the passion of all our lives<br />
We&#8217;re all connected by these hallowed glowing trails<br />
more precious than the Holy Grail</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cliff-dwelling-az.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1429" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cliff-dwelling-az.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="463" /></a></p>
<p>Cast my shadows to the wind<br />
and move on forward into tomorrow<br />
I get a feeling that&#8217;s primitive, mystical<br />
dreamlike and familiar<br />
My spirit whistled through the pines with the wind<br />
every time I needed to see you<br />
Drop in on your aura<br />
Lovingly haunt your house</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/my-spot-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1430" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/my-spot-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="445" /></a></p>
<p>Raindrops hold the most cherished of memories<br />
Sweet fragrance to the soul<br />
like the memories of our cells<br />
which hold our bodies in sweet ransom<br />
Spinning throughout, within and without<br />
Spinning to the ground in telltale spirals<br />
Cosmic little powerhouses of feeling and vision<br />
Each nucleus harboring another waking dream</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sutro-baths.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1431" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sutro-baths.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="444" /></a></p>
<p>The wind comes in and brushes my skin<br />
Rattles the window pane, freshens my brain<br />
It blows on my candles, stretching the flame<br />
Painting pictures in the shadows<br />
Spirits come rushing in on a radical whim<br />
Spinning off of barren walls<br />
Demanding to know what gives</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sutter-st-pidgeons.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1432" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sutter-st-pidgeons.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a><br />
The rain relents to a soft cool blanket of drizzly mist<br />
Pigeons shuffle through puddles and clumsily patter from ledge to ledge<br />
Water drops falling from their feathers<br />
Luxurious fog drapes down between the skyscrapers<br />
Cables hum and whine with an unearthly pitch<br />
Vibrating the wet grey streets<br />
Aroma of spices and sea salt in the air<br />
It&#8217;s a perfect San Francisco day</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/rooftop-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1433" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/rooftop-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="430" /></a><br />
Changing of the times<br />
Passing of eras<br />
Season&#8217;s friction<br />
Creation&#8217;s nectar<br />
Brute force, sweet surrender<br />
Brings me to my knees<br />
Makes my soul scream<br />
Looking backward<br />
Looking forward<br />
are essentially the same<br />
when your heart exists<br />
on the plateau with a view of eternity</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baba-in-field-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1434" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baba-in-field-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="452" /></a></p>
<p>The person that existed<br />
The girl I used to be<br />
doesn&#8217;t live here anymore<br />
She&#8217;s gone away<br />
to a far off star</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pink-panther-sportie-with-cami-2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1435" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pink-panther-sportie-with-cami-2.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="529" /></a><br />
The wellspring of my heart<br />
is very often the site where I take a fall<br />
Still, the love that lives there<br />
is the lingering spark that will save us all</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/old-friends-from-oz-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1436" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/old-friends-from-oz-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="361" /></a></p>
<p>After all life has always been about facing up your fears<br />
Walking the dim horizon of your deepest nightmare<br />
and shining light there<br />
Someday the words will be written across the sky<br />
There&#8217;ll be no need for scripted lies<br />
No need for lies, no more goodbyes</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/upper-east-side-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1439" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/upper-east-side-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="396" /></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve seen the last of the war zone<br />
The wreckage is under control<br />
Let&#8217;s just take a moment to sit in peace and breath deeply<br />
Like that wind breathing through the treetops</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sun-through-eucalyptus-treetops.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1440" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sun-through-eucalyptus-treetops.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="414" /></a></p>
<p>The vibrant echoing light of the dawn<br />
The sparkling amber of twilight<br />
Colorful portals where sleepy angels yawn<br />
Where souls rest at ease, a hallowed site</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sunset-bird.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1441" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sunset-bird.jpg" alt="" width="671" height="499" /></a><br />
The wind comes blowing<br />
howling, rushing, humming, moaning<br />
Whispering in deep breaths<br />
of another shore<br />
of an invisible sprawling ocean<br />
harboring life beyond imagination<br />
Boats and dinghies bob along the surface<br />
Masts ringing and clanging in the chimes by the door<br />
The tide is too strong to fight now<br />
I close my eyes<br />
and sail away</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/mesa-redondo-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1442" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/mesa-redondo-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="475" /></a><br />
Light drizzle passing by in the secret hours<br />
The first of a long hot spell<br />
Nature&#8217;s baptismal<br />
Praise!<br />
Moon and star charms hang low in the sky<br />
Peeking out from behind stillness haze<br />
Jewelry for my senses<br />
Shining in my mind&#8217;s eye<br />
with hope, with vision<br />
Rooster crows in the distance<br />
New day is just over my comfortable, dark horizon</p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/purple-flower-dusk-large.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1443" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/purple-flower-dusk-large.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="439" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kenny-uncle-harvey-2-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1444" title="" src="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kenny-uncle-harvey-2-copy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="533" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1427/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1427/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1427&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unsungpoet.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/tapestry-of-poems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f187d87bfd1eaa051dafe175c22e9f85?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unsungpoet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sedona-hwy-copy1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cliff-dwelling-az.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/my-spot-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sutro-baths.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sutter-st-pidgeons.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/rooftop-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baba-in-field-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pink-panther-sportie-with-cami-2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/old-friends-from-oz-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/upper-east-side-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sun-through-eucalyptus-treetops.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sunset-bird.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/mesa-redondo-copy.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/purple-flower-dusk-large.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://unsungpoet.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kenny-uncle-harvey-2-copy.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prints Charming</title>
		<link>http://gnumedialab.wordpress.com/2012/08/28/prints-charming/</link>
		<comments>http://gnumedialab.wordpress.com/2012/08/28/prints-charming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>gnumedialab</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gnumedialab.wordpress.com/?p=1622</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Film is dead. Processing is dead. Heck, Kodak is almost dead, too. But printing is a whole other proposition. Turns out there is still a present and a future in printing photographs. Anyone who visits my office will instantly see my walls covered with gigantic canvas prints of my photography made by CafePress.com and PictureItOnCanvas.com. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1622&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Film is dead. Processing is dead. Heck, Kodak is almost dead, too. But printing is a whole other proposition. Turns out there is still a present and a future in printing photographs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Anyone who visits my office will instantly see my walls covered with gigantic canvas prints of my photography made by CafePress.com and PictureItOnCanvas.com. Just the other day, I saw a Kickstarter.com campaign for a startup called Instacube, through which users will be able to wirelessly beam their Instagram pics to a desktop digital viewer. And then they can contact CafePress to order canvas prints of those same Instagram snaps.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Yeah, we really are enamored of our photographic skills, aren&#8217;t we? Ansel Adams would have loved living today.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">So I was instantly intrigued this morning to read about the new <a href="http://www.heraldonline.com/2012/08/28/4218211/walgreens-launches-photo-by-walgreens.html" target="new">Walgreens Facebook photo app</a> in which you can send your Facebook photos to Walgreens, and it will even include all the Likes, Shares and friendly comments.</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">&#8220;Hey, there&#8217;s your next canvas!&#8221; my research partner and most excellent friend Dr. Kris Drumheller poked.</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">&#8220;And then again, maybe not,&#8221; the nonplussed Marketing professor replied. </span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><img src="https://wtclass.wtamu.edu/AngelUploads/Content/2012FA_MKT_6340_70/_assoc/blogpics/walgreensapp.jpg" alt="" width="280" align="left" border="0" hspace="5" vspace="5" />But it&#8217;s interesting nonetheless. Photography took a sudden turn around 1996 with the introduction of digital cameras. Film, processing and printing started a precipitous decline. Apparently we secretly yearned for printed pics, though, even if all our pics were reduced to a bunch of code. And that&#8217;s how and why companies like CafePress and PictureItOnCanvas are doing gangbuster business. </span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Except for one little problem, in my estimation. Who wants their photos, complete with artistic angle, sepia tone filter and tilt shift blur, to be printed along with FB commentary? I&#8217;m not sure I want that on a 5X7, much less a 24X30 canvas print. Furthermore, I&#8217;m not sure my FB friends want their comments hanging on my wall, either.</span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">But I do have to credit Walgreens for a very clever app, one that leverages the changes around us, the technology, and the highly social aspect of our computing lives. This is a home run, even if it is near the foul pole.</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Sure, some will cry they have been quoted without permission, but that&#8217;s the risk we all take with social media. If you don&#8217;t want others to Share or Retweet, then don&#8217;t post it. Which means that given this latest wrinkle in FB partnerships, we had all better be a lot more careful with what we say in response to other people&#8217;s pictures. The last thing you want is your so-called friend with a drinking problem to print pics from your last party together. Worse yet, let&#8217;s just suppose you replied with a hearty &#8220;Party on, dude! That was one awesome night!&#8221;</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">So as we continue to evolve in the social media era, let us use more caution in all that we say and do, and especially what we do in front of someone else&#8217;s camera. While I still applaud Walgreens for a timely novelty, there are some things that you do not want or need to be in print. Or one someone&#8217;s desk or wall.</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Because your future should not hinge on a photograph from the past, no matter how witty your comment may have been. </span></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;"><span style="font-family:arial;font-size:small;">Dr &#8220;Present Tense&#8221; Gerlich</span></span></span></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1622/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1622/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1622&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gnumedialab.wordpress.com/2012/08/28/prints-charming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2e421f175e4f14fb1dd7d0c7639b6d64?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gnumedialab</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://wtclass.wtamu.edu/AngelUploads/Content/2012FA_MKT_6340_70/_assoc/blogpics/walgreensapp.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building the Tallest Sandcastle</title>
		<link>http://bsclarified.wordpress.com/2012/08/09/building-the-tallest-sandcastle/</link>
		<comments>http://bsclarified.wordpress.com/2012/08/09/building-the-tallest-sandcastle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 20:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cath</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts by Cath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[everyday science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bsclarified.wordpress.com/?p=1783</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Canadian National Exhibition (CNE) opens in Toronto next Friday (can’t wait!) and they hold an international sand sculpting competition every year. I’m always impressed by the size and detail of these sculptures and wonder if the competitors ever consider the science that’s behind their work? Recently, I came across an interesting piece of research [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1783&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">The Canadian National Exhibition (CNE) opens in Toronto next Friday (can’t wait!) and they hold an international</span> <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Axz4wo0gI2U">sand sculpting competition</a> <span style="color:#000000;">every year. I’m always impressed by the size and detail of these sculptures and wonder if the competitors ever consider the science that’s behind their work?</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">Recently, I came across an interesting piece of research on <a href="http://www.nature.com/srep/2012/120802/srep00549/full/srep00549.html" target="_blank">Nature.com</a>&#8216;s Scientific Report on</span> <span style="color:#000000;"><em>How to construct the perfect sandcastle</em>. Maryam Pakpour of the Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences in Iran, and colleagues from the University of Amsterdam in the Netherlands and the Laboratorire de Physique Statistique de l’ENS in France investigated to answer this question by determining the relationship between height and stability of a sandcastle.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">Just by scooping up a handful of dry beach sand, you know that you can’t build a sandcastle with it. Dry sand simply won’t hold any kind of shape as it can hardly support its own weight. You can transform these loose grains of sand into an “adhesive”, formable material by adding water. Wet sand holds because water forms liquid bridges between sand grains. But add too much water and you’re left with an unstable pile of sand that ultimately collapses (think landslides).</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">Aside from water content, the stability of sandcastles is equally dependent on having a sturdy base. Just look at the</span> <a href="http://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/1/tallest-sandcastle">world’s tallest sandcastle</a><span style="color:#000000;"> which stands at 11.53 m high. Built by Ed Jarrett of the United States, his</span> <a href="http://jarrettscastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/DSC_1042-e1307575006725.jpg">sandcastle</a><span style="color:#000000;"> has a fairly large base and progressively narrows towards the top.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_1796" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 209px"><a href="http://bsclarified.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ed-jarrett.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1796" title="ed jarrett" src="http://bsclarified.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ed-jarrett.jpg?w=199&h=300" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">World&#8217;s tallest sandcastle (Source: <a href="http://jarrettscastle.com/">http://jarrettscastle.com/</a>)</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">In this research, the team started by investigating the stability of columns of wet sand, which would allow them to determine the maximum height of sandcastles that could be built. The idea is that a column of sand reaches its maximum high when it starts to buckle under its own weight.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The team report a mathematical model that accounts for the maximum strength of sand packing, and density, and gravity and also verified their model experimentally. They found that the maximum height (h) varies with the radius of the column (R) as h<sub>max</sub> ~ R<sup>2/3</sup>. Beside the size of the sandcastle base, the model shows the height of the sandcastle could be increased by increasing the compaction of sand (a known technique to sandcastle builders). Furthermore, decreasing the density of the sandcastle would also allow a taller sandcastle to be built. The team tested this idea by building their sandcastle underwater, decreasing the effective density of the sandcastle.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><img src="http://www.nature.com/srep/2012/120802/srep00549/images_article/srep00549-f4.jpg" alt="" width="336" height="239" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">A sandcastle built underwater</span></p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">The team notes that normal beach sand can’t be used to build underwater sandcastles because the liquid bridges holding the sand grains together get destroyed. But they show it’s possible to build an</span> <a href="http://www.nature.com/srep/2012/120802/srep00549/images_article/srep00549-f4.jpg">underwater sandcastle</a> <span style="color:#000000;">using commercially available hydrophobic (water-hating) sand because air rather than water forms the bridges between sand grains.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">The tallest “sandcastle” the team built was a uniform cylinder that stands at 1 m tall, so it is unlikely that competitive sandcastle builders will follow the team’s “recipe” on building the perfect sandcastle&#8211;especially when it comes to building sandcastles with complex shapes and designs. However the study offers an improved understanding of the behaviour of partially saturated granular materials, and may be useful to those working with geophysical applications such as soil stability.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">&#8211;</span><br />
<span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=Scientific+reports&amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F22870378&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=How+to+construct+the+perfect+sandcastle.&amp;rft.issn=&amp;rft.date=2012&amp;rft.volume=2&amp;rft.issue=&amp;rft.spage=549&amp;rft.epage=&amp;rft.artnum=&amp;rft.au=Pakpour+M&amp;rft.au=Habibi+M&amp;rft.au=M%C3%B8ller+P&amp;rft.au=Bonn+D&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Computer+Science+%2F+Engineering"><span style="color:#000000;">Pakpour M, Habibi M, Møller P, &amp; Bonn D (2012). How to construct the perfect sandcastle. <span style="font-style:italic;">Scientific reports, 2</span> PMID:</span> <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22870378" rev="review">22870378</a></span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">Featured image by Flickr&#8217;s marc e marc</span></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1783&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bsclarified.wordpress.com/2012/08/09/building-the-tallest-sandcastle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://bsclarified.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/marc-e-marc-photo.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://bsclarified.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/marc-e-marc-photo.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marc e marc photo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6a5a1970f638452fa25aa01a709ab9bf?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">feore24</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bsclarified.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ed-jarrett.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ed jarrett</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.nature.com/srep/2012/120802/srep00549/images_article/srep00549-f4.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>