<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>A Sabbatical from the Twitters</title>
		<link>http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/a-sabbatical-from-the-twitters/</link>
		<comments>http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/a-sabbatical-from-the-twitters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 21:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Mom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook drools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mute button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media abstinence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social-media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter sabbatical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter timeout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/?p=3166</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m on a Twitter sabbatical. It&#8217;s not my first. But it&#8217;s the first one I haven&#8217;t blogged through. Usually I&#8217;m over at TechFanatix  complaining about it the entire time. Crying. Languishing. Not this time though. I&#8217;m not taking a Twitter time-out because I have nothing to say. I always have something to say. Whether you want [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3166&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/a-sabbatical-from-the-twitters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic12.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic12.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/424dc8e90c207d3aaf64012f88f5590a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amandalfultz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic11.png?w=461" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic12.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic11.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Prayer Surrender?</title>
		<link>http://christianthought.hbu.edu/2013/02/28/is-prayer-surrender/</link>
		<comments>http://christianthought.hbu.edu/2013/02/28/is-prayer-surrender/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Halton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benedict]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://christianthought.hbu.edu/?p=906</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Paolo Flores d’Arcais wrote a breathtaking blog post for the New York Review of Books. It’s one of the most trenchant attempts to interpret Benedict XVI’s resignation that I’ve read. He explores the theological implications of a Spirit-inspired Vicar of Christ on Earth saying that he is too old to continue in his divinely appointed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=906&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://hbuchristianthought.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/filepapa_benedetto.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-915 alignleft" alt="Benedict XVI" src="http://hbuchristianthought.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/filepapa_benedetto.jpeg?w=200&#038;h=300" width="200" height="300" /></a>Paolo Flores d’Arcais wrote a breathtaking <a href="http://www.nybooks.com/blogs/nyrblog/2013/feb/28/papal-surrender/">blog post</a> for the <i>New York Review of Books</i>. It’s one of the most trenchant attempts to interpret Benedict XVI’s resignation that I’ve read. He explores the theological implications of a Spirit-inspired Vicar of Christ on Earth saying that he is too old to continue in his divinely appointed task. Is the Holy Spirit not able to strengthen him and the church during a time of mortal weakness?</p>
<p>This is a weighty question, to be sure. But what intrigued me even more is d’Arcais’s speculation that in the face of raging power struggles that are bringing the Church to her knees, Benedict decided to surrender. To scamper off to Castel Gandolfo and after that to a former convent. Too old and feeble to fight, the now Pope Emeritus chose to pray.</p>
<p>But should we equate prayer with surrender? The author of Ephesians writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re not waging war against enemies of flesh and blood alone. No, this fight is against tyrants, against authorities, against <i>supernatural</i> powers <i>and demon princes that slither</i> in the darkness of this world, and against wicked <i>spiritual armies</i> that lurk about in heavenly places (6:12, The Voice).</p></blockquote>
<p>Possibly, Benedict had this passage in mind when he received the report he commissioned in the wake of the “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vatileaks_scandal">Vatileaks scandal</a>.” Scheming priests, money laundering bankers, and blackmailing bishops – they are just bit players in a much bigger game. Their sins would take some doing to unravel but the real challenge would be addressing the evil that propels them. That’s something that no pope, no matter how physically fit, is able to do on his own.</p>
<p>At this point – emotionally dead, physically frail, and spiritually tired – perhaps Benedict thought of Christ at Gethsemane. After his closest friends failed him and a trusted advisor betrayed him, Jesus faced his own death. The Pope may have seen similarities between his circumstances and those of his Lord. Intriguingly, Christ responded to all this by retreating in prayer.</p>
<p>If we keep reading we find that after this night of passionate petition Jesus went to his death and, as the Gospels confess, death was defeated in resurrection. Jesus didn’t surrender to pray, he prayed to continue the fight. But it was a fight that was won through self-sacrifice and persistent – defiant, even – prayer.</p>
<p>To many, Benedict’s decision seems like a foolhardy act of cowardice at best and a negligent abdication of his religious duty at worst. He gave up at a time when the church needed him the most. Yet, it might be that, in Benedict’s mind, he was taking the fight to a whole other level.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/906/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/906/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=906&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://christianthought.hbu.edu/2013/02/28/is-prayer-surrender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d0208e9e3576afaa9b5f1f4b740d3426?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">akismet-d0208e9e3576afaa9b5f1f4b740d3426</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hbuchristianthought.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/filepapa_benedetto.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Benedict XVI</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Culling, Cultural Consumption &amp; the Myth of Eternal Boredom</title>
		<link>http://homespunresources.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/culling-cultural-consumption-and-the-myth-of-eternal-boredom/</link>
		<comments>http://homespunresources.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/culling-cultural-consumption-and-the-myth-of-eternal-boredom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 18:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jenncavanaugh</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pressings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Readings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Six Ways to Sunday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultural Literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eternal Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://homespunresources.wordpress.com/?p=347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just happened upon &#8221;The Sad, Beautiful Fact That We&#8217;re All Going to Miss Almost Everything&#8221;  by Linda Holmes. It struck me as Lenten in tone, in the sense of learning to choose one good thing over another and learning to live in the balance of healthy grief and letting go. It also fits with what I try to articulate in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=347&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just happened upon &#8221;The Sad, Beautiful Fact That We&#8217;re All Going to Miss Almost Everything&#8221;  by Linda Holmes. It struck me as Lenten in tone, in the sense of learning to choose one good thing over another and learning to live in the balance of healthy grief and letting go.</p>
<p>It also fits with what I try to articulate in my book about approaching cultural goods and literacy as a Christian. I&#8217;ll pull in some significant quotes, but it&#8217;s worth reading <a title="The Sad, Beautiful Fact That We're All Going to Miss Almost Everything" href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/monkeysee/2011/04/21/135508305/the-sad-beautiful-fact-that-were-all-going-to-miss-almost-everything?sc=tw" target="_blank">here</a> in its entirety.</p>
<blockquote><p>there are really only two responses if you want to feel like you&#8217;re well-read, or well-versed in music, or whatever the case may be: culling and surrender.</p>
<p>Culling is the choosing you do for yourself. It&#8217;s the sorting of what&#8217;s worth your time and what&#8217;s not worth your time. It&#8217;s saying, &#8220;I deem <em>Keeping Up With The Kardashians</em> a poor use of my time, and therefore, I choose not to watch it.&#8221; It&#8217;s saying, &#8220;I read the last Jonathan Franzen book and fell asleep six times, so I&#8217;m not going to read this one.&#8221;</p>
<p>Surrender, on the other hand, is the realization that you do not have time for everything that would be worth the time you invested in it if you had the time, and that this fact doesn&#8217;t have to threaten your sense that you are well-read&#8230;. It is the recognition that well-read is not a destination; there is nowhere to get to, and if you assume there is somewhere to get to, you&#8217;d have to live a thousand years to even think about getting there, and by the time you got there, there would be a thousand years to catch up on.</p></blockquote>
<p>I carry around with me distinct memories of conversations with wonderfully engaged people who decided Christianity was not for them because they deemed heaven boring. If it literally consists of throwing down a single crown then standing around forever in a white robe, I&#8217;d have to agree. I think we&#8217;ll be free to come and go from the throneroom. I think the new heaven and the new earth will include all the best of the current heaven and earth &#8211; anything made with lasting value. The nations will bring their treasures, and we&#8217;ll wander the stacks in the Library at Alexandria and the galleries of the Hermitage, hit homers at Wrigley Field, do a little restoration work then catch some improv at the Globe Theatre, kick back at a Chinese movie palace, have falafel with Tolstoy, and meditate in the stone garden of Ryoanji.</p>
<div id="attachment_372" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://homespunresources.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ryoanji.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-372  " alt="" src="http://homespunresources.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ryoanji.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I could see Ryoanji becoming one of Augustine&#8217;s favorite thinking spots.</p></div>
<p>Best of all we&#8217;ll have the freedom and time to enjoy these places and artifacts in perfect relationship with others and to make more wonders together. And when they inspire us to the classic prayer &#8220;Wow,&#8221; we&#8217;ll know we&#8217;re heard and by Whom. Any time someone applauds our efforts, we&#8217;ll head back to the throneroom with that spiffy new crown, pausing to play pick-up games of frisbee with it along the way to give others credit where due, toss it in the pile, and sing a spell. The ancient Greeks envisioned a placid eternity without novelty. Jesus comes to make all things new.</p>
<blockquote><p>What I&#8217;ve observed in recent years is that many people, in cultural conversations, are far more interested in culling than in surrender. And they want to cull as aggressively as they can. After all, you can eliminate a lot of discernment you&#8217;d otherwise have to apply to your choices of books if you say, &#8220;All genre fiction is trash.&#8221; You have just massively reduced your effective surrender load, because you&#8217;ve thrown out so much at once.</p>
<p>The same goes for throwing out foreign films, documentaries, classical music, fantasy novels, soap operas, humor, or westerns. I see people culling by category, broadly and aggressively: television is not important, popular fiction is not important, blockbuster movies are not important. <em>Don&#8217;t talk about rap; it&#8217;s not important. Don&#8217;t talk about anyone famous; it isn&#8217;t important. And by the way, don&#8217;t tell me it is important, because that would mean I&#8217;m ignoring something important, and that&#8217;s &#8230; uncomfortable. That&#8217;s surrender.</em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s an effort, I think, to make the world smaller and easier to manage, to make the awareness of what we&#8217;re missing less painful.</p></blockquote>
<p>This sort of aggressive culling heightens culture war tensions in the unspoken name of self-protection; we cannot categorically dismiss hip hop or sci-fi or romantic comedy without communicating categorical dismissal of those who identify culturally with the genre. Pretty much anything you can&#8217;t be bothered with has changed another person&#8217;s life, and the larger that mental category, the truer that statement becomes. This is why I believe that Christians need to learn this balance of being discriminating without being discriminatory. We follow a Savior who came to break down the dividing walls of Jew and Greek, male and female, and so on. Adopting this vocabulary of culling and surrender would be preferable to us slamming entire swaths of culture because we heard somewhere they fail to edify. We could claim our preferences for Pixar over Saw franchises as personal choice rather than holy writ and ascribe our inabilities to enter and understand the worlds of Persian poetry, Japanese anime, and <em>Grey&#8217;s Anatomy </em>to our limited human resources of time and attention rather than defensively portraying them as unworthy of them. We can make choices and lament our limitations without making the world artificially small and manageable.</p>
<blockquote><p>If &#8220;well-read&#8221; means &#8220;not missing anything,&#8221; then nobody has a chance. If &#8220;well-read&#8221; means &#8220;making a genuine effort to explore thoughtfully,&#8221; then yes, we can all be well-read. But what we&#8217;ve seen is always going to be a very small cup dipped out of a very big ocean, and turning your back on the ocean to stare into the cup can&#8217;t change that.</p></blockquote>
<p>We&#8217;re human. We are always missing relatively everything. Let&#8217;s not pretend otherwise. We can celebrate that there is so much to miss, enjoy what we&#8217;ve been given, and look forward to more.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=347&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://homespunresources.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/culling-cultural-consumption-and-the-myth-of-eternal-boredom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fdb59e26e8096ba35ab026427021a8c8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jenncavanaugh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://homespunresources.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ryoanji.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>St. David’s Day Welsh Cakes</title>
		<link>http://edibleswansea.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/chapatti-pan-and-spice-st-davids-day-welsh-cakes/</link>
		<comments>http://edibleswansea.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/chapatti-pan-and-spice-st-davids-day-welsh-cakes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mredible</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A little knowledge is a dangerous thing.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Griddle Cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Llangynwyd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patron saint of wales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swansea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Welsh Cakes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edibleswansea.wordpress.com/?p=964</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today is the Feast of St. David, the patron saint of Wales, which means I have reached for the chapatti pan again.  Like many Welsh children I tried to eat Welsh cakes as soon as I could after they had come off the griddle; soft and melting, one was left with a burned my mouth [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=964&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://edibleswansea.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/chapatti-pan-and-spice-st-davids-day-welsh-cakes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6870ab6d25652ce083340bda64264401?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mredible</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/y-bwlwarcau-hillfort-llangynwyd-middle-bridgend-2003.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Y Bwlwarcau Hillfort, Llangynwyd Middle, Bridgend. RCAHMW. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/thumb635x353.jpg?w=250" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Collecting calennig in Llangynwyd. National Museum Wales. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ann-romney-hands-out-welsh-cakes-to-the-press-on-the-flight-to-tampa-942262994.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/food-014.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/food-018.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo: Mr Edible. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/food-022.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo: Mr Edible. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://edibleswansea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/food-031.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo: Mr Edible. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>At the Table</title>
		<link>http://andreabadgley.com/2013/03/01/at-the-table/</link>
		<comments>http://andreabadgley.com/2013/03/01/at-the-table/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 21:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>andreabadgley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[At home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner table]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshly pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home comforts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homemaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pie chart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andreabadgley.com/?p=2872</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There’s one thing you can be sure of in parenting: as soon as you think you’ve got it all figured out, everything changes.  I had finally gotten dinners going in a good rhythm: a rotation of three weeks worth of menus, complete with protein and produce options for all four palates in our family (daughter [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2872&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://andreabadgley.com/2013/03/01/at-the-table/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c946a587fd9b2d9e1f396f6996772fba?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">andreabadgley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andreabadgley.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/how-i-spend-my-waking-hours_pie-chart_andreabadgley33.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">How I spend my waking hours: Food Domination Pie Chart on andreabadgley.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tourism as Direct Trade</title>
		<link>http://elcafehabla.com/2013/03/01/tourism-as-direct-trade/</link>
		<comments>http://elcafehabla.com/2013/03/01/tourism-as-direct-trade/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 16:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rachel Northrop</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Existential Traveler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Field Notes: what it looks like on the ground]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[direct trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fair trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panama tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[When Coffee Speaks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://elcafehabla.com/?p=455</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Smart locals. These are the ones who spent their childhoods sweating on the family farm, but realized that their land could give them something more. Smart locals are the ones whose families have spent their lives being ripped off by North Americans and Europeans buying their products at prices below the cost of production; they’re [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=455&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_456" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 557px"><a href="http://elcafehabla.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1466.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-456" alt="Go directly to the source" src="http://elcafehabla.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1466.jpg?w=547&#038;h=820" width="547" height="820" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Go directly to the source</p></div>
<p>Smart locals. These are the ones who spent their childhoods sweating on the family farm, but realized that their land could give them something more. Smart locals are the ones whose families have spent their lives being ripped off by North Americans and Europeans buying their products at prices below the cost of production; they’re the ones who saw tourists on the horizon and realized it was time to make back all that money.</p>
<p>Smart locals see that agriculture is a good way to stay broke. They see that as much as those North Americans and Europeans like to eat bananas and chocolate and buy so many tropical products, they like to come to the tropics. And if they’re coming, they’re coming with money to burn.</p>
<p>Smart locals are the ones who turn their aunt’s vacant house into a bed and breakfast, who don’t try to cut corners but who try to create mini luxuries. They’re the ones who sold half the blackberry finca to have money to invest in opening a hostel, or a restaurant, or a liquor store or a tour company. They’re the ones who built a hotel on the edge of the family orange orchard to be able to market the accommodations as having a “tranquil garden view” on the list of amenities.</p>
<p>Smart locals put a logo on the side of their car and turn it into a taxi service. Smart locals know that when tourists come, they come with money to spend on food and activities and drinks and sleep. They don’t see these droves of foreigners as a threat to their culture or an annoyance, they see them as a chance to make enough money to put a new roof on their house, get their kids braces and send them to college.</p>
<p>Smart locals are entrepreneurial and happy to pocket the piles of bills tourists’ shell out, as compensation for all the money their foreign ancestors never paid to anyone local.</p>
<p>When you travel, you have choices around how to spend your money. You can go to the foreign owned Hilton, or you can seize your vacation as an opportunity to exercise a small form of social justice. You can eat at restaurants owned by locals, stay at hotels owned by the same, and go on tours run by people who are in and of the place you’re visiting.</p>
<p>On a coffee tour of a tiny mill a local coffee farmer built from scratch, a tourist asked if the coffee was Fair Trade. The guide (himself a local) responded, “when you buy a bag of this coffee you put the money into Don Tito’s hand. <i>That’s</i> fair trade.”</p>
<p>If you’re already planning on taking a vacation and you’re already ready and set to travel, take the time to seek out locales where the money will go straight into locals’ hands. It’s not up to us to judge whether or not the local uses the money to build and orphanage or to buy a bunch of beer or to get his daughter a smartphone or to give his car a new paint job; we’re no one’s financial administrators. Truly fair trade means paying people enough so that they can survive and then some, and how they manage the ‘and then some’ is entirely up to them. Truly fair trade means letting people make just as many mistakes with their money as we do with ours.</p>
<p>With tourism we are able to go directly to the places that were pillaged and economically flattened by so many years of unfair and exploitative imperial trade. And here we come- two weeks off and a bonus burning a hole in our pockets. We have the not quite rare, but certainly not common opportunity to put our cash directly into people’s hands. So buy some bananas and sugar and chocolate and coffee and kiwis and avocados and all the things that normally pass through so many middlemen just to make it to our frozen homes. Pay the tropics back for a history of injustice by turning your tourism into a species</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/category/coffee-2/'>Coffee</a>, <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/category/existential-traveler/'>Existential Traveler</a>, <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/category/field-notes-what-it-looks-like-on-the-ground/'>Field Notes: what it looks like on the ground</a> Tagged: <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/tag/coffee/'>coffee</a>, <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/tag/direct-trade/'>direct trade</a>, <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/tag/fair-trade/'>fair trade</a>, <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/tag/panama-tourism/'>Panama tourism</a>, <a href='http://elcafehabla.com/tag/when-coffee-speaks/'>When Coffee Speaks</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/455/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=455&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://elcafehabla.com/2013/03/01/tourism-as-direct-trade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8ce98693f379013e87fa882ee8b89649?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rachelnorthrop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elcafehabla.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1466.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Go directly to the source</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Time to Come Out</title>
		<link>http://sxchristopher.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/time-to-come-out/</link>
		<comments>http://sxchristopher.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/time-to-come-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 19:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>sxchristopher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sexuality and Identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coming out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[openly gay athletes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sxchristopher.wordpress.com/?p=1941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A fortnight ago American soccer player Robbie Rogers, a former Leeds United player, came out. In a statement published on his blog, Rogers described his relief at finally being rid of the secret that he had harbored for years and the happiness he felt with his decision: Life is only complete when your loved ones [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1948" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 326px"><a href="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/robbie_rogers.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1948" alt="Gareth Thomas, ex-United Leeds winger, comes out" src="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/robbie_rogers.jpeg?w=316&#038;h=438" width="316" height="438" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Winger Robbie Rogers comes out, retires from soccer</p></div>
<p>A fortnight ago American soccer player Robbie Rogers, a former Leeds United player, came out. In a <a href="http://robbierogers8.moonfruit.com/" target="_blank">statement </a>published on his blog, Rogers described his relief at finally being rid of the secret that he had harbored for years and the happiness he felt with his decision:</p>
<blockquote><p>Life is only complete when your loved ones know you. When they know your true feelings, when they know who and how you love. Life is simple when your secret is gone. Gone is the pain that lurks in the stomach at work, the pain from avoiding questions, and at last the pain from hiding such a deep secret.</p></blockquote>
<p>He spoke of how football had been his purpose and identity, but an escape as well. “Football hid my secret, gave me more joy than I could have ever imagined.”</p>
<p>And then he said he would no longer be playing. “Now is my time to step away,” he writes. “It’s time to discover myself away from football.”</p>
<p>Coming out is hard, and we each do it in our own way. I respect Rogers’ courage and admire the public manner in which he shared this with his fans and the rest of the world. There are countless gay teenage athletes, girls and boys alike, in whose lives this statement will make a difference, however small and fleeting that may be.</p>
<p>“Life is so full of amazing things,” he writes at the end of his statement. “I realized I could only truly enjoy my life once I was honest.” A powerful message, but a mixed one, too.</p>
<p>I found it sad that Rogers’ coming out would coincide with his retirement from soccer, as if he couldn’t be gay (a word he doesn’t actually use in his 400-word statement) and play the sport at the same time. It could be a coincidence, but I suspect not.</p>
<p>But it’s enough that he said it</p>
<p>He’s the not the first, of course. Dozens of professional athletes have come out, though many, like Robbie Rogers, only after they stopped competing. But their stories count. Olympian biathlete Joan Guetschow, one of the first lesbian athletes to come out <i>while</i> competing, once <a href="http://lesbianlife.about.com/od/lesbiansinsports/a/LesbianOlmypian.htm" target="_blank">described in an interview</a> how the Billy Jean King story helped her come out at as young age “I was relieved to know… even a great athlete like her felt similar to the way I felt.”</p>
<p>Gareth Thomas was another athlete who did it while playing. In 2009 he came out as the only gay professional rugby player (and by the way received the quick support of both his team, the Cardiff blues, and the Welsh Rugby Union). In an interview with BBC, Thomas expressed his hope that one day a young gay rugby player could come out and be accepted as a &#8220;talented gay rugby player”.</p>
<p>More gay and lesbian athletes—and actors and politicians and singers and all those who share the public stage and could serve as role models for gay youth—need to take this step. I believe they have an <i>obligation </i>to do so. In fact, I believe <i>all </i>gay men and lesbians have an obligation to be out not only to our friends and family but out at our workplace and in our community as well.</p>
<p>I have a hard time convincing even some of my gay friends about this, the public part, I mean. But I wanted to try anyway and I thought a letter might be a good way to start. A letter to someone who was comfortable with their sexuality but has come out only to close friends and maybe members of the family. I have an athlete in mind, but it could be anyone who enjoys some degree of visibility, an actor or teacher or singer. A scientist or politician, perhaps. Or indeed anyone with a professional, work or community audience. Which I suppose is probably all of us.</p>
<div id="attachment_1942" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 350px"><a href="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gareth_thomas.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1942  " alt="Gareth Thomas" src="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gareth_thomas.jpg?w=340&#038;h=396" width="340" height="396" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Gareth Thomas, the only gay professional rugby player to have come  out while playing</p></div>
<p>Maybe you’ve forgotten what it was like back then. Before you came out to yourself and then to your friends. Before you accepted who you are, long before that acceptance deepened into a kind of affirmation. Before you became proud, not so much of being different but of having come this far and being able to live your life authentically, or, as much as you can “given the circumstances.” Now the thought of <i>deliberate</i> disguise seems absurd. This hard-won self, with all its imperfections and failings of character, may betray a friend in a moment of weakness but won’t deny its nature. But making a statement, this public <i>declaration, </i>that’s another thing, you say. Too in-your-face.</p>
<p>You say, “What I do in my private life is no one’s business. I’m out to the people who matter. To my family and friends.”</p>
<p>But you’re not out at work, and if you’re an athlete or actor, not to your public.</p>
<p>Maybe you&#8217;ve forgotten what it was like to be gay in high school. Of course you have memories of back then, and some of them are unhappy. But they have no edge. You’ve lost that visceral feeling, the pain in the gut that Rogers noted, the intimidation of the locker room, the overwhelming pressure not to stand out. And even if you didn’t stand out and played football or ran cross-country for the school, you forget how ill at ease you felt when your teammates bragged about their sexual exploits or when they joked about faggots, and how that made you even more watchful of what you said and did.</p>
<p>The locker room of professional athletics may still be homophobic, but you’re more confident now. You’re a professional doing his or her job, with respect off and on the field, and you’re not alone any more. Maybe some of your teammates even know. But that&#8217;s as far as it goes.</p>
<p>You don’t deny your sexuality but instead relegate it to the backstage. It’s not a closet you withdraw to and you’re not ashamed of it, nor should you be. The bars and gay-friendly restaurants, the houses of your friends, straight and gay, sometimes your parents’ home, too—these are places you can be yourself, comfortable with those who are like you or who accept you.</p>
<p>But it is a small space you have carved for yourself. And though you have found allies and lovers and like-minded friends, your circumspection is not all that different from the watchfulness that marked your youth.</p>
<p>You’ve forgotten how alone you once felt. You were sure there wasn’t anyone like you on the team, and maybe even worse, there wasn’t a gay hockey or baseball player <i>anywhere</i>.</p>
<p>But you’ve moved beyond that, you say. Who even wants to remember those years? You’re comfortable now, maybe even happy with who you are. What you do in bed isn’t anyone else’s business, you say.</p>
<p>Perhaps you’d be right if it were <i>only </i>a question of what goes on in the bedroom—who’s on top, where you most like being kissed, what turns you on. Yes, this is no one’s business at all. It could even be seen as just one more variant of the sexual act, a somewhat broader category of fetish than a penchant for feet, say.</p>
<p>But it’s not just the <i>act</i> of sex. It’s all the stuff that happens <i>outside </i>the bedroom that’s important. And this is often very much a <i>public</i> affair.</p>
<p>You know that already, though. If we’re in a long-term same-sex relationship, we pay different taxes, have different health insurance coverage and have a different (zero) share in our partner’s retirement benefits than a married couple will. If our company gives an extra allotment to its married employees, it probably doesn’t give the same to us.</p>
<p>It not just laws and policies. I’m not talking about the big things, the ones that create “statements”, like whom we bring to the company picnic or how we introduce our boyfriend at a cousin’s wedding. I’m thinking instead of all the times we hear colleagues talk about their (opposite-sex) spouses and lovers, all the thousands of references to (straight) sex that come to us, narrated, illustrated, sung about and painted. You&#8217;ve listened quietly to stories countless times. Sex is supposed to be the quintessential private act, (usually) played out in the most intimate of domains: the bedroom. But it’s not, in fact, so private. It’s <i>always</i> there, this attraction. The act itself may (often) be concealed but desire is everywhere to be seen. And isn’t that our difference—desire?</p>
<p>And because it is desire and not color of skin or the shape of our lips that marks us, we are perhaps the only minority that can render its property of difference invisible, in a way that those of race or disability or age cannot.</p>
<p>We are the only minority that has struggled for equal rights while at the same time claiming the privilege to remain invisible—as if we <i>already</i> lived in that ideal tolerant society in which our difference no longer matters.</p>
<p>Not all of us, naturally. Millions of gay men and lesbians have come out not only to friends and family but also at work and in the various communities which they’re a part of. And some to their fans and teammates and voters. But we could certainly be a <em>lot </em>more visible.</p>
<p>But you say you don’t pretend to be straight. You are simply discrete. You say you haven’t given your colleagues or audience cause to believe<i> </i>you’re straight or gay, either way. You think that in the eyes of others your sexual orientation simply doesn’t have a value: it’s unknown or inapplicable, to be supplied later, if at all—a perfect null value.</p>
<p>But people, like database designers (for a different reason) are uncomfortable with nulls, and in their dealings with colleagues and acquaintances will ascribe a <i>default</i> value, often subconsciously, to all sorts of properties they know nothing about, including sexual orientation. You are assumed to be straight in the absence of evidence or cues to the contrary. Your reticence in speaking about your life—the part you say is no one’s business—makes you an accomplice to this ascription. And this matters.</p>
<p>If our sexual orientation <i>were </i>more often in-your-face, so to speak, as inescapably present and visible as skin color, perhaps we would reach that society of tolerance we dream about more quickly. We are not a silent minority, but in certain fields—I think of cinema and sports—we are a relatively (and in the NFL, a completely) <i>invisible</i> one.</p>
<div id="attachment_1951" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 379px"><a href="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/megan_rapinoe.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1951 " alt="Megan Rapinoi, openly lesbian professional soccer midfielder" src="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/megan_rapinoe.jpg?w=369&#038;h=475" width="369" height="475" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Megan Rapinoe, openly lesbian professional soccer player</p></div>
<p>I sometimes fantasize about a massive coming-out party, televised across the world, a kind of We-are-the-world happening, with gay and lesbian actors and athletes, all those men and women we’ve seen in the movies and Nike and Gatorade endorsements, in sit-coms and post-play interviews, now joining their voices in an amazing song of self-affirmation, not for themselves really, and perhaps not even for gay young people alone.</p>
<p>But that’s not going to happen. Coming out is so hard partly because you have to do it on your own. Solo.</p>
<p>Saying that what you do in your private life is no one’s business is a wish, not a position. Legislators have already made it their business. Bullies and bigots—including those that sit in the stadium bleachers—have long made it theirs, too. Our society may have become more tolerant and the school yards and playing fields somewhat safer but gay teenagers still have a four times greater risk of suicide than their straight counterparts. Until gay youth can grow up in a climate free of fear and intimidation it is <i>everyone’s</i> business what you—we—do in our lives.</p>
<p>You say you don’t need to make a statement. But your silence <i>is</i> a statement. And it says, “I consent to my invisibility and inauthenticity.”</p>
<p>Our life is a witness to our values and beliefs.We have a responsibility to our self and our history to bear witness to what we believe is true and right. We have a responsibility to our young gay brothers and sisters.</p>
<p>You may have heard about the “<a href="http://youcanplayproject.org/" target="_blank">You Can Play</a>” project. It joins gay athletes and their straight allies to challenge the homophobia in both the locker and room and the bleachers and work toward “ensuring equality, respect and safety for all athletes, without regard to sexual orientation.”</p>
<p>They aspire to creating a culture of sports which says: “If you have skill, if you have work ethic, if you can skate, pass, shoot, run, jump, hit, row or play – then you can play.”</p>
<p>This is indeed a world where it really is no one’s business who you sleep with. With the unique opportunity that your talent, hard work and self-discipline have given you, you have a chance to help make this world happen.</p>
<p>Do it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1941/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1941/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sxchristopher.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/time-to-come-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d988b81547fb42632120bfed232aedb0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sxchristopher</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/robbie_rogers.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gareth Thomas, ex-United Leeds winger, comes out</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gareth_thomas.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gareth Thomas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sxchristopher.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/megan_rapinoe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Megan Rapinoi, openly lesbian professional soccer midfielder</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do You ♥ Words With No Letters?</title>
		<link>http://stancarey.wordpress.com/2011/08/23/do-you-%e2%99%a5-words-with-no-letters/</link>
		<comments>http://stancarey.wordpress.com/2011/08/23/do-you-%e2%99%a5-words-with-no-letters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 20:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[grammar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morphology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordplay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curse words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grawlixes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lexicography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linguistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neologisms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obscenicons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punctuation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slashdot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taboo words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[usage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stancarey.wordpress.com/?p=8983</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A recent tweet from @bengreenman posed the question: “I know that there are a number of one-letter words, but are there any words with no letters?” It got me wondering. Many of the examples that follow will be in a grey area of wordishness, and I’m liable to contradict myself and change my mind about [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8983&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent tweet from <a title="@bengreenman: &quot;I know that there are a number of one-letter words, but are there any words with no letters?&quot;" href="https://twitter.com/#!/bengreenman/status/104633561369423874">@bengreenman</a> posed the question: “I know that there are a number of one-letter words, but are there any words with no letters?” It got me wondering. Many of the examples that follow will be in a grey area of wordishness, and I’m liable to contradict myself and change my mind about some of them, but let’s see where it goes.</p>
<p><a href="http://stancarey.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/i-heart-1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-8987" style="border:1px solid black;" title="I heart +1" alt="" src="http://stancarey.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/i-heart-1.jpg?w=79&#038;h=119" width="79" height="119" /></a>The first word-with-no-letters that occurred to me, probably because it’s in vogue, was <em>+1</em>. It<em></em> has <a title="Wikipedia: +1" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%2B1_%28disambiguation%29">several</a> uses. The one I see most is as a shorthand exclamation equivalent to <em><a title="Sentence first: Hear ye this here: Hear! Hear!" href="http://stancarey.wordpress.com/2009/10/07/hear-ye-this-here-hear-hear/">Hear, hear!</a></em> or <em>I agree </em>(<em>+100</em> for <em>I strongly agree</em>), but it&#8217;s used increasingly often as a noun and a verb, with inflected forms like <em>+1’s</em>, <em>+1’d</em>, and <em>+1’ing</em>. <a title="Google +1 Button" href="http://www.google.com/+1/button/">Google+</a> is helping to popularise and standardise <a title="Google+ Help: +1 spelling conventions " href="http://www.google.com/support/profiles/bin/static.py?page=guide.cs&amp;guide=1207011&amp;answer=1237207">these forms</a>, whose punctuation and morphology were explored in recent articles by <a title="Motivated Grammar: How to spell +1′d (or is it +1ed?)" href="http://motivatedgrammar.wordpress.com/2011/07/08/how-to-spell-1d-or-is-it-1ed/">Gabe Doyle</a> and <a title="Boston Globe: Ben Zimmer: +1'tastic: When a number becomes a word" href="http://articles.boston.com/2011-07-31/bostonglobe/29836275_1_google-team-google-users-googlers">Ben Zimmer</a>.<em></em></p>
<p><a title="Official Ten-Code list" href="http://spiffy.ci.uiuc.edu/%7Ekline/Stuff/ten-codes.html">Ten-code</a> numbers are codes, or even code words, but they’re not wordish enough to be words. Neither are<em> </em>the numbers in phrases like <em>20-20 hindsight</em>,<em> the terrible 2&#8242;s</em>, and <em>at 6&#8242;s and 7&#8242;s</em>. Yet numbers do move beyond maths, codes, shorthand and set phrases to genuine lexical usage. Some become niche adjectives, and some get inflected beyond mere plurality; relatively few, however, seem to attain widespread or lasting currency.</p>
<p>Notable examples include <em>69</em>, <a title="Merriam-Webster Dictionary: 86" href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/86"><em>86</em></a>, <em>1337</em> (<a title="Wikipedia: Leet" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leet"><em>leet</em></a>), and <em>404</em>. Websites that return a 404 (“file not found”) error can be described as <em>404’d</em>, <em>404ed</em>, <em>404ing</em>, <em>404-ing</em>, and so on. A UK Post Office study found that <em>404</em> is also <a title="BBC News: Don't be 404, know the tech slang " href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/technology/7775013.stm">in colloquial use</a> as an adjective meaning <em>useless</em> or <em>clueless</em>. <a title="Word Spy: 404" href="http://www.wordspy.com/words/404.asp">Wordspy</a> has an example from <em>The Buffalo News</em>, 1999:</p>
<blockquote><p><span id="more-8983"></span>It&#8217;s rather silly that teen flicks are racking up huge box office numbers and Hollywood&#8217;s acting like it&#8217;s some earth-shattering phenomenon. Studio execs, you&#8217;re so 404.</p></blockquote>
<p>Other numbers, I&#8217;m not sure about. Do people use <em>007</em> in a wordy way? What about <em>5*</em> meaning <em>top quality</em>, <em>7-11</em> for <em>convenience store</em>, <em>24/7</em> for <em>round the clock</em>, or <a title="BBC News: Magazine: Why are 99s called that?" href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/magazine/5223328.stm"><em>99</em></a> for <em>ice cream cone with a chocolate flake</em>? You&#8217;ll have noticed that some of these mix numbers with marks or symbols. Another word that does this is <a title="Wikipedia: Last-call return" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last-call_return"><em>*69</em></a> (often written<em> star 69</em>), as in “I <a title="800notes: Directory of (UN)KNOWN Callers: 402-982-0646" href="http://800notes.com/Phone.aspx/1-402-982-0646">*69ed</a> the call.”</p>
<p>There are words with no letters <em>or</em> numbers. I mentioned two when I <a title="@StanCarey: &quot;+1, @, 86, 69, £@$*! RT @bengreenman: I know that there are a number of one-letter words, but are there any words with no letters?&quot;" href="https://twitter.com/#%21/StanCarey/status/104917861683826688">retweeted</a> the original question, to which <a title="@faduda: &quot;@StanCarey @bengreenman /.&quot;" href="https://twitter.com/#%21/faduda/status/104918142672838656">@faduda</a> replied with a good example: <em>/.</em> – a common abbreviation of <a title="Slashdot: News for nerds, stuff that matters" href="http://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</a>, e.g., &#8220;&#8230;when I got <a title="Forum OpenACS Q&amp;A: Response to Open ACS handling heavy traffic" href="http://openacs.org/forums/message-view?message_id=27148">/.-ed</a>&#8221; (meaning &#8220;when Slashdot linked to me&#8221;).</p>
<p>Another non-numerical example is <em>@</em>. <a title="my Twitter page" href="https://twitter.com/#!/StanCarey">On Twitter</a>, I see phrases like &#8220;I @&#8217;d him&#8221; and “Just @ me”, where <em>@</em> means “reply using Twitter’s @ function”. It fits the bill. A Twitter friend, KeriLynn, once @&#8217;d me <a title="@StanCarey: &quot;Anyone? RT @dreaming_iris: @StanCarey Out of curiosity, do you know of any language bloggers who have written about &quot;@&quot; being a verb?&quot;" href="https://twitter.com/#!/StanCarey/statuses/64013786012598272">to ask</a> whether anyone had written about <em>@</em>’s use as a verb, but I’m none the wiser on that front.</p>
<p>♥, the heart symbol, was added to the <em>Oxford English Dictionary</em> in March 2011 as a new sense of the word <em>heart</em>. [Correction: the heart symbol was not added, just the lexical usage.] A <a title="OED: March 2011 update" href="http://www.oed.com/public/update0311#new">commentary</a> at the <em>OED</em> website says it</p>
<blockquote><p>may be the first English usage to develop via the medium of T-shirts and bumper-stickers. It originated as a humorous reference to logos featuring a picture of a heart as a symbol for the verb <em>love</em>, like that of the famous ‘I ♥ NY’ tourism campaign. . . . heart v. has gone on to live an existence in more traditional genres of literature as a colloquial synonym for ‘to love’.</p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;I ♥ X&#8221; is a very <a title="Snowclones Database: call for variations: I [shape] X" href="http://snowclones.org/2009/04/08/call-for-variations-i-shape-x/">productive snowclone</a>, while the more convenient sideways heart &lt;3 is rife in informal contexts both online and off. It too is a word without letters, and has led to <a title="Some Bits: Another gamer emoticon" href="http://www.somebits.com/weblog/culture/games/emoticons-heart.html">variants</a> like &lt;/3, &lt;$ and &lt;4. <a title="Urban Dictionary" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/">Urban Dictionary</a> has many more: just search for &lt;3.</p>
<p>You could make a case for other emoticons, like ((())) (<em>hugs</em>) and \\\/// (<em>slaps</em>) – the number of marks varies – though these usually contain a word in the middle. And how about :-* (<em>kiss</em>)? No? What if I say a couple were :-*ing, does that enhance its wordishness?</p>
<p><a href="http://stancarey.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/comic-speech-balloon-grawlix-or-obscenicon.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-8985" title="comic speech balloon grawlix or obscenicon" alt="" src="http://stancarey.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/comic-speech-balloon-grawlix-or-obscenicon.jpg?w=146&#038;h=128" width="146" height="128" /></a>I’d like to include <a title="Language Log: Obscenicons a century ago" href="http://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=2457">obscenicons</a>, also called <a title="Grawlixes Past and Present" href="http://www.statoids.com/comicana/grawlist.html">grawlixes</a> – those strings of symbols and squiggles like <em>£#@$*!</em> that function as taboo utterances in comics and cartoons; the more creative include doodles and marks not found on any keyboards. Some obscenicons are quite transparent (e.g., @$$ and $#!+) but most are not directly translatable.</p>
<p>Along similar lines, a friend suggested ****, where the context makes it clear what word has been replaced, e.g. “You’re in deep ****, buster” or “What the **** is going on?” <a title="Sentence first: Do profanity filters dream of Philip K Dick?" href="http://stancarey.wordpress.com/2009/11/10/do-profanity-filters-dream-of-philip-k-dick/">Censored profanities</a> are a <a title="Language Log: Inventory of Language Log postings on taboo vocabulary" href="http://itre.cis.upenn.edu/~myl/languagelog/archives/003673.html">fascinating case</a>, but **** probably can&#8217;t be considered a word in its own right. Even by my decadent standards.</p>
<p>If you disagree about one or some or all of these, or if you have more examples or suggestions, I&#8217;d love to hear about it. What have I missed? Have words with no letters been catalogued elsewhere? How do we decide what counts as a word and what doesn&#8217;t?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="color:#ffffff;">*</span></p>
<p><strong>Updates: </strong>Translator Ayat Ghanem made the <a title="Twitter: @ayatghanem: &quot;@StanCarey really enjoyed your article, it seems as if logograms have crossed the ages and are back!&quot;" href="https://twitter.com/#!/ayatghanem/status/106839052363378690">interesting point</a> that “it seems as if logograms have crossed the ages and are back!” Logograms never really went away, but they may be enjoying a resurgence on account of the huge growth in typed communication, some of whose platforms strongly encourage concision.</p>
<p>Another Twitter user, @LetsGoDeeper, <a title="Twitter: @LetsGoDeeper: &quot;143, '&amp;' RT @StanCarey I'm collecting words with no letters, such as +1, @, *69, ♥, 1337, £#@$*! What others are there?...&quot;" href="https://twitter.com/#!/LetsGoDeeper/status/106846353791004672">suggested</a> <em>143</em> (“I love you”) and <em>&amp;</em>, the ampersand. I don&#8217;t think these qualify: <em>143</em> is a coded phrase, and <em>&amp;</em> is just a symbol.</p>
<p>A recent post by <a title="The Virtual Linguist: 101" href="http://virtuallinguist.typepad.com/the_virtual_linguist/2011/08/101.html">The Virtual Linguist</a> (see her comment <a title="Sentence first: Do you ♥ words with no letters?: comment by The Virtual Linguist" href="http://stancarey.wordpress.com/2011/08/23/do-you-%E2%99%A5-words-with-no-letters/#comment-12046">here</a>) looked at <em>101</em> and the different ways dictionaries treat &#8216;words&#8217; with no letters:</p>
<blockquote><p>The single-volume ODE has about ten &#8216;words&#8217; made up of digits (including 9/11, 20/20, 24/7 but not including 101) at the very end of the dictionary &#8211; after the Zs.</p></blockquote>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/category/grammar/'>grammar</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/category/language/'>language</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/category/morphology/'>morphology</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/category/slang/'>slang</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/category/wordplay/'>wordplay</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/category/words/'>words</a> Tagged: <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/code/'>code</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/curse-words/'>curse words</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/google/'>Google</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/grammar/'>grammar</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/grawlixes/'>grawlixes</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/language/'>language</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/lexicography/'>lexicography</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/linguistics/'>linguistics</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/morphology/'>morphology</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/neologisms/'>neologisms</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/numbers/'>numbers</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/obscenicons/'>obscenicons</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/punctuation/'>punctuation</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/slang/'>slang</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/slashdot/'>Slashdot</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/symbols/'>symbols</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/taboo-words/'>taboo words</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/twitter/'>Twitter</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/usage/'>usage</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/wordplay/'>wordplay</a>, <a href='http://stancarey.wordpress.com/tag/words/'>words</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8983/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8983/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8983&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stancarey.wordpress.com/2011/08/23/do-you-%e2%99%a5-words-with-no-letters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1416ad5f6a6adaea3d80c1a0261e3fd9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stancarey.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/i-heart-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I heart +1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stancarey.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/comic-speech-balloon-grawlix-or-obscenicon.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">comic speech balloon grawlix or obscenicon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lady and the Lake Series</title>
		<link>http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/lady-and-the-lake-series/</link>
		<comments>http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/lady-and-the-lake-series/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 04:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stephanie Cook</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Concept]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshly pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lady and the lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shadow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[timeless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waiting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/?p=693</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Filed under: Concept, Photography, Portrait Tagged: arts, dress, freshly pressed, ghost, lady and the lake, shadow, timeless, Waiting, water<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=693&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-694" alt="Lady and the Lake" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1832-edit.jpg?w=795&#038;h=1200" width="795" height="1200" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-705" alt="" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1846-edit.jpg?w=811&#038;h=1200" width="811" height="1200" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-704" alt="" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1825-edit.jpg?w=870&#038;h=549" width="870" height="549" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-695" alt="Shadow Walking" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1868-edit.jpg?w=870&#038;h=591" width="870" height="591" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-696" alt="Waiting Shadow" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1901-edit.jpg?w=870&#038;h=545" width="870" height="545" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-697" alt="Waiting 2" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1920-edit.jpg?w=870&#038;h=577" width="870" height="577" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-698" alt="Waiting" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac2001-edit.jpg?w=870&#038;h=585" width="870" height="585" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-699" alt="Timeless Beauty" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac2029-edit.jpg?w=870&#038;h=564" width="870" height="564" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-700" alt="Dancing Ghost" src="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/untitled_panorama11.jpg?w=870&#038;h=514" width="870" height="514" /></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/category/concept-2/'>Concept</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/category/photography-2/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/category/portrait-2/'>Portrait</a> Tagged: <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/arts/'>arts</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/dress/'>dress</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/freshly-pressed/'>freshly pressed</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/ghost/'>ghost</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/lady-and-the-lake/'>lady and the lake</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/shadow/'>shadow</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/timeless/'>timeless</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/waiting/'>Waiting</a>, <a href='http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/tag/water/'>water</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/693/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/693/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=693&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://museandsparrow.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/lady-and-the-lake-series/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bc12bb66002658899f25ab8901fc9ddf?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scook1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1832-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lady and the Lake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1846-edit.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1825-edit.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1868-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Shadow Walking</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1901-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Waiting Shadow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac1920-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Waiting 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac2001-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Waiting</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/sac2029-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Timeless Beauty</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://museandsparrow.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/untitled_panorama11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dancing Ghost</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Affair</title>
		<link>http://iamf8.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/our-affair/</link>
		<comments>http://iamf8.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/our-affair/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 22:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>iamf8</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confessional poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experimental Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spontaneous prose]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamf8.wordpress.com/?p=371</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have begun to refer to that period as The Experience. As though some distant civilization arrived and occupied the Neighborhoods and alleys of my Self. Took over the garages with massive parties that bled into the basement.   And got ugly. And did shit. And changed. And cleaned up.   And fell down laughing, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=371&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have begun to refer to that period as</p>
<p><i>The Experience</i>.</p>
<p>As though some distant civilization</p>
<p>arrived and occupied the</p>
<p>Neighborhoods and alleys</p>
<p>of my Self.</p>
<p>Took over the garages with massive parties that</p>
<p>bled into the basement.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>And got ugly.</p>
<p>And did shit.</p>
<p>And changed.</p>
<p>And cleaned up.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>And fell down laughing, and</p>
<p>high again.</p>
<p>And wrote on walls.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>But only in chalk,</p>
<p>so as not to be too</p>
<p>assuming.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>(But the chalk wounded the</p>
<p>brick just with patient abuse).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>And they let out the patients in my madhouse, let</p>
<p>out the criminal and the thief and the mini-Con.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The soft junk.</p>
<p>The spiral.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The empty rooms turned</p>
<p>into impossible choreographed numbers</p>
<p>that can never be quite replicated.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Short story notes</p>
<p>in frost of window</p>
<p>the only thing left is</p>
<p>some kind of crude arrow.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The lyrics persist in the wind</p>
<p>The night of your birth and mine.</p>
<p>In a sub-state nobody will see</p>
<p>for another hundred years.</p>
<p> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/371/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/371/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=371&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://iamf8.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/our-affair/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/deab2391e7f5b65275cfabffc20d8da1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iamf8</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
