<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>What Does “Miss Saigon” Have to Do With It?</title>
		<link>http://dontwelookalike.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/what-about-miss-saigon/</link>
		<comments>http://dontwelookalike.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/what-about-miss-saigon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 12:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Don't We Look Alike?</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Discussion or Controversy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issues of race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luanne Castle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parents on adoption issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performing Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broadway theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interracial adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miss Saigon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions of adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transracial adoption]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dontwelookalike.wordpress.com/?p=735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The musical "Miss Saigon" points to some problems in the theatre, as well as to the exploitation of women in the historical world.  What does all that have to do with adoption?<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=735&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://dontwelookalike.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/what-about-miss-saigon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8168f3547b9eaea03c352caa5034ba07?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dontwelookalike</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/5c/MissSaigonPoster.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Miss Saigon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d0/Vietnamese_refugees_on_US_carrier%2C_Operation_Frequent_Wind.jpg/300px-Vietnamese_refugees_on_US_carrier%2C_Operation_Frequent_Wind.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The fall of Saigon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>There’s Football, and There’s Life. But Mainly Football.</title>
		<link>http://oldspouse.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/theres-football-and-theres-life-but-mainly-theres-football/</link>
		<comments>http://oldspouse.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/theres-football-and-theres-life-but-mainly-theres-football/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 19:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>oldspouse</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Complexities of Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daughters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fatherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gripes About Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Married Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men and Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newspaper Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parody]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Popular Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modern culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modern Living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parody]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[popular culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oldspouse.wordpress.com/?p=1119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Roger White   It hit me the other day, my genteel tribe, as I sat watching the glorious first football weekend of the holy month of September. The remote—it hit me square in the back of the head. The wife trying to get my attention again; something about dinner or a burglar or something. That [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1119&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>by Roger White  </em></p>
<p>It hit me the other day, my genteel tribe, as I sat watching the glorious first football weekend of the holy month of September. The remote—it hit me square in the back of the head. The wife trying to get my attention again; something about dinner or a burglar or something. Th<a href="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/here-is-life.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-1120" title="here is Life" src="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/here-is-life.jpg?w=150&h=100" alt="" width="150" height="100" /></a>at woman’s got aim. Anyway, then it really hit me, as I listened to that specialized vocabulary that signals the start of a new season. That magical lexicon of the gridiron just so happens to have context—and in quite similar fashion, I might add—to the life of this middle-aged hubby, dad of two teenage girls (help me, Lord), owner of a thoroughly over-mortgaged house, and slumlord to two very ill-behaved pets (one fat, incontinent dog and one nasty, lethargic cat).</p>
<p>I began listing in my head these terms that carry dual meaning in my quaint little life, but the terms kept slipping out of my head where the wife konked me with the remote. The den started getting cluttered with all these words falling to my feet, so I figured I should sweep them up and list them.</p>
<p>So here they are, expressions o’ the gridiron and their “other” meanings, in alphabetical order for your convenient reference:</p>
<p><strong><em>All-out Blitz.</em></strong> Usually run when Mom’s away, this is a designed play in which both daughters beseech Dad in unison to <em>pleeeeeease</em> take them to the corner store for basic life necessities (e.g., gum, ice cream, Pringles).</p>
<p><strong><em>End Around. </em></strong>Another regular from the daughter playbook, this is a misdirection play used to call Mom’s or Dad’s attention to one daughter while the other one either (A) sneaks in or out of the house; (B) cleans up whatever she broke; or (C) dashes to the bathroom to attempt repairs to her purple hair dye job.</p>
<p><strong><em>False Start.</em></strong> Called almost exclusively on Mom, this mix-up occurs whenever the family is set to go out, either to a restaurant, shopping, movie, etc., and Mom says “I’m ready.” Family members then wait in the car for another 25 minutes before realizing that “I’m ready” means “another half-hour” with regard to Mom.</p>
<p><strong><em>Illegal Shift. </em></strong>This penalty is called on either one daughter or the other, depending on who stole the front passenger position in the car after the first daughter clearly called “shotgun” before the outing began.</p>
<p><strong><em>Nickel Back.</em></strong> This term refers to the change Dad often gets back from mall excursions by <a href="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/yup.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1121" title="yup" src="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/yup.jpg?w=150&h=112" alt="" width="150" height="112" /></a>Daughter #1, Daughter #2, or Mom—or, more often, all three of them running the same play. (See also End Around.)</p>
<p><strong><em>Pass Interference.</em></strong> A tactic used almost exclusively by Dad, this is a time-honored anti-flirting measure employed by dads all over, usually achieved by physically stepping in between the line of sight of boys and young men trying to catch the eye of Daughter #1 or vice-versa. Recently, much to Dad’s dismay, this has begun to apply to Daughter #2, as well. (See also Shotgun Formation.)</p>
<p><strong><em>Prevent Defense.</em></strong> This is a tactic often utilized by Dad to avoid manual labor, mostly on weekends, by pretending to be soundly asleep on the couch (or whatever furniture he happens to be lounging on) when called upon by Mom.</p>
<p><strong><em>Shotgun Formation. </em></strong>Although an actual shotgun is optional here, this is the classic formation used by Dad by sitting on the front-porch swing when daughters are due home from dates.</p>
<p><strong><em>Touchback. </em></strong>A nerve-wracking phenomenon occurring almost exclusively on family road trips, this is when daughters #1 and #2 vie for territorial rights in the back seat of the car. The constantly recurring touchback commotion almost inevitably ends with the command, “If I have to turn this car around!”</p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aahh.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1123" title="AAHH!" src="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aahh.jpg?w=150&h=150" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a>Two-minute Warning.</em></strong> This mad scramble by Dad is triggered by the appearance of the mother-in-law’s car in front of the house. It takes mom-in-law approximately two minutes to make it from her car to the house, by which time Dad must have himself hidden away in the den or the master bedroom. If not, he is often subjected to many <strong><em>Bombs </em></strong>and <strong><em>Cheap Shots</em></strong> regarding personal appearance, yard maintenance, career ambition, etc.</p>
<p><em>Roger White is a freelance writer living in Austin, Texas, with his lovely wife, two precocious daughters, a very fat dachshund, and a self-absorbed cat. For further adventures, visit <strong>oldspouse.wordpress.com</strong>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1119/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1119&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oldspouse.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/theres-football-and-theres-life-but-mainly-theres-football/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/618f43431c7fcdbcb9d0e9921640b42e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oldspouse</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/here-is-life.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">here is Life</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/yup.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yup</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oldspouse.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aahh.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AAHH!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able? Los Rodriguez Life</title>
		<link>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-los-rodriguez-life/</link>
		<comments>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-los-rodriguez-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 14:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cheri Lucas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics/Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[better blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/?p=10017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?” Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10017&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?”</em></p>
<p><em>Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a close-up on one post and why we thought it was Press-worthy. We hope we can provide insight into the process and give you tips and tools to make your blog the best it can be.<br />
</em>_________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Bloggers on WordPress.com publish various types of photography posts: from black-and-white to color, from digital to film, from Instagram to Lomo to Polaroid, from a single photo to a series of images. We love the variety and don&#8217;t prefer one approach over another.</p>
<p><span id="more-10017"></span></p>
<p>Last week, we featured <a href="http://losrodriguezlife.com/2012/08/26/visiting-south-park-city/">Visiting South Park City</a>, a photo essay on <a href="http://losrodriguezlife.com">Los Rodríguez Life</a>. Husband-and-wife team Javier and Leslie started this blog to stay in touch with their families (Javier&#8217;s family lives in Chile; Leslie&#8217;s family lives in Nashville). Here, they explore everything: travel, food, and life. Images are an integral part of their blog.</p>
<p>On the <em>Daily Post</em>, we&#8217;ll highlight different kinds of photography posts promoted to Freshly Pressed. Here&#8217;s why this particular post made the cut:</p>
<h2><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-10058" title="south park city 1" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-1.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>They brought an unfamiliar location to life.</h2>
<p>I&#8217;d never heard of South Park City before reading this post (and I don&#8217;t know much about this region of Colorado), but that didn&#8217;t matter. Javier and Leslie make this abandoned 19th-century mining town look and sound intriguing. The photos of an old saloon, schoolhouse, pharmacy, train, and more appeal to readers interested in an array of topics other than photography, from history and restoration to industrialization and transportation.</p>
<p>In other words, you don&#8217;t have to photograph iconic landmarks or exotic locations to wow us. We do love your shots of picture-perfect places and far-flung locales, but we want to emphasize that <em>any</em> subject or location—even your backyard or a random street corner—can be Press-worthy if you pique our interest.</p>
<h2><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10059" title="south park city 2" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-2.jpg?w=199&h=300" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>The assortment of shots is outstanding.</h2>
<p>This post has 45 images! It&#8217;s worth noting that <em>more</em> does not automatically make a set of photos better. In this case, we were impressed by the variety of angles and compositions in these images: Wide, establishing shots of a mining town versus close-ups of rusty antiques. Exterior versus interior. Still life versus people. Together, the images transport us there. Javier and Leslie insert descriptions to clarify what we&#8217;re looking at, but they are sparse and only include necessary details. Words come second to images here; the story of South Park City truly unfolds in the photographs.</p>
<p>In your own photo essay, create a narrative. Or think bigger: create a <em>world </em>for your readers. This may require taking photos of the same subject from above or underneath, from up close or far away. Shoot a city with different rolls of film, or filters, or cameras. Lie on the ground, or climb a tree, or look out over a rooftop to document a neighborhood. Experiment with angles and points of view to bring a place or thing to life, which will provide the visuals to tell your story.</p>
<h2><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-3.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-10060" title="south park city 3" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-3.png?w=300&h=205" alt="" width="300" height="205" /></a>The presentation was professional and effective.</h2>
<p>Posts on Los Rodríguez Life are written in both English (on the left) and Spanish (on the right). This photo essay is presented in Javier and Leslie&#8217;s standard post format: two columns of text, side by side, which make it easy for readers of either language to follow. We like how these images are displayed; as you scroll down and view each large-sized image, it feels like you&#8217;re flipping through the pages of a print magazine. (For more on this blog&#8217;s design, check out the <a href="http://theme.wordpress.com/themes/modern-news/">Modern News</a> theme.) Finally, the order in which the photos are laid out is intentional—Javier and Leslie&#8217;s adventure is presented from start to finish.</p>
<p>Telling a story with text and images is different from telling a story simply with words. For photo-centric posts, consider how best to lay out and display your content. For example, you can <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/images/gallery/">create a gallery</a>, <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/slideshows/">display a slideshow</a>, or <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/images/">insert images</a> directly into your post. You should also consider at what size you&#8217;d like to display your images, and where to insert them in your post so they complement your text.</p>
<p>So, tell us: did you enjoy this Freshly Pressed pick?<em><br />
</em></p>
<p><em>For more inspiration, take a peek at our <a href="http://theme.wordpress.com/themes/subjects/photography/">photography themes</a> in the Theme Showcase. While you can publish photography-focused posts on any WordPress.com theme, our photography themes are great places to showcase your images.</em></p>
<p><em>For more on our Freshly Pressed content, check out <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/freshly-pressed-flock-of-crows/">last week’s Freshly Press-able post</a>, read our roundup of <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/freshly-pressed-editors-picks-for-august-2012/">Editors&#8217; Picks for August</a>, or read <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/freshly-pressed/">So You Want to Be Freshly Pressed</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10017/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10017/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10017&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-los-rodriguez-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36207d4c7c014b0999b995ca3971d383?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CL</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">south park city 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-2.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">south park city 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/south-park-city-3.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">south park city 3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Hipsters, Witches and Goblins Don&#8217;t Exist</title>
		<link>http://unshaned.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/42/</link>
		<comments>http://unshaned.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/42/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Shane</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hipsters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jazz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prejudice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subculture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://unshaned.wordpress.com/?p=42</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When was the last time you had a girl put a curse on you that worked? Or when did you last hear a screech in the woods and turned around to find that it was not a peacock but, in fact, a banshee? Have you ever been chased across the cemetery yards by a goblin? [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=42&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://moviesmedia.ign.com/movies/image/article/118/1186017/famous-last-words--20110808023122509-000.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="328" /></p>
<p>When was the last time you had a girl put a curse on you that <em>worked</em>? Or when did you last hear a screech in the woods and turned around to find that it was not a peacock but, in fact, a banshee? Have you ever been chased across the cemetery yards by a goblin?</p>
<p>Have you met one single person this year, in 2012, whom when you asked what they were doing with their lives, said, ‘Oh, I’m a hipster.’ One simply doesn’t hear this, at least not without irony. Why? Because, like witches, banshees and goblins, hipsters don’t exist.</p>
<p>Now, I know many will want to say, ‘Oh, but on the contrary. I see hipsters <em>everywhere</em>.’ But—I regret to have to make this potentially clumsy correlation—in the McCarthy era, people saw communists everywhere too. What you are seeing is not a member of a definable, objective counter culture. What you are seeing is a boy with a striped shirt. A girl with large glasses. A fellow in a fedora. But sadly, these are not the signifiers of what it means to be (allegedly) a ‘hipster.’ They are only the <em>symptoms</em>, and yet, not very useful symptoms, for they’re so broad and far reaching that anyone who happens to deviate from a polo-shirt and jeans might fit the part to your standard. But what <em>causes </em>these symptoms—or rather, what do we strongly associate with these trite generalizations? Pretention, the-will-to-have-done-it-first, music you don’t happen to yourself like, books you’ve never heard of, the excesses you don’t happen to favor.</p>
<p>I must make my main point here: It is my suspicion that a ‘hipster,’ in the broad sense of the word <em>today</em>, is merely an annoying person who doesn’t share any of your tastes.</p>
<p>You might say, ‘Why would you defend people like that?’ Well, I don’t feel the need to defend them just as I don’t feel the need to defend evil hexes, unicorns or dragons. I simply wish to warn people that they mustn’t feel so threatened by dragons that <em>don’t </em>actually roam the woods.</p>
<p>Now, none of us like things that are annoying and pretentious, but I hardly think it fair that a guy in a club should be ostracized by a plain-clothes person because he happens to wear a bowler hat or because he happens to be reading a biography about Che Guevara while wearing loud colors just because someone who happened to annoy the plain-clothes person carried a similar book and wore a similar shirt on their seldom visit to a non-Starbucks coffee shop.</p>
<p>You may say to me, ‘Sounds like the words of someone who’s angry about being called a hipster at some recent point.’ On the contrary! This blogger has not been accused. There are a series of sayings that broaden the terms of hipsterism beyond its metaphysical range. Surely you’ve heard them: ‘No one hates hipsters more than hipsters,’ which would cancel out the one who accuses you of being one with no real problem. My personal favorite, ‘If you know what a hipster is, you’re probably a hipster,’—as if their mere mention is some kind of self-reflective threat that could turn back in on you unless you’re <em>one step ahead </em>(in hipster fashion) by knowing that mentioning them makes you one of them: an attitude that is so reminiscent of the ‘hipster mentality’ that it would, in a technical way, still make you a hipster.</p>
<p>All over the world, there are douche-bags. You might meet them in the street or on the bus, or you might work with them. ‘Hello, my name is David and I am a douche-bag.’ You don’t hear this either. But the difference between a douche-bag and a hipster: we don’t identify a <em>douche-bag </em>as having any kind of identifiable subculture. But yet the one important thing they both have <em>in common </em>is that nobody would identify themselves as either. If no one is willing to admit that they belong to a certain group, one then has to wonder if the title is a very useful way of categorizing people.</p>
<p>As I said before, there were once <em>real</em> hipsters, which probably means little beyond the fact that the <em>real </em>hipsters considered themselves such. The movement started in the 1940’s and is linked symbiotically to jazz, which cannot be so readily said of ‘hipster’ sensibilities today. The original term ‘hipster’ replaced ‘hepcat,’ for some odd reason—I’m not sure if there was a bebop council that voted on it or not.</p>
<p>This is not to say that they were necessarily better for being the originals. Depending on your taste, you might have found them just as annoying and just as pretentious. The movement was described as white middle-class kids trying to be black—which probably says less about the movement and more about insecurity to do with cultural integration among the generation before. But if they are correct in any way, it could then be said, in regard to the history of hipsters, that white folks have failed our African American friends once again by being <em>second hand </em>racist toward these other white folks who wanted to do what one African American subculture were doing.</p>
<p>Now, I must eat <em>some </em>of my words for a moment. Maybe some of you know people that refer to themselves as hipsters without irony. However, I suspect, that if you gathered all of these people together in one room, they would (similar to the Punks) try to out-hipster each other, which would ultimately trace their contradistinction to one another, thus making them nothing like a real culture of any kind once again—which proves my point.</p>
<p>The automobile has provided us with an easier way to move from place to place. The television provided us with hours of easy entertainment. The internet provided us with an easier access to knowledge and Facebook provided us with an easier means to keep in contact with old friends. But there’s a dark side to <em>easier</em>. Dismissing certain attitudes, fashions and tastes as that of a ‘hipster’ is an <em>easy </em>way for us to cope with our own embarrassment over the cultural fashion follies, philosophy follies and awkward tastes of yesteryear. Anything can be dismissed as outdated, but the great thing about hipster-phobia is that you can dismiss anything that is considered ‘freshly retro,’ or new, or more <em>unknown</em>, as something that a culturally unattractive person would admire. And this will to stay ahead of the hipsters is, by its current definitional nature concerning hipsterism, a hipster attitude which would make anti-hipsters the biggest hipsters of all.</p>
<p>Once again, I’m not defending hipsters because I have shown that they don’t actually exist. If they did exist in the form that people claim they do, perhaps I would be talking about how much I dislike them the way people want to. But I’ll say this, even if they <em>do </em>exist, are they <em>that </em>big of a cultural threat that we have to keep hearing about them everywhere we go?</p>
<p>More importantly, before you decide that someone is objectionable, perhaps you should actually speak to them. If they’re a threat, then you can deal with it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/42/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/42/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=42&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unshaned.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/42/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a02be213564f6a24727f7337fc5af0bf?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unshaned</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviesmedia.ign.com/movies/image/article/118/1186017/famous-last-words--20110808023122509-000.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NW by Zadie Smith</title>
		<link>http://eveproofreads.com/2012/09/05/nw/</link>
		<comments>http://eveproofreads.com/2012/09/05/nw/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 09:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Eve Proofreads</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Proofreading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hamish Hamilton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NW]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penguin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penguin Proof Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zadie Smith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eveproofreads.com/?p=341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zadie Smith’s new novel, NW, surprised me. I was expecting something like White Teeth or On Beauty, but the complexity and intense poetry of this created something strong and unexpected. It primarily charts the lives of best friends Leah and Keisha who grow up together on the same estate. Though it initially focuses on Leah, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=341&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://eveproofreads.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nw-zadie-smith.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-342" title="NW Zadie Smith" src="http://eveproofreads.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nw-zadie-smith.jpg?w=198&h=300" alt="" width="198" height="300" /></a><span style="color:#000000;">Zadie Smith’s new novel, NW, surprised me. I was expecting something like <em>White Teeth </em>or <em>On Beauty</em>, but the complexity and intense poetry of this created something strong and unexpected. It primarily charts the lives of best friends Leah and Keisha who grow up together on the same estate. Though it initially focuses on Leah, I preferred the later section, ‘Host’, that adopts Keisha’s perspective in brief scenes, told with the senses of memory, that bring them from childhood to adulthood. It explores whether Keisha can successfully negotiate a class transition.  She chooses a new name, Natalie, for her new life as she succeeds professionally and marries wealthy Frank, who looks like ‘he was born on a yacht somewhere in the Caribbean and raised by Ralph Lauren’. Zadie Smith’s characters are, as always, multifaceted and very authentic. I loved her description of Keisha’s teenage angst:</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"> ‘It did not strike Keisha Blake that such feelings of alienation are the banal fate of adolescents everywhere. She considered herself peculiarly afflicted, and it is not an exaggeration to say that she struggled to think of anyone besides perhaps James Baldwin and Jesus who had experienced the profound isolation and loneliness that she now knew to be the one and only true reality in this world.’</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"> The lives of two men are also introduced in this anthropological consideration of an urban landscape. Felix and Nathan have both struggled to establish functional lives after their beginnings on the Caldwell estate. Poverty, failure and distress are never far from the lives of NW’s people; there seems to be a sort of inevitable tragedy about this novel. The moment that struck me the most was when Natalie and Nathan meet for the last time in the text. She tells him, ‘It’s weird to me that you can be so vital to another person and never know it. You were so…loved’. Yet that can do little for him.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"> There are moments that show Zadie Smith’s clever humour. Cultural references ground the chronology realistically, though some were rather lost on me. I struggled a little with some of the prose as semi-sentences often tailed off, as if I inherently knew what she was getting at. I’m afraid I didn’t. Unfortunately, my professional brain also initially interfered with my enjoyment; I kept thinking how difficult it would be to proofread! Once I got past my grammatical fixations, I found the creativity of form refreshing.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"> NW is just right in some ways. Reading it feels like a trip to London: a city sometimes dense, stressful and un-cohesive, but ultimately it provides a chance to see a cross-section of life in glimpses. It is sometimes beautiful or brutal, but it is always vital and feels essentially real and alive. </span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/341/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/341/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=341&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://eveproofreads.com/2012/09/05/nw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1c685a60b37c4f96e475828f2586b45d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eveproofreads</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eveproofreads.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nw-zadie-smith.jpg?w=198" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">NW Zadie Smith</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Fiction and The Storytelling Animal</title>
		<link>http://literacyadviser.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/the-power-of-fiction-and-the-storytelling-animal/</link>
		<comments>http://literacyadviser.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/the-power-of-fiction-and-the-storytelling-animal/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 13:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>literacyadviser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storytelling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://literacyadviser.wordpress.com/?p=3794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a former English teacher, I have often argued on the blog and elsewhere that the English curriculum in schools offers a distorted syllabus, in which non-fiction is heavily outweighed by fiction texts &#8211; no doubt reflecting the fact that most practitioners have degrees in English Literature &#8211; and that there needs to be a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a former English teacher, I have often argued on the blog and elsewhere that the English curriculum in schools offers a distorted syllabus, in which non-fiction is heavily outweighed by fiction texts &#8211; no doubt reflecting the fact that most practitioners have degrees in English Literature &#8211; and that there needs to be a re-balancing to reflect more accurately the texts with which we are surrounded in daily life. Time and again however, my attention is drawn to the importance of storytelling and the need to understand ourselves and the world through the medium of story.</p>
<div id="attachment_3807" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 208px"><a href="http://literacyadviser.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gottschall_storytelling_animal.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3807" title="gottschall_storytelling_animal" src="http://literacyadviser.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gottschall_storytelling_animal.jpeg?w=198&h=300" alt="" width="198" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Storytelling Animal by Jonathan Gottschall</p></div>
<p>In <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Storytelling-Animal-Stories-Make-Human/dp/0547391404/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1346763673&amp;sr=1-1"><em>The Storytelling Animal</em></a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonathan_Gottschall">Jonathan Gottschal</a>l of Washington and Jefferson College in the USA, explains how stories shape and define us as human beings, arguing that stories help us navigate life&#8217;s complex social problems, just as flight simulators prepare pilots for difficult situations. The theory is that storytelling has evolved, like other behaviours, to ensure our survival.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The constant firing of our neurons in response to fictional stimuli strengthens and refines the neural pathways that lead to skilful negotiation of life&#8217;s problems. From this point of view, we are attracted to fiction, not because of an evolutionary glitch, but because fiction is, on the whole, good for us. This is because human life, especially social life, is intensely complicated and the stakes are high. Fiction allows our brains to practice (sic) reacting to the kinds of challenges that are, and always were, most crucial to our success as a species.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>But isn&#8217;t fiction our &#8216;escapism&#8217;, you might argue. Surely it&#8217;s in fiction, whether it be in a good novel or the latest Dr Who series, that we find our escape from the problems of everyday life? Well yes, and no. According to Gottschall the nature of the stories we tell betrays their true purpose.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There is a paradox in fiction that was first noticed by Aristotle in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poetics_(Aristotle)"><em>The Poetics</em></a>. We are drawn to fiction because fiction gives us pleasure. But most of what is in fiction is deeply unpleasant: threat, death, despair, anxiety, Sturm and Drang. Take a look at the carnage on the fiction bestseller lists &#8211; the massacres, murders, and rapes. Look at classic literature: Oedipus stabbing out his eyes in disgust; Medea slaughtering her children; Shakespeare&#8217;s stage strewn with runny corpses. Heavy stuff. But even the lighter stuff is organised around problems, and readers are riveted by their concern over how it will all turn out.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>On the morality of stories, or whether stories have a moral purpose, Gottschall is adamant. When addressing the dire warnings of social commentators from Plato onwards that fiction corrodes</p>
<div id="attachment_3805" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://literacyadviser.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/hc-big-sleep1.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3805" title="hc.big-sleep" src="http://literacyadviser.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/hc-big-sleep1.jpeg?w=300&h=223" alt="" width="300" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The good guy usually wins</p></div>
<p>morality, especially in the young, his conviction is that they were entirely wrong, and he prefers to accept that, with some exceptions, the most popular story forms are still structured around &#8216;poetic justice&#8217;: the good guy usually does win out in the end.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;As with sacred myths, ordinary stories &#8211; from TV shows to fairy tales &#8211; steep us all in the same powerful norms and values. They relentlessly stigmatise antisocial behaviour and just as relentlessly celebrate prosocial behaviour. We learn by association that if we are more like protagonists, we will be more apt to reap the typical rewards of protagonists (for instance, love, social advancement, and other happy endings) and less likely to reap the rewards of antagonists (for instance, death and disastrous loss of social standing). Humans live great chunks of their lives inside fictional stories &#8211; in worlds where goodness is generally endorsed and rewarded and badness is condemned and punished. These patterns don&#8217;t just reflect a moralistic bias in human psychology, they seem to reinforce it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Developing this theme, Gottschall cites the Dutch scholar Jemeljan Hakemulder, who in his book <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Moral-Laboratory-Experiments-Self-Concept-Publications/dp/1556196806/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1346763739&amp;sr=1-1"><em>The Moral Laboratory</em></a>, reviewed dozens of scientific studies which indicated that fiction has positive effects on the reader&#8217;s moral development and sense of empathy. Other studies show that fiction reinforces our belief that life rewards the virtuous and punishes the vicious. Even though this is patently not the case, for a society to function at all it is necessary for people to believe in justice.</p>
<p>The notion of empathy, a core feature of works of fiction, is taken up in this <a href="http://www.ted.com/">TED</a> talk by Jessica Wise, who argues that the importance of fiction is that it has the power &#8216;to change a person&#8217;s point of view&#8217;. I think the short film would make a perfect starter for discussion in any English classroom.</p>
<div id="v-70RHtcrA-1" class="video-player" style="width:400px;height:224px">
<embed id="v-70RHtcrA-1-video" src="http://s0.videopress.com/player.swf?v=1.03&amp;guid=70RHtcrA&amp;isDynamicSeeking=true" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="400" height="224" title="Jessica Wise- How fiction can change reality" wmode="direct" seamlesstabbing="true" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" overstretch="true"></embed></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3794/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3794/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div><a href="http://literacyadviser.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/the-power-of-fiction-and-the-storytelling-animal/"><img alt="Jessica Wise- How fiction can change reality" src="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_std.original.jpg" width="160" height="120" /></a></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://literacyadviser.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/the-power-of-fiction-and-the-storytelling-animal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	<enclosure url="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_hd.mp4" length="109209600" type="video/mp4" />

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2112c73d47a8e8c34a84c35e57d0cd1b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">literacyadviser</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://literacyadviser.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gottschall_storytelling_animal.jpeg?w=198" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gottschall_storytelling_animal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://literacyadviser.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/hc-big-sleep1.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hc.big-sleep</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:group>
			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_hd.mp4" fileSize="109209600" type="video/mp4" medium="video" bitrate="3160" isDefault="true" duration="270" width="1280" height="720" />

			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_dvd.mp4" fileSize="52807680" type="video/mp4" medium="video" bitrate="1528" isDefault="false" duration="270" width="640" height="360" />

			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_std.mp4" fileSize="27509760" type="video/mp4" medium="video" bitrate="796" isDefault="false" duration="270" width="400" height="224" />

			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_fmt1.ogv" fileSize="27509760" type="video/ogg" medium="video" bitrate="796" isDefault="false" duration="270" width="400" height="224" />

			<media:rating scheme="urn:mpaa">g</media:rating>
			<media:title type="plain">Jessica Wise- How fiction can change reality</media:title>
			<media:thumbnail url="http://videos.videopress.com/70RHtcrA/jessica-wise-how-fiction-can-change-reality_std.original.jpg" width="256" height="144" />
			<media:player url="http://s0.videopress.com/player.swf?v=1.03&#38;guid=70RHtcrA&#38;isDynamicSeeking=true" width="400" height="225" />
		</media:group>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Capturing Childhood</title>
		<link>http://themommyquad.com/2012/09/04/capturing-childhood/</link>
		<comments>http://themommyquad.com/2012/09/04/capturing-childhood/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 17:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>themommyquad</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[body image]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrity kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrity moms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paparazzi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themommyquad.com/?p=278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This Labor Day weekend the six of us marked the official close of summer with a trip to the beach, complete with iPhone camera to document every moment of family togetherness. Never mind the sand that threatened to infest my very expensive piece of mobile technology: the moment needed to be recorded, dammit. Except baby [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=278&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://themommyquad.com/2012/09/04/capturing-childhood/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/341a54fd1b70285166eaf4aac6f2baea?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">themommyquad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themommyquad.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/family-beach.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">family beach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themommyquad.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/mo-beach.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mo beach</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Directions For Distractions</title>
		<link>http://dailydoseofnoor.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/directions-for-distractions/</link>
		<comments>http://dailydoseofnoor.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/directions-for-distractions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 16:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Noor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Epiphanies!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[differences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[similarities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailydoseofnoor.wordpress.com/?p=497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The rain is pouring endlessly outside, the skies are a nice dismal shade of gray, I hear the loud reverberations of a flashy storm, and my mind is sincerely and completely awake. Contrary to what is evident on my blog, I’ve been writing a lot lately. Perhaps later this year the occasion will present itself [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=497&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://dailydoseofnoor.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/directions-for-distractions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/548d417a8ecc6d2202b3aa79523a4bef?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dailydoseofnoor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailydoseofnoor.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/thewayiseeit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Way I See It #278</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotify, The Pirate Bay &amp; the Lie That They Don’t Matter</title>
		<link>http://thethingaboutflying.com/2012/08/23/spotify-the-pirate-bay/</link>
		<comments>http://thethingaboutflying.com/2012/08/23/spotify-the-pirate-bay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 20:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>joshacorman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Tape Deck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Derek Webb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illegal downloading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pirate Bay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RIAA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spotify]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thethingaboutflying.com/?p=3373</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other night I took a momentary break from trying to sleep to check my Twitter feed. Boredom, Annoyance, and Exhaustion colluded in keeping me awake by calling their pal Debate, who crashed the party in that gleeful way of his. Two friends were having a &#8220;conversation&#8221; &#8211; the limitations of Twitter or any other [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3373&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thethingaboutflying.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spotify-674281_620x258-e1345746920584.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3392" title="Spotify" src="http://thethingaboutflying.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spotify-674281_620x258-e1345746920584.jpg?w=300&h=124" alt="" width="300" height="124" /></a></p>
<p>The other night I took a momentary break from trying to sleep to check my Twitter feed. Boredom, Annoyance, and Exhaustion colluded in keeping me awake by calling their pal Debate, who crashed the party in that gleeful way of his. Two friends were having a &#8220;conversation&#8221; &#8211; the limitations of Twitter or any other social network w/r/t actually conversing should be apparent &#8211; about Spotify, the value we place on music, and our responsibilities &#8211; or lack thereof &#8211; as music consumers. Part of the discussion was centered on <a title="Derek Webb" href="http://derekwebb.tumblr.com/post/13503899950/giving-it-away-how-free-music-makes-more-than-sense" target="_blank">this piece by Christian artist Derek Webb </a>. I jumped in (giving up on any hope of sleep for the time being), and pretty soon, we were filling up the timeline. For the sake of this piece, I&#8217;m going to focus primarily on my thoughts rather than trying to recreate or fully incorporate the views of my two friends. In this way, I hope to avoid putting words into anyone&#8217;s mouth, while leaving the door open for a future guest post that might offer some alternate perspective.</p>
<p>The following questions either came up in our discussion or occurred to me later that night as I lay awake, my brain still humming from the back-and-forth.</p>
<p><strong>1. What, if any, legitimate reasons are there for pirating music?</strong></p>
<p><strong>2. Knowing what I now know about Spotify (see the Derek Webb piece), how do I feel about it?</strong></p>
<p><strong>3. How are we to adequately value music and compensate artists?</strong></p>
<p><strong>4. What, if any, responsibilities do consumers have towards artists?</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;ll tackle them one by one.</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> My gut reaction is a strong &#8216;no.&#8217; There was a time where I would have said that for discovery purposes, pirating music would be alright. In college, I illegally downloaded a ton of music. In a huge majority of the cases, if I liked what I heard, I went out and bought the artist&#8217;s output on CD, and if not, I just deleted the files from my computer. No harm, no foul. The only problem is that, on occasion, I wouldn&#8217;t actually follow through and delete an album, even one I wasn&#8217;t crazy about. In this way, I accrued a pretty sizable collection of music that I hadn&#8217;t paid anything for. I used all kinds of rationalizations to justify the presence of these files. I&#8217;d tell myself that I was just extending the &#8220;trial period&#8221; to see if the artist grew on me, or that since I bought a ton of music legitimately, a comparably few downloaded albums wasn&#8217;t a big deal. It was all BS, of course. Even though this system did result in the discovery and support of a LOT of artists who I may never have otherwise gotten into, I was playing with fire, tempting myself at every turn to just burn a CD from illegally downloaded files rather than shell out money at the used music store on a hard copy.</p>
<p>At this point, I haven&#8217;t downloaded any commercially available music in a long time. I do still download the odd bootleg now and then, but only from artists who have given their blessing for tapers to circulate their shows for free via online trading communities. There are just too many other avenues by which to discover artists now to make the practice tenable. Both the iTunes Store and Amazon MP3 Store offer recommendations based on past purchase and viewing history, extended listens of individual songs, Facebook (and, somehow, even MySpace) serve as solid discovery platforms and have led to more and more artists offering free streams of some of their music to inform consumers before they buy. This is all not to even mention streaming services (both free and paid), but I&#8217;ll get to that.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, acquiring something of value (which music obviously does, both commercially, culturally, and &#8211; just maybe &#8211; spiritually) without payment is not only illegal, but immoral.</p>
<p><strong>2. </strong>If what Webb says about Spotify is true (and I have no reason not to believe him), then it does an awful job of compensating the artists who make it such a potentially valuable commodity. I&#8217;ll confess that the internet-as-model-for-music-distribution story has yet to be written in its entirety, but what long looked to be the answer (offering consumers the chance to listen to music on-demand via a streaming services and paying artists per stream) suddenly seems much shakier as a long-term solution. The discovery aspect, as Webb mentions, is all well and good, but the service itself doesn&#8217;t make it worth it for the artist to be sought out, because more times than not, Spotify users (other streaming services may offer greater incentive to the artists &#8211; subscription service Rhapsody, for example) substitute sitting at their computer and streaming the artists&#8217; songs (which they can do thousands of times before the author sees anything resembling adequate per-song compensation) for actually buying the music.</p>
<p>This gets back to the illegal download gambit. If you use Spotify with the express purpose of seeking out new music to buy, then it would seem not to approach the ethical cliff that it might otherwise (it seems like a cliff to me, anyway). But, just like with the &#8220;promise&#8221; I made about illegal downloading, you would have to be pretty resolute to ensure that you didn&#8217;t just end up using Spotify as a personal on-demand radio station when you sit at your computer, rather than as a means to more substantial support of artists you enjoy.</p>
<p>Webb points out that Spotify goes a long way towards assuaging any potential guilt on the part of users because it&#8217;s not technically stealing, and so users&#8217; consciences are clear, even as the artists receive a paltry compensation for their art. This seems like dangerous ground to me. It simultaneously devalues music by giving it away for basically nothing, and lulls consumers into thinking that they&#8217;re doing just enough to avoid feeling bad about that fact. Perhaps Spotify should only be seen as a tool, to be used for good or ill. I&#8217;m not totally convinced of that, though.</p>
<p><strong>3. </strong>The other night I accused my friend of taking a relativistic approach in his attitude towards artist compensation. He shot back, asking where exactly I had found absolutism regarding the value of music (I know I said I wouldn&#8217;t try to present my friends&#8217; views directly here, but he raises a valid point). I&#8217;ll concede that, as far as I&#8217;m aware, God has yet to offer his two cents (no pun intended), about what exactly a song or album should cost. However, as I said earlier, music has value (if you somehow have convinced yourself that intellectual property should not be recognized in any form, then we need to have a slightly different conversation), even if it doesn&#8217;t happen to be 99¢ per song or $9.99 an album. If we accept that music has value, and that, culturally, items of value require compensation &#8211; determined by the market, in almost every instance &#8211; then we must accept that music should be bought, and for a price that is both inviting to consumers and rewarding to artists. 0.00029 cents per stream meets neither of these criteria, and, obviously, paying nothing through piracy doesn&#8217;t either. I get that Spotify and the Pirate Bay are great deals for consumers, but they blatantly ignore what we should know to be fair. To argue that the consumer alone should be the key factor in determining what music is worth is to undermine the economic principles that have governed commerce &#8211; if you cringe at art being commercialized, sorry, but it&#8217;s been that way for hundreds of years (as Nick Hornby points out, Shakespeare wrote for money) &#8211; for ages.</p>
<p>By that specious logic, people with banged up cars should be able to tell mechanics how much their repairs should cost. That isn&#8217;t the way things work, and, believe it or not, it&#8217;s a good thing. Let&#8217;s face it, if people found a way to acquire car repairs that didn&#8217;t compensate the mechanic in any reasonable way, but simultaneously cost them (the consumer) little to nothing, they would take advantage, devaluing the service that mechanics provide AND lessening the incentive to offer that service in the first place. Who in their right mind would devote time, energy, and effort to enter the field of mechanics and attempt to get better at their jobs if the <em>knew</em> that the people enjoying their services had no interest in compensating them so that they might practice their vocation &#8211; if we&#8217;re being optimistic &#8211; without the pressing financial concerns that come with not get paid for doing the thing you feel called to do? A popular claim about artists &#8211; but not <em>among</em> them, curiously &#8211; is that artists should just love what they do enough to do it anyway, and if they&#8217;re seeking compensation for their art, then they cease to be &#8220;true artists,&#8221; whatever that&#8217;s supposed to mean. What arrogance! Dance for me, monkey! Entertain me! And I&#8217;ll offer you little-to-nothing in return, which you should be thrilled about, because, after all, artists should create without any concern for recompense.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get a couple of things straight. Artists <em>do</em> create because they love what they do, and they would probably do it anyway (as someone who has written one book and is 80,000 words into writing a novel, both of which will likely never, ever be published, I can vouch for this), but to assume that they should be happy in that toil, and that seeking to make a living by doing what they love somehow cheapens their art is insulting in the worst way. When we pay for an artists&#8217; work, be they painter, author, musician, or whatever, we are buying more than just the canvas or the book or the album, we&#8217;re buying time. We&#8217;re providing them with the  space in which to create, free &#8211; at least to some degree &#8211; from worrying about day-to-day financial survival. Money is approval, whether we like it or not, but it&#8217;s also a way to provide artists with the opportunity to continue to create &#8211; for themselves and for us. Which leads me to&#8230;.</p>
<p><strong>4. </strong>None, as long as consumers have no interest whatsoever in the further creation of art. If they do, then you&#8217;d better believe the responsibility is immense; we should be crawling over each other to offer artists support. In past centuries, promising artists&#8217; work was funded through benefactors. I don&#8217;t imagine there&#8217;s a lot of benefacting going around these days, but if you happen to know any, or happen to be one yourself, please email me. Government groups like the National Endowment for the Arts constantly see their budgets, much of which already go to programs that encourage arts education and working artists, slashed. There is no magic fairy out there, keeping artists afloat. If we want to encourage great art, we must show that we value it. If we don&#8217;t, we can expect artists to struggle more and more to gain the traction necessary to get their work into the hands of even moderately large numbers of people. If we refuse to acknowledge the value of art <em>and</em> artists themselves, then, eventually, we will get what we&#8217;ve paid for: nothing.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3373/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3373/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3373&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thethingaboutflying.com/2012/08/23/spotify-the-pirate-bay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thethingaboutflying.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spotify-674281_620x258-e1345746920584.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thethingaboutflying.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spotify-674281_620x258-e1345746920584.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spotify</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ef5f115cc64ffda53a7db5101c325030?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joshacorman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thethingaboutflying.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spotify-674281_620x258-e1345746920584.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spotify</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Whiny Post About Relationships</title>
		<link>http://inthegates.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/another-whiny-post-about-relationships/</link>
		<comments>http://inthegates.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/another-whiny-post-about-relationships/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 09:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Katie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clapton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geocaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[logic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[math]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space Bag]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://inthegates.wordpress.com/?p=603</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Did I tell you about the time I set a geocaching scavenger hunt through the city for the boy I was infatuated with? Starting from Cambridge Boat Club, and directed solely with GPS coordinates, he was led to several locations, rewarded with different alcoholic treasures along the way. I waited for him, freezing, atop the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=603&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did I tell you about the time I set a <a href="http://www.geocaching.com/">geocaching scavenger hunt</a> through the city for the boy I was infatuated with? Starting from Cambridge Boat Club, and directed solely with GPS coordinates, he was led to several locations, rewarded with different alcoholic treasures along the way. I waited for him, freezing, atop the <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/prospect-hill-monument-somerville">Prospect Hill Monument</a>, the conclusion of the hunt.</p>
<div>The whole thing went terribly awry, actually. His GPS app was different than the one I had used to set the trail (which you think wouldn&#8217;t think would make a difference <em>because</em> <em>they&#8217;re GPS coordinates</em>), and he got fairly lost. Twice. And an adventure that should have taken thirty minutes stretched to an hour and then some.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div id="attachment_613" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/picture-81.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-613" title="Picture 8" src="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/picture-81.png" alt="" width="510" height="272" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I might have miscalculated the beer.</p></div>
</div>
<div>But he made it. He hurriedly ascended the mock castle steps, looking slightly irritated, yet proud that he had solved my stupidly convoluted puzzle. And then he kissed me.</div>
<div><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></div>
<div>I have never experienced the reciprocal equivalent of this story. Which is fine in the case of the above situation; all memories of that relationship are covered in a viscous, permeating filth that rotted every fond affection that bore those memories anyway. But in the grand scheme of my existence, I have never been the recipient of a gesture of romantic affection. I have never had a Valentine, received flowers, been given a sweet note.</div>
<div></div>
<div><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></div>
<div>I have never inspired love.</div>
<div><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></div>
<div>This eviscerates me. Even typing these words induces a crushing sensation in my chest, or what I imagine it would feel like if my pulmonary system were placed inside a Space Bag and the connected Shop-Vac switched on.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div id="attachment_611" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 394px"><a href="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/heart-in-a-bag2.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image-611  " title="Heart in a Bag" src="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/heart-in-a-bag2.jpeg?w=384&h=288" alt="" width="384" height="288" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You can find anything on the Internets!</p></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>This past week seemed to mark the tipping point for those in my social network in terms of them getting serious with their significant others. In the last three days alone, Facebook informed me of four engagements. (My older friends warned me of this. Next comes weddings, then, babies, plastered all over your Newsfeed.) It&#8217;s not that I am anything but ecstatic for their collective happiness—I really am. And, as you may recall, matrimonial union is <a href="http://inthegates.wordpress.com/2010/10/30/fears%E2%80%93irrational-rational/"><em>not</em> my idea of a fun time</a>. But it does serve as a cutting reminder of a feeling I have so earnestly hoped for, yet failed to evoke.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div id="attachment_614" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/thanks-buddy.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-614" title="Thanks, Buddy." src="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/thanks-buddy.jpeg?w=300&h=202" alt="" width="300" height="202" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Thanks, buddy.</p></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>If taking the mathematical approach, when all the factors of my 25 years are distilled into its constants, the lowest common denominator is&#8230;me. Thus, logically speaking, there is something inherently defective about me that has resulted in this sorry state of solitude.</div>
<div><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></div>
<div>This is not news. But it is there that I am baffled. For I have searched—honestly and achingly—for what this defect is, that I might correct it and maybe one day finally understand the sentiment behind Eric Clapton&#8217;s &#8220;Wonderful Tonight.&#8221; And while I have found many inadequacies, none are so unique or horrid as to explain why I seem to be such a leper to the opposite sex.</div>
<div><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></div>
<div>At least I don&#8217;t think they are.</div>
<div><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></div>
<div>I can see the encouraging Facebook comments now:</div>
<div>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;You&#8217;re a beautiful person, Katie.&#8221; <em>—an older friend (40+), possibly an aunt</em></li>
<li>&#8220;Love will find you when you least expect it.&#8221; <em>—English/philosophy major</em></li>
<li>&#8220;I looove you!!&#8221; —<em>a girl</em></li>
</ul>
<p>In advance, please know that I am deeply appreciative of your kindness. But save it. What I really need is some good, old-fashioned constructive criticism. Even though ego-stroking is largely what I designed this blog for, it will get me no where in solving this particular problem. (In fact, it would actually make matters worse.) So lay it on me, thick and unforgiving. Help me dig out of this hole.</p>
<p>Because I want to stop writing this morose shit.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/603/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/603/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=603&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://inthegates.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/another-whiny-post-about-relationships/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>84</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3fc3426d3dc2e1d826962298f0c60d8c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Katie O.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/picture-81.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/heart-in-a-bag2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Heart in a Bag</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inthegates.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/thanks-buddy.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thanks, Buddy.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>