<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 20:11:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Stay Strong, Keep Fighting</title>
		<link>http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/stay-strong-keep-fighting/</link>
		<comments>http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/stay-strong-keep-fighting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 16:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Broken Light: A Photography Collective</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sadness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self harm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-harm awareness day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-injury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-injury awareness day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suicidal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suicide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/?p=6941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Photo taken by a woman who has suffered from severe depression. She hopes that by telling her story that she will help fight stigma, and help people to understand things like self-harm that seem so hard to understand. She would also like to help other people suffering to feel less alone, and maybe even share [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><a href="http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/stay-strong-keep-fighting/photofinalwm/" rel="attachment wp-att-6919"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6919" alt="" src="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photofinalwm.jpg?w=547&#038;h=392" width="547" height="392" /></a></p>
<p>Photo taken by a woman who has suffered from severe depression. She hopes that by telling her story that she will help fight stigma, and help people to understand things like self-harm that seem so hard to understand. She would also like to help other people suffering to feel less alone, and maybe even share the spark of hope.</p>
<p>About this photo:<em> “It took me fifteen minutes of searching through every drawer in my house, but I finally found the one piece of orange clothing that I have. I&#8217;m wearing orange in honor of <a title="harm" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-injury_Awareness_Day" target="_blank">Self-Injury Awareness Day</a>. I know every day is some other awareness day, but this one happens to mean a lot to me. As someone who has been down the path of self-harm, and had people I love dearly who have been there, I feel terribly and empathize for all who are suffering enough to self-harm and those who love someone who does. It&#8217;s a serious issue, and should be treated as such, this day and every day.</em></p>
<p><em>The first time I really hurt myself I was in college. I was sad and in pain emotionally and I took it out on myself physically. I don&#8217;t want to be too specific in fear of it triggering anyone else, but it wasn&#8217;t pretty. I still feel terribly that my best friend had to find me slurring and covered in blood on the floor - I think I had a few drinks and some pills in me too. I was in the hospital for a night or two and released as not being a threat to myself. Life moved forward but m</em><em>y wound would not heal, not just the emotional wound, but the physical one. I needed a skin graft. When I went to the hospital to get the graft, I asked if the two skin locations would be numbed. The doctor looked at the nurse and then at me with cold eyes, and she said that since I did it to myself I should be fine with the pain and deal with it&#8230; This was just plain ignorance.</em></p>
<p><em>I learned from that experience and evolved my self-harm so it would generally not involve wounds. I thought I was being smart, but nothing about self-harm is smart. I kept coming back to it though. </em><em>For some reason it felt good. It felt like a release that I needed. It felt like it kept me from worse thoughts or actions. It felt like I was saving my life at times. </em><em>I recognize that my thinking was twisted, but it had some truth to it. It did feel like a release. It did keep me from worse things. That is how I managed to justify these unthinkable actions.</em></p>
<p><em>It happened on and off for many years, but I can now say I am harm-free! I can&#8217;t say I am trigger-free. I can&#8217;t say I am impulse-free. But I am action-free, and that is what counts. When I feel the impulses rising, I have learned to divert my energies, to distract and try to do something else, especially something creative. For some people it is yoga, for me it is photography. Also, when I know I am going to be in a triggering situation, I will plan a reward or something nice for myself afterwards. I&#8217;ll admit that these tools don&#8217;t always work, but I&#8217;m trying my hardest. If one thing doesn&#8217;t work then I try another. I&#8217;m fighting. Fighting for my family, my friends. Fighting for myself, my life, my future. </em></p>
<p><em>So other people out there who are struggling with this, please keep fighting the impulses. It is not easy, I really understand that, it can be like an addiction, but there are ways to help fight. There are therapists, and therapeutic tools, like DBT. You can make a harm-free contract with your therapist or loved ones and promise to go to them when the impulses start. You can try distracting or doing &#8216;opposite action.&#8217; If you want to isolate, and you know it will likely lead to injury, do the opposite of that &#8211; go be around people. Go somewhere, even outside for a little walk. Even if you are walking alone, you are not alone. You are never alone. I am there with you, and everyone struggling. We are walking together.</em></p>
<p><em>Stay strong. Keep fighting.”</em></p>
<p><em>____________________________________________________________</em></p>
<p>**Visit Broken Light’s main gallery <a title="bl" href="http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">here</a>. Currently accepting <a title="submit" href="http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/submit-here/" target="_blank">submissions</a>.</p>
<p>*Like us on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Broken-Light-Collective/217143911732438">Facebook</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/#%21/BrokenLightCo">Twitter</a>. Follow below for e-mail notifications.</p>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6941/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6941/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/stay-strong-keep-fighting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photofinalwm.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photofinalwm.jpg?w=150" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3c972f2a01500fa51af026e09413a4d7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brokenlightcollective</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photofinalwm.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Curfew</title>
		<link>http://lucidedit.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/curfew/</link>
		<comments>http://lucidedit.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/curfew/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Suzanne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dystopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[post-apocalyptic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing samples]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lucidedit.wordpress.com/?p=1094</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was snowing. Again. Heavy and thick, like the clouds themselves were bleeding into the wind. Greta watched through a hole in the wood that covered most of the window, wondering how the sky could contain so much snow in the first place. Although it was difficult to tell, since the light outside had been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1094&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="wp-image-1095 alignnone" alt="Abandoned Chairs" src="http://lucidedit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/blog-dystopia.jpg?w=270&#038;h=203" width="270" height="203" /></p>
<p>It was snowing. Again. Heavy and thick, like the clouds themselves were bleeding into the wind. Greta watched through a hole in the wood that covered most of the window, wondering how the sky could contain so much snow in the first place.</p>
<p>Although it was difficult to tell, since the light outside had been the same all day, curfew was approaching. The clock in the kitchen said it was just after five o’clock and curfew began at six. Greta peered through the snow, hoping to catch sight of her father’s shape among the swirling, endless white, but she couldn’t see him. She tried not to worry, but he was never late.</p>
<p>Greta glanced over her shoulder at the pot bubbling away on the stove. She had made a stew with the rabbits she&#8217;d caught yesterday, mixed with dried herbs, potatoes left over from the fall, and a can of green vegetables she’d taken from the basement storage pantry. It actually smelled pretty good and Greta’s stomach grumbled gently in agreement.</p>
<p>They would eat just as soon as father arrived.</p>
<p>Outside, the light started to change ever so subtly. The grey grew a tiny bit darker and the shadows deepened. Greta pressed her face against the glass and scoured the bleak landscape for her father.</p>
<p>Every day he made the trek into the city centre, past all the burned-out shells of buildings, over the metal bridge that had survived the devastation of ’38, and into what was left of the heart of the city. There, the council met to discuss the state of the city, listening to heart-wrenching stories and soliciting ideas that would help them rebuild the city and re-establish communication with the rest of the world.</p>
<p>Father said they were fools to believe there was a world left with which they could communicate. If there was, surely they would have come looking for us, he said. In his mind, their silence meant they had suffered the same fate – or perhaps one even worse.</p>
<p>Greta didn’t remember the storms that had preceded the devastation. She had been a baby then. But she had heard all the stories. How one storm after another had hammered the city for months on end, slowly taking out the power grids and the communication towers, sending residents into a panicked frenzy as they fought each other for supplies and food in the stores that were still standing.</p>
<p>And then the devastation had hit. Earthquakes that lasted for days, thunderstorms that blew down concrete buildings, set fires across the city, and caused flooding of Biblical proportions. Residents of the city had retreated to homes, malls and churches, hoping the buildings would still be standing when the devastation passed. Hoping that it would, in fact, pass.</p>
<p>Of course, it did pass. After a week of being pounded by every force nature could hurl at them, the ground stopped shaking and the skies cleared. The residents that had survived emerged to a completely different world. Greta vaguely remembered coming up from the basement in her father’s arms, shielding her eyes from the sunlight as they stepped outside.</p>
<p>Once the shock had worn off, the new world took shape. Limited supplies meant increased competition. Factions formed, with some groups raiding others for food, supplies and even women. It was a chaotic time, but eventually another group intervened. Members of the army, who had survived in their underground bunkers with plenty of food, access to weapons, fuel and a handful of vehicles, formed a regime and put the curfew in place. To protect our residents, they explained.</p>
<p>For ten years, the army had been the wardens of the city. Every night they swept through the streets, promoting a sense of order. In the early days some of the newly formed factions had tried to take them on. The army’s response was swift and brutal. If you were out after curfew there were no questions, no chances to explain yourself, you were simply cut down. Order requires cooperation, the army said. The safety of all of us depends on it. You must obey the rules if we are to survive.</p>
<p>Father didn’t agree with the army’s position, but, like most residents, he never missed curfew. He believed in the work he was doing at the council and said that you had to pick your battles. Greta wasn’t sure what that meant, though she knew one day she would carry on her father’s work. After all, she was his only child and this was her world.</p>
<p>The sky was almost dark now. Greta looked at the clock. It was nearly six. She wondered if she should go and look for her father, but knew how angry he would be if she did. No one goes out at curfew, except the very foolish and the suicidal.</p>
<p>She returned to the window, narrowing her gaze in the hopes that she would see something. And she did. A lone figure was struggling through the thick blanket of snow, head down against the wind. She couldn’t see his face, but she knew it was her father. Greta breathed a sigh of relief and walked over to stir the stew.</p>
<p>It was only once she reached the stove that she heard the rumble of the army patrol vehicle outside the house. Suddenly, Greta understood her father’s words. You have to pick your battles. Heart pounding, she pulled the rifle from under the kitchen floorboards. It was loaded, just in case of an emergency. Then Greta grabbed her coat and went to get her father.</p>
<p>———————————————————————————————–</p>
<p>This is my first time participating in the WordPress <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/writing-challenge-dystopia/" target="_blank">Weekly Writing Challenge</a>. This week the challenge asks us to explore our idea of what a dystopian world might look like.</p>
<p>———————————————————————————————–</p>
<p><em>Image credit: © <a href="http://www.photoxpress.com/search-stock-photos-photographer/paulo+Jorge+cruz/837540" target="_blank">Paulo Jorge Cruz</a> / <a href="http://www.photoxpress.com/" target="_blank">Photoxpress.com</a></em></p>
<div id="jp-post-flair"></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1094/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1094/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1094&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lucidedit.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/curfew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fb0b8b4cccf2115d41943a6df33ba72b?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucidedit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucidedit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/blog-dystopia.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Abandoned Chairs</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome to the Committee</title>
		<link>http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/dp-challenge-welcome-to-the-committee/</link>
		<comments>http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/dp-challenge-welcome-to-the-committee/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 09:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Karen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress Weekly Writing Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dystopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sausage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science fiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.wordpress.com/?p=2852</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week&#8217;s writing challenge: Write a short story or piece of descriptive faux-journalism describing your personal idea of a dystopia — a dark future when everything you hold dear is on the chopping block. ____________________________________________________________________ Things were much different, of course, before the Great Decision.  Kara was sure of it, although her memories of her [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2852&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week&#8217;s writing challenge:</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/writing-challenge-dystopia/" target="_blank">Write a short story or piece of descriptive faux-journalism describing your personal idea of a dystopia — a dark future when everything you hold dear is on the chopping block.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/images.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2560" alt="Daily Post at WordPress.com" src="http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/images.jpeg?w=240&#038;h=40" width="240" height="40" /></a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<div>____________________________________________________________________</div>
</blockquote>
<p>Things were much different, of course, before the Great Decision.  Kara was sure of it, although her memories of her childhood were growing hazy and it was forbidden to read the books or watch films from that period.  Still it did not keep people from talking about it, and the lunch time conversation  in the cafetaria was often dominated by talk of the Time Before, carried out in hushed tones, so that the Monitors would not overhear.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes, yes, I&#8217;m telling you it&#8217;s true,&#8221; Lalina was saying, trying to convince one of the younger girls of some outrageous fact that could not quite be believed.  &#8221;They made pictures of it, with the males and the females together, without any clothing on at all!&#8221;</p>
<p>Malika tore off another bit of bread and pushed it into her mouth, eyeing each of them around the table in turn, to see if someone might give away Lalina&#8217;s joke.  She was new to the division and had already been the victim of one of their pranks, when she had been sent into the men&#8217;s section to give Miglano, the supervisor there, a note that read, &#8220;I have a big round bottom.&#8221;  Miglano had flushed red, and immediately alerted the Monitors.  Two female officers arrived some forty-five minutes later, the crumbs of their lunch still clinging to the front of their uniforms and their breath stinking of onions.</p>
<p>&#8220;What took you so long?&#8221;  Miglano whined.  &#8221;I&#8217;ve had to wait here with her all this time, and hold this <em>note.</em>&#8221;  He spat out the word like it was an epithet.</p>
<p>In the end, the Monitors convinced Malika not to pursue a complaint against the pranksters.  There should have been repercussions, of course, but the Monitors insisted she could not possibly identify which of her co workers had given her the note and the instructions to deliver it, since she was so new there. And, since she was so new there, she didn&#8217;t want to stir up any trouble, did she?  Still, Malika was on guard and suspicious of her co workers, lest she be made a fool of again.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t believe a word of what you&#8217;re saying,&#8221; Malika said to Lalina.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s true,&#8221; Kara said.  She rarely spoke, but when she did, the others listened.  Kara was a Committee member, after all.  &#8221;My father had a stack of magazines like that, hidden in his office.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, so they had to hide them, even then?&#8221; Lalina asked.  This was a new bit of information which she planned on adding to her story.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes, I think so, but they weren&#8217;t forbidden then.  I&#8217;m not sure why he hid them.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;A magazine full of pictures of men and women without any clothes?  I don&#8217;t know whether to believe you or not,&#8221; Malika said, but it was clear her doubt was fading.  &#8221;Who would want something like that?  It doesn&#8217;t sound the least bit useful.&#8221;</p>
<p>No one at the table offered an answer, so the conversation drifted to the new standards for producing the XL-487, which the women had just been informed of that day.  Kara didn&#8217;t bother to listen.  She was a member of the Committee that Develops New Standards, and she was tired of hearing about them.</p>
<p>It was on the Committee that she had met Darlo, and last week he had confided to her that he had stopped drinking his daily ration of the Most Powerful Energy Drink.</p>
<p>&#8220;I can&#8217;t blame you.  It tastes like piss.&#8221;</p>
<p>He was stunned by her admission.  &#8221;You&#8217;ve drunk it?&#8221;</p>
<p>Kara nodded.  &#8221;Just a sip.  They sent several cases of it in the rations for the women&#8217;s quarters last year.  I was put in charge of repackaging it and shipping it back out, which I did, but not until after I tried a bottle.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But it&#8217;s forbidden for women to drink the Most Powerful Energy Drink.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s also forbidden for men <em>not </em> to drink it, so unless you want me to inform the Monitors on <em>you</em>, I suggest you don&#8217;t inform the Monitors on <em>me</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>He reached out and took her hand. &#8220;I would never inform the Monitors on you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kara let him hold her hand for a bit before she pulled away.  &#8221;The Monitors might see us,&#8221; she whispered, but she wasn&#8217;t really worried about the Monitors.  The truth of it was Darlo had become a bit of a pain, always expecting her to spend the fifteen minute Committee breaks with him, and even sending her secret notes delivered to her housing unit that said silly things like</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Thinking about you</em></p></blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Can&#8217;t wait to see you again</em></p></blockquote>
<p>While it had always been exciting to Kara to garner the attention of another Committee member, Darlo, with his beady eyes and his sausage fingers, had become tedious.</p>
<p>&#8220;The funny thing is,&#8221; Darlo explained as they walked back inside to resume their work, &#8220;I really feel like I have a lot more energy since I haven&#8217;t been drinking it.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Is that so?&#8221; Kara took her seat at the table and began unnecessarily studying the pile of papers in front of her.</p>
<p>&#8220;Kara .  . .&#8221; Darlo began, but Kara cut him off.</p>
<p>&#8220;Shhh,&#8221; she said, her finger to her lips.  &#8221;I have to read.&#8221;</p>
<p>That night, Darlo sent her another note.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>I can&#8217;t stop thinking about you.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Kara, for her part, had stopped thinking about Darlo immediately after the committee business had concluded for the day. She sighed after reading the note, just as Lalina passed by her in the hallway.</p>
<p>&#8220;What&#8217;s got you sighing?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Just another Committee note,&#8221; Kara lied and wasn&#8217;t sure if Lalina believed her.</p>
<p>&#8220;You and your Committee business,&#8221; Lalina lingered in the hallway.  &#8221;Still it must be nice getting to work on the different projects.  I swear if I have to assemble another XL-487 . . .&#8221; Her voice trailed off.</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t know if my job is any better.  I still have to assemble XL-487s.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Only three days a week, though.  The other two days you get to do something else, get to talk to different people.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not all it&#8217;s cracked up to be.  Anyway, keep your chin up,&#8221; Kara gave her friend a half-smile.  &#8221;The XL-488 is due to be released soon!&#8221;</p>
<p>Lalina laughed.  &#8221;Now that&#8217;s something to look forward to.&#8221;  She hesistated, and then spoke again.  &#8221;Say, what&#8217;s really in that note, Kara?&#8221;</p>
<p>Against her better judgment, Kara showed Lalina the note.  Lalina read it, and then read it again, before clasping her hand over her mouth to conceal a grin.  &#8221;I&#8217;ve heard about these mixed gender relationships!  I never thought you would be involved in one!&#8221;</p>
<p>Kara grabbed Lalina&#8217;s arm and dragged the woman down the hall and into her room. She locked the door before she said,  &#8221;I&#8217;m thinking I ought to be offended by that remark.  Why <em>shouldn&#8217;t</em> I be involved in a mixed gender relationship?&#8221;</p>
<p>Lalina shrugged.  &#8221;You&#8217;re always so much about business, and your Committee.  I didn&#8217;t think you even noticed the men.  And this Darlo.  He&#8217;s the chubby one that wears the belt cinched too tight about his waist?&#8221;</p>
<p>Kara put her head into her hands.  &#8221;Yes, he is.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, I know him.&#8221;  Lalina looked off into the distance, her eyes dreamy.  &#8221;I like his smile.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t like his smile, and I wish he&#8217;d stop sending me these notes.&#8221;  Kara tore the note into tiny bits before throwing it into the fire.</p>
<p>&#8220;Stop answering them, then.  That should put an end to it.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t answer them.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;How I wish I had someone sending me secret notes,&#8221; Lalina said, her voice tinged with sorrow and envy.  &#8221;It seems so exciting!&#8221;</p>
<p>Kara had an idea.  &#8221;Why don&#8217;t you answer his notes?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Me?  It&#8217;s you he&#8217;s keen on.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not sure it&#8217;s me.  I think it has something to do with the Most Powerful Energy Drink.&#8221;  Kara explained her theory to Lalina, and before long she had convinced her friend to respond to Darlo&#8217;s note.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Hello.  You don&#8217;t know me, but I&#8217;d like to get to know you.  My name is Lalina, and I&#8217;m a friend of Kara&#8217;s and she&#8217;s told me all about you.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Together, they marked the outside of the envelope DARLO and sent it off to the men&#8217;s quarters.</p>
<p>Within the hour, there was a response.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Hello, Lalina.  I think I do know you.  You&#8217;re the one with the melodious laugh I see sitting next to Kara in the cafetaria, aren&#8217;t you?  Thank you for this note.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;Look at that,&#8221; Lalina showed Kara the note.  &#8221;I&#8217;ve got a melodious laugh.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Are you going to write him back?&#8221;</p>
<p>Lalina held the note up to her nose and inhaled deeply.  &#8221;It smells like sausage.&#8221; She held it out for Kara to smell, but Kara waved her off.  &#8221;Of course I&#8217;m going to write him back.&#8221;  She turned and went back to her room.</p>
<p>At the next Committee meeting, Darlo nodded at Kara, but he didn&#8217;t pass his share of the mid-morning snack to her, and he completely ignored her during break, when he did not bother to even go outside for the fresh air.  Kara wandered out to where each of the various cliques congregated: the Smokers huddled together at one end, far from the rest, the Candy Chompers with their lollipops and breath mints that they offered to Kara as she walked by, and those who didn&#8217;t smoke or eat candy, but instead had pencils stuck in their mouths.  It was amid the Pencil Gnawers that Kara saw him, the new member of the Committee, tall with curly brown hair and very white teeth that he was using to chew a pencil.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hello,&#8221; Kara said.  &#8221;Welcome to the Committee.  My name is Kara.&#8221;</p>
<p>He took the pencil out of his mouth and held out his hand.  &#8221;Hello.  I&#8217;m Tyro.&#8221;  He smiled at her with those gorgeous white teeth.</p>
<p>She took his hand and held it longer than was necessary for the handshake.  They stood alongside one another for a moment before Kara turned to him and asked, &#8220;So, Tyro.  Have you ever thought about not drinking the Most Powerful Energy Drink?&#8221;</p>
<p>Tyro hunched down close to her and said in a voice just loud enough for her to hear,  &#8221;Well, now, Miss Kara, between you and I, I don&#8217;t drink it.  I think it tastes like piss.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kara looked straight ahead and smiled, rocking slightly back and forth on her heels, content to be a member of the Committee.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2852/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2852/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2852&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/dp-challenge-welcome-to-the-committee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8c943d0370581a094b4aa952f93e4bd3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kayeraye</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://donotgetsickinthesinkplease.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/images.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Daily Post at WordPress.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wasted Past, Unwashed Future</title>
		<link>http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/an-unwashed-future/</link>
		<comments>http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/an-unwashed-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 11:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>rarasaur</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[challenge accepted!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apocalypse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apolcalyptic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily prompt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dpchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dystopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dystopic fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rarasaur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/?p=6657</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My name is Ana Patton Mendoza.  I was born in the Year of Waste, the early days of 2015.  My granddaughter, Liliana, says I have the memory of an elephant.  Elephants were extinct long before her birth, of course, but the lifespan of language has always been longer than that of life. I am a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6657&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My name is Ana Patton Mendoza.  I was born in the Year of Waste, the early days of 2015.  My granddaughter, Liliana, says I have the memory of an elephant.  Elephants were extinct long before her birth, of course, but the lifespan of language has always been longer than that of life.</p>
<p>I am a baker.  I have green eyes.  I haven&#8217;t had a bath in over 20 years.</p>
<p>Yesterday, I celebrated my anniversary to my one true love, Gabriel &#8212; Gabe &#8212; Mendoza.  He passed away several years back, not long after my daughter and her husband.  It is a love still worth celebrating, but a time that is hard to look back upon.  Liliana, with the effortless wisdom of a 10-year-old, gifted me a journal to store my turbulent thoughts.</p>
<p>I suppose if you&#8217;re reading this, then this dusty anniversary present was found in a box with other estate items that no one wanted.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re from the future then, and I won&#8217;t pretend to know what would interest a person such as yourself.  Though I could guess.</p>
<p>I hear that I am one of the few remaining green-eyed women.  Baking is also a lost art, or so my grandfather used to tell me as I played on the floor of his bakery when I just a child.</p>
<p>I suspect, though, despite my many oddities, you&#8217;ll be most interested in the lack of bathing.</p>
<p>Baking will always find a place in society&#8211; a small, unappreciated corner, but a corner nonetheless.  And green eyes&#8211; well.  Are they really so different from brown?   I look into Liliana&#8217;s chocolate eyes and see my daughter&#8217;s eyes, and my own.  They are a different shape and color, but there is a light in them that marks us as family.</p>
<p>But no, extinct elephants and bakers with green eyes do not have substance enough for the history books.  History is about eras, and we are living in the era of the Servian.</p>
<p>Though I lived through the transition into this time, I doubt I will live through the end of it.  You&#8217;ll have to fill in the rest of the story, dearie, whoever you are.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll leave a blank page for you at the end, and I&#8217;ll start at the beginning as I remember it.</p>
<p>I was a little girl, growing up in the outskirts of Washington State.  I could have never foreseen the future&#8211; not that I ever thought past the moment.</p>
<p>I lived on a vineyard, one so big that it folded right over the edge of the horizon and kept on going.  Grandpa owned a bakery on the most southern portion of our land.  My parent&#8217;s vineyard sold directly to the major juice companies at the time, back when companies were allowed to bottle foods and juices.  You may find some bottles in the estate with the journals, though I hope not&#8211; those should have stayed with Lil and her children.  Or her children&#8217;s children.</p>
<p>Despite what the kids today would tell you, 2015 was a good year.  Yes, we were indulgent, but we were also accepting.  It wasn&#8217;t uncommon to look around a table and see that each person had a different diet, different style of clothing, and different belief system.  There were Vegans&#8211; those who didn&#8217;t eat any animal product.  There were Servians&#8211; those who served Mother Earth through the conservation of water and natural resources.  There were hipsters and hippies, techies and foodies, Hindus and Christians&#8211; all sorts.  Each subculture had rules of their own, but around the dinner table or at the school plays, we were basically the same.</p>
<p>Of course, that could just be the perception of a child.  I was young and my parents weren&#8217;t the sort to point out fences and borders.</p>
<p>At the time, no one really was.</p>
<div id="attachment_6664" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 224px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6664" alt="The early days, when it was still funny." src="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/servian.jpg?w=214&#038;h=300" width="214" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">2018</p></div>
<p>By the time I was 10, the Servians had really found a home up in Washington State.  They were funny, which is probably why so many people were willing to convert to an existence with limited bathing and no gasoline-powered cars.  In fact, the whole movement started with a joke by a late-night comic at the time.  Something about how we could fix all the world&#8217;s problems if we cut down on water by showering with a friend.</p>
<p>I only actually watched his show once, a fact that embarrasses my poor Lil to no end.</p>
<p>Today he&#8217;s considered the father of Servianism, and the kids are really into the look of the <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">propaganda</span> promotional posters that he created.  They call them vintage and the government styles everything after them.</p>
<p>To be fair, it was more than humor that turned a monologue into a movement.  We had just gotten over a lot of war,  international bickering, and a lot of the states were having to borrow the resources they needed from other states and were going bankrupt in the process.  This is before the re-unionization, of course.</p>
<p>In a way, serving our world by giving up a little luxury just made sense.</p>
<p>Washington State became officially Servian on the year I graduated high school.  To get any benefits, or even a job, conversion was pretty much required.  The news called us a hippie state, and the tech firms that operated out of the state left in a flurry of anger.  Around this time, we stopped being quite so accepting.  There were a lot of snide remarks about anyone who didn&#8217;t convert.</p>
<p>Gabe was always in a huff about it.  We were just friends at the time, but a summer job gave us the quiet moments we needed to turn a friendship into a full-fledged romance.  He turned out to be the love of my life.</p>
<p>We married and decided to save as much as possible in order to leave the state, so we went full Servian and stopped bathing entirely.  This effort provided us with an enviable tax refund every year.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see, that was the spring of &#8217;37.</p>
<p>It took us 5 years to get enough together, what with getting married and having our first child, Lillith.</p>
<p>In the winter of &#8217;42, we moved to one of the last non-Servian states&#8211; Las Vegas.  We enjoyed about a month of showers, baths, and cars that moved 10 times faster than anything we had seen in a long while.  Then the Federal Conservation Act passed, out of the blue.</p>
<p>Well, it was out of the blue for me.  I suppose if you followed the political unrest and finances of each state, you&#8217;d have seen it coming.  Gabe was always talking about the nation&#8217;s inevitable push towards a forced Servian society, but he was paranoid like that.  I thought of it more like a fad, a temporary thing&#8211; an optional conversion that maximized your tax benefits.</p>
<p>Gabe, bless his heart and curse his perception, was right.</p>
<div id="attachment_6665" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 307px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6665" alt="2044" src="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/terrorism2.jpg?w=297&#038;h=300" width="297" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">2044</p></div>
<p>The FCA wasn&#8217;t a small act.  No, it came with enforcement, and it was only about month after it&#8217;s announcement that soldiers ripped through our city, disconnecting water pipes and doing whatever they could to lay down the law.</p>
<p>Las Vegas was a wreck.  Gabe and I managed just fine because we had basically grown up Servian, but the rest of that state <em>really</em> wasn&#8217;t ready to handle it.  There were riots.  Spectacular Las Vegas riots.</p>
<p>On a Wednesday afternoon, I saw a car bomb go off in front of the Bellagio.  The next morning, the re-unionization happened.  The president said in an effort to stabilize the economy, the states should come together as one.</p>
<p>If I had known I&#8217;d be one of the last survivors of my generation, I promise I would have paid more attention to the hows and the whys.  But I was a mom, a wife, and a baker&#8211; and it was all I could do to focus on that.  All I know is that the re-unionization put the Constitution in question and that&#8217;s when things really started getting strange.</p>
<p>The Union was profitable, though.  I remember that much, at least.  We watched a little video in the cafe where I worked that showed how Servian society had completely rolled back the nation&#8217;s debt.  Just a few years into it all, and we had a surplus in the quadrillions.</p>
<p>It was a smelly, but good, few years for the Union.  The world took our lead, and they called it our coming of age story.  Servianism went world-wide.</p>
<p>Then the problems started.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re supposed to call them <em>sacrifices</em>, to make them feel like noble deeds and purposeful choices.</p>
<p>But I lost my husband, my daughter, and my son-in-law to those &#8220;sacrifices&#8221;. <em> It wasn&#8217;t my choice. </em> It&#8217;s a flaw in the system&#8211; an ugly, terrible flaw.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure why we didn&#8217;t see the problems on smaller scales before the culture took over the nation, but in retrospect, I suspect they were kept quiet and hushed by the media.</p>
<p>Gabe would be proud of me.  Now I&#8217;m a conspiracy theorist, too.</p>
<p>The flaw of an unhygienic, unwashed people is obvious to anyone&#8217;s who has ever lived differently.  It is in the illnesses. The infections.  The contamination.</p>
<p>We had to stop companies from bottling or boxing up foods because it was too easy to bottle up a toxin and pass it all over the Union.  The vineyard I grew up on withered and died.  We isolated ourselves in every way possible.  The population thinned and is continuing to thin.  That&#8217;s all political speak.  It means that wives and sisters, husbands and fathers, children and grandparents are <em>dying</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_6667" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6667" alt="2076" src="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/serviansservetomorrow.jpg?w=300&#038;h=220" width="300" height="220" /><p class="wp-caption-text">2076</p></div>
<p>The country is filthy because the people are filthy, and the media and government keep promoting all this because it&#8217;s making them filthy rich.  They tell us we have taller buildings, and smarter children, but what good is all that if no one survives to see it?</p>
<p>In a week, we roll into the 80&#8242;s, and I&#8217;ll turn 65.  There will be a party in town for me, celebrating my grand old age.  They are genuinely happy for me, but inside I cringe at the idea that 65 is old.</p>
<p>Sitting on the floor of my grandpa&#8217;s bakery, I still remember him telling me that if had a chance to go back to his 70&#8242;s, he&#8217;d party every day.  Who knows how old he was at the time? 80? 90? 100, even?</p>
<p>100 wasn&#8217;t unheard of in my day.</p>
<p>Liliana, on the other hand, has never met anyone older than me.  She&#8217;s never used an operational shower, or seen an elephant, or drank professionally bottled grape juice.</p>
<p>Her life today won&#8217;t be her life forever, though.  Someone of my grand old age, even just a baker like myself, knows<em> that,</em> at least.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve started to hear people call themselves liberals. Today I saw a man set himself on fire, next to a sign explaining that he&#8217;d rather die than pass on his infection to his family.  I wonder if he had the cold, or flu, or something that I would have laughed at back in the 20&#8242;s.</p>
<p>Either way, it&#8217;s the beginning of a change.   In fact, they&#8217;re calling 2080 the Year of Change&#8230; but the people who name these years surely don&#8217;t live them.</p>
<p><em>I</em> was born in 2015, you know.  The year they call the Year of Waste.  I have green eyes.  I am a baker.  My name is Ana Patton Mendoza, and I haven&#8217;t had a bath in over 20 years.  I was once married to the love of my life, a man named Gabe, who died from a minor throat infection as an involuntary Servian.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping this finds you well.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping whoever is reading this is clean and<em> old</em>&#8211; much older than myself.  I&#8217;m hoping this journal is found and that you understand what I&#8217;ve said and the life I&#8217;ve lived, even though my writing is poor and my details are vague.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know what lessons I suppose you should learn from this.  That celebrities and the educational elite bear a responsibility for the sensations they create and the causes they support?  That greed is a dark and sinister path?  That of all the resources on the planet to waste, the waste of life&#8211; animal or human&#8211; is the biggest waste of all?</p>
<p>Language, I&#8217;ve always said, has a much longer lifespan than life itself, and the language of a grandmother worried for her granddaughter is one that transcends time.</p>
<p>I suppose that&#8217;s the main reason that I&#8217;m writing anything at all, then.  Change didn&#8217;t happen in time for my daughter and it&#8217;s unlikely it&#8217;ll happen in time for me.  If it does not happen for my granddaughter, either&#8211;  if you are not her daughter, or her daughter&#8217;s daughter&#8211; please consider yourself part of our story since you&#8217;ll be writing the last page.</p>
<p>As part of our story, as part of our family, please remember her.  She is 10 years old.  She has brown eyes, and loves her silly old grandma.  She is a baker, or will be. She was born a Servian, a citizen of the Union of the States.  She has never had a bath.  Her name is Liliana.</p>
<p>___________________________________________</p>
<p><strong>Weekly Writing Challenge:</strong> Write a short story or piece of descriptive faux-journalism describing your personal idea of a dystopia — a dark future when everything you hold dear is on the chopping block. <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/writing-challenge-dystopia/" target="_blank">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/writing-challenge-dystopia/</a></p>
<p>(For any of those participating in the dystopic future challenge who might want to create similar images as the one above, I used <a href="http://www.photofunia.com" target="_blank">http://www.photofunia.com</a>.  Have fun with it!)</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/category/about/challenge-accepted/'>challenge accepted!</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6657/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6657&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/an-unwashed-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/serviansservetomorrow.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/serviansservetomorrow.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">serviansservetomorrow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5bd9564edf7ca5da9507cffc12b5ea95?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rarasaur</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/servian.jpg?w=214" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The early days, when it was still funny.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/terrorism2.jpg?w=297" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2044</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/serviansservetomorrow.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2076</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Secret to Great Social Content</title>
		<link>http://tarahunt.com/2013/02/28/the-secret-to-great-social-content/</link>
		<comments>http://tarahunt.com/2013/02/28/the-secret-to-great-social-content/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 04:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tara Hunt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eMarketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[content marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social web]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tarahunt.com/?p=2183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[Hedgehog &#38; Fox - as found for sale on Etsy by StayAwake in London, Ontario] First off, the title of this post is misleading. There is no formula, everything is social and it&#8217;s not about the content at all. But with that out of the way, there IS a different philosophy to creating social content [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2183&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hedgehog_fox.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2185" alt="hedgehog_fox" src="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hedgehog_fox.jpg?w=630&#038;h=472" width="630" height="472" /></a>[<a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/60007735/woodland-animal-pair-hedgehog-and-fox" target="_blank">Hedgehog &amp; Fox - as found for sale on Etsy by StayAwake in London, Ontario</a>]</p>
<p>First off, the title of this post is misleading. There is no formula, <a href="http://www.amazon.ca/Rules-Creating-Value-Social-ebook/dp/B0097DM41E" target="_blank">everything is social</a> and it&#8217;s not about the content at all.</p>
<p>But with that out of the way, there IS a different philosophy to creating social content and the key to uncovering it lies with a theory posited by Isaiah Berlin*, a philosopher in an essay called &#8220;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hedgehog_and_the_Fox" target="_blank">The Hedgehog and the Fox</a>&#8221; where he refers to a poem by the ancient Greek Archilochus, who describes the two characters as follows:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8220;The fox knows many little things, but the hedgehog knows one big thing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Foxes are multidisciplinary, adaptable, self-critical, tolerant of complexity, cautious and empirical, while Hedgehogs are specialized, stalwart, stubborn, order-seeking, confident and ideological. While Hedgehogs look for evidence to support their beliefs and are highly susceptible to confirmation bias, Foxes tend to appear to the outside world as uncertain and a bit scattered.</p>
<p>Bear with me here. This matters.</p>
<p>Quite often, people seek out things like formulas and best practices and all sorts of ways to ensure the best outcomes. Books and posts and articles and infographics are gobbled up whole in order to satisfy an eager marketers desire to implement a &#8216;highly impactful&#8217; content strategy. These types are Hedgehogs. They will see a popular 700&#215;700 inspirational quote being passed around Facebook like wildfire and think, &#8220;A-ha! That&#8217;s the key! We need to create more square inspirational quotes!&#8221; This results in something like this:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-27-at-9-41-22-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2184" alt="Screen Shot 2013-02-27 at 9.41.22 PM" src="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-27-at-9-41-22-pm.png?w=567&#038;h=339" width="567" height="339" /></a></p>
<p>Not saying that these sorts of techniques are without merit. Hell, it&#8217;s been shared 225x and liked 1,274x. I, myself, have deployed a few of these bad boys and achieved great results. But when analyzing any data behind the content I&#8217;ve produced, there just isn&#8217;t enough evidence to support that a formula alone makes for good, sharable, interesting content. And formulas grow tired and have declining returns.</p>
<p>Hedgehogs use formulas and pump out content that satisfies formulas and when the returns on that content decline, they look around and find new formulas to mimic. This is not only unsustainable, but it&#8217;s insulting to the people who are following your content. These messages speak to the choir (who will sing on key), but will rarely incite others to join in.</p>
<p>Foxes, on the other hand, approach content very differently. They may pick up ideas from what&#8217;s hip and happening and learn from other successes, but they spend WAY more time figuring out what it is that their customers really care about and work on delivering THAT. This takes all of the multi-disciplinary, adaptable, self-critical, tolerance for complexity and empirical talent they have. They can&#8217;t &#8220;plan&#8221; a calendar months in advance. That would be ludicrous and a waste of time. Their content morphs and bends with too many variables, the biggest of which is the needs of the audience itself.</p>
<p>I wrote about these Foxy creatures <a title="Let Me Wave my Magical Content Wand" href="http://tarahunt.com/2013/01/11/magic-content-wand/">at length in my last post on content</a>. It&#8217;s not hard to find them, either. Just look at the YouTubers that are killing it with subscribers. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/SerialPranksters" target="_blank">Two of them stayed at my house last weekend</a> and when <a href="http://carlospache.co" target="_blank">Carlos</a> asked them about their &#8216;secret sauce&#8217;, they looked at him puzzled. In their minds, there was no such thing as a &#8216;secret sauce&#8217;. They just run around with a camera and whatever they think is funny, they record and post. When I told them there were <em>some</em> basic principles, they pushed back and said, &#8220;If you start using rules, you stop using your instincts.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">IF YOU START USING RULES, YOU STOP USING YOUR INSTINCTS.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">That is a phrase very much worth repeating. Whether it&#8217;s Roman and Dennis of <a href="http://www.youtube.com/SerialPranksters" target="_blank">SerialPranksters</a> or the incredibly funny <a href="http://www.youtube.com/JennaMarbles" target="_blank">Jenna Marbles</a> or my personal fave <a href="http://www.youtube.com/harto" target="_blank">Hanna Hart</a>, there is no way you can decipher a formula for success. The only things they have in common is that they are naturally funny, have great instincts for what others will find funny and just keep producing. Sometimes they produce huge hits and sometimes they produce misses, but they are consistent and adaptive. (and uniquely themselves)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I&#8217;ve tried to explain to clients over the years that the best gauge of what will be well-received is something that they, themselves, would find entertaining or useful. But Hedgehogs have a very tough time shifting to this perspective.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">&#8220;I would find my PRODUCT entertaining and useful. It&#8217;s the BEST!&#8221; they answer.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This is where the self-critical aspect comes into play. Most Foxes will say that they are really bad salespeople, but in actuality, they are great salespeople&#8230;especially in a cynical world. They don&#8217;t think of themselves or their product as &#8220;the most amazing whatever&#8221;. They never stop wanting to improve and, as a result, end up growing rabid fan-bases because of their humble approach and customer empathy. Many beloved brands I&#8217;ve studied carry the self-critical gene: <a href="http://www.zappos.com" target="_blank">Zappos</a>, <a href="http://www.threadless.com" target="_blank">Threadless</a> (their motto was actually, &#8220;We are never good enough&#8221;), <a href="http://www.etsy.com" target="_blank">Etsy</a>, and <a href="http://www.southwest.com/" target="_blank">Southwest Airlines</a>&#8230;just to name a few. They are more focused on their customer&#8217;s happiness than their own any day and it shows with loyalty and sales.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">But back to content. There is no secret because &#8216;secrets&#8217; and &#8216;formulas&#8217; and &#8216;best-practices&#8217; belong in the realm of Hedgehogs. But if you are a stubborn Hedgehog, and you admit it, there ARE a few ways to become more Foxy:</p>
<ol>
<li>put down the content calendar and just hang out with your customers (AND your competitors&#8217; customers) more. Not with a clipboard taking notes or with the desire to convince anyone to try your product. JUST CHILL and absorb.</li>
<li>stop thinking of your audience as content consumers. They do not live for your &#8216;sharables&#8217;. They aren&#8217;t sitting with index fingers hovering over the like button, eagerly awaiting your next witty post. They have lives and you are a small, teensy part of their daily thoughts. If they don&#8217;t think of anything else other than you, you have a bigger problem on your hands.</li>
<li>go to a movie, read a book, subscribe to blogs, skim through magazines &#8212; outside of your industry and outside of your comfort area. Embrace diversity and different points of view. Have conversations with people you would never dream of having conversations with.</li>
<li>think really hard about what you are truly passionate about. What makes you laugh, cry, sing&#8230;what inspires you. What are you drawn to? Think about this honestly outside of the context of your business. Do more of that. Learn how to trust your instincts again and when they lead you astray&#8230;</li>
<li>don&#8217;t fret. Some things will work and some things won&#8217;t. But keep going and learning from those mistakes. Take criticism with a grain of salt and start to learn what is constructive and what is not. Being experimental and open doesn&#8217;t mean you have to bend with every whim either. You&#8217;ll learn over time and hone that instinct beautifully.</li>
</ol>
<p>The &#8216;secret&#8217; to great social content is about a new approach to thinking. One that is service-oriented and empathetic. A question I always pose to people I work with on content is, &#8220;Is this going to make people feel better? Smarter? More in control of their lives? Help them look good to their friends? Help them make more friends? Give them tools to grow? Save them a headache? Time?&#8221; If the answer is no, you are really just adding noise. If a tv, paper or magazine constantly put out content that did nothing but serve their own interests, they wouldn&#8217;t last long. Every brand has to think like a newsroom now (while every newsroom has to think like a brand, really).</p>
<p>So the secret? Think like a fox, stop following advice and tap into those instincts.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>* credit where credit is due: I read about Berlin in Nate Silver&#8217;s awesome book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007V65R54/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B007V65R54&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=hormarunc-20">The Signal and the Noise: Why So Many Predictions Fail-but Some Don&#8217;t</a> - where the theory inspired this entire post. And I can&#8217;t help but point out that I did not gain inspiration for a post by reading a social media book, but a book about statistics, predicting outcomes, sports and politics.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2183&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tarahunt.com/2013/02/28/the-secret-to-great-social-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hedgehog_fox.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hedgehog_fox.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hedgehog_fox</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2649fce53397f60611f508e742ad2980?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Miss Rogue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hedgehog_fox.jpg?w=630" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hedgehog_fox</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://missrogue.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-27-at-9-41-22-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2013-02-27 at 9.41.22 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One of The Guys From Mastodon Lives on My Block</title>
		<link>http://tyrannyoftradition.com/2013/02/27/im-pretty-sure-one-of-the-guys-from-mastodon-lives-on-my-block/</link>
		<comments>http://tyrannyoftradition.com/2013/02/27/im-pretty-sure-one-of-the-guys-from-mastodon-lives-on-my-block/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 17:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Keith Spillett</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General Weirdness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlanta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cal Ripken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cannibal Corpse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Mumphrey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mastodon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rick Wakeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ron Kovic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tyrannyoftradition.com/?p=2933</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[About two weeks ago, the house up the street had a moving van in front of it.  At first, I didn’t think much of it.  After all, I live in Atlanta and people are always moving around in order to avoid the rampaging hordes of flesh-eating reptiles that roam the streets at night.  Had I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2933&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2934" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://tyrannyoftradition.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1361_photo.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-2934" alt="It's one of these guys.  I'm not sure which.  Most white people in their 30s look alike to me." src="http://tyrannyoftradition.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1361_photo.jpg?w=490&#038;h=396" width="490" height="396" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s one of these guys. I&#8217;m not sure which. Most white people in their 30s look alike to me.</p></div>
<p>About two weeks ago, the house up the street had a moving van in front of it.  At first, I didn’t think much of it.  After all, I live in Atlanta and people are always moving around in order to avoid the rampaging hordes of flesh-eating reptiles that roam the streets at night.  Had I not built a Y2K shelter some years back, I would have probably been devoured myself.  My family and I hide there during the evenings, watching old VHS copies of <a class="zem_slink" title="The Young and the Restless" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Young_and_the_Restless" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">The Young and The Restless</a> until the wee hours of the morning with shotguns in our hands.  My 4-year-old is particularly skilled at shooting the beasts when they try to overpower the deadbolt.  She’s a great shot for 4.  I’m hoping that one day she can lead the humans as we rise up and try to take back control of our cities from the robot overlords.  Maybe she won’t.  We all grow up thinking we are going to be something special.  Sometimes, we just end up working in retail.</p>
<p>The fellow coming in and out of the moving van seemed nice enough.  He had longish hair and a mustache that made him look something like either <a class="zem_slink" title="Ron Kovic" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ron_Kovic" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Ron Kovic</a> or a relief pitcher for the Brewers in the mid-70s.  I greeted him with my usual Sufi chant and politely asked if he minded if I took a lock of his hair in order to fuse his DNA with a water buffalo.  He looked a bit shocked, so I put my shirt back on.  That way he would not have to stare at the eyes that had begun to grow out of my stomach.</p>
<p>Suddenly, a feeling of recognition overwhelmed me.   I knew this fellow.  He was in the band Mastodon.  I don’t know how I knew, I just knew.  I immediately asked him to autograph my copy of .<a class="zem_slink" title="38 Special (band)" href="http://www.38special.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">38 Special</a>’s “Wild-Eyed Boys of The South”.  I had been carrying this copy of the album with me for months asking celebrities to sign it.  So far, I had gotten <a class="zem_slink" title="Rick Wakeman" href="http://www.rwcc.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Rick Wakeman</a>, the former Yes keyboard player who currently works at the Publix deli counter in Decatur, and <a class="zem_slink" title="Jerry Mumphrey" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jerry_Mumphrey" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Jerry Mumphrey</a>, the former Yankees outfielder who lives inside of my right kidney, to put their names on it.  Had this Mastodon guy signed it, it would have completed my collection and allowed me to pass into the cosmic netherworld of alien dwarves.  But he refused.</p>
<p>He broke my heart.  As a fan, all I ask is for a little acknowledgement.  After all, I’ve spent hours of my life listening to that album with the whale on the cover of it.  Is a signature too much to ask for?</p>
<p>It’s like the time I broke into Cal Ripken’s home and demanded that he sing all of the lyrics to &#8220;Covered With Sores&#8221; by Cannibal Corpse at gunpoint.  I wasn’t asking a lot.  My request certainly didn’t warrant the two and a half years I served in the Allenwood Federal Correctional Facility.  Or the removal of all of my teeth at the hands of some hired goon named Vito.  But the Ripkens can be brutal when you cross them.  I learned that the hard way.</p>
<p>So here I am.  It’s 2:30 in the afternoon.  I am covered in honey and ox blood from head to toe.  Waiting.  Hoping.  I’ve been in the guy from Mastodon’s living room for 3 hours now playing Black Ops 2 on his Xbox.  I wonder if he’s at the supermarket.  Or collecting and trading pig exoskeletons with his church group.  Or meditating at an ashram in Utah.  Or at the park reading his dog-eared copy of V.C .Andrews’ masterpiece “Flowers in the Attic”.  He has to come home at some point.  Doesn’t he?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2933/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2933/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2933&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tyrannyoftradition.com/2013/02/27/im-pretty-sure-one-of-the-guys-from-mastodon-lives-on-my-block/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a03685fecaafc1599ba1ffc521cb3caf?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tyrannyoftradition</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tyrannyoftradition.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1361_photo.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">It&#039;s one of these guys.  I&#039;m not sure which.  Most white people in their 30s look alike to me.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spires Into the Sky</title>
		<link>http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/spires-into-the-sky/</link>
		<comments>http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/spires-into-the-sky/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 15:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kavita</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bombay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[By the sea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dversepoets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My love(s)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OpenLinkNight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skyline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[True cities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://kavisionz.wordpress.com/?p=7305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Long after the days and nights have merged unceremoniously into an eclipse of hardened truth Long after life has perished and death has vaporized into a cloud of tearful smog Long after voices have dropped like insignificant pennies into bowls held by callous hands Long after dreams have realized into bittersweet delusions catalyzed by an [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7305&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://kavisionz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130220-104636.jpg"><img class=" " title="The urban mantra" alt="The urban mantra" src="http://kavisionz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cities.jpg?w=400&#038;h=590" width="400" height="590" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photography and image editing by Kavita</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">Long after the days and nights<br />
have merged unceremoniously<br />
into an eclipse of hardened truth<br />
Long after life has perished<br />
and death has vaporized<br />
into a cloud of tearful smog<br />
Long after voices have dropped<br />
like insignificant pennies<br />
into bowls held by callous hands<br />
Long after dreams have realized<br />
into bittersweet delusions<br />
catalyzed by an ambitious cocaine<br />
Long after the feet have run<br />
beyond those thorny pinnacles<br />
coveted by many a faraway eye</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The city still breathes<br />
in her million pulsating hearts<br />
The city still bleeds<br />
into a million curious minds</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Mostly thriving<br />
Sometimes conniving<br />
But always striving<br />
To seduce the unknown<br />
To accompany the lonely<br />
To hold back her own</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And she lives&#8230;<br />
like none other&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mylivesignature.com" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" style="border:0!important;background:transparent;" alt="" src="http://signatures.mylivesignature.com/54488/367/D24188FA3D8FF12BD4C8809AFC83B4CC.png" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">*Posting this for <span style="color:#37768b;"><em><strong><a title="OpenLinkNight @ d'VersePoets" href="http://dversepoets.com/2013/02/19/open-link-night-week-84/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#37768b;">OpenLinkNight @ d&#8217;VersePoets</span></a></strong></em></span>&#8230; my favorite stop for inspiration! *</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/category/poetry/'>Poetry</a> Tagged: <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/bombay/'>Bombay</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/by-the-sea/'>By the sea</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/city/'>City</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/dversepoets/'>dversepoets</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/my-loves/'>My love(s)</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/new-york/'>New York</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/openlinknight/'>OpenLinkNight</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/reality/'>Reality</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/skyline/'>Skyline</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/true-cities/'>True cities</a>, <a href='http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/tag/urban/'>Urban</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7305/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7305/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7305&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kavisionz.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/spires-into-the-sky/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/832ba186f76c58d0208115fc7bcd4845?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kavisionz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kavisionz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cities.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The urban mantra</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://signatures.mylivesignature.com/54488/367/D24188FA3D8FF12BD4C8809AFC83B4CC.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Cruel Goddess Ana</title>
		<link>http://penpaperandcrazy.wordpress.com/2013/02/26/the-cruel-goddess-ana/</link>
		<comments>http://penpaperandcrazy.wordpress.com/2013/02/26/the-cruel-goddess-ana/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 20:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pen/Co-conscious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anorexia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DID]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eating disorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eating disorders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goddess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goddess Ana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MPD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEDA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personifying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-harm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strength]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thinking thin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thinspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trigger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[words]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://penpaperandcrazy.wordpress.com/?p=1446</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Trigger warning for a more in-depth discussion of my eating disorder issues and mentioning of my (stupid) perusal of pro-Ana websites. I do not want to encourage any eating disorders.  That is not my intent with this post at all.  Please let me know if you find it &#8220;pro-eating disorder&#8221; because I am not in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1446&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Trigger warning for a more in-depth discussion of my eating disorder issues and mentioning of my (stupid) perusal of pro-Ana websites.<br />
I do <span style="text-decoration:underline;">not</span> want to encourage any eating disorders.  That is not my intent with this post at all.  Please let me know if you find it &#8220;pro-eating disorder&#8221; because I am <span style="text-decoration:underline;">not</span> in that mindset, despite my struggle.</strong></em><br />
_________________________________________________________________</p>
<p>This week is <a href="http://nedawareness.org/" target="_blank">National Eating Disorder Awareness week</a>.  Unfortunately, what it&#8217;s done for me is just made me more aware of mine and the fact that I am no where near a stable recovery (though I am trying).</p>
<p>I slipped up today in my perusing of eating disorder blogs.  Usually I&#8217;m good and just read the strictly supportive/recovery based ones.  The ones that do not encourage Thinking Thin or Thinspiration or any of that harmful talk.  I found a couple new ones yesterday that were absolutely lovely and gave me all sorts of smiles.</p>
<p>Today I stumbled across a pro-Ana (a term for anorexia) blog.  I didn&#8217;t realize it at first because it wasn&#8217;t overt like some.  I won&#8217;t link it here because that just perpetrates the cycle of harm and I will not be a part of that.</p>
<p>What bothered me was the way the blog talked about the Goddess Ana.  Personifying a disorder into this figure of anti-eating, rib-showing, thigh-gap encouraging &#8220;deity&#8221; they could pray to for assistance.   I am horrified.  I hate that I immediately got an image of what this goddess would look like.  And she would be cruel.  She would demand constant sacrifice; the blood, sweat, tears, and pounds of her worshipers.</p>
<p>I thought we were past the old days of sacrificing young women to appease the gods.</p>
<p>Apparently not.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve merely moved on to a darker strain of sacrifice.  Instead of a quick knife or even a pyre of flame- it is a slow torture of starvation.  It is giving that little piece of you daily to a tall, impossibly thin and icy eyed woman who says it is <strong><em>never</em> </strong>enough.  Just a couple more pounds.  Always just a couple more.  Her mouth is a black hole and it devours your strength, your health, your sanity with gulping force, the sharp teeth glittering in a border of poisoned words.</p>
<p>And words have power.  I give this goddess power merely by encouraging this descriptive personification.  I can&#8217;t help it.  But I will not let such a cruel goddess rule me.  I line my personal angels and guardians up around me.  I do not look into her eyes or step anywhere near that gaping mouth.  I will not dedicate myself to a goddess who demands such a high sacrifice.</p>
<p>I will not.</p>
<p>And I can only hope that other women and girls (and men and boys) will find the strength to turn away.  To know that they are beautiful just as they are.  They were beautiful all those weeks ago before they heard the call of the Goddess Ana.  Before the siren&#8217;s song started.</p>
<p>We are stronger than we know.</p>
<p>Be gentle, be loving, be strong.  <strong>You are worth it.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_1541" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 526px"><a href="http://penpaperandcrazy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/nedawarenesweek.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-1541" alt="http://nedawareness.org/" src="http://penpaperandcrazy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/nedawarenesweek.png?w=516&#038;h=215" width="516" height="215" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://nedawareness.org/" rel="nofollow">http://nedawareness.org/</a></p></div>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<p><em>Note:  I purposely put some tags that may seem slightly &#8220;pro-Ana&#8221; in hopes that someone will stumble across this post when looking for tips or encouragement.  And I hope this encouragement of a different sort, of a truly positive sort, will start the healing process.<br />
Happy National Eating Disorder Awareness week.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1446/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1446/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1446&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://penpaperandcrazy.wordpress.com/2013/02/26/the-cruel-goddess-ana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cf9eadf58ea15aabe7d3b906b0a2d045?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">penpaperandcrazy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://penpaperandcrazy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/nedawarenesweek.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://nedawareness.org/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does the Market Care About the Sequester?</title>
		<link>http://acrossallsports.com/2013/02/28/does-the-market-care-about-the-sequester/</link>
		<comments>http://acrossallsports.com/2013/02/28/does-the-market-care-about-the-sequester/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 17:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Danny Vinik</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economic Policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dow soaring as sequester nears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequester and Wall Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequester Hitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wall Street reaction to sequester]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acrossallsports.com/?p=2189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The sequester officially takes effect tomorrow and there has been almost zero negotiations between the White House and Republican leaders over avoiding the cuts. Instead, both sides have spent most of their energy blaming the other side. The media has done an excellent job covering this aspect of the sequester, but it has ignored another [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2189&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://acrossallsports.com/2013/02/28/does-the-market-care-about-the-sequester/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0d449053b05aa89592f03e663db1824f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dvinik</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2004sox.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dow-2-28.jpg?w=595" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dow 2.28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2004sox.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dow-3-day.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dow 3 day</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feel the Beat of the Rhythm of the Nineties</title>
		<link>http://brotherjonspage.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/1990/</link>
		<comments>http://brotherjonspage.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/1990/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 11:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brother Jon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[90's music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AC/DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Better Than Ezra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BroJo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brother jon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeBarge is a Movember hero!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Clapton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Michael]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gin Blossoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[le clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metallica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rage Against the Machine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Hot Chili Peppers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brotherjonspage.wordpress.com/?p=8913</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You see what I did there? Yeah, I took the title of a totally great song&#8230;from a different decade&#8230;and switched it around for my post title, just like Le Clown. I&#8217;m quite certain that everyone thinks that their &#8220;era&#8221; of music is the best&#8230;even those from the &#8217;70&#8242;s. I&#8217;m no exception. The other day Le [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8913&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://brotherjonspage.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/1990/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>96</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ef259f53287a146f05605cbabd8d6334?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pdhagar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brotherjonspage.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/90s.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
