<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 00:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The question of &#8220;Why?&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://hotmilkforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-question-of-why-14/</link>
		<comments>http://hotmilkforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-question-of-why-14/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 18:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hotmilkforbreakfast</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eradication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poppy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hotmilkforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-question-of-why-14/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I had a very good friend comment to me about this blog, asking me to share more about myself.  Personally, I am not a shy guy; but I come from many generations of upper Midwestern Germans, where you apologize a lot, just in case you’ve offended someone. And you DEFINITELY do not tell stories about [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=295&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/1.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>I had a very good friend comment to me about this blog, asking me to share more about myself.  Personally, I am not a shy guy; but I come from many generations of upper Midwestern Germans, where you apologize a lot, just in case you’ve offended someone.</p>
<p>And you DEFINITELY do not tell stories about something amazing and awesome that has happened to you, or things you’ve accomplished, because that is boasting, and no-one likes a braggart.</p>
<p>Well, I am prepared to take a deep breath, and explain about why I am doing this and how I got here.</p>
<p>Over the last three+ years, I’ve been living and working in Afghanistan.  Since the US Military and other government agencies have been active there since 2001, that’s really not that big of a story.  What is different about what I’ve done, is that most of that time, I haven’t lived on a Forward Operating Base (FOB) or traveled in convoys of large armored vehicles, armed with heavy weapons and wearing body armor.</p>
<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/photo-1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/photo-1.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>Because I haven’t been dressed like the Michelin Man in body armor, festooned with weapons, travelled in 20 vehicle convoys of Jawa-tracks like in Star Wars, I’ve had the opportunity to actually speak to, live with, and make friends with real Afghans, who aren’t just there to beg for goodies from the unending pockets of Uncle Sam.</p>
<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/brothers.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/brothers.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>In fact, I’ve been shot at and run off the road by US and British soldiers because, as a bearded man driving a car on the road, I must deserve to be shot at and/or run off the road.  That perspective changes your attitude in a hurry.</p>
<p>I started this journey for unusual reasons, though.  Despite 26 years of military experience, and some farting around as a military historian, I had yet to have “seen the elephant”, despite enduring Saddam Hussein’s incompetent missileers and one half-hearted ambush during the opening days of the 2003 Iraqi invasion, I had yet to engage in one single engagement with “the enemy”.  Some part of me wanted to correct this deficiency.  So, when I heard from a friend that there was a private security contract that would hire me, pay a reasonable amount of money and would absolutely guarantee that I would “see the elephant” in as many gunfights as I could stand, I jumped at it.  So, I joined the US Department of State’s Poppy Eradication Force, and travelled to Afghanistan in early 2009.</p>
<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/5.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/5.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>After a short stop in Kabul, they flew me down to Helmand Province, where poppy eradication was already underway.  And my wishes to face the enemy and exchange rounds was satisfied immediately.  Moments after landing, several rockets impacted in our immediate area and over the next 6 months, our eradication efforts resulted in almost two gunfights a day and several near misses with both IEDs and bullets.</p>
<p>It seems the Poppy producers don’t care to lose their valuable crop, so they would shoot at us coming in, and shoot at us going out, and try to blow us up with IEDs any time they could in between.</p>
<p>Two things stick with me from that.  First, I learned that not only did I do well during combat, but I found, shockingly, that I enjoyed it.  I liked the risk taking, the sounds, and the incredible feeling of exultation when sharp bits go zooming past your head and you are still alive.</p>
<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/6.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/6.jpg?w=399" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>Detaining and interrogating suspicious guys near Gereshk</p>
<p>The second thing that I remember is what happened on March 11<sup>th</sup>, 2009, that would change my path.  On March 10<sup>th</sup>, we sat on a series of hills north of Gereshk, a town in Helmand, where we observed eradication operations.  During that time, we detained five individuals that we thought were acting suspiciously.  After searching and questioning them, we decided to let them go.  The next day, our Afghan National Army escort decided to go back to that same place to give away some leftover food from our mess, and they parked in the same place where we had parked the day before.</p>
<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/4.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/4.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>After the explosion that obliterated their truck, we found the same five guys from the day before in a nearby building, and after a short, sharp firefight, we captured them.  Thinking about sitting on that IED for several hours the day before, and about letting go the guys who set it off, started me thinking about why I came there and what I was hoping to accomplish.</p>
<p>After a lot of soul-searching, I decided to sign up for one of the cultural programs that were currently going on.  And that is how I found myself wandering around Afghanistan, hanging out, talking to people and learning as much as I could and making friends with several Afghans and a few fellow traveller Westerners, including Afghan-Americans, Americans, and various Europeans of an assorted flavor.</p>
<p><a href="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2436.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" src="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2436.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p>One thing I noticed, is the disbelief that most people we ran into about what we did and how we did it.  Soldiers looked at us with disbelief, and I was called a liar several times because “no-one goes out there without a convoy/security/etc.”. Talking to Americans who’ve never been to Afghanistan, I get nothing but Lassie looks from people when I try to explain what I do there, and I have finally given up and just tell people “I supported the Army”.</p>
<p>The truth is, there are very few Americans who have the slightest clue about how Afghans live their lives.  Especially the Americans who are stationed there, who only see Afghans in extremis, or in non-Afghan situations like on the FOBs. It is even more difficult to explain to my fellow countrymen about how much fun I had there, and what a lovely place Afghanistan is.  The purpose of this blog is to try to give people who cannot go there a picture of what Afghanistan is like.</p>
<p>Afghan kids are like kids anywhere, and Afghan parents love their children, and want their country to modernize, and want industry and the freedom to travel, so that they can see the rest of the world.  Afghans tend to like America, and its freedoms, but are annoyed at the heavy handed and inconsistent manner in which American non-policy is carried out.  But my point here is not to become a political pundit or to give lectures on American policy.  Other people (who are mainly dilettantes and wholly unqualified to run their ignorant yaps) have assumed that mantle.</p>
<p>And now, back to my entertaining and (hopefully) informing about my Afghan adventures.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/295/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/295/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=295&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hotmilkforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-question-of-why-14/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1d762f85aa5e0fa7c29ed850c3a54bf6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hotmilkforbreakfast</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/1.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/photo-1.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/brothers.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/5.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/6.jpg?w=399" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/4.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hotmilkforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2436.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Myth of the Citizen Journalist</title>
		<link>http://talesofgrim.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-myth-of-the-citizen-journalist/</link>
		<comments>http://talesofgrim.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-myth-of-the-citizen-journalist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 16:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>grimachu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current-events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://talesofgrim.wordpress.com/?p=328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My mind tends to wander and mull over things when I walk and I&#8217;m trying to up my exercise for my mental and physical health so my mind&#8217;s been wandering a lot lately. On this wander, for no reason in particular, though perhaps percolated through from watching the first episode of The Newsroom (I won&#8217;t [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=328&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft" style="border:2px solid transparent;" src="http://www.smak.be/tentoonstellingen_afbeeldingen/2005%20speakers%20corner_web2.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="452" />My mind tends to wander and mull over things when I walk and I&#8217;m trying to up my exercise for my mental and physical health so my mind&#8217;s been wandering a lot lately. On this wander, for no reason in particular, though perhaps percolated through from watching the first episode of <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wC8ovJYAU3U" target="_blank"><strong>The Newsroom</strong></a> (I won&#8217;t be a regular watcher though. We have this myth of the citizen journalist, the blogger, the brave new cutting edge of political, social and scientific commentary and news. Newspaper readership is plunging and news shows and channels are polarising politically and becoming more and more extreme and opinionated in chasing a smaller and smaller audience.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a problem though. The citizen journalist isn&#8217;t a journalist. They&#8217;re not bound by ethics (little wonder then that journos are increasingly forgetting <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News_International_phone_hacking_scandal" target="_blank"><strong>theirs</strong></a>). Many of them are just soapboxing their own opinions, spouting a particular dogma, chasing a particular demographic as though they were selling something rather than informing us. They are selling us something, what we want to hear. Fox News is probably the most egregious case of a politicised news channel, commercialising right wing politics and providing comforting mooing noises to the American right wing. They&#8217;re by no means the only ones to do so and one can find similar bias going the &#8216;other way&#8217; if you look for it. I lean left so I&#8217;m not so sensitised to it, but I acknowledge that it&#8217;s there.</p>
<p>The irony is that this is absolutely not what we need from the mainstream media any more. If I want opinion I can read any of thousands of blogs. I can dip into my twitter feed or search on the hashtag of the item in question, like the #arabspring. I get ill informed emails and facebook messages from distant relatives and friends of friends all the time. I am drowning in opinion, conjecture and dogma the entire time I&#8217;m logged into the internet. These aren&#8217;t citizen journalists, they&#8217;re <em>gossips</em>.</p>
<p>Gossip is great, witnesses are great, people like <a href="http://www.penny-red.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Laurie Penny</strong></a> who go out there and become part of the news and report from the front lines are all well and good but they&#8217;re not giving us THE news. They&#8217;re giving us THEIR news. It&#8217;s the same with Fox etc in the US and to a lesser extent here in the UK, at least on television. We&#8217;ve been somewhat spoiled by the BBC which, other than its simpering towards the Royal Family gets criticised from all sides of the political spectrum which is generally a good indicator that they&#8217;re doing something right. Our printed news sources are as partisan and biased, if not more so, than the US though.</p>
<p>Market pressure, the commodification of information, has ruined television news on an international basis and it is creeping in to the UK now despite our public institutions. It&#8217;s making these big news companies do things that they&#8217;re simply not suited to. No television broadcast can hope to keep up with the internet when it comes to breaking stories. No television broadcast can tailor itself to fit someone&#8217;s views precisely. People stream their own opinion-based news from the blogs, RSS feeds, twitter subscriptions etc that they make for themselves.</p>
<p>Broadcast TV can&#8217;t compete with that and equally individualist internet journalism cannot hope to compete &#8211; still &#8211; with the prestige and weight that broadcast news does.</p>
<p>What broadcast news should be doing is not giving us more opinion, not trying to stay on top of breaking stories. What broadcast news with the money and resources that it still commands should be doing is offering us THE news, free from bias. Broadcast news should be doing the analysis, the depth, talking to the experts. &#8216;This is what happened, this is what educated and intelligent people are saying was involved&#8217;. Not blame games, just the pursuit of truth and accuracy with an integrity that makes it trustworthy.</p>
<p>Leave the opinion and shouting to the &#8216;citizen journalist&#8217;.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=328&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://talesofgrim.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-myth-of-the-citizen-journalist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d8257d41e8a0ce792552759b73f272f7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grimachu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.smak.be/tentoonstellingen_afbeeldingen/2005%20speakers%20corner_web2.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vintage Book Covers: Misc 3</title>
		<link>http://shewalkssoftly.com/2012/07/23/vintage-book-covers-misc-3/</link>
		<comments>http://shewalkssoftly.com/2012/07/23/vintage-book-covers-misc-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 01:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>shewalkssoftly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[absurd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vintage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shewalkssoftly.com/?p=16754</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The giant radioactive rodent welcomes you to this post. Civilization staggered! I actually could have made a lot of money this way&#8230; Who WOULDN&#8217;T? Go on with your bad self! And while we&#8217;re on the subject&#8230; Why what a unique cover for a party hosting book. I guess &#8220;The New Hostess&#8221; sits naked by the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=16754&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The giant radioactive rodent welcomes you to this post.  <em>Civilization staggered!</em><br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/38702878017379497_qbnyuzgb_f.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/38702878017379497_qbnyuzgb_f.jpg" alt="" title="38702878017379497_QBnYuzGb_f" width="393" height="640" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16755" /></a></p>
<p>I actually could have made a lot of money this way&#8230;<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/219972763019290191_xddxryhw_f.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/219972763019290191_xddxryhw_f.jpg" alt="" title="219972763019290191_XDdxRYHw_f" width="450" height="615" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16756" /></a></p>
<p>Who WOULDN&#8217;T?<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/13581236346933285_yz2chavy_f.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/13581236346933285_yz2chavy_f.jpg" alt="" title="13581236346933285_Yz2ChaVy_f" width="450" height="684" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16757" /></a></p>
<p>Go on with your bad self!<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/222013456601022017_udzuyz6s_f.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/222013456601022017_udzuyz6s_f.jpg" alt="" title="222013456601022017_UDzUyz6s_f" width="255" height="400" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16758" /></a></p>
<p>And while we&#8217;re on the subject&#8230;<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dicky-delightful-in-rainbow-land.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dicky-delightful-in-rainbow-land.jpg" alt="" title="Dicky-Delightful-in-Rainbow-Land" width="450" height="603" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16759" /></a></p>
<p>Why what a unique cover for a party hosting book.  I guess &#8220;The New Hostess&#8221; sits naked by the fire and cooks the guests to serve on bread.<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/host.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/host.jpg" alt="" title="host" width="424" height="637" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16760" /></a></p>
<p>This is more the usual fare:<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/scan10018-706x1024.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/scan10018-706x1024.jpg" alt="" title="Scan10018-706x1024" width="450" height="652" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16762" /></a></p>
<p>Incredible cover.<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sculpture-by-alan-aldridge-1966-via-flickr.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sculpture-by-alan-aldridge-1966-via-flickr.jpg" alt="" title="Sculpture by Alan Aldridge, 1966, via Flickr." width="394" height="640" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16763" /></a></p>
<p>Careful with that &#8220;man-about-town,&#8221; Night Club Nurse&#8230;<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/nightclubnurse-1.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/nightclubnurse-1.jpg" alt="" title="NightClubNurse-1" width="389" height="662" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16765" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230;or you may become:<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/elliott-registered-nympho.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/elliott-registered-nympho.jpg" alt="" title="elliott-registered-nympho" width="450" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16764" /></a></p>
<p>Stick with:<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_00061-650x1024.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_00061-650x1024.jpg" alt="" title="IMG_00061-650x1024" width="450" height="708" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16766" /></a></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s another pulp gem.  I&#8217;m assuming &#8220;world&#8217;s oldest trap&#8221; refers to the woman on the left:<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hell.jpeg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hell.jpeg" alt="" title="hell" width="400" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16767" /></a></p>
<p>If THIS guy hands you a frog in your pudding, you eat it.  You eat it and you shut up.<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/file0002.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/file0002.jpg" alt="" title="File0002" width="265" height="400" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16768" /></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;ll end on an uplifting note.<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/scan10056-691x1024.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/scan10056-691x1024.jpg" alt="" title="Scan10056-691x1024" width="450" height="666" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16769" /></a></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t worry&#8230;it gets&#8230;well, not better I guess&#8230;<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/to-be-old-and-sad.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/to-be-old-and-sad.jpg" alt="" title="to-be-old-and-sad" width="450" height="617" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16770" /></a></p>
<p>Oh fine, go have some:<br />
<a href="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/196539971208636466_zuyw9p7t_f.jpg"><img src="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/196539971208636466_zuyw9p7t_f.jpg" alt="" title="196539971208636466_ZUyw9p7T_f" width="450" height="609" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16771" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/category/absurd/'>absurd</a>, <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/category/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/category/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/category/vintage/'>vintage</a> Tagged: <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/tag/absurd/'>absurd</a>, <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/tag/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://shewalkssoftly.com/tag/vintage/'>vintage</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/16754/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/16754/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=16754&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shewalkssoftly.com/2012/07/23/vintage-book-covers-misc-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c2f3979e88d9d842cb5ca90349759843?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shewalkssoftly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/38702878017379497_qbnyuzgb_f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">38702878017379497_QBnYuzGb_f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/219972763019290191_xddxryhw_f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">219972763019290191_XDdxRYHw_f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/13581236346933285_yz2chavy_f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">13581236346933285_Yz2ChaVy_f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/222013456601022017_udzuyz6s_f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">222013456601022017_UDzUyz6s_f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dicky-delightful-in-rainbow-land.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dicky-Delightful-in-Rainbow-Land</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/host.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">host</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/scan10018-706x1024.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Scan10018-706x1024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sculpture-by-alan-aldridge-1966-via-flickr.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sculpture by Alan Aldridge, 1966, via Flickr.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/nightclubnurse-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">NightClubNurse-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/elliott-registered-nympho.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elliott-registered-nympho</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_00061-650x1024.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_00061-650x1024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hell.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/file0002.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">File0002</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/scan10056-691x1024.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Scan10056-691x1024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/to-be-old-and-sad.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">to-be-old-and-sad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shewalkssoftly.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/196539971208636466_zuyw9p7t_f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">196539971208636466_ZUyw9p7T_f</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sorry, American Bar Association, I Am Not My Hair</title>
		<link>http://businesslitigationatty.com/2012/07/26/sorry-american-bar-association-i-am-not-my-hair/</link>
		<comments>http://businesslitigationatty.com/2012/07/26/sorry-american-bar-association-i-am-not-my-hair/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 17:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>businesslitigationatty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[American Bar Association]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maryland daily record]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Careerist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://businesslitigationatty.wordpress.com/?p=975</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today the American Bar Association&#8217;s online news site brings us a hard-hitting piece of journalism on . . . . women&#8217;s hair. Well, not just any women&#8217;s hair, thank goodness. The ABA has not transformed overnight into an In Style knock off. Yet. In an article entitled, &#8220;Is Long Hair a Bad Choice for Older [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=975&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today the American Bar Association&#8217;s online news site brings us a hard-hitting piece of journalism on . . . . women&#8217;s hair.  </p>
<p>Well, not just any women&#8217;s hair, thank goodness.  The ABA has not transformed overnight into an In Style knock off.  </p>
<p>Yet.</p>
<p>In an article entitled, &#8220;<a href="http://www.abajournal.com/mobile/article/is_long_hair_a_bad_choice_for_older_career_women/">Is Long Hair a Bad Choice for Older Career Women</a>,&#8221; Debra Cassens Weiss suggests that women over forty who wear their hair long &#8220;are making a mistake.&#8221; </p>
<p>Admittedly Weiss is quoting from a post at <a href="http://thecareerist.typepad.com/">The Careerist</a>, an American Lawyer Media site featuring today, directly beneath the hair post, an article called &#8220;Corporate Lawyer Pens Cookbook About Weeds.&#8221; Weiss goes on to quote the author of The Careerist hair piece, writing that Hillary Clinton&#8217;s hair has been “growing like an unruly potted plant” and that she looks “haggard and rumpled.&#8221; According to Weiss, The Careerist spoke with &#8220;a California entertainment lawyer and a law firm consultant&#8221; for further information. The lawyer &#8211; who, for the love of God, should be outed and immediately shunned &#8211; said that for older women, &#8220;[e]ven if the hair is long, glossy, and well-maintained, the juxtaposition of aging or—to be politically correct—&#8217;mature&#8217; facial features and youthful hairstyle doesn&#8217;t work[.]&#8221; </p>
<p>Yes, Weiss is only highlighting a post featured in another online publication.  But Weiss is also writing for the American Bar Association.  And she should know better.  </p>
<p>I&#8217;d be less thoroughly pissed off if Weiss offered some response to this ludicrously vapid piece of reporting.  Surely there is someone out there capable of offering a more reasoned commentary on the current Secretary of State for the United States than that her hair has gone vegetative.  But if there is, the ABA is not interested in finding him or her.  He or she will remain, alas, forever unquoted.</p>
<p>And I point this out because it follows rather closely on the heels of another, admittedly more local, journalistic gaffe here in Maryland.  Last week, the local legal paper, The Maryland Daily Record, published a piece on its online blog, <a href="http://thedailyrecord.com/ontherecord/">On The Record</a>, which discussed opportunities for women on the bench.  I can&#8217;t link to the article itself because it has been summarily pulled from the site in response to a wave of criticism from women lawyers and judges, and to the paper&#8217;s credit it has since apologized.  The objectionable material included the use of a photo of the Spice Girls.  I am fairly certain &#8211; but correct me if I&#8217;m wrong, certainly &#8211; that if United States Magistrate Judge Paul W. Grimm is formally elevated to the bench of the United States District Court for Maryland, the Daily Record will not illustrate its coverage of the event with a photograph of Justin Beiber.  </p>
<p>I attended a bar association meeting recently and the Spice Girls conundrum was the topic of conversation in a way it really hasn&#8217;t been since Posh became Victoria Beckham.  And one of the points I heard made repeatedly was that there is a real disconnect between older women lawyers and their younger, Gen Y counterparts when it comes to issues like these.  The author of the Spice Girls post appears to be a member of the Gen Y camp.  And she is not a lawyer, although she wrote her article under the Maryland Daily Record masthead, so presumably she had some oversight.  I have heard some calling for &#8220;sensitivity training&#8221; for younger women, as if to be a woman demanding respectful treatment is to have a disability. Sensitivity isn&#8217;t really the issue.  Real world experience, and familiarity with history, is.</p>
<p>Perhaps these younger women have never experienced the pleasure of appearing at opposing counsel&#8217;s office for a deposition, only to be invited to set up their court reporting equipment in the conference room.  Or of being called &#8220;sweetheart&#8221; or &#8220;hon&#8221; (an old Baltimore favorite) or &#8220;babe.&#8221; But I worry that in fact they have, and that instead of being taken aback they take it in stride.  As if being condescended to is a cost of doing business as a female.  </p>
<p>Is it? Should it be? </p>
<p>Is there a point at which the members of a traditionally disadvantaged class are expected to put down their weapons &#8211; assuming they ever wielded any to begin with &#8211; and make nice? Is that what is happening here?</p>
<p>I contemplated closing this post with a reference to the Lady Gaga song, &#8220;Hair,&#8221; in which she chants repeatedly that she is &#8220;as free as [her] hair.&#8221; And that would be cute, possibly, and would give me the opportunity to include a Lady Gaga picture, which might just drive some traffic to this page.  And screw that, because the willingness to do and say anything in the name of driving traffic is quite possibly a major part of the heretofore described disconnect.  Attention is not self-justifying.  </p>
<p>I sincerely hope that in the race to appear on the first page of Google, we are not sacrificing what we learned in other, older, and less virtual contexts.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/975/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/975/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=975&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://businesslitigationatty.com/2012/07/26/sorry-american-bar-association-i-am-not-my-hair/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4d4fa747aaa96644589ee2f904d17a3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">businesslitigationatty</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four Cents Worth Of Etiquette</title>
		<link>http://blurtblog.net/2012/07/23/four-cents-worth-of-etiquette/</link>
		<comments>http://blurtblog.net/2012/07/23/four-cents-worth-of-etiquette/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 04:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>omawarisan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Foolishness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bagel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[etiquette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blurtblog.net/?p=12483</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A question of etiquette arising from ordering breakfast.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12483&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://blurtblog.net/2012/07/23/four-cents-worth-of-etiquette/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>35.410694 -80.842850</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>35.410694</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-80.842850</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f8d9a95a68e0ffc503c1f733119020d5?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">omawarisan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/24/43144973_ff8b66935c_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cheers Bar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.coinnews.net/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/Four-2009-Bicentennial-Lincoln-Penny-Images.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Pros and Cons of Making &#8216;The Hobbit&#8217; Into a Trilogy</title>
		<link>http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-pros-and-cons-of-making-the-hobbit-into-a-trilogy/</link>
		<comments>http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-pros-and-cons-of-making-the-hobbit-into-a-trilogy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 15:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Robert Snow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[an unexpected journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lord of the Rings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martin freeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter jackson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hobbit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[there and back again]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trilogy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/?p=2926</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Could the story of this project get any more complex? The Hollywood Reporter found out yesterday that “talks are accelerating” between director Peter Jackson and Warner Bros. to expand his upcoming two Hobbit films into a trilogy. Jackson believes that there’s enough material in J.R.R. Tolkien’s additional writings to support an additional film, and wants [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2926&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-pros-and-cons-of-making-the-hobbit-into-a-trilogy/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2929" title="Hobbit 4" src="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-41.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="339" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Could the story of this project get any more complex? <a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/hobbit-third-movie-warner-bros-353719">The Hollywood Reporter</a> found out yesterday that “talks are accelerating” between director Peter Jackson and Warner Bros. to expand his upcoming two <em>Hobbit</em> films into a trilogy. Jackson believes that there’s enough material in J.R.R. Tolkien’s additional writings to support an additional film, and wants to secure funding from the studio to start two more months of shooting in New Zealand.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">At first, I thought this was a bad idea. I’m generally opposed to lengthening movie and television series, because history has shown that it <a href="http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2011/08/04/twelve-years-is-simply-too-much/">doesn’t end well</a>. But for once, I’m of two minds in the case of <em>The Hobbit</em>. I’d like to see a strong, succinct adaptation of Tolkien’s novel, and I’m unsure of what might happen if a third film is greenlit. At the same time, I know there are advantages to Jackson’s plan.<span id="more-2926"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Of course, Peter Jackson is no stranger to longer versions of his work. Die-hard <em>Lord of the Rings</em> fans agree that you’re not getting the complete experience unless you watch the special Extended Edition Blu-rays and DVDs. So are we really surprised that Jackson couldn’t part with some of the footage he’s shot for the two confirmed films?</p>
<div id="attachment_2936" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 494px"><a href="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-61.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2936" title="Hobbit 6" src="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-61.jpg?w=484&h=289" alt="" width="484" height="289" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Peter Jackson hinted at the possibility of a third film at Comic-Con</p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;">On the “pros” side, with a third <em>Hobbit</em> film, we’d get more of what we love from adaptations of Tolkien’s work, more Middle Earth: jolly hobbits, brave warriors, epic battles and beautiful landscapes. And there’s certainly enough written material to back it all up. J.R.R. Tolkien wrote exhaustive appendices for his novels that include enough notes, family trees and side narratives and to make several movies. A third film would feel just as “Tolkienian” as any of the others.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">What I’m worried about, however, is a split focus. We’ve known for years that the two-film concept would already draw heavily from the appendices and follow side-stories that don’t appear in the <em>Hobbit</em> novel. Most notably, we&#8217;d find out what happens to Gandalf after he parts ways with the Company of Dwarves outside Mirkwood. With a third film, there will be even more screen time devoted to other characters, and Bilbo Baggins could end up having a smaller role, like that of Frodo in <em>The Lord of the Rings</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_2933" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 496px"><a href="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-3.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2933" title="Hobbit 3" src="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-3.jpg?w=486&h=323" alt="" width="486" height="323" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The focus of the story could drift away from Bilbo if a third film is made</p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;">As spectacular as it would be to get another epic trilogy from the minds of Jackson &amp; co., by moving things to a grander scale, the story could lose the “bedtime story” quality of the original novel. <em>The Hobbit</em> is a different read than <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> &#8211; the narrator often addresses the reader directly as if Bilbo’s story is being recited from memory. By including more side-stories that don’t focus on Bilbo, the films could lose some of the simple charm that sets <em>The Hobbit</em> apart.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">On the positive angle again, there’s potential here for the series to be even more lucrative for Warner Bros. I’m not praising this because I want to see Hollywood executives get richer, but because the cash injection will mean more jobs in the film industry for New Zealanders and more money for the studio to spend on future projects. Who knows &#8211; it could convince a studio to tackle one of Tolkien’s more esoteric works, like <em>The Silmarillion</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_2937" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 495px"><a href="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2937" title="Hobbit" src="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit1.jpg?w=485&h=291" alt="" width="485" height="291" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">More films means more money, which could mean future adaptations of other Tolkien works</p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then again, Warner Bros. may still say no, and project will move ahead in its current form. With this development just unfolding in the days since Comic-Con, greenlighting a third film would involve more than just financing. Actor contracts and licensing rights would also have to be secured &#8211; and a lot of the <em>Hobbit</em> cast is getting very busy with other projects, thanks to the advance buzz. Like it or not, by next week <em>The Hobbit</em> might start a new chapter of its development saga. Here’s hoping the journey is worth it.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">-</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">What do you think about Jackson’s pitch for a <em>Hobbit</em> trilogy? Will it do justice to Tolkien’s work? Or are the risks too great? Are there any other pros or cons with the idea? Let me know in the comments section below! If you liked this post, share it with your friends and followers, and browse through my other movie-related articles:</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">-</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/5-flaws-in-the-dark-knight-rises-that-couldnt-be-avoided/">5 Flaws in <em>The Dark Knight Rises</em> That Couldn&#8217;t Be Avoided</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/07/09/4d-movies-the-latest-greatest-gimmick-comes-to-north-america/">4D Movies: The Latest, Greatest Gimmick Comes to North America</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/05/01/how-do-you-sell-a-48-fps-movie/">How Do You Sell a 48 fps Movie?</a></p>
<p style="text-align:right;">-</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2926/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2926/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2926&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://robertsnow.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-pros-and-cons-of-making-the-hobbit-into-a-trilogy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-5.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-5.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hobbit 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0f9f5e2fd2b0490871ed163740afbddb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robertsnow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-41.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hobbit 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-61.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hobbit 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hobbit 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertsnow.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/hobbit1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hobbit</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The games we play</title>
		<link>http://welcometothemotherhood.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-games-we-play/</link>
		<comments>http://welcometothemotherhood.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-games-we-play/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 14:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Carinn @welcometothemotherhood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Non-fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jenga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newlyweds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[struggle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://welcometothemotherhood.wordpress.com/?p=621</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We rode the train from Florence back to Venice in silence. It seemed like a really great idea, I consoled myself. Ian&#8217;s gazed was fixed somewhere out the window, out of our train car. This two-week trip to Europe was our farewell to east coast living.  It had been 11 days of pure perfection.  Zurich, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=621&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://welcometothemotherhood.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/the-games-we-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4cdc0c5b67c07c54b1df5af87ed7c5ca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">welcometothemotherhood</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://welcometothemotherhood.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/jenga.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jenga</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiffany Mountain</title>
		<link>http://myeverydayphotos.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/tiffany-mountain-2/</link>
		<comments>http://myeverydayphotos.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/tiffany-mountain-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 03:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Teri J Pieper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[hike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Butte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ladybugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lookout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Methow photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Methow Valley Ciderhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiffany Mountain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whitebark pine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildflowers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://myeverydayphotos.wordpress.com/?p=2969</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Trying to get in one hike per week is not always easy. Everyday life and work gets in the way, of course, and then there&#8217;s the weather. Friday I was planning a mountain outing and the weather forecast was for extreme thunderstorms and lots of rain. I cancelled my plans and was glad of it. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2969&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trying to get in one hike per week is not always easy. Everyday life and work gets in the way, of course, and then there&#8217;s the weather. Friday I was planning a mountain outing and the weather forecast was for extreme thunderstorms and lots of rain. I cancelled my plans and was glad of it. We were lucky to have lots of rain, thunder and lightning and wind. Other places also had flash flooding and 80 mph winds that pushed down trees and knocked out power.</p>
<p>I managed to get some work done on Friday and changee my hike to the other side of the valley and headed for Tiffany Mountain, elevation 8242&#8242;. It&#8217;s a long drive up Boulder Creek from the East Chewuch Road, 22 miles from Winthrop to the trailhead. The valley had scattered fog from the rain the day before and puffy white clouds appeared up high. The<a title="trail description" href="http://www.wta.org/go-hiking/hikes/tiffany-mountain" target="_blank"> Freezeout trail </a>to Tiffany is three miles, one way, with a steep part to start, then a gradual grade and finishing with another steep part to get to the top. The elevation gain is 1740&#8242;. This area is great for wildflowers but Luna and I were a couple weeks early for the main part of the bloom. We may have to do it again!</p>
<p>Looking up at the mountain I could always see white clouds behind it. At the top, looking down the other side towards Tiffany Lake, all I could see was cloud &#8211; no view of the lakes or even towards the Okanogan. The clouds were piled up against the ridge. It was mostly sunny for us with a few sun blocks off and on. The temperature was comfortable and I needed my windbreaker at the top where it was breezy and cool.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Fog in the river valley before I left home.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-5.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2970" title="July 21, 2012-010-5" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-5.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;">This area is part of the Tripod fire from 2006.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2971" title="July 21, 2012-010-9" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-9.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="751" /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;">I have to confess &#8211; I saw this piece of wood from a long ways away and was convinced it was a grouse.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2972" title="July 21, 2012-010-40" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-40.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="676" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I think these are dead whitebark pines. Whitebark pines are in decline around the west for a variety of reasons. You can learn more about them <a title="whitebark pine foundation" href="http://www.whitebarkfound.org/index.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2973" title="July 21, 2012-010-45" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-45.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="368" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The &#8216;easy&#8217; part of the trail, with the summit in view. In a couple of weeks, the meadow will be ablaze with wildflowers.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2974" title="July 21, 2012-010-47" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-47.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">From the top, looking south along the ridge. The Okanogan and Conconcully are on the other side that is covered in clouds.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2975" title="July 21, 2012-010-70" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-70.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="679" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And looking northwest; down to the right in the mist, way down, is Tiffany Lake. I did get a glimpse of a pika in the rocks and heard their high-pitched calls</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2976" title="July 21, 2012-010-73" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-73.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="672" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Ladybugs clustered on lichen covered rocks near the summit.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2977" title="July 21, 2012-010-77" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-77.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="649" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Good Luna &#8211; look at the camera!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2979" title="July 21, 2012-010-90" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-90.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="373" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Even with several tries, I never did get her to look at the camera with me!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2978" title="July 21, 2012-010-87" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-87.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="352" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Heather is just starting to come in to bloom</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2980" title="July 21, 2012-010-97" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-97.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="351" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Close-up of a whitebark pine</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2981" title="July 21, 2012-010-104" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-104.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="341" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I learned a long time ago from a botanist that flowers like this are commonly referred to as DYC&#8217;s &#8211; darned yellow composites.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2983" title="July 21, 2012-010-113" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-113.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Asters &#8211; another member of the composite family</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2982" title="July 21, 2012-010-110" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-110.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="353" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Sedum lanceolatum</em>, maybe. Definitely a sedum.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2984" title="July 21, 2012-010-120" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-120.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="371" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Luna and I took a side trip to look at First Butte Lookout. Only five miles the sign said. Five rough miles. Now I&#8217;ve seen it and don&#8217;t have to wonder about it anymore.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2986" title="July 21, 2012-010-133" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-133.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="705" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Always have to remember to cool my feet after a good hike.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2987" title="July 21, 2012-010-137" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-137.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="345" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And the reason I picked a hike on that side of the valley? Ken was playing music with his friend Bill at the <a title="Methow Valley Ciderhouse" href="http://www.methowvalleyciderhouse.com/" target="_blank">Methow Valley Ciderhouse</a>! A cold glass of Howling Wolf Cider really hit the spot!</p>
<p><a href="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-143.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2988" title="July 21, 2012-010-143" src="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-143.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="702" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2969/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2969/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2969&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://myeverydayphotos.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/tiffany-mountain-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/efe8233cc730290772773af02c10805f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tjpieper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-40.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-40</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-45.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-45</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-47.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-47</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-70.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-70</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-73.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-73</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-77.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-77</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-90.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-90</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-87.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-87</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-97.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-97</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-104.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-104</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-113.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-113</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-110.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-110</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-120.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-120</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-133.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-133</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-137.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-137</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myeverydayphotos.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/july-21-2012-010-143.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">July 21, 2012-010-143</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tetris + books = my life</title>
		<link>http://sychela.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/tetris-books-my-life/</link>
		<comments>http://sychela.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/tetris-books-my-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 22:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>sychela</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Awesome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Being a girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tetris]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sychela.wordpress.com/?p=2243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been trying to figure out how to illustrate what I feel like my life has become: a cross between Tetris and books. Unfortunately, I&#8217;m not an artist, so I can&#8217;t just draw it, and I don&#8217;t have any great skills with Photoshop, and I just didn&#8217;t feel that one of my typical MS Paint [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2243&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been trying to figure out how to illustrate what I feel like my life has become: a cross between Tetris and books.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, I&#8217;m not an artist, so I can&#8217;t just draw it, and I don&#8217;t have any great skills with Photoshop, and I just didn&#8217;t feel that one of my typical MS Paint mashups was going to do this justice.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve obtained a lot (and I mean A LOT) of new books lately. This is on top of already having a bunch of things that I haven&#8217;t read yet (and yet I keep thinking, &#8220;I love humorous non-fiction; I bet I will really like that book I bought when Borders went out of business and everything was 70% off&#8221;).</p>
<p>But then a couple weekends ago, I bought 7 or 8 used books at the library book sale, and I think I&#8217;ve only read about 3 of them.</p>
<p>I even checked out three books that day, although who knows why I felt like that was necessary.</p>
<p>I got books for my birthday this weekend (thank God some of them are for kids, so they&#8217;ll go quickly).</p>
<p>Although one of them is the FOURTH <em>Game of Thrones</em> book, and I have yet to start the third one! (Which I&#8217;m dying to do.)</p>
<p>I bought Jonathan&#8217;s book club book off of him, because he was just going to return it to the store. (But it&#8217;s <em>The Leftovers</em> by Tom Perrotta! I didn&#8217;t know anything about it when I turned over the cash, because I just have faith in Tom Perrotta, but it&#8217;s about the Rapture, and I don&#8217;t know if you know this about me but I&#8217;m kind of into Rapture stuff.)</p>
<p>And then I have to purchase my own book club&#8217;s next book, which I plan on doing from Amazon, but then I&#8217;ll want to add something else so I get to $25 so I have the free shipping.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s just a torrential downpour of books, and there&#8217;s no way I can keep up with them all. It&#8217;s like one of the later levels on Tetris, but instead of pretty colored shapes, it&#8217;s all books. But they&#8217;re piling up so fast!</p>
<p>At least books fit together well. Until you run out of space, that is.</p>
<p>Oh, I get it &#8211; it&#8217;s just like Tetris only none of the layers disappear when you fill them in. I guess that would happen if I actually read things, and then gave them away.</p>
<p>Why did I used to have so much time to read? I guess in New York I had the commute every day, and then both my roommates worked a show schedule, so I spent a lot of time alone. (Not in a sad way.)</p>
<p>But now, I just don&#8217;t have that same amount of time.</p>
<p>Although, I&#8217;m doing a cameo in wardrobe at Marin Theatre Company this weekend (started last weekend), and there is PLENTY of time to read then. Partly because the show is super easy (yay!) and partly because the show is short, so the break between shows is hours (yay!). So I&#8217;m going to try to get through as much this week as possible.</p>
<p>I would say, &#8220;And then I&#8217;m going to try to lay off acquiring books for awhile,&#8221; but it&#8217;s just not that easy.</p>
<p>That being said &#8211; anyone reading anything good lately?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2243/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2243/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2243&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sychela.wordpress.com/2012/06/19/tetris-books-my-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a87cf5012c9f3c8c0cde83dd88a82b35?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sychela</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Particular Happiness of Strawberry Cake</title>
		<link>http://rich-full-life.com/2012/07/26/the-particular-happiness-of-strawberry-cake/</link>
		<comments>http://rich-full-life.com/2012/07/26/the-particular-happiness-of-strawberry-cake/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 15:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>RFL</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Funny Thing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[What I'm Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strawberry Cake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strawberry Short Cake Doll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Particular Sadness of Lemon Cake]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rich-full-life.com/?p=1651</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems like I&#8217;ve seen a lot of pictures of strawberry cake lately. It was probably only two until I googled strawberry cake images this morning. Now I&#8217;ve really seen a lot of pictures of strawberry cake, but none quite as compelling as the two that inspired this post. It&#8217;s not my favorite cake, but [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1651&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems like I&#8217;ve seen a lot of pictures of strawberry cake lately.</p>
<p>It was probably only two until I googled strawberry cake images this morning. Now I&#8217;ve really seen a lot of pictures of strawberry cake, but none quite as compelling as the two that inspired this post.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not my favorite cake, but when I was pregnant, I craved it, and would send random texts to my best friend from the grocery store exclaiming, &#8220;Did you know they sell individual servings of cake? I need cake by the piece. Portion control, right? I&#8217;m going to buy this cake, go home and eat it off my giant tummy table and watch America&#8217;s Next Top Model. Why am I so fat? Shit, now I&#8217;m crying again. About cake. What is happening?&#8221;</p>
<p>I was standing in line at the grocery store this week, and one of the magazines had strawberry cake as their cover picture. I couldn&#8217;t look away.</p>
<div id="attachment_1652" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 209px"><a href="http://richfulllife.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/i-wish.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1652" title="I wish" src="http://richfulllife.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/i-wish.png?w=199&h=300" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This note has been recreated.</p></div>
<p>I typed a quick note to myself on my phone, &#8220;I wish I was strawberry cake.&#8221;</p>
<p>The picture reminded me of church potlucks. Church potlucks reminded me of macaroni salad, banana pudding, and weird jell-o molds, which reminded me that I&#8217;m old enough now that I should really have a signature recipe for something to bring to parties when food is requested.</p>
<p>I think what you bring to parties has an evolution cycle that improves as you grow up, turn your focus outward, and start to realize the effort that can go into hosting a party. Bringing food becomes one of the ways that you can help and contribute. Having an adult income and being female helps too.</p>
<p>In my 20&#8242;s, I brought beer and my boobs to parties, and I figured that was enough (okay the beer was enough). I always offered to bring pasta and jarred sauce, the only thing I could make at the time, but no one ever wanted my kick-ass &#8216;scetti.</p>
<p>Their loss.</p>
<p>In my 30&#8242;s, I&#8217;ve started bringing fruit and vegetable trays. I usually swing by a local deli that has a great yogurt dipping sauce, and Chuy&#8217;s which has great jalapeno ranch dip, because I&#8217;m not afraid to drive the extra mile for implied effort, to avoid cooking, and to avoid losing Pyrex.</p>
<p>But, I really need to perfect an appetizer or dessert that makes people ask for the recipe, and that they request when I&#8217;m invited to things. I always feel a little left out of those conversations.</p>
<p>Maybe I&#8217;ll get there in my 40&#8242;s and maybe my recipe will be strawberry cake with perfect, fluffy frosting that wasn&#8217;t scraped from a paper container.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s good to have dreams.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m giving this cake a lot of thought, and I think I can trace the inspiration back to a book I read about a year ago called, <em>The Particular Sadness of Lemon Cake</em> by Aimee Bender. It&#8217;s about a young girl who can taste the emotions and feelings of anyone who has prepared her food. This ability begins on her 9th birthday when her mother bakes her a lemon cake filled with particular sadness.</p>
<p>An aptly named book.</p>
<p>I really enjoyed the premise of this book, the vivid descriptions, and the connections many of us hold between emotions and food. It went off track a little for me at the end, and I thought it got a little weird. It was like she came up on deadline, couldn&#8217;t figure out how to end it, and said, screw it, what if people could meditate themselves into a state where they disappear into furniture (spoiler, sorry).</p>
<p>Strong beginning, fizzled ending, but I probably just didn&#8217;t get it.</p>
<p>But, have you ever found yourself associating people with the food they bring to gatherings? Like Rudy, he&#8217;s banana pudding with real whipped cream and Nilla Wafers. Or J is spinach/artichoke dip, or basil, cheese torta (a freaking work of art) and cherry crisp. Wein is sausage biscuit/meatball thingys, and that&#8217;s cool because she&#8217;s a vegetarian but she thinks about what other people like first. M and I equally divide being the queso, and veggie/fruit trays (she has 2.75 kids, I&#8217;m just not a great cook or planner). Another friend is black bean and corn salsa.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s what I meant, when I hastily typed, I want to be strawberry cake.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s upbeat, it&#8217;s visually appealing, and it tastes great. If a potluck dish does say anything about the person who prepared it, I think strawberry cake says, &#8220;happy person who shares delicious desserts.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_1653" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://richfulllife.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/strawberry-shortcake.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1653" title="strawberry shortcake" src="http://richfulllife.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/strawberry-shortcake.jpg?w=300&h=224" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">She still has her original smell and Muppet Baby tights. Her hat is strategically dipped below one non-slutty eye. Pop tarts make mini-crisps now. They aren&#8217;t very good.</p></div>
<p>It also reminds me of a Strawberry Shortcake doll I had and loved as a child (and found in my garage in about 30 seconds&#8211;memory hoarder). The doll has pink, curly hair, and still smells of artificial strawberries and plastic. A surprisingly pleasant combination.</p>
<p>The problem is, I&#8217;m not really strawberry cake.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m more like canned bean dip and Fritos that could eventually evolve into some sort of home-made cream cheese and bacon dip (this is turning into a weird life metaphor and it is making me hungry).</p>
<p>Being a bacon dip is probably fine too, but I wish I was strawberry cake.</p>
<p>Does this make any sense at all?</p>
<p>Do you think that the dish you bring to parties represents your attitude or personality in any way?</p>
<p>If so, what dish are you?</p>
<p>Did anyone else have this same Strawberry Shortcake doll?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1651/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1651/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1651&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rich-full-life.com/2012/07/26/the-particular-happiness-of-strawberry-cake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>82</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/32df47eec5342633d73e7f3e222c3e75?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rachellec2c</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richfulllife.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/i-wish.png?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I wish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richfulllife.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/strawberry-shortcake.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">strawberry shortcake</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>