<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Dr. Kara, Medicine Woman</title>
		<link>http://orchestradirectorswife.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/dr-kara-medicine-woman/</link>
		<comments>http://orchestradirectorswife.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/dr-kara-medicine-woman/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 16:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Orchestra Director's Wife</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chickens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Updates]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://orchestradirectorswife.wordpress.com/?p=725</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My chickens are my pets, but they are also my friends and children. When they hurt, I hurt. I know this sounds a little &#8216;out there&#8217; and screams &#8220;she needs to get a life,&#8221; but if you can imagine how you feel about your dog or cat&#8230;that&#8217;s how I feel about my girls. I know [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=725&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug302012-021.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-726" title="Aug302012 021" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug302012-021.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a></p>
<p>My chickens are my pets, but they are also my friends and children. When they hurt, I hurt. I know this sounds a little &#8216;out there&#8217; and screams &#8220;she needs to get a life,&#8221; but if you can imagine how you feel about your dog or cat&#8230;that&#8217;s how I feel about my girls.</p>
<p>I know people eat chicken. I still eat chicken, but when I look at my girls, I don&#8217;t see something to eat. I see working girls who work hard to provide us with healthy nourishment every day, and even more, animals that look to me to take good care of them.</p>
<p>From what I have read, most chicken owners are their own veterinarians. Their line of thought is that going to the vet is so expensive these days, that the cost of taking them there outweighs what they are hoping to save by having them. They either learn to be their own veterinarian, or put the chicken out of it&#8217;s misery when it gets sick.</p>
<p>I have tried to learn as much as I can about chicken health and illness. I have had to doctor my chickens numerous times, including giving them shots of antibiotics. Chickens are prone to lung ailments. The first time they got sick,  as much as I hated to give them antibiotics, when it came down to watching my girls suffer and possibly die, or give in to antibiotics, I chose the latter.</p>
<p>I had a bit of a crisis yesterday afternoon. Marvelanne was acting really lethargic and staying off by herself. That was not like the typical Marvelanne that I know and love.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day when all of the chickens were outside the sliding glass door hollering at me to bring them some yogurt, I heard her call, and it&#8217;s usually one of the loudest. She sounds like an opera singer when she knows she&#8217;s about to get a treat. &#8220;Ha, Ha, Ha, Ha, Haaaaaaaaaaaa!&#8221; she cries, hitting every accented note with crystal clarity, open-throated and resonating.</p>
<p><a href="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug252012-017.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-727" title="aug252012 017" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug252012-017.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="387" /></a></p>
<p>She is very friendly, and curious, and  is always among the first to spy something of interest. Sometimes Bud will go out and dig in the dirt with a shovel. All of the chickens congregate because there are often lots of worms in the dirt. Normally, Eula and Marvelanne will hop onto the shovel before he even gets the dirt turned and start scratching in order to be the first to nab a prize.</p>
<p>I told Bud my concerns and he went out and looked. He even dug a few rounds of dirt, and Marvelanne stayed off in the corner. She wasn&#8217;t tempted by the prospect of a worm at all.</p>
<p>I know this might sound strange, but I always pray for my chickens and ask the Lord to take care of them, heal them, or give me the wisdom to know what to do. I&#8217;m so grateful for answered prayer on that one.</p>
<p><a href="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/allchickensbowl1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-733" title="Allchickensbowl" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/allchickensbowl1.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="313" /></a></p>
<p>Marvelanne is usually a vigorous layer, and gives us an egg almost every day. In spite of the fact that she is one of the smallest hens, her eggs are usually the largest. I knew she had not laid an egg yesterday. I checked around her vent to see if anything looked amiss, but couldn&#8217;t tell much. I looked and felt in the area, and I thought it might have felt swollen, but then again, I&#8217;m not accustomed to feeling chicken bottoms, so I wasn&#8217;t sure.</p>
<p>I immediately went to the Internet, and &#8216;egg impaction&#8217; was a term I had run across before, so something just told me to Google that search term. I found that it&#8217;s pretty common and she was showing some of the signs, one of which is lethargy. It can also be very serious. I also ran across many forum posts by distressed chicken owners saying that the chicken was acting lethargic and the next few posts was the original poster saying the chicken had died. YIKES! I didn&#8217;t want to &#8216;wait and see&#8217; on this one.</p>
<p>In case you don&#8217;t know what a chicken vent is, it&#8217;s the place where the egg comes out and also where the poop comes out. The egg and the poop originate in two different places, but they exit in the same place.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Click on the picture to find out more on how a chicken lays an egg.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.afn.org/~poultry/egghen.htm"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-728" title="hen8" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/hen8.gif" alt="" width="232" height="160" /></a>(Photo Courtesy of afn.org)</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Click on the picture to find out more about chicken anatomy:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.theartofdoingstuff.com/anatomy-of-a-chicken/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-730" title="6967471676_bf85b22e8a_o" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/6967471676_bf85b22e8a_o.jpg" alt="" width="465" height="804" /></a>(photo courtesy of theartofdoingstuff.com)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">(Incidentally, if the vent is smiling at you, it&#8217;s a young chicken. If it&#8217;s frowning at you, like the above picture, it&#8217;s an old chicken. It seems that as you get older, even in the chicken world, everything starts heading south).</p>
<p>One of the suggestions for egg impaction is to soak the chicken&#8217;s hind end in warm water and gently massage it. Supposedly, the warm water and massage help the chicken to relax. Well who WOULDN&#8217;T, with that kind of special treatment? I thought to myself, &#8220;It certainly won&#8217;t hurt anything if my diagnosis is wrong,&#8221; so I wrapped Marvelanne in a towel and and brought her in to the kitchen sink.</p>
<p>Bud brought me a clean towel and was assisting. His moral support, alone, helped a lot!  Bud did further research while I held Marvelanne and waited for the kitchen sink to fill up. I gently cupped water in my hands and splashed it over her bum (Oh my! I&#8217;m feeling rather English). When the water was high enough, I began to massage her. She DID seem to be enjoying it at the very least, and only *almost* flew away once in the beginning. After that, I think she enjoyed the royal treatment and she began to relax.</p>
<p>About that time, Bud came in to give me further instructions, based upon his research findings. He told me I needed to apply lubricant around and IN the vent. He carefully instructed me that as I reached in, the egg would be &#8216;up&#8217;, rather than &#8216;down&#8217;. Okay. Good to know! I hadn&#8217;t yet seen the illustration I posted above!  When I saw &#8216;egg impaction&#8217; and &#8216;warm bath and massage&#8217;, I was so panicked I had immediately jumped into action. Thank goodness for a meticulous assistant!</p>
<p>I let some of the water out of the sink, and as I held Marvelanne with one hand, Bud put some lubricant on the fingers of my other hand. As I started to rub just around the outside of the opening, and started to push inside, I COULD FEEL AN EGG CRESTING JUST INSIDE THE VENT&#8230;.and out it came!  It plopped into the water left in the sink. I&#8217;ve never had children, but I&#8217;ve always wondered what it would be like to experience a &#8216;water birth&#8217;. Bud asked me how it felt to be a &#8216;midwife&#8217;. I&#8217;d say it felt pretty darn good, but even more, I felt great knowing I had helped to ease the suffering (and possibly saved the life) of my girl.</p>
<p>When I put Marvelanne outside, she had to tend her hind end for a while because I&#8217;m sure it felt strange being all wet like that. She continued to peck and preen the wet feathers for a while, but then she bounced back to her normal old self. By the time the rest of the hens had retired to the hen house as dusk approached, she was out scratching and hunting in the garden. She stayed out so long that bossy Eula, who has taken it upon herself to make sure everyone gets inside the hen house before she goes to bed, went over and herded Marvelanne into the hen house.</p>
<p>All I can say, is &#8216;THANK YOU, Jesus, for being concerned about what concerns me, and helping me take care of my girls.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug272012-043.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-732" title="Aug272012 043" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug272012-043.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="509" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1221860067591_1191.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-685" title="img_1221860067591_1191" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1221860067591_1191.jpg" alt="" width="165" height="17" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>I will say of the Lord, He is my refuge and my fortress: my God; in him will I trust.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Surely he shall deliver thee from the snare of the fowler, and from the noisome pestilence.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em><sup> </sup>He shall cover thee with his feathers, and under his wings shalt thou trust: his truth shall be thy shield and buckler.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>~Psalm 91:2-4~</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2955631i768nf9l31.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-738" title="2955631i768nf9l31" src="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2955631i768nf9l31.gif" alt="" width="275" height="157" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://orchestradirectorswife.wordpress.com/category/chickens/'>Chickens</a>, <a href='http://orchestradirectorswife.wordpress.com/category/updates/'>Updates</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/725/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=725&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://orchestradirectorswife.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/dr-kara-medicine-woman/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ea9d41e4e1418fe200f1c3b203fa4105?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Orchestra Director&#039;s Wife</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug302012-021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aug302012 021</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug252012-017.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aug252012 017</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/allchickensbowl1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Allchickensbowl</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/hen8.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hen8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/6967471676_bf85b22e8a_o.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">6967471676_bf85b22e8a_o</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aug272012-043.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aug272012 043</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1221860067591_1191.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">img_1221860067591_1191</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orchestradirectorswife.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2955631i768nf9l31.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2955631i768nf9l31</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One World Permaculture, Zambia</title>
		<link>http://oneworldpermaculture.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/one-world-permaculture-zambia/</link>
		<comments>http://oneworldpermaculture.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/one-world-permaculture-zambia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>oneworldpermaculture</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chickens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one world permaculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[permauclture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whole life learning center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zambia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oneworldpermaculture.wordpress.com/?p=55</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, if you don’t know me and you are reading this, now is when I will introduce Michael. The first time we met was at the teacher training before the school year at the Austin Ecoschool. I was to be the Language Arts teacher and he taught Music, Art, and Social Studies. I had just [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=55&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, if you don’t know me and you are reading this, now is when I will introduce Michael. The first time we met was at the teacher training before the school year at the Austin Ecoschool. I was to be the Language Arts teacher and he taught Music, Art, and Social Studies. I had just returned form Zambia and told him how I was planning to return the following year to do permaculture consulting and youth service project. He said that he wanted to come with me. I shrugged in a, “I Dare Ya” kind of way and let him know that I would love the help.  I&#8217;m pretty sure our co-workers could see the sparks flying that weekend. By December we were dating and he followed through on his word and came with me to Zambia in July as the Head of Construction of the coop. We traveled for a week to Victoria Falls and Botswana for a life-changing safari. It was at Vic Falls under the full moon, where he popped the question. You can see the picture below if you are wondering my answer. So, that’s Michael.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1743.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-57" title="gettin' hitched" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1743.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>Once in Lusaka, we got right to work at the Destiny School which had about 600 students. Arise Africa has a children sponsorship program there so about 30 of the 600 are being fed one meal a day by donors. This project was for the other 570 children. We met with the headmaster and created an agreement that the chickens were to be kept for the eggs and would not be slaughtered until they stopped laying eggs. We also agreed that the eggs were for the children and would not be sold for profit for the school unless production grew to a point where everyone was fed first. We had nine days to build the chicken coop, get chickens, and prepare the community to care for them.</p>
<p>Buying materials was the first BIG hurdle to work around. We couldn&#8217;t go into the market to buy materials for many reasons, including safety.  We had some amazing helpers who made the project possible by doing the bargaining at the market, translating and giving us transportation. Isaac is seen below on the left. This project would not be possible without his translation skills both for language and culture. Chulo is on the right and he helped with construction and is also one of the two men who are responsible for long-term chicken care.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1710.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-58" title="working" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1710.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>A few problems that came up while building the coop:</p>
<ul>
<li>Working in metric measurement as an ignorant American</li>
<li>Not being able to see materials up close before purchase due to safety at the market</li>
<li>Japanese plugs, connected to British and US machinery</li>
<li>Planning to keep chickens safe from humans looking to steal (everybody is hungry)</li>
<li>Language barriers with co-workers</li>
<li>Time in Africa is much slower that the US (less gets done) and we were on a schedule</li>
</ul>
<p>Solutions to these things:</p>
<ul>
<li>A good sense of humor</li>
<li>Universal measurement like arms and feet</li>
<li>Allowing the coop to be the size of the materials so that we didn’t need to use machinery/tools</li>
<li>Seeing the coop as a chicken fortress and designing as such</li>
<li>Body language and modeling as universal language. As well as music</li>
<li>More patience and good humor, which the Zambians made easy because they are so great! Especially the kids!</li>
</ul>
<p>As Michael led the building, I tried to help. Every time I picked up a hammer and nail Chulo would come take it from me and complete whatever task I was on. Isaac helped explain that I felt confident with tools. Chulo agreed that he would let me work as long as he could help. Anytime I worked he would stop what he was doing and help me with my task until it was complete. It made me feel silly that it was so strange for a woman to build, but I understood that it was a sign of respect.</p>
<p>We had plenty of help building which gave me time to go from class to class reading letters from the Austin children and tell the story of how the chicken coop was made possible by the kids in Austin, TX. I shared the designs that the children made and introduced the idea of compassion and inspiration. This was the first time in most of their lives that these children had the opportunity to think about learning about what they were interested in. I acknowledged that I know children go to school so that they can get a good job to help feed their families. Most of these children have between 4-8 siblings and have lost at least a parent and/or sibling to AIDs and/or malnutrition. It is the totally taboo to talk about this fact, but it&#8217;s true. I had to remind myself that helping others find their light will help them grow in many ways that I cannot foresee.</p>
<p>In each class I asked the group what they loved to do and not one hand went up. I couldn&#8217;t believe it, all of the children I know love talking about this. I shared pictures of the children from Austin and told them all of the things each child enjoyed learning about, including sports, nature, cooking, and helping others. Slowly hands went up and children shared subjects like Math and English. I invited them to think about things they wanted to know more about. I got wide eyed stares. I realized that they wanted to share, but were afraid to have the wrong answer. I told them that there was no wrong answer for this question and invited them to think about it and find me with answer over the week I had left there. If they wanted to share, I wanted to listen.</p>
<p>After I visited the 6<sup>th</sup> grade class the children flowed out after me smothering me with hugs and hand shakes. A group of girls came to me spouting out all of the things they wanted to learn about including designing clothes, music and helping grow food for their families. One boy came to me wide eyed telling me about how much he loved football(soccor). It was then that I realized adults never ask these children what they love to do and that they rarely get to share about it. When life is full of working to survive these conversations can get lost, but in that moment the spark was awake inside their hearts and their faces came to life. From that moment on, all of the children wanted to help build the coop and connect in any way practicing English and Nyanja. Below are Joseph and Chama helping me paint tar on the wood to help with rot.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1712.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-59" title="joseph and chama" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1712.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>After many trips to the market for materials and nails the structure was up and the roof was on. You can see how excited I was about the roof. It felt like a miracle. You know how we can go to a hardware store and buy boxes of nails or screws? In Lusaka at Buseko market, you choose one nail that you like and a nice young man goes from stall to stall looking in jars and boxes for however many nails say you need. That process took about an hour. We used about 130 nails on this coop.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1846.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-61" title="IMGP1846" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1846.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>Marvin uses my shades used as safety goggles, while the side of a hammer whacks the screwdriver to help the door not stick. Behind you can see how they built the wall up so that the coop can’t be seen from the street. This safety measure seemed funny sense the back wall of the school was only three feet tall.  I think they raised that wall soon after we left.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1856.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-62" title="IMGP1856" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1856.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>Below, Michael and his special helper Martin show case the tall roosts to help keep the chickens off the ground and away from ants as well as the beautiful nesting boxes. The boxes were picked up on the side of the road from some vendors who did beautiful work out of bamboo and grass. Martin came to school on Saturday just to see Michael and help build the coop. He and his brother were there for six hours with us that day.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1899.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-63" title="IMGP1899" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1899.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>Finally, it was chicken day! One may ask how do you get 32 hens to a school in the middle of Lusaka, Zambia? By mini bus, of course! Arise owns a mini bus that it runs the bus lines to help make money for the non-profit. They let us use it for the week, Thank you Arise! Abraham, the driver cleaned the bus daily. When we asked him if he would be willing to pick the hens up while we finished getting the coop ready on the last day, he did not hesitate. I figured they would come in boxes but as they arrived back to the school we saw 32 hens in the bus, in NO cages or boxes! After we transferred the chickens to the coop Abraham gave the bus’s interior a serious hose down. <a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2006.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-64" title="IMGP2006" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2006.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a> <a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2009.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-65" title="IMGP2009" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2009.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>Below is one of my student&#8217;s designs compared to the coop. . . pretty similar!</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/chicken-coop-7.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-72" title="chicken coop 7" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/chicken-coop-7.jpg?w=1024&h=745" alt="" width="1024" height="745" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2075.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-67" title="IMGP2075" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2075.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>The day before we left there was a school assembly to introduce the coop and all of the educational materials that Arise Africa brought in during the summer. Isaac helped us deliver the message that the chickens and their eggs belong to the children at the school. We reviewed how to care for the chickens.  It felt like a celebration. Below is a picture of a couple of my new friends from the assembly. Oh man, I love these children!</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2064.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-68" title="IMGP2064" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2064.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>The morning we left there were 20 eggs! It works out that each child gets about one egg a week, which is the only protein that some of them get in a week.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2090.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-69" title="IMGP2090" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2090.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
<p>The 6th and 7th grade classes at Destiny wrote letters to the Austin youth which I hand carried home. Upon my return I made a slide show telling the story from beginning to end to share with each of the schools involved along with the letters from the children. I shared numerous stories about the children with the Austin youth as I did at the Destiny school and gave them their letters. It felt like a great success.</p>
<p>Through this experience I gained the confidence and experience to teach Permaculture Design at Austin Community College. I will be sharing the One World Permaculture Project again this year and will be taking it to New Delhi, India this Fall.</p>
<p><a href="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zambia-letter.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-70" title="zambia letter" src="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zambia-letter.jpeg?w=700&h=1024" alt="" width="700" height="1024" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/55/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/55/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=55&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oneworldpermaculture.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/one-world-permaculture-zambia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f2585df14bc5b7fd4c5772604b515618?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oneworldpermaculture</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1743.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gettin&#039; hitched</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1710.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">working</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1712.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joseph and chama</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1846.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP1846</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1856.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP1856</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp1899.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP1899</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2006.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP2006</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2009.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP2009</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/chicken-coop-7.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chicken coop 7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2075.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP2075</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2064.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP2064</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imgp2090.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMGP2090</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oneworldpermaculture.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zambia-letter.jpeg?w=700" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zambia letter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Pie for Denise McNair: Food and Politics in the South</title>
		<link>http://norwizzle.com/2012/08/28/a-pie-for-denise-mcnair-food-and-politics-in-the-south/</link>
		<comments>http://norwizzle.com/2012/08/28/a-pie-for-denise-mcnair-food-and-politics-in-the-south/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 19:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>norwizzle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yesteryear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[16th Street Church Bombing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Civil Rights era]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southern Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strawberry pie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The South]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://norwizzle.com/?p=177</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It should come as no surprise to any Southerner that last year&#8217;s runaway hit and Oscar contender The Help focuses on the two most plundered Southern issues of our time: food and race relations. Completing the trinity of sacred subjects in the South is football—and Roll Tide, I said ROLL TIDE—that subject is indeed religious in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=177&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/southern-cook-book.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-178" title="southern-cook-book" src="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/southern-cook-book.jpeg" alt="" width="447" height="676" /></a></p>
<p>It should come as no surprise to any Southerner that last year&#8217;s runaway hit and Oscar contender <em>The Help</em> focuses on the two most plundered Southern issues of our time: food and race relations. Completing the trinity of sacred subjects in the South is football—and Roll Tide, I said ROLL TIDE—<em>that</em> subject is indeed religious in its fervor. But that&#8217;s another topic for another time. Today, I have the politics of food and the food of politics on my mind.</p>
<div id="attachment_179" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/minny-pie-the-help.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-179" title="Minny-pie-The Help" src="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/minny-pie-the-help.jpeg?w=300&h=215" alt="Minny's Chocolate Pie from The Help" width="300" height="215" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">That ain&#8217;t vanilla from Mexico you&#8217;re tasting Hilly Holbrook.</p></div>
<p>We all know about that famous pie in <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/victoria-haschka/oscar-recipes-chocolate-pie_b_1290385.html" target="_blank">The Help</a>. And if you don&#8217;t know the backstory behind Minny&#8217;s terrible-awful, far be it from me to spoil it for you. Let&#8217;s just say there was more than sugar in that sucker and leave it at that. The movie did bring to mind, though, how often food and racial politics are intertwined in the movies, books and all the pundit palavering about the South. There seems to be an endless supply of all three, especially from folks who don&#8217;t live here and never have. For the record, some of what they say is true and some of it is pure hyperbole. Nonetheless, that movie made me think, and it brought to mind C.F. Penn&#8217;s Hamburgers, which made me hungry.</p>
<div id="attachment_180" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/penns.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-180  " title="penns" src="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/penns.jpeg?w=300&h=194" alt="" width="300" height="194" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">C.F. Penn&#8217;s Hamburgers: The best deep-fried half bread, half beef burger you will ever eat.</p></div>
<p>In the part of north Alabama where I&#8217;m from, <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/C-F-Penn-Hamburgers/189401257741637" target="_blank">Penn&#8217;s Hamburgers</a> is a culinary institution. The Depression-era burgers are still prepared the same way they were for the first time almost a century ago when three of them cost a quarter. A whisper of hamburger meat is mixed with fresh soft bread crumbs and seasonings, then deep-fried. The toothsome crispy patties are sandwiched between two halves of a spongy white-bread bun, then piled high with tear-inducing fresh cut onions, a proud slathering of yellow mustard, and occasionally a melty slice of cheese. No ketchup, Yankee. Don&#8217;t even ask.</p>
<p>The creator, Charles F. Penn and his family lived just two doors away from me in the house I grew up in, and I can remember his wife would let me visit every day each summer like some neighborhood orphan she felt obliged to take in. I was drawn to that pretty white house with black shutters not only by Mrs. Penn&#8217;s adorable Collie dogs, but also her magnificent library (it was Mrs. Penn who got me started at 5 with a lifelong Nancy Drew obsession). I had never known anyone with a library in their home before and the idea of an entire room devoted only to books astounded me. My dad would take me at least once a week to the Penn&#8217;s on Main Street in Hartselle, and together we&#8217;d sit on the spinning bar stools at the counter and tuck into a couple of those greasy, delicious burgers while I silently savored my &#8220;special&#8221; friendship with the nice lady who loaned me books and whose family owned the place.</p>
<div id="attachment_181" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cecilsphotos/5426318657/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-181  " title="penn's hamburger" src="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/5426318657_815f52d919_z.jpeg?w=300&h=192" alt="" width="300" height="192" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Penn&#8217;s Hamburgers interior, photo by Cecil Holmes</p></div>
<p>Years later, long after I had moved away from home and my immunity to Penn&#8217;s grease (which you need to eat the burgers with any regularity) had declined, my mother brought up the burger joint again, though in a much different context. It was in 2001, when I was a reporter and covering the <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2001/04/25/us/church-bombing-trial-begins-birmingham-city-s-past-very-much-present.html?pagewanted=all&amp;src=pm" target="_blank">16th Street Church Bombing Trial</a> in Birmingham, Alabama. Nearly 40 years after Tommy Blanton, <a href="http://www.trutv.com/library/crime/terrorists_spies/terrorists/birmingham_church/12.html" target="_blank">Frank Cherry</a> and God knows who else planned and executed a bombing that murdered four sweet little girls preparing for church services, justice was about to get served on a platter. And the whole world, it seemed, had shown up for the spectacle—there were reporters from Pravda, the BBC, and the <em>New York Times</em> attending, along with spectators from across the country. What I will never forget is the churchlike atmosphere of that trial, the parade of eyewitnesses to the sordid history of it all, and the defeated, haunted look in Chris McNair&#8217;s eyes when I asked him if he would be willing to speak with me on camera about the loss of his only daughter. &#8220;Someday I&#8217;m gonna tell a story,&#8221; he said, politely declining my request, and referring to the terrible-awful done to him. Earlier that day, Mr. McNair had testified about identifying the remains of his only daughter Denise, one of the four victims in the bombing, and who, in her all-too-brief lifetime, had wondered incessantly why she couldn&#8217;t order a sandwich at the same counters as white children. This was no fictional moment in a movie that could be rewound or rewritten; this was real, palpable pain born of a hatred I couldn&#8217;t even comprehend.</p>
<div id="attachment_182" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ss_boomer_denise_doll.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-182  " title="SS_boomer_denise_doll" src="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ss_boomer_denise_doll.jpeg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Denise McNair, one of four victims who died in the 1963 bombing of the 16th Street Baptist Church.</p></div>
<p>When I recounted the story to my mother, she said simply that she could remember clear as anything seeing black people lined up at the back door of Penn&#8217;s Hamburgers when she was a little girl, filing in under the &#8220;Colored&#8221; sign that ushered them in separately from the white customers. She added that she always wanted to know what was so good about those hamburgers that people would suffer such humiliation just to get one. I had no idea how to respond to that, and still don&#8217;t. But it makes you think, doesn&#8217;t it? And, surely it can be no coincidence that the raging fire of the Civil Rights movement was ignited by a <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/news/nation/2010-02-01-sit-ins-civil-rights_N.htm" target="_blank">sit-in</a> at a lunch counter. Breaking bread together—the act of communion—is a truly sacred thing, and to close that circle and exclude any living soul who believes in the same hereafter that you do seems to me a sin of sins.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t offer much in the way of recompense. And, hell, I have my own struggles to worry about—chief among them how I am going to make it as a freelance writer if that&#8217;s the path my life takes, or if anyone even cares about what I have to say or write about (my landlord who is fond of getting rent money from me is no doubt hoping, as I do, that someone out there does). But as long as I can afford groceries, and today I can, I can do this one small thing. I can make a pie for you little Denise McNair, a true-blue Southern pie for a beautiful Southern girl. It&#8217;s just a pie, I know&#8230;but then again, in the South, a pie is never really &#8220;just a pie,&#8221; now is it?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/title287142109.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-186" title="Strawberry Pretzel Crust Pie" src="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/title287142109.png" alt="" width="355" height="221" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Denise McNair&#8217;s Strawberry Pretzel Pie</strong></p>
<p><strong>Crust:</strong></p>
<p>1 1/2 cups crushed pretzels</p>
<p>3/4 cup sugar</p>
<p>2/3 cup melted butter</p>
<p><strong>Filling:</strong></p>
<p>1 (8-ounce) package cream cheese, softened to room temperature</p>
<p>1 can sweetened condensed milk</p>
<p>1 cup heavy whipping cream*</p>
<p>1 teaspoon vanilla</p>
<p><strong>Topping:</strong></p>
<p>1 quart strawberries, halved</p>
<p>1/3 cup apricot preserves</p>
<p>1. Preheat oven to 350°. In a large bowl, mix together pretzels, sugar and butter. Press into a deep-dish 9-inch pie pan.</p>
<p>2. Bake for 8-11 minutes, just until crust turns golden on the edges. Remove from oven and cool.</p>
<p>3. In the bowl of a stand mixer, cream together cream cheese and condensed milk until mixture is light and fluffy. Add heavy whipping cream and vanilla, beating on medium low for 2-3 minutes, or just until soft peaks form. Spoon into prepared, cooled crust.</p>
<p>4. Layer top with halved strawberries. Place apricot preserves in a glass measuring cup or small bowl and microwave on HIGH for 20-30 seconds, just until preserves get warm and thin. Strain preserves through a fine mesh strainer and lightly brush over strawberries with a pastry brush. Chill pie 4-6 hours and serve.</p>
<p>* If you prefer, substitute a package of instant white chocolate pudding mix mixed with 1 cup milk or half-and-half for the whipping cream.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/177/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/177/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=177&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://norwizzle.com/2012/08/28/a-pie-for-denise-mcnair-food-and-politics-in-the-south/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b63f508d444c89ea1832b24e5127b314?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">norwizzle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/southern-cook-book.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">southern-cook-book</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/minny-pie-the-help.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Minny-pie-The Help</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/penns.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">penns</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/5426318657_815f52d919_z.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">penn&#039;s hamburger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ss_boomer_denise_doll.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SS_boomer_denise_doll</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://norwizzledotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/title287142109.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Strawberry Pretzel Crust Pie</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Is Claret? A Tasty Adventure in Bordeaux</title>
		<link>http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/what-is-claret-the-question-that-sparked-a-tasty-adventure-in-bordeaux/</link>
		<comments>http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/what-is-claret-the-question-that-sparked-a-tasty-adventure-in-bordeaux/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 15:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Schwingen In Switzerland</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alsace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bordeaux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bordeaux wine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabernet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabernet Franc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabernet Sauvignon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin McCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merlot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merriam-Webster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red wine from bordeaux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wine from bordeaux]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/?p=8932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We’ve been watching British television and one of our favorite shows is “Grand Designs.”  The host, Kevin McCloud, kept referring to “claret.”  Being idiot Americans, we had no idea what sort of beverage it was (other than it was a deep purplish-red color).  Thanks to the magic of the internet, we learned it is “a red [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8932&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00781.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8978" title="DSC_0078" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00781.jpg?w=1024&h=678" alt="" width="1024" height="678" /></a>We’ve been watching British television and one of our favorite shows is “<a title="Grand Designs" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Designs" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Grand Designs</a>.”  The host, <a title="Kevin McCloud" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kevin_McCloud" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Kevin McCloud</a>, kept referring to “claret.”  Being idiot Americans, we had no idea what sort of beverage it was (other than it was a deep purplish-red color).  Thanks to the magic of the internet, we learned it is “a red wine from Bordeaux, or wine of a similar character made elsewhere” (according to <a href="www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/claret">Merriam-Webster</a>).  After that moment &#8211; and visiting France’s other wine regions (<a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/2011/11/04/burgandy-part-un-a-geology-lesson/">Burgundy</a>, <a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/2012/04/24/chateauneuf-du-pape-rocked-us-literally/">Cotes du Rhone</a>, <a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/2012/06/11/too-much-can-get-you-alsauced-alsaces-wine-route-route-du-vin/">Alsace</a>, Champagne) &#8211; I wanted to go see what could make stoic Brits wax rhapsodic about this wine.  Luckily, it was pretty easy to convince Wildcat and Hokie to take an girl’s road trip.</p>
<p><a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00062.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8966" title="DSC_0006" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00062.jpg?w=1024&h=678" alt="" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p>A few hours into our trip, they might have started to regret it.  To get to Bordeaux from Geneva, you have to drive across all of France to the Atlantic.  We broke down in the middle of nowhere on our way (for more, check out their accounts <a href="http://switzerlandhughes.weebly.com/index.html">here</a> and <a href="http://theswisswatchblog.com/2012/07/30/an-ode-to-bordeaux/">here</a>).  We arrived in Bordeaux just in time to get a good night&#8217;s sleep so that we could begin our &#8220;education&#8221; bright and early the next day.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00141.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-8967" title="DSC_0014" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00141.jpg?w=460&h=614" alt="" width="460" height="614" /></a></p>
<p>Bordeaux is larger and more complex than France&#8217;s other wine regions.  It has  an astounding variety of different appellations (recognized types that correspond to demarcated zones that were established in 1855 by <a title="Napoleon III" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Napoleon_III" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Napolean III</a>) in part because the region is large.  It is also topographically and climatically diverse.  It&#8217;s soils are geologically complex and vary significantly from one appellation to the next.  Its location on the Atlantic coast and on rivers further inland (the <a title="Gironde estuary" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gironde_estuary" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Gironde River</a> and its tributaries, the Garonne and Dordogne) creates dramatically different weather conditions across the region.</p>
<p><a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0025.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-9003" title="DSC_0025" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0025.jpg?w=1024&h=678" alt="" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Bordeaux wine" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bordeaux_wine" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Bordeaux wines</a> are all about blending.  Part science, part art, the results are pure magic.  The grapes in the blends should complement each other and make a complex, interesting, balanced and harmonious blend.  The goal is to make the blended wine better than the individual grapes that contribute to it.  In other words, the whole (the blended wine) should be more than the sum of its parts (the individual grapes).</p>
<p><a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_01181.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8982" title="DSC_0118" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_01181.jpg?w=1024&h=542" alt="" width="1024" height="542" /></a></p>
<p>The grapes most commonly used in blending <a class="zem_slink" title="Bordeaux wine" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bordeaux_wine" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Bordeaux wines</a> are: <a class="zem_slink" title="Merlot" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merlot" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Merlot</a>, <a title="Cabernet Sauvignon" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cabernet_Sauvignon" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Cabernet Sauvignon</a> and  Cabernet Franc.  The Merlot grapes give the wine color, roundness and suppleness.  The Cabernet Sauvignon grapes provide the tannins, the wine&#8217;s backbone and structure.  In young wines, it is very aromatic and provides increasing complexity as it ages.  The Cabernet Franc grapes add a gentleness, a counterpoint to the Sauvignon.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8974" title="DSC_0053" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00531.jpg?w=1024&h=678" alt="" width="1024" height="678" /></p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t already guessed from the definition of &#8220;claret,&#8221; most of Bordeaux&#8217;s wines are red (around 85%).  Bordeaux is the world&#8217;s number one producer of both Cabernet and Merlot grape varieties.  Sante!</p>
<p><a href="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00771.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8977" title="DSC_0077" src="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00771.jpg?w=1024&h=678" alt="" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8932/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8932/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8932&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://schwingeninswitzerland.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/what-is-claret-the-question-that-sparked-a-tasty-adventure-in-bordeaux/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a1fd6c6afaf6510e93e4f5e8179d6640?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">schwingeninswitzerland</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00781.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0078</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00062.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0006</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00141.jpg?w=766" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0014</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0025.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0025</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_01181.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0118</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00531.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0053</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://schwingeninswitzerland.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_00771.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0077</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: The Sweetest Voice</title>
		<link>http://claudiagiulia.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/the-sweetest-voice/</link>
		<comments>http://claudiagiulia.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/the-sweetest-voice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 01:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>claudiagiulia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2012]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://claudiagiulia.wordpress.com/?p=2229</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every Sunday, for the past 17 years, my mother’s garrulous voice has greeted me at the end of the phone line. I will have just waken up, most likely to a sunny Californian day, while she will be getting  dinner ready, in her cozy apartment in Italy, the curtains drawn, the tv humming in the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2229&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/74/Alt_Telefon.jpg/300px-Alt_Telefon.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="258" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo credit: Wikipedia</p></div>
<p>Every Sunday, for the past 17 years, my mother’s garrulous voice has greeted me at the end of the phone line. I will have just waken up, most likely to a sunny Californian day, while she will be getting  dinner ready, in her cozy apartment in Italy, the curtains drawn, the tv humming in the background. For 17 years, her voice has embodied my connection to a home that is no more, to a family than hangs by a thread and a love that has survived intact the wrath of my teenage years and my many moves.</p>
<p>The slight shrill in my mother’s “hello” will let me know immediately that everything is fine, while a more subdued and lower tone will presage unpleasant news. A brief humming just before she speaks, her trademark hesitation, conveys trouble, somebody else’s trouble typically, while the mention of my full name prefaces a question she is loath to ask.</p>
<p>That voice that praised me, scolded me, lulled me to sleep, admonished me and, above all, loved me is the voice I hear in my head every time I think of my mother. It’s part of my being as much as my own voice belongs to me. Someone told me that,  when a loved one dies, the first thing we forget is the sound of their voice. No photograph can give it back and, while recording devices can preserve a sound for posterity, they are a far cry from  accessing a memory at will as we go through our day. If all goes according as nature intended, my mother will die before me and the morbid thought of the loss of those Sunday phone calls has crossed my mind as I watch the two of us age.</p>
<p>After much prodding on the part of both her daughters, we convinced my mother to spend a couple of months  in Los Angeles with me, rather than her customary two weeks. As I write or make dinner or even while I putter in another room, I can hear my mother softly singing or talking to the dogs as she stubbornly cleans and irons and tries to make herself useful. It’s hard to resist her happy sound, not to yield to the high tones or the broken notes, especially when she ventures outside to shout for the dogs, who probably disappeared chasing a rabbit or a squirrel. The concern I hear in her calls is the same she couldn’t disguise whenever I tiptoed through the front door, late at night, back from another revelry in my college years, letting me know she had waited up (although she always denied it in the morning).</p>
<p>And then the more placid “Good night” or “Here you are, you scoundrels” will follow, her worries assuaged by our return, everything and everyone once again where they belong.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The sound of her presence has brightened my house and made those who inhabit it, human and canine, happier and calmer. I believe it’s because the melody of her speech is irresistible and has the power to draw us in. It will be a much emptier shell when she leaves &#8211; the dogs’ snorting, the bubbling of the fish tank and the humming of the fridge will go back to being my day’s soundtrack. Until I reach for that phone and wait for the long, ringing tone of Italian lines and the shrilly “Pronto” will let me know everything and everyone is where they belong.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2229/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2229/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2229&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://claudiagiulia.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/the-sweetest-voice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de68d41a010f9658fad432e7c6de8652?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">claudiagiulia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/74/Alt_Telefon.jpg/300px-Alt_Telefon.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Sounds of the Blogosphere</title>
		<link>http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/sounds-of-the-blogosphere/</link>
		<comments>http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/sounds-of-the-blogosphere/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 20:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bottledworder</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stylistic conventions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/?p=2864</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These are the records of the Earthling Bottledworder (henceforth to be referred to as EB in the third person) trapped in the spaceship Over-Enterprise for several months on its voyage to the Blogosphere. Earlier records show that EB had entered the Blogosphere in hopes of finding strange new worlds only to find the denizens of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2864&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These are the records of the Earthling Bottledworder (henceforth to be referred to as EB in the third person) trapped in the spaceship<em> Over-Enterprise</em> for several months on its voyage to the Blogosphere.<br />
<span id="more-2864"></span><br />
Earlier records show that EB had entered the Blogosphere in hopes of finding strange new worlds only to find the denizens of dear old planet Earth in remarkable new avatars singing old songs in new ways.</p>
<h5><strong><span style="color:#000000;">Excerpt report</span></strong></h5>
<p>In this section, EB refers to the <strong>sounds of an activity called <em>Blogging</em></strong> that life-forms in the Blogosphere seem to engage in periodically.</p>
<h4><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>The low hum of the cafe or the public house</strong></span></h4>
<p>This seems to be a sound very familiar to EB on earth. It&#8217;s the low hum of bright Bloggers engaging in earnest discussions on similar topics. They greet EB on a cold, winter&#8217;s evening with warmth and promise as he enters their circle. Some rustling sounds are audible as bloggers shift over, make space for EB and share ideas over the clinking of ice and music and videos through sedate nods and handshakes. EB is impressed with the friendliness of the creatures, especially with how they offer to share their carefully crafted fare in the public sphere.</p>
<div id="attachment_2888" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/beer.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2888" title="Beer" src="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/beer.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="Picnic Day in Davis, California" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Just like on earth on Picnic Day in Davis, California. Photo credit: Bottledworder</p></div>
<h4><strong><span style="color:#000000;">The shouting and the hollering at the fishmarket</span></strong></h4>
<p>EB&#8217;s next visit to another part of the planet is a stark contrast. The life-forms in the fishmarket rush at him with great speed as he enters. As soon as he approaches bombarding distance, they dump their words at him with loud thuds and clanks and some rat-a-tat through readers and feeds and social media shares before he has absorbed the first one. The din is deafening but highly entertaining as creatures compete with each other. The whole atmosphere is usually genial and EB is pleasantly surprised to find plenty of very talented life-forms in this fishmarket adept at slicing and dressing fish with the utmost agility. The whooshing of knives as they flash through the air and land on chopping blocks as bloggers cut and delete and copy and paste are the only sounds audible above the din.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/23766028@N00/525811798" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Fishmarket Tsukiji" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1128/525811798_63644a70ee_m.jpg" alt="Fishmarket Tsukiji" width="240" height="180" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Fishmarket Tsukiji (Photo credit: das farbamt)</p></div>
<h4><strong><span style="color:#000000;">The good ol&#8217; hearty slaps on the back</span></strong></h4>
<p>EB says that this is an activity Blogosphere creatures engage in by pressing <em>like </em>buttons. The sounds can range from a gentle pat to a hearty slap on the back. The creatures know how to interpret these gestures. EB advises you to keep an ear out. These are one of the most pleasant sounds in the Blogosphere and many a blogger will play these sweet sounds over and over by reloading their pages in fascination.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/92607898@N00/7882956434" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="ACMS 21/08/12: Rapt Audience" src="http://farm9.static.flickr.com/8440/7882956434_a4534de5a7_m.jpg" alt="ACMS 21/08/12: Rapt Audience" width="240" height="180" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">ACMS 21/08/12: Rapt Audience (Photo credit: Diamond Geyser)</p></div>
<h4><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>The voices</strong></span></h4>
<p>Bloggers. You can hear them. The sweet melodies, the intermittent crackles, the inspired rhapsodies, the long harangues, the gentle conversational tones, the smalltalk, the angry roars, the businesslike lists and the stream-of-consciousness flows. EB records that he has encountered all of these voices in Blogland. Some inhabitants will set up a tent and sing only a particular tone so that it&#8217;s easy for EB to know which tent to visit for what song. Others sing many different tunes all day as their hearts please. Sweet creatures, these bloggers. Mostly.</p>
<div id="attachment_2893" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/heraldsq.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2893" title="Herald Square" src="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/heraldsq.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="New York City" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you hear the din? This is Herald Square in New York City though. Photo credit: Bottledworder</p></div>
<h4><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>The sounds of silence</strong></span></h4>
<p>EB records that not all life-forms in the Blogosphere make a sound. Some tread by shyly and noiselessly, others pass by in stealth and others are predators. In most places in Blogland though, there&#8217;s life activity. But there are wastelands too where voices of solitary bloggers sing in vain waiting for a sound of a fellow blogger only to be greeted by the deafening silence of the night. But some Bloggers are naturally hermits and prefer to sing in solitude.</p>
<div id="attachment_2047" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3699.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2047" title="IMG_3699" src="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3699.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dundas Square, Toronto. A space full of people, kids of all ages rushing through the fountains, concerts and street musicians in the evenings but rather empty in the morning. Photo credit: Bottledworder</p></div>
<h5><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Notes:</strong></span></h5>
<p>EB&#8217;s last records show that these sounds of the Blogosphere compensated for his longings for planet earth. He became rather delusional in the last records confusing Blogland for his home and the voices as that of Earthlings.</p>
<p>The last sound heard from the spaceship (according to a blog in Blogland) was that of the vigorous clicking of the <em>like</em> button.</p>
<p>Written in response to <a title="Weekly Writing Challenge: The Sound of Blogging" href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/08/27/weekly-writing-challenge-the-sound-of-blogging/" target="_blank">Weekly Writing Challenge: The Sound of Blogging</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2864/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2864&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/sounds-of-the-blogosphere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/93a27b5a03ea73d11e2eb796bca379a6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bottledworder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/beer.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1128/525811798_63644a70ee_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fishmarket Tsukiji</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.static.flickr.com/8440/7882956434_a4534de5a7_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ACMS 21/08/12: Rapt Audience</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/heraldsq.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Herald Square</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bottledworder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3699.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3699</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Reveille!</title>
		<link>http://tidbitsandtreasures2011.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/reveille/</link>
		<comments>http://tidbitsandtreasures2011.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/reveille/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 21:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wanda</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Memory Lane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tidbitsandtreasures2011.wordpress.com/?p=1588</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s safe to say that a military recruit will be jolted awake within 24 hours of when he or she raised their right hand to take the enlistment oath. It&#8217;s also safe to say that reveille may be the most hated sound among military people. It never comes anytime than really early, and it definitely [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1588&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s safe to say that a military recruit will be jolted awake within 24 hours of when he or she raised their right hand to take the enlistment oath.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also safe to say that reveille may be the most hated sound among military people. It never comes anytime than really early, and it definitely doesn&#8217;t come quietly. There&#8217;s no such thing as sleeping through it because at the same moment as it sounds, every light in the barracks is also turned on. And it&#8217;s not unheard of for the company commander or a deputized watchstander to add to the cacophony by crashing trash can lids together. Talk about a rough way to start the day!</p>
<p>I report this from firsthand experience, still a strong memory 40+ years later.</p>
<p>Travel delays made for a very late middle-of-the-night arrival to bootcamp and lost luggage meant borrowing pajamas from another recruit, but I finally was able to get to bed around 3 a.m. on the morning of our company&#8217;s first full day in bootcamp. It seemed I had barely closed my eyes when REVEILLE (yikes!) sounded.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://tidbitsandtreasures2011.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/reveille/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/wlSwpBeeMMI/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>I woke up—how could I avoid it?—but I had absolutely no idea what was going on! In fact, it took a moment or two for me to even remember where I was. Realization was quickly overcome by the reality of my new situation. I had a new boss—several actually—and nothing in my growing up years came close to preparing me for my first reveille, never mind the rigors of ten weeks of bootcamp!</p>
<p>Bootcamp is as challenging as it is transformative. I&#8217;m not going to attempt to describe bootcamp—anyone who&#8217;s been has their own particular memories and stories to tell—and anyone who hasn&#8217;t been has probably heard enough stories to be glad that&#8217;s one experience they missed.</p>
<p>My bootcamp experience notwithstanding, I have always been a morning person. What has changed over time is how I choose to wake up—reveille is NOT, in my opinion, a good way to start the day. Still, I do need something to rouse me from sleep. It&#8217;s taken some experimentation, but I&#8217;ve finally settled on a method that works for me.</p>
<p>I want to wake up to something I know. Using the radio is not a good solution because it&#8217;s impossible to know what even a favored radio station might play at any given moment. I don&#8217;t want to be startled awake so I avoid alarms. The only feasible solution for me then is to rely on recorded music. Even that presents a challenge because the selected music has to meet several important criteria: first, it has to start softly and gradually get loud enough to wake me from a sound sleep; second, it has to be a tune I enjoy enough that I won&#8217;t tire of it too quickly; and third, since the clock radio is on my (retired) husband&#8217;s side of the bed, it has to be something he can at least tolerate for the 30 seconds or so it usually plays before he turns it off.</p>
<p>So, in the spirit of this week&#8217;s DPChallenge, I&#8217;m sharing my current wake-up call with you as a kinder, gentler alternative to military reveille. This tune has stood the test of time, as I&#8217;ve used it on a 5-days-per-week basis for the last two years or so. With best wishes for your own wake-up routine, I hope you will enjoy this recording of <em>Don&#8217;t Fall in Love with a Dreamer </em>by Kenny Rogers and Kim Carnes.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://tidbitsandtreasures2011.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/reveille/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/S7MYPShPNsM/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1588&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tidbitsandtreasures2011.wordpress.com/2012/08/30/reveille/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d61d3b0b9fe4170474304fc44d05b890?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tidbitsandtreasures2011</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Where’s the Click-Foomph?</title>
		<link>http://sharkyovengloves.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/wheres-the-click-foomph/</link>
		<comments>http://sharkyovengloves.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/wheres-the-click-foomph/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 02:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ramblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cookers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sounds]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sharkyovengloves.wordpress.com/?p=3390</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few days ago The Daily Post at WordPress.com asked bloggers to ponder the importance of sound in blogging as part of their Weekly Writing Challenge.  Their suggestions include writing about one&#8217;s association of certain sounds with specific memories or favourite sounds.  Now I&#8217;m not part of Post A Day and I&#8217;ve never taken part in the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3390&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sharkyovengloves.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/wheres-the-click-foomph/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e064cbef674adff4a26435f005ccadc9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sharkyovengloves</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sharkyovengloves.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/165-induction-cooker-kitchen.jpg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">No gas cooker for me…</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sharkyovengloves.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/165-gas-flame.jpeg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Click-foomph. Oooooo fire…</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anticipation vs. Reality</title>
		<link>http://everythingisblooming.wordpress.com/2012/08/26/anticipation-vs-reality/</link>
		<comments>http://everythingisblooming.wordpress.com/2012/08/26/anticipation-vs-reality/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 19:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ashley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[We're all in this together.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[American Girls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anticipation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growing up]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://everythingisblooming.wordpress.com/?p=635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My mother and I bond over a few things: Shopping, milk chocolate, Patrick Dempsey, and the occasional bowl of oatmeal. When I was young, she spent her weekends sewing me dresses. I could find her at the kitchen table, a foot steady on the pedal I was too afraid to touch, with pieces of a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=635&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My mother and I bond over a few things: Shopping, milk chocolate, Patrick Dempsey, and the occasional bowl of oatmeal. When I was young, she spent her weekends sewing me dresses. I could find her at the kitchen table, a foot steady on the pedal I was too afraid to touch, with pieces of a dress neatly pinned to the tissue pattern stacked in the order she would need them. A stocky tomato was placed to the left of the machine, and as she would guide the dress under the darting needles, her fingers would deftly pull them out and puncture the wiry flesh of the cushion. I would push them in as far as they would go, so the primary colored pinheads dotted the surface like pimples.</p>
<p>On Sundays, my father would be in the living room yelling at the television screen. I remember his rough &#8220;YEAHHHHHHHHH!&#8221; as the Packers scored, and my mother spitting, “Aww shit…” when she made a mistake and had to tear up a row of stitches.</p>
<p>Since the things she created were usually for me, I often felt as if I should help her in some way. Sometimes I was able to pick out the pattern. I’d sit on a thick stool  and lean over the slanted steel cabinets that cased the patterns at Walmart while I flipped through the heavy books. I was a dork: I lived in a fantasy world of dolls and historical fiction. I envied my cousin, who had an American Girl doll until I got one of my own. I had the books and would daydream about Samantha’s Victorian upbringing, where even her swimming suit was a superfluously frilly dress. I wanted to wear a wool cape and warm my hands in a white fur muff. I wished the desks at my school were like the swirly wrought iron one in Samantha&#8217;s collection. I wanted to wear stockings and buckle shoes . The more frills and buttons the better. And so at those pattern books at Walmart, I would pick the dresses with the pleats and collars. I picked out a long coat with a nautical neckline, so I could dress like the girls I imagined in my books.</p>
<p>I thought that if I wore those clothes, then I would be transported to those times. It wasn’t that I had a life that needed escaping. I don’t remember my parents fighting. I remember my father working during the days and my mother cashiering at the grocery store at night. When my brother and I would fall asleep on the couch, my father would pry us awake, telling us we needed to go get mom.</p>
<p>While I flipped through the books, imagining all the dresses I would have made for me, she would walk the aisles to find fabrics to dresses she had already decided to make for me. Like most mothers, I assume, she had her own idea of how to dress me, and that&#8217;s probably for the best. Though I always liked the dresses she made for me, they were never exactly how I had imagined them.</p>
<p>I think I see the dresses much how I view reality today. I have hopes for how things will turn out, but while I daydream about things, I&#8217;m aware of the stink that reminds me things will probably not turn exactly how I’m imagining. Reality rarely lives up to daydreams. The dresses were the first lesson of that.</p>
<p>So what&#8217;s better? The anticipation of a daydream or the contented reality that plays out? I&#8217;m glad to have grown out of my daydreaming tendencies, but however enjoyable my reality may be, sometimes I wish I could just stay in my head, constantly looking forward to the potential of a situation. This sounds a lot like disappointment, which is the exact opposite of what I want to convey. Today, for instance, I woke up to a rainy morning and had the urge to sit on my couch reading <a href="http://www.ninetymeetingsinninetydays.com/lorriemooore.html">Lorrie Moore stories</a> all day. From my bed, it seemed perfect: brew a pot of coffee and spend the day dehydrated and lost in second-person prose. What I ended up doing was having a single cup of coffee and finishing High Fidelity, punctuated by dozing every fifteen minutes or so.</p>
<p>Was it a good morning? YES. Do I still want to read Lorrie Moore? YES. Will I get to that? YES. But the marathon reading session in my bed probably won&#8217;t be as picturesque as I&#8217;m imagining because my spun-sugar candle isn&#8217;t as fragrant as I had hoped, and my coffee will get cold, or I&#8217;ll have to go to the bathroom, or I&#8217;ll need to heat up dinner, or I&#8217;ll get distracted by Netflix.</p>
<p>Maybe I have an answer to this: Anticipation is often better than reality, but it doesn&#8217;t help any to complain about it, so maybe the best thing to do is to daydream about simpler times when the thing you most hoped for was to wear a gaudy dress like the one in your doll catalogs.</p>
<p><a href="http://everythingisblooming.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/13942_1156685009512_7228996_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-636" title="13942_1156685009512_7228996_n" src="http://everythingisblooming.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/13942_1156685009512_7228996_n.jpg?w=300&h=232" alt="" width="300" height="232" /></a></p>
<p>You should also make it a point to thank your mom for not making those gaudy dresses because those pictures would be humiliating.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/635/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/635/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=635&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://everythingisblooming.wordpress.com/2012/08/26/anticipation-vs-reality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d044128a64f66e5b38516b9889e1d09e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">everythingisblooming</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://everythingisblooming.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/13942_1156685009512_7228996_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">13942_1156685009512_7228996_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>If You Tell 140 Million People Something, Is That Private?</title>
		<link>http://somelaw.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/if-you-tell-140-million-people-something-is-that-private/</link>
		<comments>http://somelaw.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/if-you-tell-140-million-people-something-is-that-private/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 15:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ryan Garcia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Laws]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Platforms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reasonable Expectation of Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Subpoena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warrant]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://somelaw.wordpress.com/?p=246</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The ongoing saga over the Twitter subpoenas in the Occupy New York criminal case just entered another round as Twitter appealed the previous court&#8217;s ruling regarding turning over Malcolm Harris&#8217; tweets.  I&#8217;ve written about the story before (here and here) but this latest round of papers has some interesting arguments. There are two main parts of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><img title="Yelling" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_LTSok2PZ5LI/R1bFnduhXlI/AAAAAAAAAMM/DENAFZRAqb4/s320/yelling_lg.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="200" /><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Hey! Do not listen to this! This is my own private thoughts and I don&#8217;t want you to hear me!&#8221;</p></div>
<p>The ongoing saga over the Twitter subpoenas in the Occupy New York criminal case just entered another round as <a href="http://gigaom.com/2012/08/27/twitter-files-appeal-in-major-social-media-case/">Twitter appealed the previous court&#8217;s ruling</a> regarding turning over Malcolm Harris&#8217; tweets.  I&#8217;ve written about the story before (<a href="http://somelaw.wordpress.com/2012/07/10/even-when-twitter-loses-they-win/">here</a> and <a href="http://somelaw.wordpress.com/2012/05/14/quick-updates-law-watch-walk-texting-illegal-nj-annoying-legal-az-subpoenaing-twitter-not-enough-everywhere/">here</a>) but this latest round of papers has some interesting arguments.</p>
<p>There are two main parts of Twitter appeal: one deals with the ability of Twitter or the user to respond to the subpoena, an issue I discussed earlier and not as interesting as the other; the second issue deals with the reasonable expectation of privacy in tweets.  If you want to read all of Twitter&#8217;s appeal, <a href="http://www.aclu.org/files/assets/brief-harris-appellateterm.pdf">here&#8217;s the full document</a>.  But I&#8217;ll be going over the most interesting part about expectations of privacy.</p>
<p>First, a quick primer.  Harris was arrested as part of the Occupy New York march that ended up obstructing traffic on a bridge.  He contends the police told him to go on the road, they say otherwise.  After his arrest, Harris made his Twitter account protected so only authorized people can read the tweets.  The government would like to look at his tweets to see if they shed light on the issue (&#8220;Cops say don&#8217;t go on the road but let&#8217;s do it anywhere #iwannagetarrested&#8221;).  Cue court battle.</p>
<p>Now, back to that reasonable expectation of privacy.  Twitter first argues that there is an expectation of privacy in this case because the government cannot access Harris&#8217; tweets without assistance from Twitter.  In this case it is because Harris has now made his Twitter account protected (so only individuals he authorizes can see his tweets) but they say that this can also happen because the tweet could be deleted or no longer visible (only the last 3200 tweets are currently visible through Twitter).  Nowhere in the brief does Twitter address the fact that Harris&#8217; accounts were public during the time period that the government has requested the tweets.</p>
<p>This brings up a rather fascinating aspect of social media.  We often hear about how risky it can be when people who use social media for minor communications suddenly discover that social media is recorded forever: that joke you made in context suddenly seems offensive out of context later, the comment you made in anger looks very bad the next day, the things you said after a night of drinking&#8230;well, you know how that goes.  But this is the opposite of that problem&#8211;it is not the permanence of the message but the fluid nature of the content.  We&#8217;ve seen instances of content changing over time as comments can be edited, etc., and now we face the issue of changing privacy settings on content.</p>
<p>Here, Harris&#8217; tweets were initially public.  They were broadcast to over a hundred million accounts for anyone to see.  Later, they were protected so that only specific accounts could see them.</p>
<p>So, are those messages now private because of the current setting or are they public because that&#8217;s how they started?</p>
<p>I think the answer has to be that outside of factors beyond a person&#8217;s control, we must treat content according to the least restrictive method in which it was ever made available.  Meaning if the content is ever broadcast to the entire world, whether the first post or later, it&#8217;s game over for an expectation of privacy.  Trying to come up with any other rule immediately runs into the problem of how you treat copies of content that suddenly becomes more restrictive&#8211;retweets, shares, simple emails of the content to other people.  It&#8217;s the fundamental difficulty in trying to implement a universal right to be forgotten or the magical social media content eraser button suggested by the FTC this year.  If you post something publicly and I retweet it, then you protect that tweet what happens to my retweet?  (Ignore some technical answer like Twitter keeps them connected&#8211;imagine I manually typed it in with a hat tip to you.)</p>
<p>I think Twitter knows this as well but they&#8217;re trying every argument they can.  Twitter tries to compare this case to emails (since emails have some judicial precedent on being protected):</p>
<blockquote><p>[I]f an email is entitled to Constitutional protection but an unavailable Tweet is not, what exactly is the dividing line that will allow citizens to understand when the Constitution protects their communications?</p></blockquote>
<p>To me, the answer seems fairly clear&#8211;the dividing line is who you&#8217;re telling.  If you sent an email to three people you may have an expectation it will only go to those three people (a weak one at best since that Forward button works really, really well).  But if you sent an email to 150 million accounts I&#8217;m not sure what protection you think that communication should be given.</p>
<p>Twitter also has some arguments about why the tweets should be protected even if they are public but that&#8217;s more procedural and not as interesting to me today.  Maybe next week.</p>
<p>The ACLU, EFF, and a few other organizations are also joining the fight, filing their own <a href="http://www.aclu.org/files/assets/2012-08-27-amicus_brief.pdf">amicus brief in support of Twitter</a>.  They make a much bigger deal of a small point Twitter brought up&#8211;that people have a reasonable expectation of privacy in their location and movements over time.  In this they are trying to draw parallels to cases that require the government to obtain a warrant before trailing someone for an extended period of time.  While I understand that comparison, I think it fails.  A person&#8217;s public tweets are not just moving through the world, minding their own business.  Tweets are tapping on the shoulder of a hundred million people and telling them the line at Starbucks is really long today.</p>
<p>The fact that most people don&#8217;t care or don&#8217;t listen doesn&#8217;t change the intent.  When you tweet, you want to be heard.  If you walk to the subway stop you may or may not want to be seen.  You also don&#8217;t have a choice if you want to use the subway but you always have a choice not to tweet.  I think a stronger comparison could be made as to browsing activity&#8211;you could compare my browsing habits (when I do not interact with what I read/consume) to moving through the world.  I do think a warrant should be required for the government to look at my browsing history for a month, but not if I tweet every website I visit.</p>
<p>Given that this is a case of first impression and the press attention, I&#8217;m hoping we see some analysis from the appeals court in their decision rather than a quick one line opinion.  We&#8217;ll have to wait and see but it&#8217;s apparent this issue isn&#8217;t going away.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://somelaw.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/if-you-tell-140-million-people-something-is-that-private/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/458a9e0ea022128fa432dfb259c81e52?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hose311</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_LTSok2PZ5LI/R1bFnduhXlI/AAAAAAAAAMM/DENAFZRAqb4/s320/yelling_lg.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yelling</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>