<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 20:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>In Praise of the Cinematic Baguette</title>
		<link>http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/in-praise-of-the-cinematic-baguette/</link>
		<comments>http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/in-praise-of-the-cinematic-baguette/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 16:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nevalalee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Clayton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Dragon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thomas Harris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Gilroy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV Tropes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Which Lie Did I Tell?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Goldman]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/?p=14814</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;ve seen this baguette before. In any movie or television show in which a character is shown carrying groceries, a big loaf of french bread is invariably seen peeking out over the top of the bag. On the few occasions when it isn&#8217;t there, a similar role is assumed by a leafy bunch of carrots, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=14814&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wilkinson.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-14815" alt="Tom Wilkinson in Michael Clayton" src="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wilkinson.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>You&#8217;ve seen this baguette before. In any movie or television show in which a character is shown carrying groceries, a big loaf of french bread is invariably seen peeking out over the top of the bag. On the few occasions when it isn&#8217;t there, a similar role is assumed by a leafy bunch of carrots, or, in exceptional cases, celery. As the comically detailed <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ISOStandardUrbanGroceries">TV Tropes entry</a> on the subject points out, you&#8217;ll see the baguette among groceries carried by the unlikeliest of characters, like Liam Neeson in <em>Taken</em>, who carries not one, but two. (He&#8217;s in Paris, after all.) And given how often this loaf of bread turns up, it was only a matter of time before a clever screenwriter, in this case Tony Gilory in <em>Michael Clayton</em>, gave us a grocery bag full of nothing <em>but</em> baguettes. In this instance, it&#8217;s partially intended as a reflection of the unstable mental state of the character played by Tom Wilkinson, but it&#8217;s also a nod to a cinematic convention that, over time, has come to seem like a particularly ludicrous visual cliché.</p>
<p>And yet that baguette is there for a reason. For one thing, it&#8217;s a convenient prop that is unlikely to wilt under hot studio lights or after hours spent on location. It&#8217;s also a handy bit of narrative shorthand. If we see a character carrying a paper bag without any clues about what it contains, we immediately start to wonder what might be inside. The baguette poking out over the top is a visual flag that, paradoxically, actually makes the bag less visible: as soon as we understand that it&#8217;s just a bag of groceries, we stop worrying about it. (<a title="Hannibal’s crossing" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2011/09/13/hannibals-crossing/">Thomas Harris</a>, a shrewd exploiter and creator of narrative tropes, even utilizes it as a plot point in <em>Red Dragon</em>, when Francis Dolarhyde, the killer, uses a big bunch of leafy celery as camouflage in his escape from a crime scene: &#8220;He stuffed his books and clothing into the grocery bag, then the weapons. The celery stuck out the top.&#8221; And when he passes the police a moment later, carrying what is obviously just a bag of groceries, they don&#8217;t give him a second glance.)</p>
<p><a href="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/goldman.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5198" alt="William Goldman" src="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/goldman.jpg?w=300&#038;h=214" width="300" height="214" /></a></p>
<p>Most clichés, after all, start out as a piece of authorial shorthand that allows the reader or viewer to focus on what really matters. William Goldman, who is close friends with Gilroy, makes a similar point in his wonderful book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Which-Lie-Did-Tell-Adventures/dp/0375703195"><em>Which Lie Did I Tell?</em></a> He ticks off some of the most notorious examples of how the movies depart from real life—the hero can always find a parking space when he needs one, the local news invariably happens to be talking about a necessary plot point when a character turns on the television, taxi fares can always be paid with the first bill you happen to grab without looking down at your wallet—and goes on to make an excellent observation: all of these clichés are about saving time. In a good movie, everything that isn&#8217;t relevant to the story goes out the window, which is why we see so many ridiculously convenient moments that allow us to move on without pausing to the next important scene. That baguette serves a useful purpose. If they gave awards to props, it would at least merit a nod for Best Supporting Actor.</p>
<p>The trouble, of course, is that as soon as a narrative device proves its usefulness, it&#8217;s immediately copied by every writer in sight. And it&#8217;s easy to understand why: such tricks are worth their weight in gold. In my own novels, I&#8217;m constantly trying to find the right balance between advancing the plot and avoiding story beats that seem too obvious or convenient. (For example, in both <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Icon-Thief-Alec-Nevala-Lee/dp/0451236203">The Icon Thief</a> </em>and <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/City-Exiles-Alec-Nevala-Lee/dp/0451238788">City of Exiles</a>,</em> there&#8217;s a scene in which a suspect cracks a bit too easily under interrogation, just because I wanted to get on to the next big thing. I try to disguise such moments as best as I can, but I can&#8217;t claim the effect is entirely successful.) And whenever a writer discovers a novel piece of shorthand, or a clever spin on an old cliché, it&#8217;s like stumbling across a new industrial process. You&#8217;d like to patent it, but once it&#8217;s in print, it&#8217;s there for anyone to use. So the search for new tropes goes on, as it should. Because a baguette, as we all know, doesn&#8217;t stay fresh for long.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/14814/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/14814/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=14814&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/in-praise-of-the-cinematic-baguette/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a86a6b77ede854a68ec81fa62c7a80eb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nevalalee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wilkinson.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tom Wilkinson in Michael Clayton</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/goldman.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">William Goldman</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Of Cigarettes and Swing Sets</title>
		<link>http://dadicusgrinch.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/of-cigarettes-and-swing-sets/</link>
		<comments>http://dadicusgrinch.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/of-cigarettes-and-swing-sets/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 02:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael T.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[CHILDHOOD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banana Splits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy Island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hee Haw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lawrence Welk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dadicusgrinch.wordpress.com/?p=644</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a beautiful Saturday morning in 1975. I have already eaten my Cap&#8217;n Crunch (and the roof of my mouth is properly shredded). I have watched my fill of Saturday morning cartoons&#8211;The Flintsones, Banana Splits, Shazam and Isis&#8211;and I am eagerly awaiting the arrival of the newest addition to the Trainer family. No, not another [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=644&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dadicusgrinch.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/of-cigarettes-and-swing-sets/smoking/" rel="attachment wp-att-652"><img class=" wp-image-652 alignleft" alt="smoking" src="http://dadicusgrinch.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/smoking.jpg?w=264&#038;h=347" width="264" height="347" /></a>It&#8217;s a beautiful Saturday morning in 1975. I have already eaten my <a class="zem_slink" title="Cap'n Crunch" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cap%27n_Crunch" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Cap&#8217;n Crunch</a> (and the roof of my mouth is properly shredded). I have watched my fill of <a class="zem_slink" title="Saturday morning cartoon" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saturday_morning_cartoon" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Saturday morning cartoons</a>&#8211;<em>The Flintsones, <a class="zem_slink" title="The Banana Splits" href="http://www.bananasplits.com" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Banana Splits</a>, Shazam</em> and <em>Isis</em>&#8211;and I am eagerly awaiting the arrival of the newest addition to the Trainer family. No, not another baby (thank God), but a brand new swing set. Yes, our yard will finally have an attraction that I will be able to use as leverage when I want to swing on Cindy&#8217;s <a class="zem_slink" title="Swing (seat)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swing_%28seat%29" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">tire swing</a> or swim in Mike&#8217;s above ground pool.</p>
<p>I can hardly contain my excitement. I am there from the moment my dad, my Uncle Nicky, and a few of the other dads in the neighborhood begin digging holes by the rear fence—four holes for the four steel posts of the swing set. A few of my friends want in on the action, and before long, it seems like the whole neighborhood is in our backyard.</p>
<p>My dad and his cronies (that&#8217;s what my mom calls them) are busy fetching tools, swing parts, and beers, so there is a lot of commotion; a lot of people going this way and that. We are told to go play on the front lawn as the backyard  is now strewn with important materials. A few of us begin a game of <a class="zem_slink" title="Tag (game)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tag_%28game%29" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">TV tag</a>. Now, I&#8217;m not sure if this game ever achieved national fame, but TV tag was one of those consummate &#8217;70s lawn games. Someone would be “IT”, and everyone else would run around. As kids were chased by &#8220;IT&#8221;, they could kneel on one knee and call out a TV show. If they did this before being tagged, they were safe. How I loved that game. And, how I tried to call out the coolest <a class="zem_slink" title="Television program" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Television_program" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">TV shows</a> before the others. If I could last long enough to shout out <em>Happy Days, <a class="zem_slink" title="Laverne &amp; Shirley" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laverne_%26_Shirley" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Laverne and Shirley</a>, Love Boat, </em>and<em> <a class="zem_slink" title="Fantasy Island" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantasy_Island" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Fantasy Island</a></em>, then my mission was complete. No way did I want to be in the game &#8217;til the end, since kids were forced to choose lame shows like <em><a class="zem_slink" title="Lawrence Welk" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/celebrity/lawrence_welk" target="_blank" rel="rottentomatoes">Lawrence Welk</a></em> and <em><a class="zem_slink" title="Hee Haw" href="http://www.heehaw.com" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Hee Haw</a></em>. Yeah, TV tag was far out, man. You dig?</p>
<p>As we are engrossed in our fun, my dad comes out to the driveway and walks across the lawn. He needs a tool from our next door neighbor. As he passes by, we stop the game. He says something funny, then tosses the butt of his lit cigarette onto the grass behind us. As he leaves, I have an idea.</p>
<p>I walk over and find the cigarette—still burning. My friends crowd around me in a circle. “Pick it up,” I hear (maybe in my head), and so I do. I hold it in my hand, rolling it between my thumb and forefinger. My friends stare at me wildly. OOOhhhh—that’s bad. But I don’t feel bad. I feel cool. As I raise the butt to my mouth, I see them&#8211; my father’s feet entering the circle that has formed around me. From my crouching position, I look up towards him. He towers above me. I pitch the cigarette to the ground as he grabs my arm.</p>
<p>“You should know better!” he yells. “Get up to your room.” “But I…” “Now!” he commands.</p>
<p>I look at my friends’ faces, their expressions all seem to say, &#8220;Yeah, we knew this was going to end badly.&#8221;</p>
<p>As I walk inside, I am flush with embarrassment, then shame, then anger. I stomp up the stairs. Each foot a THUD—punctuating my frustration. THIS (thud) IS(thud) NOT(thud) FAIR(thud)! I (thud)DIDN’T(thud) MEAN(thud) TO&#8212;&#8212;SLAM! I shut the door hard, fully aware that no one is around to hear it.</p>
<p>For the remainder of the day, I watch all the activity from my bedroom window. My father and his friends work hard to get the swing set in by nightfall. My brothers and sisters play and laugh with their friends. Everyone breaks for a cookout. And I am alone. Alone. I don’t even remember eating that day. I like to think I was not allowed to eat—starved as a part of my punishment.</p>
<p>And as I stare at my dad in the yard, I realize why I am so angry. If I had known the word “hypocrite” as a six year-old, I would have called him one (under my breath of course). Because that’s what he was: a hypocrite. He said <b><span style="text-decoration:underline;">I</span> </b>should know better. Well, <b><span style="text-decoration:underline;">HE</span></b> should know better. He shouldn’t smoke. He shouldn’t throw lit cigarettes near kids who are playing on the lawn. He shouldn’t punish me for the whole day. A time out should last ten minutes, not ten hours. Hypocrite!</p>
<p>And therein lies the curse of my father. Even when he was trying to show his devotion towards his kids, his anger and frustration would get the better of him.  A gesture of love and kindness, like installing a swing set for your kids, is marred by a man&#8217;s inability to see the effects of his actions. A day spent working for the benefit of  family is spoiled by too many beers and not enough patience. This curse haunts me as a father, when I overreact about something insignificant, or I blame the kids for something I know was my stupid fault, or when I am impatient because I didn&#8217;t allow enough time to get everything done. Being a father certainly allows me to have more empathy for my own dad. But one thing I try to never be is a hypocrite. I am not in favor of the old &#8220;do as I say, not as I do&#8221; form of parenting.</p>
<p>**********************************************</p>
<p>The next morning, I am eager to make up for lost time. It is very early, and no one in the house is up yet. I sneak  into my sister Erin&#8217;s room and wake her. We tiptoe down the stairs and out into the yard, our bare feet trekking<a href="http://dadicusgrinch.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/of-cigarettes-and-swing-sets/a118-1/" rel="attachment wp-att-653"><img class="size-full wp-image-653 alignright" alt="a118 (1)" src="http://dadicusgrinch.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/a118-1.jpg?w=590"   /></a> through the wet, dewy grass. We behold the swing set in all of its lime green and rust orange glory. We are like two warriors coming upon the hidden city. We hop onto the swings and start to glide; our legs travelling back and forth…back and forth… back and forth. The chains squeak with an oily newness. We feel special. The first to ride on our new toy. We smile at each other, laugh, and then BOOOOM! The entire set crashes to the ground. Erin and I fall flat on our faces and look up to see the swing set uprooted from its newly-cemented-as-yet-to-dry holes. Oh my God! What are we going to do?</p>
<p>Had we waited for the okay to ride on the swings, this wouldn’t have happened. We head inside. I am filled with a sense of dread at the thought of another day of being held captive in my room.</p>
<p>“Mom…? Dad…?”</p>
<p>I hear them waking. Drowsy footsteps come to the bedroom door. I take a deep breath.</p>
<p><em>This stupid swing set is nothing but trouble</em>, I think to myself.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/644/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/644/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=644&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dadicusgrinch.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/of-cigarettes-and-swing-sets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6fd57a569463364d90938b87e393f0ad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dadicusgrinch</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dadicusgrinch.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/smoking.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">smoking</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dadicusgrinch.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/a118-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">a118 (1)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Non-Fatalistic, Real-Life Tips for Freelance Writers</title>
		<link>http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/10-non-fatalistic-real-life-tips-for-freelance-writers/</link>
		<comments>http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/10-non-fatalistic-real-life-tips-for-freelance-writers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 03:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alaina Mabaso</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freelance writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting published]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to be a freelance writer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary Roach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mehmet Oz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing career]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/?p=1833</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I may look back on this blog post in a few years and cringe that I was callow enough to compose an advice article about writing professionally when I have been doing it for only five years. But a growing number of people have asked me for advice. While this is aimed primarily at writers, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1833&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1838" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><img class="size-full wp-image-1838" alt="This is what my cubicle looks like at the beginning of a day of writing copy at the office. " src="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/copywriter-start-of-day-e1355364518871.jpg?w=590"   /><p class="wp-caption-text">This is what my cubicle looks like at the beginning of a day of writing copy at the office.</p></div>
<p>I may look back on this blog post in a few years and cringe that I was callow enough to compose an advice article about writing professionally when I have been doing it for only five years. But a growing number of people have asked me for advice.</p>
<p>While this is aimed primarily at writers, I have an inkling that the same principles apply to current or aspiring professionals in graphic design, fine arts, photography, or any number of fields.</p>
<p>FYI, this ain’t a tutorial on the Art of Writing. It’s not about the pros and cons or financials of freelancing. And I am not a fiction writer. This is about finding and keeping freelance writing gigs in journalism, PR, marketing, copywriting and related fields. And each of the ten tips is accompanied by a holier-than-thou example from my own life &#8211; I am not foisting ideas upon you that I wouldn’t try myself.</p>
<p>Just so you know, I have no degree or formal training in writing, besides a Bachelor of Arts degree in Theater Arts and English (I know, I know, I practically have to beat the high-paying employers off wherever I go).  This is all stuff I learned on the job.</p>
<p>Also, nobody start salivating about using my tips to make tons of money. I am not rich. What we’re talking about here is paying the bills with enough left for an occasional movie or dinner out.</p>
<p><b>1)  </b><b>Be a spider.</b></p>
<p><b><a href="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/networking-spider.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1834" alt="" src="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/networking-spider.jpg?w=590"   /></a></b></p>
<p>Ew, <i>spiders</i>.</p>
<p>Are you done?</p>
<p>Each person you build a good relationship with is a thread in your web. Each gig they hear about and each job list they subscribe to is like a bug flying into your sticky trap. (Like my stellar analogy? You’re welcome.)</p>
<p>Some people will advise aspiring writers to endlessly thumb the <a href="http://www.writersdigestshop.com/writers-market-2013?cid=3&amp;gclid=COXLup6flrQCFUKd4AodTA4Adg">Writer&#8217;s Market</a> and pitch, pitch, pitch (sell editors on a story) if they want to get published. I think your energy is just as well spent in building a network that will give you a shot at the assignments editors already have in mind.</p>
<p>Make lists. Set contact goals. Be friendly and bold. The worst someone can do is say no or ignore you. Do not be afraid to reach out to people of a different age, race, or sex. Don’t just stalk your idols on Twitter. Write to them. Swallow your shyness and brashly introduce yourself to the VIP at the party. If I can waltz up and introduce myself to Dr. Mehmet Oz that time we wound up at the same church service, you can too.</p>
<div id="attachment_1835" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 275px"><a href="http://www2.turnto10.com/entertainment/2011/aug/02/dr-mehmet-oz-im-18788/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1835" alt="Unfortunately, he does not glow like this in person. " src="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dr-oz.jpg?w=265&#038;h=300" width="265" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Unfortunately, he does not glow like this in person.</p></div>
<p>Ask people out for breakfast, lunch, dinner or coffee – even if you’ve never met. Spark friendships and pick their brains for opportunities or resume tips. Maintain the relationship with occasional friendly e-mails and invitations and always thank others for their time.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example</i>:</p>
<p>In the last five years, I’ve written for at least twenty different editors. Out of those, how many did I approach out of the blue with a pitch?</p>
<p>Only one.</p>
<p>The rest became interested in giving me an assignment when I contacted them via tips from my network, or because I had already worked with an editor or a writer they knew.</p>
<p>Maybe I’m a just a good networker and a bad pitcher. But if you’re pitching nonstop and getting nowhere, maybe you should work your way in with a different approach.</p>
<div id="attachment_1836" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1836" alt="If any of my current editors are reading this, feel free to try and figure out which stick figure you are. If any future editors are reading this, please be assured that I am extremely respectful. " src="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/editors-via-networking-e1355363397667.jpg?w=300&#038;h=151" width="300" height="151" /><p class="wp-caption-text">If any of my current editors are reading this, feel free to try and figure out which stick figure you are. If any future editors are reading this, please be assured that I am extremely respectful.</p></div>
<p><b>2)  </b><b>The Networking Sandwich</b></p>
<p>And <em>now</em> you’re saying, “OK. Crap. It’s not <i>what</i> you know, but <i>who </i>you know.”</p>
<p>This is only partly true.</p>
<p>Finding gigs is a networking sandwich:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1837" alt="" src="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/networking-sandwich.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></p>
<p>Quality work earns you admiring contacts. Network among those contacts to find new jobs. Then prove yourself to your new contacts with more quality work.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example:</i></p>
<p>Even with a strong recommendation, those editors I mentioned in the first example began by asking me if I could provide some clips as a test of my skill and style.</p>
<p>If my work was lousy, those connections would be useless.</p>
<p><b>3)  </b><b>Marshall the Troops</b></p>
<p>Once you’ve had some practice building your own network, position yourself as a leader. Think of ways you can bring people together to share the resources in your fields, and be an affirmative facilitator of the conversation.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example: </i>I joined a writers’ networking group that was about to fizzle because the original organizers didn’t want to continue the effort. I saw an opportunity and stepped up to take charge of it, organizing meetings and maintaining and expanding the contact and RSVP lists. It takes a lot of time of and effort, but the friends I’ve made and the work opportunities we’ve all shared have been worth it. I helped other members find new markets for their essays, and other members helped me find new work as a copywriter.</p>
<p><b>4)  </b><b>Get in Their Faces</b></p>
<p>It can be easy for a freelance writer to slump behind a computer and a phone to meet the day’s deadlines. Nowadays, it’s possible to work with an editor – or your fellow writers &#8211; for months or even years without meeting face to face.</p>
<p>But don’t be that writer.</p>
<p>Invite your editors and colleagues out for lunch. Take advantage of local industry events. Be more than an e-mail address or another byline to the people you work with. Making that effort will give you one more way to stand out in a competitive field.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example: </i>I had written for a publication for about two years without meeting my editor in person, so when the publication began to host events for its readers and contributors, I made a point of going and introducing myself. Now, the relationship with that editor, plus my continued work, has grown into an Associate Editor job offer. I start next week.</p>
<p><b>5)  </b><b>Think Hyper-Local. </b></p>
<p>Your career will never start until <i>Psychology Today</i> accepts your pitch, right?</p>
<p>Wrong.</p>
<p>Major newspapers and magazines aren’t hiring. Thanks, Internet. But the flip side of online media is that there are lots of new, highly-targeted local markets that are probably looking for good freelancers.</p>
<p>Is there a local news site in your town or a locally-focused magazine in your city? Research the site or publication and pitch that editor with your hometown knowledge, or leverage your network to get in touch.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou example</i>: About two years ago, the branch of NPR media in Philadelphia was launching a <a href="http://www.newsworks.org/">new series of websites</a> targeted to specific neighborhoods. A former co-worker of mine was a former co-worker of one of the new editors, and I asked for an introduction. I now write a wide range of stories and essays for several editors there. Riches and glory? No. A paycheck and entertaining work? Yes.</p>
<p><b>6)  </b><b>Work for free. (For awhile.)</b></p>
<p>You thought you could start your career with a big, fat contract? I admit, it’s not unheard of (I am beginning to suspect my downfall is my disinterest in young adult paranormal romance).</p>
<p>But get real. You need to get your foot in the door somewhere, and build up a body of bylines. It’s ok to volunteer your time and skills when you’re just starting out, if the experience is relevant to the career you want to build.</p>
<p>But be careful. You will run into people – even editors – who claim to think that the privilege of a byline in a competitive market should be more than enough compensation to you. Or they might tell you that the entry you get to shows or events as a writer should be enough of an incentive for you to provide your work for free. They are wrong.</p>
<p>You decide the line between unpaid experience that benefits you in the long run, and an editor or publication that tries to exploit your skills.  Once you’ve made the transition to paid work (unless you choose to volunteer for a good cause), stick to it.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example:</i></p>
<p>I wanted to become an arts writer, so when I heard about a website that needed theater critics when I was a year or so out of college, I jumped. They didn’t pay their writers, but over two or three years, I amassed hundreds of bylines and took in hundreds of professional shows – a better education than four years of college. But I slowly quit writing for the site when my growing experience allowed me to pick up paying gigs. The editor tried to coax me back earlier this year, still without compensation, and I said no. I am grateful for the start I got, but right now I have too many assignments to spend time on work that doesn’t benefit my bank account or my own platform.</p>
<p><b>7)  </b><b>Volunteer, Altruistic or Not.</b></p>
<p>If you think you have writing skills but need practice in a real-world setting, don’t have a professional network, or have yet to build your resume, you can kill all those birds with one stone.</p>
<p>Find a small, hard-pressed office of people nearby who are trying to do some good in this world and ask them if they need someone to write their blog posts, website or press releases or handle social media or PR.</p>
<p>Voila: experience, skill-building, and the start of your network.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou example:</i></p>
<p>When my former playwriting teacher connected me to a nascent <a href="http://rebeccadavisdance.com/">dance company</a> that needed help developing original librettos, I met with the young and socially-conscious artistic director. I ended up joining the board and working on several librettos as well as managing PR campaigns for the company’s shows. It was like a second job for zero pay, but the experience was priceless, I felt good about the cause, and I don’t even know how many gigs I’ve landed over the years that were the result of networking among the esteemed friends and mentors I met through that company.</p>
<p><b>8)  </b><b>Be Versatile.</b></p>
<p>A former editor once told me over Pad Thai that the key to a viable writing career was getting in good with one high-paying magazine.</p>
<p>Wrong.</p>
<p>I know because I did it. I began writing for an international trade journal that sometimes paid me upwards of two thousand dollars per piece. My whole month’s budget was made with one article. I was in heaven.</p>
<p>Then the mag ran into financial trouble and my apologetic editor told me they’d been forced to axe their freelancer budget. Good thing I had cultivated work in several other markets, just in case.</p>
<p>There are no guarantees for the freelance writer: even the sweetest gig could evaporate next month. Be willing to tackle a variety of fields and topics. A big reason I am able to pay the bills by writing is that I don’t let new arenas intimidate me. Arts, science, medicine, aviation, farming, business, architecture: whatever it is, I track down some experts to tell me all about it, and write that piece.</p>
<div id="attachment_1839" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/06/03/what-it-is-like-to-be-a-freelance-writer/"><img class="size-full wp-image-1839" alt="From an earlier post titled &quot;What It Is Like to Be a Freelance Writer&quot; " src="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/writer-questions.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From an earlier post titled &#8220;What It Is Like to Be a Freelance Writer&#8221;</p></div>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example:</i></p>
<p>Often, to make ends meet, you must be willing to transition between different realms of work. I had been a blogger, essayist and journalist for years when an opportunity to become an agency copywriter came my way (thanks, networking). I didn’t say, “Oh dear, I have no advertising experience.” I showed up, scared witless, and began learning.</p>
<p><b>9)  </b><b> Prostrate Yourself on the Altar of the Blogosphere</b></p>
<p>Yeah, yeah, the whole reason writers’ careers are crumbling everywhere is that witless scribblers are giving their stuff away for free on blogs.</p>
<p>Ahem.</p>
<p>That’s one way of looking at it. But I think that’s a pessimistic, no-fun view.</p>
<p>There are tons of reasons to maintain a blog, as long as you can commit to posts of consistent quality. Yes, any 21<sup>st</sup>-century writing manual can tell you that you need to build your own platform and audience as a writer – no big ol’ publisher is going to do it for you anymore (hence the difference between writing that builds your own presence and brand, and writing for free for a random publication that’s willing to exploit you).</p>
<p>But reasons for blogging go beyond this. I find that the more you write, the more you write. Blogs keep you sharp between assignments. They’re also an outlet for what’s personally important to you, keeping your drive and ambitions fresh. They can be your editor-free playground (believe me, tailoring your stuff to several different editors every week can get tiring). And on the other hand, I have landed work with new editors or employers because they checked out the blog, or even purchased pieces from it. I’ve also developed pieces on the blog that I later worked into paid, published essays.</p>
<p>And once you’ve build up a modest audience, a blog is a fantastic excuse to hit up other writers you admire for interviews.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example:</i></p>
<p>I have been a huge fan of bestselling author <a href="http://maryroach.net/">Mary Roach</a> for years. I got up my courage one day and contacted her through her website. She kindly agreed to <a title="ALAINA MABASO’S BLOG INTERVIEW: Author Mary Roach on her days below the bottom rung, hair styling on the Colbert Report, and the dangers of book tours." href="http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/01/21/alaina-mabasos-blog-interview-author-mary-roach-on-her-days-below-the-bottom-rung-hair-styling-on-the-colbert-report-and-the-dangers-of-book-tours/">an interview for this blog</a>.</p>
<p>I found out that her early career was very similar to what I’m doing now. Later, she e-mailed me to say she had enjoyed the interview, and added “Keep at it. I expect to be saying, ‘I knew her back when…’”</p>
<p>Awesome.</p>
<p><b>10)  </b><b>Be Big-Minded</b></p>
<p>If you want to be a writer, you’ll hear a lot about how competitive the field is. You will feel the impulse to hoard your leads, keep good markets to yourself, and shrug when others ask you for specific advice, lest they threaten your piece of the pie.</p>
<p>People have romantic notions about writing careers, and if you have some measure of success, others will come out of the woodwork to poach you for THEIR networks.</p>
<p>Remember, networking is a two-way street. If your editors are looking for new talent, share that with people who have the right skills. Don’t be stingy with useful tips to people who ask for them.</p>
<p>I had lunch with a contact once who happily took my advice on local editors to approach. But when I asked if my new colleague could offer any contacts to me, the person expressly refused to reciprocate, saying I would be too much competition (yes, I never said it wasn’t a jungle out there).</p>
<p>That is one way of doing business.</p>
<p>But to me, sharing valuable contacts is just one more incentive for me to stay at the top of my game. I don’t mind if editors add my colleagues to the team. I want work because my skills merit it, not because I froze out other people who might also be eligible.</p>
<p>And if you help someone today, who’s to say the tables won’t be turned tomorrow?</p>
<p>Let your confidence in your own skills translate into a helping hand for others, and watch your friendships increase as fast as your work opportunities.</p>
<p><i>Holier-than-thou Example:</i></p>
<p>This blog post.</p>
<p>UPDATE: Welcome, Freshly Pressed readers! Thanks for visiting. Share your thoughts in the comments, or, you know, start a heated argument &#8211; this is the Internet after all.</p>
<p>Also of interest to bloggers, book-lovers and linguaphiles:</p>
<p><a title="Pandora’s Inbox: One Blogger’s Favorite E-mails from Would-Be Advertisers" href="http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/pandoras-inbox-one-bloggers-favorite-e-mails-from-would-be-advertisers/">Pandora&#8217;s Inbox: One Blogger&#8217;s Favorite E-Mails from Would-Be Advertisers</p>
<p></a><a title="Literary Lies: The Five Things You Really Mean When You Say “It’s On My List”" href="http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/10/24/literary-lies-the-five-things-you-really-mean-when-you-say-its-on-my-list/">Literary Lies: The Five Things You Really Mean When You Say, &#8220;It&#8217;s On My List&#8221;</p>
<p></a><a title="The Linguist’s Comeuppance" href="http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2011/08/11/the-linguists-comeuppance/">The Linguist&#8217;s Comeuppance</p>
<p></a></p>
<a name="pd_a_6765135"></a>
<div class="PDS_Poll" id="PDI_container6765135" data-settings="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/static.polldaddy.com\/p\/6765135.js&quot;}" style="display:inline-block;"></div>
<div id="PD_superContainer"></div>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/6765135">Take Our Poll</a></noscript>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1833/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1833&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alainamabaso.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/10-non-fatalistic-real-life-tips-for-freelance-writers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bc103caf9df97dc9ae808cb1e543c97c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alainamabaso</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/copywriter-start-of-day-e1355364518871.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This is what my cubicle looks like at the beginning of a day of writing copy at the office. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/networking-spider.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dr-oz.jpg?w=265" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Unfortunately, he does not glow like this in person. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/editors-via-networking-e1355363397667.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">If any of my current editors are reading this, feel free to try and figure out which stick figure you are. If any future editors are reading this, please be assured that I am extremely respectful. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/networking-sandwich.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://alainamabaso.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/writer-questions.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">From an earlier post titled &#34;What It Is Like to Be a Freelance Writer&#34; </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 120: I’m Afeared</title>
		<link>http://weinstein365.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/day-120-im-afeared/</link>
		<comments>http://weinstein365.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/day-120-im-afeared/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 11:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fransiweinstein</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[revenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angry cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[litter boxes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[punishments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://weinstein365.wordpress.com/?p=1587</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yup.  I&#8217;m afeared, all right.  And all you cat lovers out there will know exactly what I&#8217;m talking about.  We know that, of all the animals, cats are the most misunderstood creatures.  They do like people.  And they are affectionate.  Just on their terms, is all.  But there is one thing you never do to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1587&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yup.  I&#8217;m afeared, all right.  And all you cat lovers out there will know exactly what I&#8217;m talking about.  We know that, of all the animals, cats are the most misunderstood creatures.  They <em>do</em> <a href="http://weinstein365.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/day-120-im-afeared/angrycat/" rel="attachment wp-att-1589"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1589" alt="angrycat" src="http://weinstein365.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/angrycat.jpg?w=257&#038;h=300" height="300" width="257" /></a>like people.  And they <em>are</em> affectionate.  Just on their terms, is all.  But there is one thing you <em>never</em> do to a cat.  Never.  Ever.  Come on, I know you know what it is.  Work with me, here.</p>
<p>That is correct.</p>
<p>You do not, I repeat, you do not mess with their litter.  This is not negotiable.  You hear me?  You do not mess with their litter.  Or their litter boxes, by the way.  They take all matters concerning their &#8216;toilette&#8217; very seriously.  As I found out the hard way, not all that long ago.</p>
<p>My intentions were honourable.  I was walking through a very upscale shopping mall near where I live.  Amidst all the designer boutiques, there is a pet store.  Yes, a designer pet store.  You would not believe the stuff they have in there.  As you can imagine, they cater mostly to dogs.  But over the years they have added some items, for those of us who fancy felines as companions.</p>
<p>In the window, next to a pet-sized, ruby-hued, tufted, velvet chaise, were the most fabulous litter boxes.  They were <span id="more-1587"></span>covered (a must unless you&#8217;re crazy enough to love vacuuming).  They came in an array of fabulous colours.  And they were not in that shiny plastic that we&#8217;re used to.  Whatever they were made out of, the finish was matte and frosted.  The &#8216;pan&#8217; was much deeper than usual.  And the cover swung back and forth, from front to back.  So you didn&#8217;t have to take it off, to clean the inside.  They were very futuristic looking.</p>
<p>My first impression was, &#8220;WOW!  Those are johns I&#8217;d love to have, if I was a cat.&#8221;  They were the <a title="TOTO" href="http://www.totousa.com/Products/Toilets.aspx">TOTO</a> of cat boxes.  As I stood there, gazing at them, I could just hear my little darlings:  &#8221;Buy them for us, Mommy.  Please, please, please.  Buy them.&#8221;   I still had three little darlings then, so I bought two.  To replace the two I already had, which were the plain, utilitarian versions available at every hardware store and every pet shop.</p>
<p>Absolutely nothing wrong with them.  They&#8217;d served me very well for many years, and several cats.  They&#8217;re just not in this league.</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t wait to get home.  Cats are curious, so you can imagine the flurry of activity when I opened the door and they saw my arms were full.  I took the covers off and turned them over, so they couldn&#8217;t climb in and use them before they were filled with litter.  I had decided I&#8217;d dispose of the old ones first.  Finally we were ready for a test drive, as it were.</p>
<p>At first they all just stood there.  They stared at each other with quizzical expressions on their little faces.  As if to say, &#8220;What the hell are these?&#8221;  Then they looked at me.  And not with the expressions of glee and gratitude I had imagined.  But I hadn&#8217;t fully twigged to the severity of the situation yet.  I know that cats don&#8217;t particularly care for change, but I was sure they&#8217;d be happy as clams shortly.  Who wouldn&#8217;t be, after all?</p>
<p>They just needed a bit of time.  Then they sniffed, pawed, walked around them, climbed in, climbed out, climbed on top.  And then left.  Without so much as a backward glance.</p>
<p>Not the most auspicious beginning.  But I went on, about my business.  Oblivious to the conspiring that was going on, in the other room.  Or the punishment they had in store for me.  Over the course of the next twenty-four hours, I was taught a lesson I will never forget:  I woke up to find a turd at the foot of my bed.  I was greeted by another one, strategically placed right in front of <em>my</em> toilet.  Another rested beside a food dish.  Theirs, thankfully, not mine.</p>
<p>A combination of allergies and bad sinuses have taken their toll on my sense of smell, but when I came back home after several hours away, there was no mistaking it.  <em>Sniff.  Sniff.  Sniff, sniff.</em>  You got it.  Urine.  With trepidation I walked around examining the floors, the sinks and the furniture.  Also my bed, which had been so pointedly targeted the night before.</p>
<p>Way too predictable.  Cats are clever, lest we forget.  They&#8217;d never be that obvious.  They wouldn&#8217;t repeat themselves.  About an hour later, while I was down on all fours in my bedroom closet, I found a pair of slippers and boots that were suspiciously wet.  And it was only when I backed out of there, still on my knees, that I saw the baskets.  Four in all.  One for their toys and three lined in sheepskin.  One for each of my &#8216;treasures&#8217; to curl up in.</p>
<p>Well, they wouldn&#8217;t be doing that anymore.  Nor would they ever be playing with those toys again.</p>
<p>&#8220;Okay&#8221;, I said, holding back tears.  &#8221;I surrender.  Nothing fancy.  I get it&#8221;.  Obviously, the store wouldn&#8217;t take back the Neiman Marcus version of litter boxes.  I asked around, but my friends were all afraid to tempt fate.  My vet didn&#8217;t want them.  I put a notice up on the bulletin board in the building where I live, to no avail.  I would have given them away for free, just to avoid throwing them away.  But in the end, the dumpster was where they ended up.  Just before I ran back to the hardware store to pick up the plain, plastic litter boxes we&#8217;ve all been using for ages.</p>
<p>So what has me all a quiver?</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been using the same litter since I adopted these kitties, many moons ago.  Everyone&#8217;s very happy with it.  Very happy.  I found out yesterday that it&#8217;s no longer available in Canada.  Nowhere.  I called every store that&#8217;s ever sold it.  Got the same answer.</p>
<p>I am thinking I need to wrap everything in plastic wrap, just in case.  Everything.  Take everything off the floor, that&#8217;s on the floor.  Stock up on rubber gloves and garbage bags.  Put my shoes in plastic boxes, on the balcony.  Maybe even move out there, myself.  Thinking ahead, and strategically for once, I am also trying to introduce them to the new litter gradually.  Thank God I still have some of the old litter left.  So I will mix the two together, for a couple of days, and gradually move to just the new one.  Yeah, right.</p>
<p>Who am I kidding?  Let&#8217;s face it, folks. I am screwed.  I am SO screwed!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1587/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1587&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://weinstein365.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/day-120-im-afeared/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5a851b1a494a69cca0eda1bf1f953af0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fransiweinstein</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://weinstein365.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/angrycat.jpg?w=257" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">angrycat</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joy</title>
		<link>http://oedaday.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/joy/</link>
		<comments>http://oedaday.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/joy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 19:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>akreed</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indian music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ravi Shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sitar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oedaday.wordpress.com/?p=335</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[joy n. a feeling of great pleasure and happiness The word joy is inevitably being said more these days as it is the holiday season. &#8220;Joy to the world&#8221; yadda yadda yadda. I was thinking about joy today while eating lunch. I must have heard it on some Target commercial or perhaps on a sign somewhere. In [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=335&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>joy </strong><em>n. </em>a feeling of great pleasure and happiness</p>
<p><a href="http://oedaday.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/joy/ravi-shankar-horizontal-gallery/" rel="attachment wp-att-339"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-339" alt="ravi-shankar-horizontal-gallery" src="http://oedaday.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ravi-shankar-horizontal-gallery.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The word joy is inevitably being said more these days as it is the holiday season. &#8220;Joy to the world&#8221; yadda yadda yadda. I was thinking about joy today while eating lunch. I must have heard it on some Target commercial or perhaps on a sign somewhere. In my mind, joy has a more profound meaning than just &#8220;great pleasure.&#8221; I feel like I often feel happiness or, more often contentment, but joy seems somehow more pure and untainted. I think we all have moments of happiness in our lives, but our moments of joy are far, far fewer and yet more crystalized in our memories.</p>
<p>I think the OED may have fallen short in defining this word so broadly. I associate joy with childhood. It is happiness that knows no cynicism &#8211; pleasure in its purest form. When we are children, we find joy in simple things &#8211; like climbing trees or being tickled. The idyllic childhood has you feeling this happiness in an unfettered, unspoiled way. The longer your span of enjoying this joy &#8211; or untainted happiness &#8211; the happier your childhood. When we are young, we haven&#8217;t experienced a lot of evil yet &#8211; hopefully. We are naive. We aren&#8217;t looking around the corner for the catch or the ghost that spoils it all. It&#8217;s a lot like the way a child runs &#8211; with complete abandon &#8211; because they don&#8217;t know to expect fatigue or pain yet. The moment is singular and completely in the present.</p>
<p>When we grow older, we collect the moments when our joy was abbreviated, either by the course of nature or by other people. We become cynical, hardened, expecting our happiness to be short lived or false. We are far likelier to experience contentment &#8211; joy&#8217;s smug, adult counterpart. Contentment is what we settle for when we are adults because joy is so fleeting and hard to attain intentionally. In this day and age childhood has been expanded far into the twenties, but I don&#8217;t think that childhood joy endures. It morphs into a strange hipster irony &#8211; almost a reflection of joy &#8211; that mocks its existence because it&#8217;s easier to be cool and impress people than to get to the unattainable joy.</p>
<p>There are moments in my adulthood when I have experienced joy like I used to as a child. It was not on the day my son was born. Watching him fly out of my body into the arms of my doctor while my husband held my left leg and stared in horror is not what I would describe as joyous. It was a wonderful moment in some ways, but there was too much fear and surprise involved to call it joy. I most often find joy in music&#8230;and I&#8217;m not talking Beethoven or a Puccini opera&#8230;although those would work. I find joy in just listening to all sorts of music and just being there, in the moment&#8230;or sometimes singing in the car while Graham bops around. It could be Katy Perry or Metallica, there&#8217;s just something about music that brings on a moment of joy for me.</p>
<p>Today marks the passing of a great musician, Ravi Shankar, who I became familiar with when I was 19 years old. My father was very sick from radiation treatment for his brain tumor and I had a job working in a factory soldering circuit boards. I was supposed to be a freshman at Providence College but had to stay back a semester because my father&#8217;s health was so precarious, as was our financial situation. I used to go to the public library after work and check out CDs from the basement music department. I had heard sitar and raag in the Beatles music I sometimes listened to so one day I checked out a Ravi Shankar CD. I brought it home and listened to it over and over. There was something very relaxing and quietly joyful in the strings, something I really, really needed during that difficult time.</p>
<p>My father&#8217;s tumor was in the occipital lobe of his brain and he had lost a great deal of his eye sight when they removed the tumor and could no longer read books &#8211; which was one of the ways I am convinced that my father found joy. I remember sitting in our small living room listening to my CD on a set of headphones when my father asked to hear what I was listening to. So I played him the Ravi Shankar music that I was so fond of. I like to think that that moment was one of joy for my father &#8211; just existing in the music the way he used to escape in his books. We played it many times after that and it became our habit to listen to music in the same way we used to share books. There was something about the sound of the sitar that healed both of our pain. It was like listening to audible peace. The memory brings me joy whenever I hear those strings.</p>
<p>R.I.P Ravi Shankar</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZYlPcbNAPH8?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/335/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/335/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=335&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oedaday.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/joy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/051217291538fa96ef67cd7955d44d8f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">akreed</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oedaday.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ravi-shankar-horizontal-gallery.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ravi-shankar-horizontal-gallery</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mitochondrial Disease</title>
		<link>http://blahger.net/2012/12/12/mitochondrial-disease/</link>
		<comments>http://blahger.net/2012/12/12/mitochondrial-disease/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 21:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kathleen McLaughlin-Hoppe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[chronically ill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death and dying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grown children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[large family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metabolic disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mitochondrial disease]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blahger.net/?p=652</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve known for quite a few years that I have a rare disease. Actually, as a kid, I had such strange ailments that my parents took me to Mayo Clinic, where I we were told it was Lupus. My sister still carries that as a diagnosis. Doctors said I would probably never have children. What [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=652&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://blahger.net/2012/12/12/mitochondrial-disease/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1559c998dfd98b78ac8cd67d5d89e695?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">akismet-1559c998dfd98b78ac8cd67d5d89e695</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theblahger.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/mitoperson.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mito person</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Calling All Elves: Get Off Pinterest and Gather ‘Round!</title>
		<link>http://greymatterlife.com/2012/12/12/calling-all-elves-get-off-pinterest-and-gather-round/</link>
		<comments>http://greymatterlife.com/2012/12/12/calling-all-elves-get-off-pinterest-and-gather-round/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 17:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jennifer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I Declare!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elf on the Shelf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspective]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://greymatterlife.com/?p=2979</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Billy here, Elf on the Shelf. I hijacked the hot mess’s computer because I just can’t take it anymore. So put your glue guns down, shut down your frantic Pinterest searching and gather round. I’m just going to come right out with it… What exactly are you all doing? Have you forgotten what we are? [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2979&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://greymatterlife.com/2012/12/12/calling-all-elves-get-off-pinterest-and-gather-round/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://greymatterlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/billy-1-of-1.jpg?w=93" />
		<media:content url="http://greymatterlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/billy-1-of-1.jpg?w=93" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Billy (1 of 1)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c05d48bd90c4c1ae881f96261cae9b20?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jkgiliberto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greymatterlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/billy-1-of-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Billy (1 of 1)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Dear Old Friend, Ebenezer Scrooge</title>
		<link>http://thewildwomanwithin.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/my-dear-old-friend-ebenezer-scrooge/</link>
		<comments>http://thewildwomanwithin.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/my-dear-old-friend-ebenezer-scrooge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 20:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>eM</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Connecting with Others]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A Christmas Carol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charles Dickens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ebenezer Scrooge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redemption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scrooge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirit of Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual transformation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thewildwomanwithin.wordpress.com/?p=3984</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I understand the deliverance of redemption, total transformation of the spirit—but my dear old friend, Ebenezer Scrooge, wasn&#8217;t such a bad chap before all that. To be sure, there were moments when the dark knight of his soul simply ran amok with him—but old Scrooge was a frugal, thinking, and sorely misunderstood man. Coal is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3984&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thewildwomanwithin.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/my-dear-old-friend-ebenezer-scrooge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ffb8c176f2e3b9beff041effa11b8aa7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thewildwomanwithin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thewildwomanwithin.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/scrooge.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Scrooge</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The Night Before [Physics] Finals&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://irreverentreview.com/2012/12/06/the-night-before-physics-finals/</link>
		<comments>http://irreverentreview.com/2012/12/06/the-night-before-physics-finals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 19:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jodi McMaster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Erwin Schrödinger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heisenberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quantum computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quantum mechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schrödinger's cat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncertainty principle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Werner Heisenberg]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://irreverentreview.com/?p=193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My brilliant daughter-in-law, Laura Keith McMaster, wrote this in the midst of her almost nonstop studying: The Night Before [Physics] Finals Twas the night before finals, when all through the house The computer was whirring, with the clicks of a mouse. The Eigen values were calculated and written with care, In hopes that my A+ [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>My brilliant daughter-in-law, Laura Keith McMaster, wrote this in the midst of her almost nonstop studying:</em></p>
<h3><em>The Night Before [<a class="zem_slink" title="Theoretical physics" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theoretical_physics" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Physics</a>] Finals</em></h3>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:QuantumHarmonicOscillatorAnimation.gif" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="A harmonic oscillator in classical mechanics (..." alt="A harmonic oscillator in classical mechanics (..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/90/QuantumHarmonicOscillatorAnimation.gif" height="373" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A harmonic oscillator in classical mechanics (A-B) and quantum mechanics (C-H). In (A-B), a ball, attached to a spring, oscillates back and forth. (C-H) are six solutions to the Schrödinger Equation for this situation. The horizontal axis is position, the vertical axis is the real part (blue) or imaginary part (red) of the wavefunction. (C,D,E,F), but not (G,H), are stationary states (energy eigenstates), which come from solutions to the Time-Independent Schrödinger Equation. (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p>Twas the night before finals, when all through the house<br />
The computer was whirring, with the clicks of a mouse.<br />
The Eigen values were calculated and written with care,<br />
In hopes that my A+ soon would be there.</p>
<p>The <a class="zem_slink" title="Schrödinger equation" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schr%C3%B6dinger_equation" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">TISE</a>&#8216;s were nestled, all snug in their function,<br />
Later the time dependent was added in junction.<br />
When writing operators, remember the hat,<br />
Or suffer the fate of <a class="zem_slink" title="Schrödinger's cat" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schr%C3%B6dinger%27s_cat" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Schrodinger&#8217;s cat</a>.</p>
<p>Uncertainty Principle, give <a class="zem_slink" title="Werner Heisenberg" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Werner_Heisenberg" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Heisenberg</a> his due,<br />
<a class="zem_slink" title="Inequality (mathematics)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inequality_%28mathematics%29" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Greater than or equal to</a>, <a class="zem_slink" title="Planck constant" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planck_constant" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">h bar</a> over two.<br />
A hard working student with an excellent teacher,<br />
Makes acing the PGRE an attractive feature.</p>
<p>Angular momentum equal r cross p,<br />
Without <a class="zem_slink" title="Spherical coordinate system" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spherical_coordinate_system" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">spherical coordinates</a>, an atrocity.<br />
Commutator [x, p] means x times p minus p times x,<br />
a canonical relations gives you h-bar complex.</p>
<p>Mechanics of quantum, and the vibrations,<br />
Give <a class="zem_slink" title="Quantum computer" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_computer" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Quantum Computing</a> and more applications.<br />
The giants before me gave quantum its birth,<br />
The proofs they came up with are of great worth.</p>
<p>I am amazed how the Schrodinger equations,<br />
come round and round with completing permutations.<br />
Fingers are numb and brain is so tired,<br />
Must keep going so Clark won&#8217;t get fired.</p>
<p>We love to learn the <a class="zem_slink" title="Quantum mechanics" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_mechanics" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">quantum theory</a>,<br />
But the convoluted algebra makes us all teary.<br />
DeBroglie says that lambda equals h over p,<br />
This elegant solution has filled me with glee.</p>
<p>Quantum proving mechanics gives me delight,<br />
I throw my hands up, exclaim &#8220;This is the life!&#8221;</p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.ns.umich.edu/new/releases/21012-a-bridge-to-the-quantum-world-dirac-electrons-found-in-unique-material" target="_blank">A bridge to the quantum world: Dirac electrons found in unique material</a> (ns.umich.edu)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.mnn.com/green-tech/research-innovations/stories/quantum-trick-allows-researchers-to-pet-schr%C3%B6dingers-cat-wit" target="_blank">Quantum trick allows researchers to &#8216;pet&#8217; Schrödinger&#8217;s cat without killing it</a> (mnn.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn22453-entangle-schrodingers-cat-to-up-its-quantum-weirdness.html?cmpid=RSS|NSNS|2012-GLOBAL|online-news" target="_blank">Entangle Schrödinger&#8217;s cat to up its quantum weirdness</a> (newscientist.com)</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/193/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/193/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://irreverentreview.com/2012/12/06/the-night-before-physics-finals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8ea9331f740ef7dc65a57f281a38a786?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crossfitfattie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/90/QuantumHarmonicOscillatorAnimation.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A harmonic oscillator in classical mechanics (...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will The Legitimate Syrian Government Please Stand Up?</title>
		<link>http://statelegitimacy.com/2012/12/12/will-the-legitimate-syrian-government-please-stand-up/</link>
		<comments>http://statelegitimacy.com/2012/12/12/will-the-legitimate-syrian-government-please-stand-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 13:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>anthonybehan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[constitution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rule of Law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://statelegitimacy.com/?p=173</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A draft declaration from talks in Marrakech on the situation in Syria from the Friends of Syria has recognised the opposition as &#8216;the legitimate representative of the Syrian people&#8217;.  Which is nice for them, I guess.  Not so nice, one would presume, for the president of Syria, Bashar Al-Assad and his friends.  Syria has generally [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_174" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 320px"><a href="http://statelegitimacy.com/2012/12/12/will-the-legitimate-syrian-government-please-stand-up/bashar-al-assad-310x233/" rel="attachment wp-att-174"><img class="size-full wp-image-174" alt="Bashar-al-Assad-310x233" src="http://statelegitimacy.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bashar-al-assad-310x233.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bashar Al-Assad: Time&#8217;s Up</p></div>
<p>A draft declaration from talks in Marrakech on the situation in Syria from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friends_of_Syria_Group" target="_blank">Friends of Syria</a> has <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/world-powers-recognize-syrias-opposition-coalition-draft-084140301.html" target="_blank">recognised</a> <em>the opposition</em> as &#8216;the legitimate representative of the Syrian people&#8217;.  Which is nice for them, I guess.  Not so nice, one would presume, for the president of Syria, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bashar_al-Assad" target="_blank">Bashar Al-Assad</a> and his friends.  Syria <a href="http://www.nationsencyclopedia.com/World-Leaders-2003/Syria-FOREIGN-POLICY.html#b" target="_blank">has generally been</a> on the wrong side of US foreign policy, and even when the US has needed its support, for example in the lead up to the Invasion of Iraq in 2003, the extent to which it was willing to court Syrian support was arms length and defensive.  President Obama&#8217;s <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/12/12/world/middleeast/united-states-involvement-in-syria.html?hp" target="_blank">declaration of support</a> for the opposition coalition yesterday was not unexpected, and is likely to hasten the demise of the ruling family in Syria, which has been in place for over forty years.</p>
<p><span id="more-173"></span>It&#8217;s a funny language that&#8217;s used, though.  In essence, this is more of a negative statement about the legitimate government (i.e. Assad) than it is a positive statement about the pretenders.  France has been <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/dec/07/france-funding-syrian-rebels" target="_blank">offering hard support</a> to those fighting the régime, while Russia may be creating the space necessary to stand down its support for Assad, not withstanding a <a href="http://www.voanews.com/content/russia-criticizes-us-for-recognizing-syrian-opposition/1563252.html" target="_blank">public persistent support</a>.  The Assad government is legitimate (or at least has been legitimate in the past) because of its erstwhile monopoly on the use of force, international recognition through institutions such as the United Nations and the Arab League, and bilateral acknowledgement even in the management of hostile relationships, such as that with the US.  Domestically, the Syrian government had been taking steps in recent times to accede to popular demands for increased democratisation in the aftermath of the Arab Spring.  The <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/81771718/Qordoba-Translation-of-the-Syrian-Constitution-Modifications-15-2-2012" target="_blank">new constitution</a> was passed in February this year, in a much criticised plebiscite, but it has not been able to take hold give the upheaval in the country &#8211; cynics would argue that it was never going to be anything more than a bauble to throw at the critics in any case.  China, people would argue, has <a href="http://english.people.com.cn/constitution/constitution.html" target="_blank">a constitution</a> with an exhaustive bill of rights, for all the good it does.</p>
<p>There is no doubt that should the opposition groups find some cohesion amongst the factions, tribes, and interests that drive them, and present some kind of unified front, then the pronouncement in Marrakech will afford them some prospect of power in post-Assad Syria.  There are almost certainly spooks and diplomats from the West scouring the ranks of the opposition for sound leaders, people with whom they can work, people who they can influence, and reason with.  There are efforts being made to cajole and coerce, to shape and to influence the machinations of the opposition, and to try and find some points of agreement, some common platform upon which a stable régime can be constructed.  <em>The West</em>, should such an infrastructure be forthcoming, will legitimise such a government once Assad has been deposed, and will bolster the position of the fledgling administration by ensuring financial and military support in order to suppress dissenting voices, in particular those of the old order.</p>
<p>That, in effect, delivers a legitimate government.  It is legitimate because it has control; it is legitimate because it is recognised; it is legitimate, because it is in the interests of those in the region, and those with interests in the region, to be legitimate.  As for the people of Syria themselves, the ruling elite will be protected by the process of legitimation.  They will bring with them the people who they represent, and apportion power and gold as appropriate to secure the bulk of support.  There remains a question beyond that, however.  Syria is a very large country, with over twenty million people in an area more than four times the size of Switzerland.  Bringing everyone along will be tough, and just as with the Ba&#8217;athists in post-Saddam Iraq, any small minority will in absolute terms remain potentially very large.  They will not be without support, especially if the new régime is seen as being a puppet of the US.</p>
<p>The question then remains whether the new government will be genuinely legitimate from the perspective of the people themselves.  The protection of fundamental human rights &#8211; and by that we&#8217;re talking very fundamental &#8211; security, access to food, shelter, water &#8211; will afford the government some cover.  Civil and political rights will be harder to guarantee, but in the absence of civil war, that is likely to be OK for a little while.  Regional and border relations will be important too &#8211; relations with Israel and Iran, two firebrands in the region, and with Egypt, will be telling.  The new government, legitimised by the international community, will need to build its legitimacy over time with the people.  And to torture some metaphors, it will take baby steps, while walking on eggshells.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://statelegitimacy.com/2012/12/12/will-the-legitimate-syrian-government-please-stand-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/843468c935f623cf9d75709342fb2e59?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anthonybehan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://statelegitimacy.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bashar-al-assad-310x233.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bashar-al-Assad-310x233</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
