<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>On Innocence Lost, From the Eyes of Gen X</title>
		<link>http://childhoodrelived.com/2012/12/22/innocence-lost-from-the-eyes-of-gen-x/</link>
		<comments>http://childhoodrelived.com/2012/12/22/innocence-lost-from-the-eyes-of-gen-x/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Angie Z.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1980s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challenger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generation X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innocence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newtown shootings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://childhoodrelived.com/?p=9978</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The smoke twisted and turned across the sky in a fluffy white cotton candy stream.  I didn’t know what it was supposed to look like – should it look like this?  I looked to my teacher’s eyes and I knew – something was wrong.  The Challenger was broken. But there I sat among the neat [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9978&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://childhoodrelived.com/2012/12/22/innocence-lost-from-the-eyes-of-gen-x/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/37e33c53f25a9de095ad19acb9e62896?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zangie1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://childhoodrelived.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/challenger_explosion.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Challenger_explosion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://childhoodrelived.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/challenger_crew.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Challenger_crew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://childhoodrelived.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/savannahsmiles1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eventually . . . Savannah smiles.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://childhoodrelived.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/milk_carton_kid.jpg?w=169" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">milk_carton_kid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://childhoodrelived.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/newtown_angels.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Newtown_angels</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Please Santa, Bring Dvorak to My iPad!</title>
		<link>http://rolandbenedetti.com/2012/12/24/please-santa-bring-dvorak-to-my-ipad/</link>
		<comments>http://rolandbenedetti.com/2012/12/24/please-santa-bring-dvorak-to-my-ipad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Roland</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rolandbenedetti.com/?p=313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Santa, I don&#8217;t ask for much geeky stuff, but one very good gift in that area would be a Dvorak keyboard for my iPad. And please don&#8217;t give me a side real hardware keyboard, I am talking of a touchscreen keyboard (the combo external keyboard + iPad looses the battle with my Mac Air&#8230;). [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Santa, I don&#8217;t ask for much geeky stuff, but one very good gift in that area would be a Dvorak keyboard for my iPad. And please don&#8217;t give me a side real hardware keyboard, I am talking of a touchscreen keyboard (the combo external keyboard + iPad looses the battle with my Mac Air&#8230;).</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/31512354@N00/730311163" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted" title="Dvorak Simplified Keyboard" alt="Dvorak Simplified Keyboard" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1074/730311163_2912a98110_m.jpg" width="240" height="80" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dvorak Simplified Keyboard (Photo credit: Gustavo da Cunha Pimenta)</p></div>
<p>I switched to the Dvorak keyboard map not so long ago, last July. Reason for that was not to be faster (like many others) even if this would be a nice side effect, but exploring solutions to solve the pain of a recurring carpal tunnel syndrome. My friend Paolo advised this, explaining it would make my finger, hand and wrist move way less, as a result, it should reduce the inflammation and then the pain. If you are interested in the Dvorak keyboard, jut read it on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Simplified_Keyboard">Wikipedia</a>, or from <a href="http://ma.tt/2003/08/on-the-dvorak-keyboard-layout/">Ma.tt</a> already almost 10 years ago!</p>
<p>For learning resources, you will find plenty around the web so I won&#8217;t say much here beside a short feedback if you are interested:</p>
<p>I am not yet 100% up to speed but really happy with that switch &#8211; I am still fighting a bit for all special characters and also for french accents&#8230; but I made progress in speed compared to my Qwerty typing. I am finally touch-typing and have my pain slightly diminished, which was the main goal. While not perfect yet, still very positive change!</p>
<p>I must say though that I can&#8217;t type for a too long time or pain still comes back but it is definitely an improvement compared to Qwerty. I also still have a hard time using it when not really in a &#8216;typing mode&#8217;, for instance when taking notes in meetings. And finally, I am just a bit annoyed by the blind or Dvorak stickers that I use on my keyboards as it is not the most comfortable solution. One day I will take the time to remove and switch keys.</p>
<p>Actually, now, the very main issue is coming from iOS. The Dvorak keyboard would be a perfect story for me if only I could use it not only on my computers but also on my iPhone and iPad but I can&#8217;t! It simply seems impossible to find a way to have a Dvorak map configured on the iOS system. Come on Apple, what the heck!? Can you believe that?</p>
<p>This is supposed to be so easy to support, certainly not more than a bunch of configuration files to change. Instead of that, we are in the paradoxical situation where we were able to find a solution for hardware keyboard and not for purely software ones&#8230;</p>
<p>And let me add that this is a typical example (among plenty of others) where I would love iOS to be more open if not open source. We are so far from it now with Apple. Openness would enable a bunch of happy few to make this thing happen quickly, without hurting Apple or asking their contribution, and pleasing many other users&#8230; but no! This has a taste of &#8220;innovation is over&#8221;&#8230; I will certainly keep a very interested eye on Android phones and tablets, and feel the change coming stronger and stronger.</p>
<p>And to conclude, I took 20 minutes to write this post because, even if just a drop in the ocean, I wanted to contribute to the Dvorak keyboard cause! It is super interesting and deserves more attention from device and system makers. It also needs to be known by more users. I believe that it is an interesting option with lots of potential for people like me. When I think about people writing, typing, translating, transcribing all day; I strongly feel Dvorak could be a much bigger change worth to consider.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rolandbenedetti.com/2012/12/24/please-santa-bring-dvorak-to-my-ipad/dvorak/" rel="attachment wp-att-324"><img alt="My Dvorak keyboard for learning" src="http://rolandbenedetti.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dvorak.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My Dvorak keyboard for learning</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;">And if you have a solution to my problem, please let me know!</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/313/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/313/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rolandbenedetti.com/2012/12/24/please-santa-bring-dvorak-to-my-ipad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>40.728925 -73.954635</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>40.728925</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-73.954635</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0900a5e690b81753c72ad44611eef505?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rolandbenedetti</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1074/730311163_2912a98110_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dvorak Simplified Keyboard</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rolandbenedetti.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dvorak.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My Dvorak keyboard for learning</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ooh Ooh That Smell &#8212; IBM&#8217;s 2012 &#8220;5 in 5&#8243;: Innovations Of The Senses</title>
		<link>http://turbotodd.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/ooh-ooh-that-smell-ibms-2012-5-in-5-innovations-of-the-senses/</link>
		<comments>http://turbotodd.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/ooh-ooh-that-smell-ibms-2012-5-in-5-innovations-of-the-senses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 19:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>turbotodd</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare transformation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibm research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibm software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cognitive computing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ibm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[r&d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://turbotodd.wordpress.com/?p=6878</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Turbo debriefs on IBM's 2012 "5 in 5," five projected innovations based on market and societal trends and emerging technologies that could dramatically change our world.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6878&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>IBM released its annual &#8220;5 in 5&#8243; list yesterday, the seventh year in a row whereby IBM scientists identify a list of innovations that have the potential to change the way people work, live and interact during the next five years.</p>
<p>The IBM 5 in 5 is based on market and societal trends, as well as emerging technologies from IBM&#8217;s R&amp;D labs around the world. This year, the 5 explores innovations that will be underpinnings of the next era of computing, what IBM has described as &#8220;the era of cognitive systems.&#8221;</p>
<p>This next generation of machines will learn, adapt, sense, and begin to experience the world as it really is, and this year&#8217;s predictions focus on one element of the this new era: The ability of computers to mimic the human senses &#8212; in their own manner, to see, smell, touch, taste and hear.</p>
<p>But before you try and spoon-feed your iPad some vanilla yogurt, let&#8217;s get more practical.</p>
<p>These new sensing capabilities will help us become more aware, productive, and help us think &#8212; but not do our thinking for us.</p>
<p>Rather, cognitive systems will help us see through and navigate complexity, keep up with the speed of information, make more informed decisions, improve our health and standard of living, and break down all kinds of barriers &#8212; geographical, language, cost, even accessibility.</p>
<p>Now, on to our five senses.</p>
<p><strong>1) Touch: You will be able to touch through your phone.</strong>  Imagine using your smartphone to shop for your wedding dress and being able to feel the satin or silk of the gown, or the lace on the veil, from the surface on the screen. Or to feel the beading and weave of a blanket made by a local artisan half way around the world. In five years, industries like retail will be transformed by the ability to &#8220;touch&#8221; a product through your mobile device.</p>
<p>IBM scientists are developing applications for the retail,<strong> </strong>healthcare and other sectors using haptic, infrared and pressure sensitive technologies to simulate touch, such as the texture and weave of a fabric &#8212; as a shopper brushes her finger over the image of the item on a device screen. Utilizing the vibration capabilities of the phone, every object will have a unique set of vibration patterns that represents the touch experience: short fast patterns, or longer and stronger strings of vibrations. The vibration pattern will differentiate silk from linen or cotton, helping simulate the physical sensation of actually touching the material.</p>
<p><strong>2) Sight: A pixel will be worth a thousand words.</strong> We take some 500 billion photos a year, and 72 hours of video is uploaded to YouTube every minute. But computers today only understand pictures by the text we use to tag or title them; the majority of the information &#8212; the actual content of the image &#8212; is a mystery.</p>
<p>In the next five years, systems will not only be able to look at and recognize the contents of images and visual data, they will turn the pixels into meaning, making sense out of it similar to the way a human views and interprets a photographs. In the future, &#8220;brain-like&#8221; capabilities will let computers analyze features such as color, texture patterns or edge information and extract insights from visual media, having a potentially huge impact on industries ranging from healthcare to retail to agriculture.</p>
<p>But please, no Escher drawings, at least for now&#8230;that&#8217;s just plain mean.</p>
<p><strong>3) Hearing: Computers will hear what matters. </strong> Ever wish you could make sense of all the sounds around you and be able to understand what&#8217;s not being said? Within five years, distributed systems of clever sensors will detect elements of sound such as sound pressure, vibrations and sound waves at different frequencies.</p>
<p>It will interpret these inputs to predict when trees will fall in a forest or when a landslide is imminent. Such a system will &#8220;listen&#8221; to our surroundings and measure movements, or the stress in a material, to warn us if danger lies ahead.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m ever hopeful such systems will be able to &#8220;listen&#8221; to my golf swing and help me course correct so I can play more target golf!</p>
<p><strong>4) Taste: Digital taste buds will help you to eat smarter.</strong> What if we could make healthy foods taste delicious using a different kind of computing system built for creativity? IBM researchers are developing a computing system that actually experiences flavor, to be used with chefs to create the most tasty and novel recipes. It will break down ingredients to their molecular level and blend the chemistry of food compounds with the psychology behind what flavors and smells humans prefer.</p>
<p>By comparing this with millions of recipes, the system will be able to create new flavor combinations that pair, for example, roasted chestnuts with other foods such as cooked beetroot, fresh caviar, and dry-cured ham.</p>
<p>&#8220;Top Tasting Computer Chefs,&#8221; anyone?</p>
<p><strong>5) Smell: Computers will have a sense of smell.</strong> During the next five years, tiny sensors embedded in your computer or cell phone will detect if you&#8217;re coming down with a cold or other illness. By analyzing odors, biomarkers and thousands of molecules in someone&#8217;s breath, doctors will have help diagnosing and monitoring the onset of ailments such as liver and kidney disorders, asthma, diabetes, and epilepsy by detecting which odors are normal and which are not.</p>
<p>Already, IBM scientists are sensing environment conditions to preserve works of art, and this innovation is starting to be applied to tackle clinical hygiene, one of the biggest healthcare challenges today. In the next five years, IBM technology will &#8220;smell&#8221; surfaces for disinfectants to determine whether rooms have been sanitized. Using novel wireless mesh networks, data on various chemicals will be gathered and measured by sensors, and continuously learn and adapt to new smells over time.</p>
<p>Watch the video below to listen to IBM scientists describe some of these new innovations and their potential impact on our world.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='560' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/wXkfrBJqVcQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6878/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6878&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://turbotodd.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/ooh-ooh-that-smell-ibms-2012-5-in-5-innovations-of-the-senses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7e2b7ae53dda834b23b1583307f73bc4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Turbo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unrequited Love</title>
		<link>http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/unrequited-love/</link>
		<comments>http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/unrequited-love/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 17:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kbwriting</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[(c)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/?p=173</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The only unfulfilled love I&#8217;m willing to talk about openly is writing. And the realization that the love affair will never be reciprocated hurts just as much as that first time someone came out and said, &#8220;I like you. I just don&#8217;t like-like you.&#8221; Writing will never like-like me. I&#8217;m too old, and it&#8217;s not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The only unfulfilled love I&#8217;m willing to talk about openly is writing. And the realization that the love affair will never be reciprocated hurts just as much as that first time someone came out and said, &#8220;I like you. I just don&#8217;t like-like you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Writing will never like-like me. I&#8217;m too old, and it&#8217;s not that I&#8217;m too old as much as born at the wrong time – the non-generation. I&#8217;m not a baby boomer. I&#8217;m not a Me. I&#8217;m too old to be a Gen-Xer. Or Y and Z for that matter. I missed the computer age – I didn&#8217;t even have a computer until I got married and I was forty-one before I actually owned my own – a laptop, which took me a year to finally use with any kind of regularity. My kids know the VCR as the machine next to the TV that has never worked.</p>
<p>I read Julie Andrews autobiography recently. She grew up in the fifties, and I was sad to discover that her voice is my voice. That&#8217;s how I write. Very formally, describing how the leaves rest on the rooftop, narrative on top of narrative with very little emotion unless it&#8217;s purple prose. I write like someone who grew up in the fifties, only I have no story to tell. My parents weren&#8217;t alcoholics, I did not overcome drug abuse, I wasn&#8217;t abused or molested. My parents sent me to college. I lived at home until I got married.</p>
<p>This non-generation of girls was expected to grow up, be prim and proper, but still know everything, go to school, college and be anything you wanted, anything boys could be even President of the United States. At least until you got married and had kids and in that order. And when the kids were in high school you could go back to work because women were independent now.</p>
<p>You can&#8217;t be a writer. A writer is impractical. And they drink. They don&#8217;t have two nickels to rub together either.</p>
<p>Get a degree and then you can write.</p>
<p>Get married. You can write later.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re still young. You can&#8217;t wait to have kids. Writing will always be there.</p>
<p>Well, guess what?</p>
<p>Writing didn&#8217;t wait for me. Writing found someone else. Writing computerized. Modernized. Writing grew up, and changed with the times where it needed to. More do it yourself. More travel. More health care and fitness. New writers came along. Younger and prettier and having seen people like me get left behind knew just what to do to keep up.</p>
<p>Writing won&#8217;t ever come back for me, and I just can&#8217;t catch up. My writing is tired and old; timid. Like me.</p>
<p>My best friend, like any good friend, pushes me towards the love that got away, prods, challenges, shames, but he can only push so far. I keep my hand on the ledge. I don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s down there. I lean over, but I can&#8217;t see very far, and what I can see is dizzying.</p>
<p>What if I fall?</p>
<p>What if I catch up to writing and I&#8217;m just not good enough? Staying back and wondering is better than being rejected again, isn&#8217;t it?</p>
<p>Isn&#8217;t it?</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/c/'>(c)</a>, <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/2012/'>2012</a>, <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/essay/'>essay</a>, <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/love/'>love</a>, <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/memoir/'>memoir</a>, <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/workshop/'>workshop</a>, <a href='http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/tag/writing-2/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/173/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://griffinsandgingersnaps.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/unrequited-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/24b12436aa02204ae24aa13662c35256?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kbwriting</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;I wouldn&#8217;t say that!&#8221; He replied hotly.</title>
		<link>http://bentrubewriter.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/i-wouldnt-say-that-he-replied-hotly/</link>
		<comments>http://bentrubewriter.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/i-wouldnt-say-that-he-replied-hotly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 11:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ben Trube</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bentrubewriter.wordpress.com/?p=912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m reading a bad book right now. Maybe it&#8217;s the fact that I&#8217;m in revision mode, or maybe it&#8217;s because I enjoyed this book as a kid and don&#8217;t find it living up to my expectations. The book is Vendetta by Peter David (yes ST:TNG for those of you clicking along at home). Normally I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=912&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m reading a bad book right now.</p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s the fact that I&#8217;m in revision mode, or maybe it&#8217;s because I enjoyed this book as a kid and don&#8217;t find it living up to my expectations. The book is <a title="Vendetta (Memory Alpha)" href="http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Vendetta" target="_blank">Vendetta</a> by Peter David (yes ST:TNG for those of you clicking along at home). Normally I find David&#8217;s writing to be spot on and funny, but this one&#8230;</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s where it started:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;You&#8217;re not the one who was ankle-deep in blood,&#8221; said Crusher.</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I sure was!&#8221; said Geordi hotly.</em></p>
<p>*sigh*</p>
<p>Yes, the writing&#8217;s bad but that&#8217;s not what&#8217;s bothering me. What&#8217;s bothering me is that this isn&#8217;t how these characters would act.  Guinan wouldn&#8217;t say sir to Picard, Picard wouldn&#8217;t reveal his frustrations openly, and Geordi (hot-head that he is) would have a better comeback than &#8220;I sure was!&#8221; Sounds almost cheerful doesn&#8217;t it?</p>
<p>This got me to thinking about my characters, are they full enough that something could seem OUT of character, or even IN character.  How do I give my characters a distinct personality, one that can have variation certainly, growth most definitely, but never have a moment like this one that jars you out of your suspension of reality and makes you think about checking your e-mail.</p>
<p><strong>1) Understand your character&#8217;s relationships to other characters: </strong>Your character has friends, enemies, family members, co-workers, and everything in between. Each relationship has a slightly different dynamic, but all stemming from the base of your character&#8217;s personality. It may be that your character doesn&#8217;t like to make enemies and so tries to be his gregarious self around someone who doesn&#8217;t like him, but awkwardly. Some relationships with co-workers are strictly professional, whereas others are more casual. One might think of this as a spectrum of intimacy, or the amount a character can be their &#8220;real&#8221; self around another character. What&#8217;s important is that this remain consistent. A superior is always, sir, until a situation arises to naturally make the relationship more casual.</p>
<p><strong>2) Characters will change with experience:</strong> But these should be experiences we see. If your main character is a gregarious and funny person and becomes somber and reflective, you had better show us why. Change is good, it enriches our understanding of the person we&#8217;re trying to bring to life, but that change needs to happen on the page. If a cop changes after he loses his partner, a partner who was alive and drinking in the previous book, then he&#8217;d better kick the bucket somewhere on the page. Otherwise we&#8217;re being left out of the important experiences of our character&#8217;s life, and that changes the reader&#8217;s level of intimacy.</p>
<p><strong>3) Know more about your character than your readers do:</strong> Your character&#8217;s favorite color may not come up on the first page. The kind of whiskey they like, their hobbies, a good story reveals these details gradually. If the leg work&#8217;s been done up front to establish this character, then when a new detail is revealed it is shown to be a part of the whole, even when it seems inconsistent. One of my favorite examples of this is Ron Swanson from Parks &amp; Rec. He&#8217;s a gruff libertarian man, who likes to play as Duke Silver, a saxophone playing jazz lethario. He remains consistent in that he keeps this part of himself separate from most of the people in his life, and it provides color to his outward gruffness to see such a suave and fun loving side.</p>
<p><strong>4) A measured response is often better than a freak out:</strong> Geordi freaks out all over the place in this book, with little provocation. It&#8217;s overly dramatic, even if the reasons for it are sometimes understandable. It&#8217;s like in singing, the louder moments are made all the better by the quiet ones around them. Frustration is best kept on a low boil that is then allowed to burst rather than constantly bubbling over. I&#8217;m not saying there aren&#8217;t people who react to crisis this way, and it may be that you want to portray a certain level of immaturity in your character, but make sure that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re going for. This could also probably be distilled down to eliminating all or most of the &#8220;[character] said [blank]-ly&#8221; tags from sentences.</p>
<p><strong>5) It takes time to build a relationship:</strong> No character is fully formed in the first sentence they utter. There definitely is room to change the direction of a character, or flesh them out in later chapters, or even in later books. A certain about of leeway can be afforded so you don&#8217;t have to feel locked in. Just make sure that new details aren&#8217;t too drastically different from established norms, unless they&#8217;re a contrast like our good friend Ron.</p>
<p><strong>6) Your moral compass:</strong> Briefly it&#8217;s also a good idea to know what your character&#8217;s values are, would they never kill, do they oppose mastication, that sort of thing. Again, morality can change over time, but rarely all at once.</p>
<p>What makes your characters distinct? What would be out of character?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/912/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/912/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=912&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bentrubewriter.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/i-wouldnt-say-that-he-replied-hotly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/107d0368f079bbfcee2188ca6199b97f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thefractalman</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Drink Beer, Dammit</title>
		<link>http://beerbecue.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/i-drink-beer-dammit/</link>
		<comments>http://beerbecue.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/i-drink-beer-dammit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 10:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>beerbecue</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big beer boogeyman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big beer vs craft beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craft beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craft vs crafty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[i drink beer dammit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Curmudgeon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what is craft beer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://beerbecue.wordpress.com/?p=3584</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think I&#8217;m late to the recent craft beer hullaballoo that followed the Brewer&#8217;s Association&#8217;s bitchy, little missive about the Big Beer Boogeyman trying to swoop on craft beer&#8217;s game with brews like Blue Moon and Shock Top. There has been enough whining, though. So, this might not be popular, but the Curmudgeon must speak. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3584&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think I&#8217;m late to the recent craft beer <a style="font-size:15.199999809265px;font-style:normal;line-height:19.200000762939px;" href="http://www.denverpost.com/business/ci_22189184/craft-vs-crafty-big-and-small-breweries-square" target="_blank">hullaballoo</a> that followed the Brewer&#8217;s Association&#8217;s <a style="font-size:15.199999809265px;font-style:normal;line-height:19.200000762939px;" href="http://www.brewersassociation.org/pages/media/press-releases/show?title=craft-vs-crafty-a-statement-from-the-brewers-association" target="_blank">bitchy, little missive</a> about the Big Beer Boogeyman trying to swoop on craft beer&#8217;s game with brews like Blue Moon and Shock Top. There has been enough whining, though. So, this might not be popular, but the Curmudgeon must speak.</p>
<p>I drink beer. Period. And I&#8217;ve said it before: So as long as your beer is tasty, I’ll drink it&#8230;well, as long as it wasn’t made from orphan tears, or something messed-up like that. But I&#8217;m willing to make an exception if the orphans were already crying anyway.</p>
<div id="attachment_3597" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 261px"><a href="http://beerbecue.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/orphan.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image-3597" alt="orphan" src="http://beerbecue.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/orphan.jpeg?w=251&#038;h=201" width="251" height="201" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Except for her. Keep this orphan&#8217;s tears the F away from my beer.</p></div>
<p>For me, it started on December 12th, when SABMiller executive chairman Graham Mackay asserted that the basis for craft beer success is the desire for more variation and interest and &#8220;it&#8217;s also local, anti-marketing, anti-global, anti-big, and more focused on experience and knowing that about where beer is from.&#8221; This elicited immediate mockery from the Big Beer haters about how Big Beer just doesn&#8217;t get it, and how it&#8217;s about quality and taste.</p>
<p>Then, the next day, the Brewer&#8217;s Association fired-off a press release reiterating their standard for what constitutes craft beer, lamenting Big Beer&#8217;s sinister foray into the craft beer market, and claiming that Big Beer should be required to clearly label their masquerading beers as being made by the Big Beer Boogeyman (and, thus, not true &#8220;craft beers&#8221;). Hmmm. So, apparently it&#8217;s not all about taste. Otherwise, why does this matter?</p>
<p>Now, <a href="http://thisiswhyimdrunk.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/9-beers-americans-no-longer-drink-and-why-big-beer-doesnt-get-it-part-1-5/" target="_blank">thisiswhyimdrunk</a> makes a compelling case for the distinction between the Brewer&#8217;s Association lamentations and Graham Mackay&#8217;s claims of anti-big sentiment. However, it&#8217;s hard to deny the general contempt for Big Beer that courses through the veins of the majority of beer nerds. The accusations run the gamut: Their beers all taste like crap (not true); they are unrelenting and sometime nefarious in their efforts to gain market share (probably true); they like to eat kittens (totally true).</p>
<div id="attachment_3598" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://beerbecue.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/whiplash.png"><img class=" wp-image-3598" alt="whiplash" src="http://beerbecue.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/whiplash.png?w=240&#038;h=328" width="240" height="328" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Graham Mackay thinking about kitten recipes.</p></div>
<p>But we operate in a capitalist system. Making money and gaining market share is what you&#8217;re supposed to do. It&#8217;s what makes the system function well, subject to smart regulation and enforcement, of course.</p>
<p>In fact, the capitalist system is like a zoo with lions, tigers, polar bears, and cute little animals like koalas and penguins. When a polar bear escapes and fulfills his lifelong fantasy of eating a penguin, or when the lions and tigers get out and eat the koalas and some zoo patrons, do you blame the lions and tigers and bears? No. Sure you might think the carnivores are dicks for eating cute animals and people, but that&#8217;s what they do (and partly what makes a zoo cool). You should be blaming the f-ing zookeepers.</p>
<p>And what do you think the purpose of the Brewer&#8217;s Association cockamamie definition of craft is (which actually seems simultaneously over-inclusive (Sam Adams Light) and under-inclusive (August Schell Brewing))? It&#8217;s about inventing a term to solidify a market niche and to gain and protect market share to the exclusion of others. Gasp!</p>
<p>And the label idea is silly. It&#8217;s not even worthy of the zoo&#8217;s suggestion box. These offending Big Beer brews are a completely different product line from their other beers and are geared to an entirely different market. Of course they&#8217;re going to label and market them differently. Are you mad that a Lexus doesn&#8217;t come with &#8220;TOYOTA&#8221; emblazoned across the back? The few people who actually care about this will know or easily find out.</p>
<p>It all boils down to this: I&#8217;ve had some good brews made by Big Beer and many terrible beers from so-called craft breweries. To me, it&#8217;s all about gettin&#8217; the yummy in my tummy and what&#8217;s best and available at the time, not about what constitutes craft beer or who gets to call it that. So, maybe the Big Beer Boogeyman realized that he needs to get in on selling tasty beer. Wah. Deal with it. Just drink beer.</p>
<p><strong>Update: </strong>Go read John Cochran&#8217;s thoughts (From Terrapin Beer) <a href="http://johnatterrapin.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/craft-vs-crafty/" target="_blank">here</a>. He masterfully drives home the point: This is all so silly. He also lists some of the goofier results from the Brewer&#8217;s Association line-in-the-sand.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3584/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3584/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3584&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://beerbecue.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/i-drink-beer-dammit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1147c0d1c36de1a3c36d58b48fcc13d2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wingnutp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://beerbecue.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/orphan.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">orphan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://beerbecue.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/whiplash.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whiplash</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shedding Skin</title>
		<link>http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/shedding-skin/</link>
		<comments>http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/shedding-skin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>glassrabbitbone</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anorexia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bulimia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cutting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-harm]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/?p=8</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s hard to believe, in the state I am now, that there was ever a time when I was happy with myself. You see, I&#8217;ve never been thin—I&#8217;ve always, always been the fat girl, and though no one ever said anything, I could tell.  I could tell when all my friends went clothes shopping without me, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s hard to believe, in the state I am now, that there was ever a time when I was happy with myself.</p>
<p>You see, I&#8217;ve never been thin—I&#8217;ve always, <em>always</em> been the fat girl, and though no one ever <em>said</em> anything, I could tell.  I could tell when all my friends went clothes shopping without me, when no one asked me to homecoming, when my horse riding instructor praised the other girls and told me to work harder.  Logic, of course, tells me: it was because I was fat.  I lived with seething hatred of this body for years, but only recently did this hatred manifest itself.</p>
<p>At 175 pounds and 5&#8217;5&#8221;, I was, less than a year ago, just beginning to fall into the pit.  One night I dragged a shaving razor across my thigh and watched as the bad feelings poured out.  I put a bandage on it and swore to never touch a blade again.  But the next night I did it again and soon there was an arsenal in my bedside drawer and red zebra stripes covering my hips and wrists.</p>
<p>It was around this time, too, that I decided I needed to rid myself of my second skin.  I was huge, fatter than fat, disgusting, a whale.  At first I tried something called intermittent fasting, which involved fasting for 24 hours at least 2 times a week.  The other days I was allowed to eat normally.  The idea was that it would cut calories effortlessly, while the pattern of fasting would rev up my metabolism.</p>
<p>While intermittent fasting is a legitimate method for losing weight, I couldn&#8217;t imagine that my parents would approve of me refusing food 2-3 days out of the week.  Thus to complete my fasts, I began coming up with all manner of crazy ways to hide that I was not eating.  I woke up early to avoid my parents&#8217; prying eyes as I had my breakfast of green tea.  When they got suspicious, I crumbled bits of toast onto a plate and left it out on the counter before hiding the uneaten evidence in the trash.  I made excuses to my friends at lunch time and hoarded sandwiches in my room until I could eat them again, though soon I began throwing out the whole brown bag.  Later on, I mastered the art of spitting my food into a napkin, and once chewed and spit two whole slices of toast, unnoticed and without swallowing a bite, right in front of my father.</p>
<p>As the pounds began to drop off, I became more obsessed, restricting even on my non-fasting days.  By spring I was eating 300-600 calories a day and beating my ass on the treadmill to make up for mistakes.  At 150 pounds, people began to notice.  &#8221;Oh, you look like you&#8217;ve lost weight!&#8221; they&#8217;d say happily, never suspecting something could be wrong.  My friends all paid more attention to me.  When I asked a boy to prom, he happily accepted.  And my riding instructor couldn&#8217;t stop telling me how much better I looked (skinnier girls look more elegant on horses).  I got nothing but positive feedback and I was over the moon.  After all, for someone as fat as I was, losing weight could only be a good thing.  But I still wasn&#8217;t skinny enough. No, not even close.</p>
<p>By summer I was falling victim to binges, and my self-hatred grew even more vehement.  As much as I jammed my fingers down my throat, I could not bring my mistakes back up.  After nearly slitting my throat one night, I finally told my mother that her daughter sliced up her skin.  I didn&#8217;t tell her that I wanted to die, nor that my nightmares consisted of fat-laden food that I could not stop eating.  No, I told her about the cutting, and she was kind and supportive and everything a mother should be.  And so I stopped cutting.  I found peace and I stopped starving.  With the pressure of senior year gone, something shifted and I was, for that blessed three-month period, happy.  At least I think I was.</p>
<p>And here I am now, in college—an art major, no less—with dreams of becoming a medical illustrator.  After moving into the dorms, it didn&#8217;t take long for the blades to make their way back into my drawer.  My weight has settled at 145; though this is the lowest I&#8217;ve ever been and is considered a &#8220;healthy weight,&#8221; I cannot be satisfied with it.  With every bite I put in my mouth, I can feel myself losing control.  There is too much here for me to handle, and I need the comfort of starvation again.  It&#8217;s disgusting, I know, and it&#8217;s wrong and no one—none of you—should ever think this way, but I&#8217;ve been eating less and less these past few weeks and making excuses again and I can feel the cold fingers of these thoughts wrap themselves around me, pulling me back into the arms of hunger.</p>
<p>This goes beyond wanting to be skinny.  I have pegged food as the enemy, you see, and I am finding that I can only feel sane when I do not eat.  I am strong when I starve.  I am powerful, I am in control.  I can feel yesterday&#8217;s mistakes and poisons clearing out of this disgusting body and soon, soon I will be clean and pure.</p>
<p>Call me insane.  But I <em>will</em> be thin.  I&#8217;ll be thin if it&#8217;s the last thing I do.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/shedding-skin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>93</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/270b5c8d554c544118d82ca5d5c365a8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">glassrabbitbone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>But He Can Always Speak</title>
		<link>http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/but-he-can-always-speak/</link>
		<comments>http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/but-he-can-always-speak/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 18:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Soul Walker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bottom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rising.]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/?p=1336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From here on the floor with the grains of the wood and the stains of blood and whiskey from here is where I rise. Splinters in the wood and scratches all around become the grain of life and so we find a path and pattern in the most unlikeliest of places&#8211; on this floor. There [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1336&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From here<br />
on the floor<br />
with the grains of the wood<br />
and the stains of blood<br />
and whiskey<br />
from here is where I rise.</p>
<p>Splinters in the wood<br />
and scratches all around<br />
become the grain of life<br />
and so we find a path<br />
and pattern<br />
in the most unlikeliest of places&#8211;<br />
on this floor.</p>
<p>There are lines that speak of order<br />
even down so low as this<br />
and it is God&#8217;s sweet grace<br />
to open our eyes that we might see<br />
the lines beneath the whiskey<br />
and dirt<br />
and blood.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1336/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1336&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/but-he-can-always-speak/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>100</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/baf4ad28fa0be9fc37a0b17a824da698?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">asoulwalker</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corruption! It&#8217;s How We Roll!</title>
		<link>http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/corruption-its-how-we-roll/</link>
		<comments>http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/corruption-its-how-we-roll/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 13:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>docreedy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIRoA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government effectiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/?p=251</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, yes, we get the idea that Afghanistan is kind of a corrupt place. But really, with the lawlessness and the massive rift between the political elite and everyone else, what else would we expect? I was part of a meeting that took place in a small village in Paktiya Province. It had been pre-arranged, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=251&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, yes, we get the idea that Afghanistan is kind of a corrupt place. But really, with the lawlessness and the massive rift between the political elite and everyone else, what else would we expect?</p>
<p>I was part of a meeting that took place in a small village in Paktiya Province. It had been pre-arranged, so all of the village elders came out in force, as did every other male in the village, from age 5 to 85. The village was at the top of a small hill that had a cliff that overlooked the nearby river valley. In fact, it may have looked an awful lot like the village in the banner picture of this blog. As we walked up the goat-trails (easier said than done while in full body armor), the men laid out a giant cloth on the ground and a bunch of padded cushions that were upholstered in red fabric that read, “Japan!”</p>
<p>After the official meeting, we broke into small groups to just chat. I started talking with a man in his early 30s who complained bitterly of politicians doing nothing but hoarding all sorts of money for themselves, playing favorites with projects, and giving public jobs to their family members. Since there was an election coming up, I asked him why he didn’t run for office and try to change things.</p>
<p>He gave me a grin that was somehow proud and sheepish at the same time.</p>
<p>“Because I’d be even worse.”</p>
<p>I had to laugh and he laughed along with me.</p>
<p>Corruption not only happens, it’s expected. But why? Because power corrupts?</p>
<p>Well, partially. People are people, after all, whatever culture we may have been raised in. But there are some particularities of Afghanistan that make what we would call corruption a good idea.</p>
<p>First is the expectation of violence. When you’ve lived through 30 years of war and then combine that with a couple thousand years’ worth of empires marauding through your territory, stability is not exactly the status quo. You expect chaos. You develop a mentality of preparing for it. So to protect yourself and your family, you gather all the resources you can and hold onto them (not unlike zombie apocalypse preparedness). In other words, you become a hoarder par excellence.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=253" rel="attachment wp-att-253"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-253" title="Courtesy of A&amp;E's Show" alt="" src="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/hoarders.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>And if you happen to get into a lucrative position, you take advantage of that and get as much as you can, be it a well in your backyard built by the Americans or a new road to your village or a whole bunch of jobs for your family so you can collectively stockpile as much money as humanly possible before this government goes the way of all the ones before it.</p>
<p>There’s another element to this, though too. Across the Middle East and Central Asia, honor and shame play a major part in society. Sure, honor is important to us all, but in these areas, honor is much more tied up in the family than it is in the US or Europe.  If my brother or cousin or third cousin twice removed does something dishonorable, it doesn’t really reflect on me, but if I live in Afghanistan, my cousin’s shame is my shame. And shame isn’t just about being looked down on, but think Scarlet Letter levels of excommunication. If I am shamed, basic things like getting married, getting a job, etc. are jeopardized.</p>
<p>So to avoid situations like that, you work really hard to earn honor and prestige. Across the Mid East/Asia region there are various formal and informal honor codes that create systems for people to earn honor. Many are pretty similar across countries. Hospitality is a big element of them (to refuse it is to <em><strong>seriously</strong></em> insult your host). Another is protecting guests in your home as fiercely as if they were your family. A third is providing sanctuary, even to your worst enemy.</p>
<p>And charity is a big one (it&#8217;s actually a requirement in Islam). Charity is especially important if you are a powerful or wealthy person. If you have money (or tons of cropland or goats or whatever), you earn immense honor by sharing your wealth, most particularly with your extended family. It earns you loyalty, respect, prestige. It can make you into a Big Man/tribal leader/warlord/sheikh/chieftain/etc. It&#8217;s a pretty common pattern around the world. A leader is someone who shares his wealth.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=254" rel="attachment wp-att-254"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-254" title="&quot;I'd be worse&quot; Village" alt="" src="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/corruption-village.jpg?w=529&#038;h=396" width="529" height="396" /></a></p>
<p>It’s not so different in our culture, really. Every time I go to visit the undisputed matriarch of my family (my little Italian grandmother), she presses $20 into my hand. She has done so since before I can remember and it doesn’t matter that I’m now over 30 with an income that’s probably three times her retirement pay. I wouldn’t dream of refusing it. It’s what she does, a point of pride and, yes, honor. (Besides, if there’s any doubt as to where I get my stubbornness, let me assure you, it’s that side of the family.)</p>
<p>Where it becomes problematic in Afghanistan is when people who live by that ideal get into political power. Taking care of their extended family via what we would call favoritism and nepotism is, in their eyes, the right thing to do. You take care of your own. Period. It just happens that when you do that with public funds and positions, people tend to get a little persnickety about it. While admitting that they would do the exact same thing.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, by no means does everyone do this. There are a <i>lot</i> of Afghans who believe the political system should be free of this kind of thing. They don’t play favorites, they don’t succumb to nepotism, they push hard for anti-corruption investigations and convictions. There just also happen to be a lot of people who have decided to do the best they can for themselves. And for those guys, when they help their people out, they consider it to be the smart, honorable, expected thing to do.</p>
<p>It only becomes “corruption” when you’re the one not getting a cut.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/251/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/251/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=251&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/corruption-its-how-we-roll/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>101</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/60a37fb41070185f13c1abcb21564742?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">docreedy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/hoarders.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Courtesy of A&#38;E&#039;s Show</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/corruption-village.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;I&#039;d be worse&#34; Village</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Don&#8217;t Have to Leave, But You Can&#8217;t Stay Here</title>
		<link>http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/you-dont-have-to-leave-but-you-cant-stay-here/</link>
		<comments>http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/you-dont-have-to-leave-but-you-cant-stay-here/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 15:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Wegner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college choice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/?p=323</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blogging, I told someone the other day, is a bit like controlled free-writing for me. In theory, there is a focus to each day&#8217;s post but I&#8217;m not holding myself to the same rigorous standard I might apply to academic writing. This approach lends itself to a wide-variety of posts&#8211;no one will ever accuse me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=323&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blogging, I told someone the other day, is a bit like controlled free-writing for me. In theory, there is a focus to each day&#8217;s post but I&#8217;m not holding myself to the same rigorous standard I might apply to academic writing. This approach lends itself to a wide-variety of posts&#8211;no one will ever accuse me of being an &#8220;educational&#8221; or &#8220;political&#8221; blog partly because each day&#8217;s post depends, in many respects, on what I read in the paper.</p>
<p>But today, I want to revisit yesterday&#8217;s post because I fear I might have sounded a little less than enthused about the place I work. Let me say categorically that ASU is a great university. I have colleagues who are some of the best teachers in the business. One of the most frustrating things for me to read are blanket attacks on college professors. My colleagues here, unlike faculty at large research universities, teach a full load, research in moderation, and serve both the campus and the community.</p>
<p>Put simply&#8211;they are some of the finest educators I know, dedicated to helping our students achieve success. We have undergraduate programs that are some of the finest in the nation. Our Physics, Biology, Chemistry, and Geo sciences students regularly participate in undergraduate research, get accepted to medical schools and graduate schools. I&#8217;m partial to our English department and the employability. Our students go to graduate school, teach, and, at times, become officers in the military. Our kids graduate, get jobs, and have some of the lowest student loan debt in the nation. I could go on and on.</p>
<p>But, as I noted yesterday, I still don&#8217;t want my son to go here.</p>
<p>When my wife and I had our first son, I told her my parenting model was Homer Simpson and that the key to great parenting was keeping our expectations low. Remember, I told her, the mind is powerful and we should encourage our kids to repress as many memories as possible.</p>
<p>Of course, the real goal of parenting is to create human beings who are better than you. We do that by giving them appropriate opportunities and steering them into making good choices. Sometimes we have to be surreptitious. And many times we have to let them fail. But most importantly, we have to let them be uncomfortable.</p>
<p>When my son goes off to college, I want him to live someplace where being the tall white kid isn&#8217;t the norm. I want him to live someplace where he doesn&#8217;t know anyone, where the couple living next door is the same gender, and the couple on the other side is multi-racial. And I want him to live someplace where the washing machine is across town and only works with quarters.</p>
<p>I love my son but I don&#8217;t want him to come home every weekend.</p>
<p>Most importantly, I want him to struggle with ideas independent of my wife and I. He needs to see and hear things outside the context of his comfort zone. Certainly, he&#8217;ll be home on the holidays, crashing on the couch, but when he does I&#8217;m hoping he&#8217;s different. He should see us as small town, backwards, and out of touch as the world of ideas and people opens up before him. I have faith he&#8217;ll eventually change perspectives and realize we aren&#8217;t quite as dumb as he thinks, but when he goes to his 10 year reunion, I hope people look at him and say, &#8220;you&#8217;re different.&#8221; That&#8217;s not a bad thing. (At my 10 year reunion, someone told me I talked different. I felt like saying, I&#8217;ve got a PhD in English. I damn well better sound different or I&#8217;ve wasted my money!).</p>
<p>I understand parents who want to keep their kids close. I&#8217;m sure they have the same hopes and dreams. We want our children to be happy and safe (and employed!). Many parents hope their children stay around and live near by. There&#8217;s something to be said for that. We live 7 hours from my wife&#8217;s parents and holidays are a pain. I know her brothers, sisters, and parents would love to see her and our children more often. My relatives live even farther way and I haven&#8217;t seen many of them for years.</p>
<p>And sometimes that&#8217;s the price we pay for sending our kids off into the world. Periodically, I&#8217;ll ask my students where they&#8217;ve traveled. I&#8217;ll have some military children who have been everywhere, a couple of folks who have, at least, crossed into Mexico (we are two hours from the border here), and I&#8217;ll have 5-10 kids who have never been outside Tom Green County. I realize sometimes this is economic, but not always. Usually, it&#8217;s a conscious decision by the parents who don&#8217;t see the need.</p>
<p>Our job as parents, though, isn&#8217;t to encourage our kids to stay around because we want to be near them. We aren&#8217;t supposed to try and turn them into a little us. Our job is to open the world and give them a chance to live in it. I would be thrilled if my kids move off, find love, and come back to San Angelo. But if they come back, they need to make that choice. This needs to be the place they want to live; not the place they have always lived.</p>
<p>The goals of education and the goals of parenting are often the same: we want smart, critical thinking kids, who can both follow direction but who are also capable of telling us how to improve those directions. We want, as the old adage goes, to teach our kids to fish instead of just giving them fish. These goals are long range and largely impossible to measure because they require pushing, pulling, getting out of the way, and, in general, making stuff up as we go along. They require help but they also require times when we don&#8217;t help. We can manufacture successes when necessary and allow failure when it&#8217;s appropriate.</p>
<p>And it also means, eventually, letting go and hoping nothing really bad happens. That is particularly true when our kids turn 18 and that&#8217;s what we hope to do as we encourage our son to choose a school where he can be un-comfortable so he can learn to think, live, love, and become himself.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/323/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=323&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/you-dont-have-to-leave-but-you-cant-stay-here/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>84</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/aa7dc7d9a744a230446a2c2e85d364b3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wegnerjohn</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
