<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 23:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Operahuset &#8211; Oslo Opera House</title>
		<link>http://geoffwah.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/operahuset-oslo-opera-house/</link>
		<comments>http://geoffwah.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/operahuset-oslo-opera-house/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 17:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>geoffwatt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Norway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operahuset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oslo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geoffwah.wordpress.com/?p=1733</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Despite how the photos look, being on this building was so bright I could barely keep my eyes open. &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160;<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1733&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite how the photos look, being on this building was so bright I could barely keep my eyes open.</p>
<p><a href="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1734" title="Operahuset_1" src="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_1.jpg" alt="" width="549" height="366" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1735" title="Operahuset_2" src="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_2.jpg" alt="" width="549" height="366" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1736" title="Operahuset_3" src="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_3.jpg" alt="" width="549" height="366" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1737" title="Operahuset_4" src="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_4.jpg" alt="" width="549" height="823" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_5.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1738" title="Operahuset_5" src="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_5.jpg" alt="" width="549" height="366" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1733/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1733/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1733&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://geoffwah.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/operahuset-oslo-opera-house/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/82fabb81e0389d2505dc5669691ccc52?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">geoffwatt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Operahuset_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Operahuset_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Operahuset_3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Operahuset_4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geoffwah.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/operahuset_5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Operahuset_5</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Schlock and awe!</title>
		<link>http://thetwobruces.com/2012/07/23/schlock-and-awe/</link>
		<comments>http://thetwobruces.com/2012/07/23/schlock-and-awe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 01:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>2Bruces</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corporate greed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Jersey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Betamax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crap.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eight tracks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victrola's]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thetwobruces.com/?p=675</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you read the Sunday papers like I do (Bruce likes to look at the comics and the Walmart flyers &#8211; I am trying to break him of THAT habit!)), then you know the primary reason for that edition is to sell you crap you don&#8217;t need. Get over it, there is no news on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=675&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you read the Sunday papers like I do (Bruce likes to look at the comics and the Walmart flyers &#8211; I am trying to break him of THAT habit!)), then you know the primary reason for that edition is to sell you crap you don&#8217;t need. Get over it, there is no news on a Sunday. They print that sucker days in advance. The only thing remotely news worthy are the sports scores so you can see how much you now owe your bookie.</p>
<p><a href="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/bookie-final1.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-681" title="bookie-final" src="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/bookie-final1.jpeg" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></a> (dribble.com)</p>
<p>As we mentioned earlier, it&#8217;s just to sell you stuff. Do you think all this &#8220;new&#8221; technology is making your life better? OK, altogether now, a big, emphatic NO! Of course not. It&#8217;s what keeps whatever is left of our economy moving until we can find another war. The sad part of it all is this stuff is made in China&#8230;as if we didn&#8217;t have enough issues with trade. Before long we&#8217;ll all be flying the flag of the United States of Walmart. But, it doesn&#8217;t have to be that way. Bruce and I have found a way to deal with this.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve done some research and found that the new technology really isn&#8217;t any better than the old. Blu-Ray? Yeah, right &#8211; we gotcha Blu-Ray right here! That sucker&#8217;s nothing more than a DVD player with a tuning knob. And we fell for it. Not any damn longer! No! It&#8217;s just new paint on an old building. The old stuff was good and it worked, mostly.</p>
<p>Bruce and I are proud to announce the Grand Opening of the new F&#8217;ed Up Freddie&#8217;s Antique Tech Emporium, or just Freddie&#8217;s for those with small. impressionable children. The premise is simple and based upon the notion that &#8220;They just don&#8217;t build &#8216;em like they used to.&#8221; And they&#8217;re right. They don&#8217;t. But, did you ever wonder what happened to all those new, unopened still boxed, never used DVD players after the Blu-Ray player came out? Bruce and I do. Through shrewd investments and an our off-shore account (Staten Island!), we&#8217;ve been buying up all this &#8220;new&#8221; merchandise and we&#8217;re now ready to pass on these incredible savings to you. It may not now be the newest technology, but hey, it works and it is new, so to speak.</p>
<p>Think about it. You&#8217;re not that old where you don&#8217;t want to hear some of those old scratchy 78RPM records you inherited when your great grandfather died. But the phonograph is dead. Not any more! Come on down to our Route 22 warehouse in Paramus, New Jersey and see the wide selection of RCA Victrolas. We got &#8216;em!</p>
<p><a href="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-682" title="imgres" src="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres.jpeg" alt="" width="194" height="240" /></a>(collectorsweekly.com)</p>
<p>Portable radios and TV&#8217;s? All makes, all colors and all styles in stock now for immediate delivery! We know there are plenty of women out there just pining for a new 8 track player to play their tapes of &#8220;Bread&#8221; again. Wait no more &#8211; we got home and car players ready for you.</p>
<p><a href="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres1.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-683" title="imgres" src="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres1.jpeg" alt="" width="275" height="183" /></a> Or even Neil Diamond! (ebay.com)</p>
<p>And it doesn&#8217;t stop there. Relive the sixties (not your age) with a transistor radio. How about a stereo with a record changer? Yeah, those were cool, especially when you stacked the records with &#8220;Bolero&#8221; strategically placed for the big make-out scene you had planned. Good times, good times.</p>
<p>But while we&#8217;re all getting older, it doesn&#8217;t mean we have to grow up. We can hold on to those symbols of our youth, our innocence, our disposal cash.</p>
<p>Freddie&#8217;s stock is complete with Walkman&#8217;s, phonographs, laser disc players, betamax players, VHS players, reel-to-reel tape decks(for the snobby afficianadoes), discmans, slide projectors, AM radios, B+W TV&#8217;s, digital audio tape decks, 8mm film projectors, radar ranges, box cameras, and so much more it&#8217;ll give you a headache. But our prices won&#8217;t! All of this merchandise is new!</p>
<p><a href="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres2.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-684" title="imgres" src="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres2.jpeg" alt="" width="259" height="194" /></a> Spock shilling for Magnavox! (article.wn.com)</p>
<p>And buying from Freddie&#8217;s helps the economy. All of this stuff had been written off already, years ago. No tax deductions from retailers, just pure, sweet American profit. Let&#8217;s get this country moving again with F&#8217;ed Freddy!</p>
<p>Remember F&#8217;ed Up Freddie&#8217;s slogan, &#8220;It ain&#8217;t the latest, but it was the greatest!&#8221;</p>
<p>This message has not been approved by the Chamber of Commerce nor the National Federation of Independent Businesses. Does that surprise you?</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/category/advertising/'>Advertising</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/category/corporate-greed/'>Corporate greed</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/category/new-jersey-2/'>New Jersey</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/category/television/'>Television</a> Tagged: <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/tag/betamax/'>Betamax</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/tag/crap/'>crap.</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/tag/eight-tracks/'>eight tracks</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/tag/technology/'>Technology</a>, <a href='http://thetwobruces.com/tag/victrolas/'>Victrola's</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=675&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thetwobruces.com/2012/07/23/schlock-and-awe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1a9a63863d03535601f6271ab39bbcf6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2bruth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/bookie-final1.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bookie-final</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imgres</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres1.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imgres</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thetwobruces.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/imgres2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imgres</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Death Penalty May Have Hurt Penn State Less</title>
		<link>http://keystonesportsspot.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/death-penalty-may-have-hurt-penn-state-less/</link>
		<comments>http://keystonesportsspot.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/death-penalty-may-have-hurt-penn-state-less/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 00:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pete Dombrosky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Penn State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happy Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Sandusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Paterno]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Emmert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCAA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penn State Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penn State Scandal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://keystonesportsspot.wordpress.com/?p=511</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When the Joe Paterno statue was taken down outside Beaver Stadium on Penn State’s campus Sunday, a small portion of the recent scandal’s visibility was also removed. No longer would people be able to gaze upon a symbol whose new meaning is deception and human indecency. But sanctions handed out to Penn State this morning [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=511&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When the <strong>Joe Paterno</strong> statue was taken down outside Beaver Stadium on Penn State’s campus Sunday, a small portion of the recent scandal’s visibility was also removed. No longer would people be able to gaze upon a symbol whose new meaning is deception and human indecency.</p>
<p>But sanctions handed out to Penn State this morning ensured that the football program will continue to serve as a public reminder of those horrible acts conducted by <strong>Jerry Sandusky</strong> and the subsequent cover up by Paterno and other Penn State officials.</p>
<p><strong>NCAA President Mark Emmert</strong> announced that Penn State will be penalized with a $60 million fine, a four-year football postseason ban and vacation of all wins since 1998. The school also must reduce its number of scholarships from 25 to 15 per year for four years.</p>
<p>It was a harsh penalty, but it wasn’t the death penalty. That would have meant football at Penn State would have been suspended completely for up to four years.</p>
<p>During the announcement this morning, Emmert said that the death penalty would have hurt too many innocent people. “Suspension of the football program would bring with it significant unintended harm to many who had nothing to do with this case. The sanctions we have crafted are more focused and impactful than that blanket penalty.”</p>
<p>Many believe that Penn State got lucky in not receiving the death penalty. But I’m not so sure. These sanctions may actually be more impactful than the death penalty when it comes to the football program and public perception of the university. Penn State must now endure the “living-death penalty.”</p>
<p>With these actions, the NCAA is doing more than just keeping the football program from playing in the postseason and limiting recruiting and finances. These sanctions will keep the football program in full view of public scrutiny as it carries out its sentence. It is a public shaming stemming from the infamy that Penn State officials brought on themselves. The Nittany Lion will be shut into the stockade and the world will decide whether or not to let the tomatoes fly.</p>
<p>If the football program was completely shut down for a few years, the talk of Penn State football in any media capacity would die off quickly. There would be no football to speak of. Beaver stadium would be empty every Saturday and no one would feel the usual buzz in the air of a fall day in Happy Valley. Maybe this scenario of talking about nothing would work in a plot line of Seinfeld, but not for the national media. It would be an unsettling quietness, but it would be quiet nonetheless.</p>
<p>Then in a few years, Penn State would return to playing football and recruiting players like it always has. It would be a rebirth of football in State College, rising from the ashes and establishing a new identity forged in the absence of football. Their difficult sentence would be over and a new page would turn, helping people to forget about the previous chapters written before it.</p>
<p>The death penalty would have meant a fresh start eventually.</p>
<p>Instead, Penn State will begin a four-year span of meaningless football and public scrutiny. There will be no break from media analysis for the football program. There will be no fresh starts. There will be no bowl games, no Big Ten Championships and no hope to make the NCAA playoff when it begins in 2014. But there will be plenty of time each Saturday for broadcasters to talk about the events leading to the current situation. Viewers at home and at Penn State games will witness the walking-dead Nittany Lions carry out their penalty every week of the season. Talk may die down as time goes on, but the scandal will always be the 800-pound gorilla in Beaver Stadium.</p>
<p>Public perception of Penn State football won’t be helped by a mediocre team, either. With the loss of scholarships and inability to play for Big Ten Championships, National Championships and bowl games, the talent wells for Happy Valley are bound to hit drought conditions. Elite players won’t want to come to Penn State to play for nothing. These young men will play for Penn State’s competition and make the Nittany Lions’ road to success on the field that much harder.</p>
<p>The football team will be bled to death slowly for the next four years and beyond as fewer and fewer top recruits commit. A team of walk-ons just won’t win many games. In the coming years, Penn State will set a different precedent besides the sanctions imposed against them: Never in college football history will such a pedestrian team get so much media attention.</p>
<p>But public perception and sanctions aside, I believe Penn State will recover from this someday. The next decade will be an uphill crawl for everyone who represents the university – the football team, students, alumni and fans (myself included). Success with honor may not have meant anything to Jerry Sandusky, Joe Paterno and other Penn State brass, but it still means something to the rest of us and it’s our duty not to forget what happened while still moving on to set a new standard of excellence.</p>
<p>Football at Penn State will be relevant some day in the future, but it will be the most publicly scrutinized return to relevance in the history of college football.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/511/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/511/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=511&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://keystonesportsspot.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/death-penalty-may-have-hurt-penn-state-less/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1751ecb922ee7d781f72f6b22286ac16?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">petedombrosky</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DIY Monday: 5 Easy Steps To Make Your Own Blog Header! Give it a go!</title>
		<link>http://sweetjellybean.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/diy-monday-5-easy-steps-to-make-your-own-blog-header-give-it-a-go/</link>
		<comments>http://sweetjellybean.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/diy-monday-5-easy-steps-to-make-your-own-blog-header-give-it-a-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 15:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>AJ's Mom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[MOM.ents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simply Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog header]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY banner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Make your own header]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pixlr Express]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sweetjellybean.wordpress.com/?p=2303</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[DIY take two! I might have repelled most of you  let alone gave you unnecessary headache, because of the DIY post I published at three o&#8217;clock this morning. For that, I sincerely apologise. I might have gotten carried away for making it so overly beginners-friendly like post and have covered even the minute detail of things you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2303&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sweetjellybean.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/diy-monday-5-easy-steps-to-make-your-own-blog-header-give-it-a-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/jelly-bean-009-580-751.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/jelly-bean-009-580-751.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jelly-bean-009-580-75</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b1496c1cf98e61bceed84504eb93c7c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sweetjellybean</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/cutecolorsbabyline2.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cutecolorsbabyline2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/2-e1343052575719.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/4-e1343052819505.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/6.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/7.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/8.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/result.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Result</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/cutecolorsbabyline2.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cutecolorsbabyline2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/foreverbanner2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ForeverBanner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/splendiolavender2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Splendiolavender</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/currentwfbcbanner.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OldWFBCbanner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sweetjellybean.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/twentyelevenbannersample.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TwentyElevenBannerSample</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Calling Me Short, 50 Cent!!!: My 24th Birthday and 23 Accomplishments of the Last Year</title>
		<link>http://thegirlwiththeblog.com/2012/07/23/stop-calling-me-short-50-cent-my-24th-birthday-and-23-accomplishments-of-the-last-year/</link>
		<comments>http://thegirlwiththeblog.com/2012/07/23/stop-calling-me-short-50-cent-my-24th-birthday-and-23-accomplishments-of-the-last-year/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 16:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thegirlwiththeblog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Misguided attempts at holiday blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accomplishments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grey Gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horoscopes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupy Wallstreet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pippa Middleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Titanic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thegirlwiththeblog.com/?p=881</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On this day, last year, I reluctantly turned 23. I welcomed my inevitable aging with 2 bottles of Arbor Mist and FX reruns of Superbad, followed by fits of crying  and my now infamous Waffle House date. I wasn’t going into 23 with dignity if I could avoid it. Well, ladies and gentleman, I am [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=881&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thegirlwiththeblog.com/2012/07/23/stop-calling-me-short-50-cent-my-24th-birthday-and-23-accomplishments-of-the-last-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/37faf52ca870460b9db1be6eead271cd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">twosortsofpeople</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlwiththeblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dawson-cries.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dawson cries</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlwiththeblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sad-birthday.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sad birthday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlwiththeblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/grey-gardens.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grey gardens</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlwiththeblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/republican-debate.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">republican debate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlwiththeblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/titanic-3d.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">titanic 3d</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlwiththeblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/pippa-undateable.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pippa-undateable</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confession No. 51 — Why sweat the big things? Worry about the small (really important) stuff.</title>
		<link>http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/07/22/confession-no-51-why-sweat-the-big-things-worry-about-the-small-really-important-stuff/</link>
		<comments>http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/07/22/confession-no-51-why-sweat-the-big-things-worry-about-the-small-really-important-stuff/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 17:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam J. Holland</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ice Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reminiscing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[7UP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reminiscing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://unorthodoxepicure.com/?p=1443</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been accused a time (or six) of being a complainer. While I&#8217;m not ready to accept that, I do admit to griping about certain things in life that are worthy of being bitched about. Along with my high cholesterol and blood pressure, my tendency to sweat the small things will probably shave some years [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1443&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been accused a time (or six) of being a complainer. While I&#8217;m not ready to accept that, I do admit to griping about certain things in life that are worthy of being bitched about.</p>
<p>Along with my high cholesterol and blood pressure, my tendency to sweat the small things will probably shave some years from my life.</p>
<p>Some of my biggest day-to-day frustrations involve mustard. When I squeeze the bottle and get a couple drams of yellow-colored water — instead of the thick yellow contents — it almost ruins my day. Brown mustard is even worse.</p>
<p>Ketchup&#8217;s no better except I rarely, if ever, use it on a sandwich. So, no chance of soaking down the bread. One thing that really bothers me about ketchup, though, are the little packets. First, they are too damn small. And, what the hell is that syrupy goop that ends up on every third packet? It&#8217;s as irritating as chigger bites.</p>
<p>Though I don&#8217;t usually verbalize my issue with powdered drink mixes — especially the &#8216;lite&#8217; ones — I tend to go over again and again (in my head) the raunchy taste of the dust. And it never fails: someone in the next room empties a single powder packet into a bottle of water and I inhale — and taste — saccharin or some other nasty artificial sweetener.</p>
<p>Most people probably share my complaint about can openers. I&#8217;d rather they not work at all, instead of cutting just enough of the lid to make a mess while still preventing me from prying. These moments make me want to put my fist through the wall.</p>
<p>Speaking of canned goods, someone out there could probably get rich just keeping up with manufacturers who surreptitiously reduce the amount of product — but keep the price the same. They&#8217;ve been doing it with coffee for years, but when it comes to stuff like coconut milk or pumpkin, it&#8217;s a real pain in the neck, and one reason that Thanksgiving is not high on my list of favorite holidays. Yes. This bothers me that much.</p>
<p><strong>What I don&#8217;t bitch about</strong><br />
The weather in my northeast Texas town reached 104 degrees yesterday. It&#8217;s uncomfortable. It&#8217;s also par for the course. Summer is hot. Anyone who has a complaint (and there are plenty who do) should move to Maine, where there is snow on the ground half the year. As for me … I just make sure the air-conditioner is in working order (we spent $800 just this past month on an emergency service call); the electric bill is paid on time; and that there is plenty of baby powder available for my use. Besides, the hotter the summer, the better October feels.</p>
<p>Car wrecks and traffic tickets have also never really bothered me. I&#8217;m speaking of those experienced and received by my beautiful bride, since I have a spotless record in both categories. Wrecks and tickets are inconvenient, expensive and sometimes scary. Still, I tend to get more ticked at the improper grammar or misspelled words written on the citation by the officer.</p>
<p>And traffic itself? Sure, I&#8217;ve been known to yell a few expletives in my car. But it&#8217;s mainly been when I&#8217;ve been on an emergency route to my bathroom. Ever notice that in such situations we tend to catch every red light? Or end up behind Grandpa Grunt? Otherwise, I&#8217;m generally calm in the car.</p>
<p>I have never lost a moment of sleep over people&#8217;s fashion sense, or lack thereof. So some guys wear their pants around their knees and some people believe it&#8217;s OK to go out in public in pajamas. Is this really worth talking about on Facebook? I also don&#8217;t advertise my headaches or fire ant stings. Oh, I could. But, let&#8217;s face it. Does anyone really care?</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t complain about my job, my boss or my co-workers. Why? Because I love all of them. Always have. I&#8217;m fortunate in that way … but I&#8217;m also a PR guy, so complaining would be bad for the ol&#8217; image.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t complain about mail delivery, politicians or taxes. So long as emails, elections and accountants are plentiful, there is always hope.</p>
<p>So, my reputation is not so deserved after all. Just don&#8217;t get me started on garbage disposals or line-jumpers.</p>
<hr />
<p>As I&#8217;ve mentioned before, it is uncommon for me to get a sweet tooth. It&#8217;s even rarer for me to crave ice cream. But this past week I did and, as luck would have it, the freezer was empty. I would&#8217;ve complained, but my family was 1,500 miles away. So I decided to recreate a frozen ice cream-like treat from my childhood — named for the soft drink it contains. In the process of trying to obtain the recipe, I ended up enacting a temporary boycott on the company that makes it (the name includes a &#8216;lucky&#8217; number, followed by a common preposition) because they responded to me with poorly written form letter. My luck changed when my good friend Jen, of <a href="http://jcocina.com/">Juanita&#8217;s Cocina</a> (pronounced coh-seen-ah), confirmed that my dad&#8217;s memory was correct: this sweet cold stuff has only two ingredients. For that, the old recipe gets a new name in honor of Jen.</p>
<h2 style="text-align:center;">Soda Pop Sherbet <em>(formerly known as 7UP Ice Cream)</em></h2>
<div id="attachment_1459" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 586px"><a href="http://unorthodoxepicure.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/soda-pop-sherbet2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1459" title="soda pop sherbet2" src="http://unorthodoxepicure.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/soda-pop-sherbet2.jpg" alt="" width="576" height="510" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This was the homemade &#8216;ice cream&#8217; that I grew up on — sans the slice of Meyer Lemon. Only two simple ingredients and about 30 minutes in the ice cream maker and the memories came flooding back.</p></div>
<p>1 quart &#8211; lemon-lime soda (or any soda of your choosing)<br />
1 14 0z. can — Sweetened condensed milk</p>
<p>Place ingredients in ice cream maker, following manufacturer&#8217;s instructions. This will produce an icy soft-serve, which is exactly what I enjoyed as a child. Want a firmer sherbet? Place in the freezer for another hour, or so.</p>
<p>Like what you&#8217;ve read here? Please tell 50 of your closest friends and come join me on <a href="http://www.facebook.com/UnorthodoxEpicure">Facebook</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1443/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1443/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1443&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/07/22/confession-no-51-why-sweat-the-big-things-worry-about-the-small-really-important-stuff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9d0b5753a211733e623bd21083223bac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adamjholland</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unorthodoxepicure.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/soda-pop-sherbet2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">soda pop sherbet2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I hide from my fatness and other such illusions.</title>
		<link>http://loosing100lbs.wordpress.com/2012/07/19/fat-illusions/</link>
		<comments>http://loosing100lbs.wordpress.com/2012/07/19/fat-illusions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 03:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Renee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Day-To-Day Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dieting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://loosing100lbs.wordpress.com/?p=31</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, it seems that when you make a commitment to start acknowledging your weight, you become aware of so many things that you didn&#8217;t previously allow yourself to pay attention to. Like, what you look like naked. Every fat dimple, every half-started roll, every plain of soft flab, and each and every damn stretch mark &#8211; they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=31&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, it seems that when you make a commitment to start acknowledging your weight, you become aware of so many things that you didn&#8217;t previously allow yourself to pay attention to. Like, what you look like<strong><em> naked</em></strong>.</p>
<p>Every fat dimple, every half-started roll, every plain of soft flab, and each and every damn stretch mark &#8211; they all glare at you accusingly.</p>
<p>I must admit, I&#8217;ve gotten really good at <strong><em>not</em></strong> looking at my body.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been married for 8 years, it&#8217;s not like my husband and I don&#8217;t have sex or take showers together &#8211; <em>because we do</em>. It&#8217;s not like no one sees my naked body but me, right? And, don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m NOT saying that I haven&#8217;t been self-conscious during all those moments of intimacy either.</p>
<p>Trust me, I&#8217;m fully aware that if I straighten my back just so that the curve of my waist will be smoother and thus my side roll less obvious to my husbands touch. I&#8217;ve figured out that if I keep my mouth closed when my head is back in ecstasy my double chin isn&#8217;t so double-y (mirror). I suck in my stomach when I&#8217;m getting undressed before a shower and I always wait until my husband has his glasses off before I take off my underwear.</p>
<p>I suppose all  these little tricks add up and before long, I even tricked myself&#8230; I learned how to hide my fatness behind some fairly flimsy illusions and because the truth is so much harder to stomach &#8211; I fell for my own lies.</p>
<p>Now, when I&#8217;m really seeing &#8211; not looking, <em>seeing</em> &#8211; my body, I find that my level of self-consciousness has sky-rocketed.</p>
<p>I hide a lot behind clothing. I dress professionally and appropriately for my weight and age (30) and these habits keep me fairly comfortably in my daily environment. I am conscientious and particular about what I wear but I also don&#8217;t tend to obsess about it either so long as I have items that I like and feel good in. The way that I dress de-emphasizes the fact that I&#8217;m quite as overweight as I am because the styles I choose are flattering (<em>I watch What Not To Wear and take good mental notes</em>).</p>
<p>So, when stripped bare (<em>emotionally and physically</em>) I find it hard to <strong><em>not</em></strong> look away. I&#8217;m making a concerted effort to avoid this &#8211; to look &#8211; to embrace &#8211; and use what I see as motivation to make changes and keep them up.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t like that, all of the sudden, I have a little mental freak out when my husband walks in on me while I&#8217;m changing my blouse or putting on pants or &#8211; <strong><em>heaven forbid!</em></strong> &#8211; getting out of the shower. I demand privacy and shrink from his gaze. It&#8217;s not like he hasn&#8217;t seen me before but now&#8230; now it&#8217;s like I&#8217;m afraid he&#8217;ll start seeing my body like I&#8217;m beginning to see my body.</p>
<p>I suppose that this phase will pass &#8211; the more I become familiar with my body the more likely I&#8217;ll be able to notice changes and that will help keep me motivated. I don&#8217;t, however, what to become so acclimated that I begin to fall into the same comfort zone I&#8217;ve been in &#8211; where I once again don&#8217;t really &#8220;see&#8221; my body anymore.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a delicate balance -<em> this loosing weight thing</em> &#8211; between sanity and a complete breakdown.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/31/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/31/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=31&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://loosing100lbs.wordpress.com/2012/07/19/fat-illusions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7328e4fa8ab03f93cedd084ceb75f055?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">loosing100lbs</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is blogging addictive?</title>
		<link>http://lanternpost2012.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/is-blogging-addictive/</link>
		<comments>http://lanternpost2012.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/is-blogging-addictive/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 17:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Daniela</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living in our time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FAQs Help and Tutorials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet access]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lanternpost2012.wordpress.com/?p=1148</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Is there such a thing as addiction to blogging? I am starting to think that there might be. If so what are the signs? There are probably serious people who already have, or are going to as we speak, conduct a serious research into the matter, but from a newbie blogger’s perspective, it seems to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1148&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lanternpost2012.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/is-blogging-addictive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>95</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>-41.286460 174.776236</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>-41.286460</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>174.776236</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9a7647a0a91f0b92e253465a2b4a5596?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lanternpost2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3334/3183290111_989c5b1bec_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Internet Access Here Sign</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Domestic Dilemma: Why I Hate Food</title>
		<link>http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/domestic-dilemma-why-i-hate-food/</link>
		<comments>http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/domestic-dilemma-why-i-hate-food/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 21:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>SnowfoxBandit</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cornbread muffins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crimblade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culinary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green beans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grocery shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mac n cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[okibrownie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peanut butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rogue leader]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/?p=723</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am not a natural cook. This shouldn&#8217;t come as such a surprise to me, I suppose. I wasn&#8217;t raised in a household that cooked often; while we always had great party food and put together a good spread on special occasions, the memories that stand out the most are those of microwaved bags of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=723&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am not a natural cook.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 135px"><img title="kraft" src="http://media.lunch.com/d/d7/202792.jpg?2" alt="" width="125" height="185" /><p class="wp-caption-text">so delicious!!</p></div>
<p>This shouldn&#8217;t come as such a surprise to me, I suppose. I wasn&#8217;t raised in a household that cooked often; while we always had great party food and put together a good spread on special occasions, the memories that stand out the most are those of microwaved bags of frozen veggies; a fridge containing nothing but milk, applesauce, a few gallons of distilled water, and a &#8220;Bag O&#8217; Salad&#8221;; my elation when I learned how to make my own mac &#8216;n&#8217; cheese; and my belief that chicken only existed as a white, dry chicken breast that hopefully wouldn&#8217;t take too many chews to go down. (Imagine my delight when I discovered chicken thighs existed in my later college days, and that &#8220;dark meat&#8221; wasn&#8217;t just a Thanksgiving delicacy.)</p>
<p>College students aren&#8217;t known for their culinary skills, but I always wanted to obtain them somehow. Especially as I moved away from the college crowd and essentially turned into a pseudo-adult who was still taking college classes (this was accomplished by living in a house with older friends, spending time with older friends, working two jobs, commuting 45 miles to school, and not getting shitfaced on disgustingly cheap liquor at every possible opportunity), I felt that it was time to enhance my attempts at adulthood by learning how to cook for myself and my house-family. I was also too broke to continue keeping Jimmy John&#8217;s on speed dial.</p>
<p>Cooking&#8217;s pretty simple, right? There&#8217;s a recipe, and you follow it. I&#8217;m even lucky enough to have most of the basic equipment in the house already, thanks to not living alone. (Hint to my fellow pseudo-adults: &#8220;Basic equipment&#8221; means more than just having a fridge and a microwave.)</p>
<p>Okay, but what do I <em>want</em> to make, though? I&#8217;m a simple person, and Rogue Leader is the same. I like apples and peanut butter. Caesar salads. Cheese and sausage. Sandwiches (or the paleo version, which replaces the bread with a lettuce wrap!). When we went to Crimblade and Okibrownie&#8217;s for dinner, his grilled beef and veggie skewers blew us away. We knew food could be that delicious and incredible, but not that it was possible for real people like us to make it that way.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 366px"><a href="http://thepurebar.com/files/2011/03/apples-and-peanut-butter.jpg"><img title="PBapples" src="http://thepurebar.com/files/2011/03/apples-and-peanut-butter.jpg" alt="" width="356" height="275" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I could live off of this.</p></div>
<p>Over the past several months, I have been attempting to become known for more than just my cornbread muffins &#8212; which until recently were my sole culinary triumph. (I have now added simple sauteed green beans to that list for a grand total of two things I can cook that other people want to eat. Sadly, neither constitutes a meal.) But while I can handle breakfast (greek yogurt, a fried egg, or maybe a banana) and lunch (sandwiches and fruit for the win), I have <em>no idea</em> what people eat for dinner.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve made several pretty tasty meals in the past few months, actually. But while I highly enjoyed the (usually) successful endeavors, none of them stuck. &#8220;Wait, we have to eat dinner again tonight? Didn&#8217;t we just do that yesterday?&#8221;</p>
<p>Honestly, though, the worst part of this entire process is the actual procuring of food. I <em>loathe</em> grocery shopping. It&#8217;s a constant reminder of how much effort it takes me to figure out a whole week&#8217;s worth of healthy dinners that I can still somehow afford &#8212; and then when I finally find everything I need, pay more than I wanted to at the checkout line, and get it all home &#8212; <em>I still have to turn it into meals.</em></p>
<p>I keep trying, but we&#8217;ve been home from vacation for a week and still have nothing but good beer, a greek yogurt, and eggs in our half of the fridge. Maybe it&#8217;s time for me to stop trying to be a domestic goddess and just figure out how to feed myself first.</p>
<p>Any suggestions?</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/apples/'>apples</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/cooking/'>cooking</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/cornbread-muffins/'>cornbread muffins</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/crimblade/'>crimblade</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/culinary/'>culinary</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/domestic/'>domestic</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/food/'>food</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/green-beans/'>green beans</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/grocery-shopping/'>grocery shopping</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/health/'>health</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/mac-n-cheese/'>mac n cheese</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/okibrownie/'>okibrownie</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/peanut-butter/'>peanut butter</a>, <a href='http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/tag/rogue-leader/'>rogue leader</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/723/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/723/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=723&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesnowfoxblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/domestic-dilemma-why-i-hate-food/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/923b43b7b46cb8846e490631d9f4fb2f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">snowfoxbandit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://media.lunch.com/d/d7/202792.jpg?2" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kraft</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thepurebar.com/files/2011/03/apples-and-peanut-butter.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PBapples</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Lemon Peeler for My Love: A Gift-giving Guide for the Ex in Your Life</title>
		<link>http://lostnchina.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/lemon-peeler/</link>
		<comments>http://lostnchina.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/lemon-peeler/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lostnchina</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[henkels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lemon peeler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[single woman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tina Fey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wusthof]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lostnchina.wordpress.com/?p=2730</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve ever questioned your man&#8217;s love for you, just take a look at the presents that you&#8217;ve received from him during the course of your relationship.  Perhaps you can the remember the story behind that 50th birthday diamond necklace, or the memories from your 10th wedding anniversary when you were whisked away to a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2730&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lostnchina.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/lemon-peeler/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sml-fish.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sml-fish.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sml fish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bf809b65e4c501846bda6e3ae155eb7b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lostnchina</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/lemon-peeler1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lemon peeler</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/oversized-ladle3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oversized ladle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/il_fullxfull-342794223.jpg?w=778" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">frumpy frock</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/egg-slicer.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">egg slicer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sw-jedi-gown-p.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oversized robe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/chia-obama-2-thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chia-obama-2-thumb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/tony_soprano-special1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tony_soprano special</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/cheap.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cheap</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostnchina.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/its-not-me1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">its not me</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>