<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Sip Heard \&#8217;Round the World</title>
		<link>http://semilledge.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/the-sip-heard-round-the-world-marco-rubios-desperate-grasp-for-a-tiny-gulp/</link>
		<comments>http://semilledge.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/the-sip-heard-round-the-world-marco-rubios-desperate-grasp-for-a-tiny-gulp/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 20:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>semilledge</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[State of the Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SOTU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marco Rubio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida Senator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://semilledge.wordpress.com/?p=374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If, like me, your vote to watch Tuesday&#8217;s episode of &#8220;Dance Moms&#8221; was vetoed by nobler Americans in favor of watching the State of the Union address, you may have seen Florida Senator Marco Rubio deliver the GOP response. More likely is that in all your social media goings on, you&#8217;ve stumbled upon some sort [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=374&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If, like me, your vote to watch Tuesday&#8217;s episode of &#8220;Dance Moms&#8221; was vetoed by nobler Americans in favor of watching the State of the Union address, you may have seen Florida Senator Marco Rubio deliver the GOP response. More likely is that in all your social media goings on, you&#8217;ve stumbled upon some sort of reference to his awkward intermission and grapple for a tiny bottle of water.</p>
<p><a href="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/marco-rubio-water-hed-2013.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-379" alt="Image" src="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/marco-rubio-water-hed-2013.jpg?w=642" /></a></p>
<p>Courtesy of adweek.com</p>
<p>Bless him. &#8220;Marco Rubio water&#8221; pops up in the Google search bar before you can even finish typing the poor guy&#8217;s last name. In case you missed it, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=19ZxJVnM5Gs">here&#8217;s</a> the video. Or one of them. There are many YouTube submissions of the gaffe with titles ranging from the demure to &#8220;Marco Rubio is THIRSTY.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always been a bit of a fan of Rubio&#8217;s, simply because, in the words of the Scottish Korean man from the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4h3ewZxrqU4">Starburst commercial</a>, he&#8217;s a juicy contradiction. At 41-years-old, Rubio is the GOP&#8217;s next big thing. The Miami native is the son of Cuban immigrants, but only about 18% of Latino voters classify themselves as Republican. (Resurgent Republic has a great <a href="http://www.hispanicvoters2012.com">site</a> full of other statistics on Hispanics in America.)</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t tell you much about Rubio&#8217;s speech, aside from that uncomfortable reach off-screen for the world&#8217;s tiniest bottle of water. The media has dubbed the bottle snag &#8220;The new &#8216;Watergate.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art-rubio-2-1-620x349.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-481" alt="Image" src="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art-rubio-2-1-620x349.jpg?w=610" /></a></p>
<p>Courtesy of theage.com.</p>
<p>Far from a scandal, &#8220;The new &#8216;Watergate&#8217;&#8221; has made Rubio look pretty darn good. It seems that the public has responded well to the gaffe. Rubio&#8217;s response? &#8220;I needed water. What am I going to do?&#8221;</p>
<p>An <a href="http://www.theage.com.au/technology/technology-news/the-new-watergate-rubios-awkward-sip-goes-viral-but-senator-has-last-laugh-20130214-2ee4x.html">article</a> on theage.com highlights some of the most hilarious tweets about the incident, in addition to explaining that Rubio had taped the response to the State of the Union in Spanish immediately before he addressed the nation. Of course the guy was thirsty.</p>
<p>An NPR <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/monkeysee/2013/02/13/171903635/rubio-s-water-bottle-and-the-authenticity-craving?ft=1&amp;f=1001&amp;sc=tw&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter">story </a>extolled Rubio&#8217;s authenticity. On a night where everything from suits to speeches to hugs and handshakes were choreographed, Rubio&#8217;s thirst may have been the only authentic thing. It generated an honest response, both on the part of the Senator and the public. It was obviously unplanned (that great big reach out of camera shot) and incredibly uncomfortable. And we ate it up.</p>
<p>So, my hat&#8217;s off to Senator Rubio. Thank you for providing us social media fodder and the opportunity to show off our water puns. But most of all, on a night that was planned to the T, thanks for giving us a little something human. Stay thirsty, my friend.</p>
<p><a href="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mqaskjq.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-510" alt="Image" src="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mqaskjq.jpg?w=710" /></a>Courtesy of reddit.com.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/374/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/374/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=374&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://semilledge.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/the-sip-heard-round-the-world-marco-rubios-desperate-grasp-for-a-tiny-gulp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/80cfd0ea65f0061d29b2630f103846c4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">semilledge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/marco-rubio-water-hed-2013.jpg?w=642" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art-rubio-2-1-620x349.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mqaskjq.jpg?w=710" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The State of Obama’s Union</title>
		<link>http://jamesdboys.com/2013/02/13/the-state-of-obamas-union/</link>
		<comments>http://jamesdboys.com/2013/02/13/the-state-of-obamas-union/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 20:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. James D. Boys</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Political Perspectives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2016 Presidential Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Clinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marco Rubio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medicare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[State of the Union]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jamesdboys.com/?p=1090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After the glitz and glamour of President Obama’s second inauguration, Washington finally got down to business last tonight with the State of the Union Address. This was another opportunity for the president to talk at Congress, if not necessarily to Congress. Certainly, he has not proved very adept at talking with Congress so far. The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1090&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/BiTyTJc92Bc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>After the glitz and glamour of President Obama’s second inauguration, Washington finally got down to business last tonight with the State of the Union Address. This was another opportunity for the president to talk at Congress, if not necessarily to Congress. Certainly, he has not proved very adept at talking with Congress so far. The State of the Union is the equivalent of the budget speech in the UK, an occasion of high politics and low manners, at which the president’s supporters cheer, his opponents boo and the pundits ponder. It is, if you will, presidential pantomime.</p>
<p>The State of the Union address has evolved with the nation. Until 1913 it was merely a written report delivered to Congress as required by the Constitution. Later, it was delivered in person, but as late as the 1960s it was delivered in the afternoon with little consideration for the growing TV audience. However, with the rise of the Imperial Presidency came the emergence of the State of the Union as a Prime Time event, scheduled with military precision and designed to be one of the signature events in the Washington, D.C. calendar. It is an all too rare opportunity for the president to address both houses of Congress, the members of the Supreme Court and a TV audience that has reached as high as 52.4 million in 2009.</p>
<p>Of course, give ‘em and inch and they will steal the evening, and some presidents have been known to talk and talk, none more so than Bill Clinton, who in 1995 and 1999 came dangerously close to talking for 90 minutes. That’s the length of a football game, but without the change of ends at half time. Perhaps Clinton’s verbosity can be forgiven in light of his incredible capacity to ad-lib the first 20 minutes of his 1994 State of the Union Address, when the incorrect speech was loaded into his TelePrompter. Slick? Absolutely. Thank goodness he never went into the car business. For this, after all, is a presidential sales pitch; an opportunity for the president to demonstrate his mastery of Washington and to talk directly to the American people, literally over the heads of Congress and to ask for support on issues that half of the chamber would resist tooth and nail.</p>
<p>This year was no different. Forget any misperceptions about a new term and a new start in which Republicans and Democrats put aside their differences for national unity. The State of the Union, despite the theatrics, is about cold, hard politics and the stakes are higher than ever with the president determined to push ahead with his priorities; climate change, nuclear weapons reduction, gun control, tax reform, immigration reform and the withdrawal of forces from Afghanistan. All were touched on, dwelt on or in some cases lingered over last night, as the president sought to press the right buttons within the chamber, with viewers at home and with the all important ‘randomly selected group of voters’ who were being polled for instant feedback and which will do much to drive the direction of policy in the months ahead.</p>
<p>Obama opened by announcing, “The state of our union is stronger.” But stronger than what precisely? Mexico? Greece? A house of cards? Bill Clinton used to intone, “The State of our Union is strong.” Such a declaration would be welcome in 2013, but would appear to be merely a useful fiction. Obama’s address covered a wide range of issues; a smorgasbord of delights for his supporters, and a sack of ashes for his opponents. There was little here that was unexpected, little here that was conciliatory and little here that will alter perceptions or feelings on either side of the political aisle. As expected there were no niceties from the president, or anything except superficial pleasantries from his opponents in the chamber. Neither side are in the mood for compromise. Both have recently been re-elected, with new mandates to continue doing what they have been doing for the past 4 years.</p>
<p>Medicare reform was proposed, coupled with a plea to “save hundreds of billions of dollars by getting rid of tax loopholes and deductions for the well-off and well-connected.” Tax reform was not going to be a topic that kept viewers glued to their seats, but it was what was being proposed, along with job creation proposals to stimulate the economy. This was, in many ways, a speech that could have been given a year ago as America prepared for an election campaign, and was, therefore, an indication of how little has been achieved in the last twelve months.</p>
<p>Immigration reform was addressed as the president laid claim to having put “more boots on the southern border than at any time in our history,” and having reduced “illegal crossings to their lowest levels in 40 years.” One wonders how the government claims to be able to record the rate of illegal crossings whilst being unable to prevent them? Obama proposed a concept of Earned Citizenship, “a path that includes passing a background check, paying taxes and a meaningful penalty, learning English, and going to the back of the line behind the folks trying to come here legally.” The big question, however, must surely be: How long before drones are patrolling the boarders to prevent such incursions? Perhaps that will be addressed next year.</p>
<p>It had already leaked that 34,000 American personnel would be withdrawn from Afghanistan this year and that the combat mission would be complete in 2014, but the president reiterated the fact nonetheless. Good news, it seems, will be taken wherever it can be found. For that matter, enforced measures are always better if they can be presented as a generous offer, hence the president’s revelation that the White House would “engage with Congress to ensure…that our targeting, detention, and prosecution of terrorists remains consistent with our laws.” Such a declaration was the result of revelations that have emerged from the Senate Confirmation hearings that have been continuing on Capitol Hill and which look set to rumble on, with questions remaining in relation to kill or capture policies.</p>
<p>The time allocated to foreign as opposed to domestic affairs was telling. Traditionally, presidents have spent their first terms addressing domestic issues and their second on international relations, seeking to win Nobel Prizes. President Obama, of course, has done both already, having passed health care reform in his first 2 years and won the Nobel Peace Prize in his first year in office. Accordingly, this does all rather risk becoming The Curious Case of Barack Obama; the man who lived his presidency in reverse and so what Obama does for his second act will be telling. He cannot run for re-election, so he could be courageous and take on vested interests and lobby groups that have previously been untouchable. Last night he addressed the issue of gun violence that has received so much media coverage of late. However, he didn’t campaign on this issue and has said previously that he has no intention of removing guns from gun owners. This has not prevented gun shops from doing a roaring trade from customers who fear the end is neigh for their right to bear arms. This was, however, the emotional highpoint of the speech, as the president insisted that victims of gun violence “deserve a vote” and urged Congress to declare where they stood on the issue that has killed over a thousand Americans since the shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary School. Long before that vote is even contemplated, however, it appears that the chance of reform in this area is dissipating fast.</p>
<p>For whilst Obama is beyond the reproach of voters, his party is not, so again, discount any notion of a president free to do as he wishes for the next four years. He will come under intense pressure from those who are seeking to replace him in 2016 not to stray from the mainstream for fear of driving voters from the Democratic Party and into the hands of the Republicans on a whole range of contentious issues that could decide the next two election cycles. For make no mistake, the American system of government is geared up for campaigning, not governing. In less than two years the entire House of Representatives and a third of the Senate will have been re-elected, and once that is out of the way, all eyes will turn to the presidential election of 2016 and any residual political clout that Obama retains at that point will rapidly disappear.</p>
<p>With so much at stake it is little wonder that the president’s opponents are ill-prepared to allow him the entire spotlight and now they get the chance to respond in a rather down at heel address shortly after the president speaks, in a process that actually serves to demonstrate the gulf that exists between the President of the United States and any other mere mortal. This year’s lucky contestant was Marco Rubio, the Republican Senator from Florida, by way of Havana. Senator Rubio is the Republican Party’s Great Hispanic Hope in 2016, so it was no surprise that he was selected to respond to the president, in what is in all probability the opening salvo of the 2016 election. In his response, Senator Rubio urged the president to abandon his ‘obsession’ with higher taxes, but his moment in the national spotlight was sullied by his decision to take a breather and provide Poland Spring bottled water a much needed product placement. Such are the little things that memories of such events are made of.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Dr. James D. Boys is a Visiting Senior Research Fellow at King’s College, London. He maintains a website at <a href="http://www.jamesdboys.com/">www.jamesdboys.com</a> and can be followed on Twitter @jamesdboys</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1090&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jamesdboys.com/2013/02/13/the-state-of-obamas-union/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f1a3f80f3da71a68c32e8a2ebe88c57d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jamesdboys</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LeBron James vs. Michael Jordan: My Take on the Debate</title>
		<link>http://spencerunfiltered.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/lebron-james-vs-michael-jordan/</link>
		<comments>http://spencerunfiltered.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/lebron-james-vs-michael-jordan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>E. Spencer Kyte</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SPORTS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Russell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kareem Abdul Jabbar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kobe Bryant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LeBron James]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Jordan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar Robertson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wilt Chamberlain]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://spencerunfiltered.wordpress.com/?p=189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Do I really have to pick just one?<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=189&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://spencerunfiltered.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/lebron-james-vs-michael-jordan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://spencerunfiltered.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/michael-and-lebron.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://spencerunfiltered.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/michael-and-lebron.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MICHAEL AND LEBRON</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/27cc1a5343eb17f4d067c05d24fc4751?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">keyboardkimura</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Coffee</title>
		<link>http://i-am-not-a-lawyer.com/2013/02/13/on-coffee/</link>
		<comments>http://i-am-not-a-lawyer.com/2013/02/13/on-coffee/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 19:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>theoriginalsung</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greece]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[La Colombe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nikos Kazantzakis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://i-am-not-a-lawyer.com/?p=1135</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Place&#8221; is associated with just about everything that our senses come across. In whatever activity our body and mind take part in, we do so in a &#8220;place&#8221;; whether or not one recognizes or appreciates such a phenomenon is an entire dialogue on its own. Our daily commute takes place somewhere (train, subway, bus, parking [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1135&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Place&#8221; is associated with just about everything that our senses come across. In whatever activity our body and mind take part in, we do so in a &#8220;place&#8221;; whether or not one recognizes or appreciates such a phenomenon is an entire dialogue on its own. Our daily commute takes place somewhere (train, subway, bus, parking lot-like I-66); our work takes place somewhere (cubicle, hole-in-the-wall, highrise); our mingling chatter takes place somewhere (sidewalk, bar, lunch line at the salad place that for some reason always has a line); our gastronomic activities take place somewhere (Korean deli, at my desk in front of a computer monitor, Indian lunch buffets with unnamed but delicious curry creations).</p>
<p>Coffee epitomizes the imprinting power of place. In turn, place symbolizes an attached ambiance, a feel, a mood, a hue associated with the place that holds the coffee.</p>
<p>A vast number of coffee drinkers, for decades, drank coffee not only for the sake of coffee, but more so for the attached ambiance. The price one paid for a cup of black liquid gold was not limited to the beans themselves, but included the chair one sat in, the light fixtures above one&#8217;s head, and the streaming music. I recall, as a youngster in Korea, a time when (before the onslaught of Starbucks and other chains) coffee shops were referred to as &#8220;dabang.&#8221; These peculiar establishments &#8211; now almost unheard of, practically extinct &#8211; were the preferred meet-and-greet points for just about any occasion, particularly for blind dates. The servers slash waitresses, affectionately referred to as &#8220;madame,&#8221; played the roll of hostess more than a mere server. Patrons oft returned to a said dabang just for a renowned madame&#8217;s company.</p>
<p>And the coffee. Dabang establishments have left a permanent imprint on Korea&#8217;s coffee culture, a tattoo-like presence. The term &#8220;dabang coffee&#8221; is still used when one would like to sip a cup with cream and sugar, with more cream and sugar. Coffee was first introduced in Korea to the royal family at the start of the twentieth century, and as the beverage began to take to the masses, the unfamiliar and rather bitter taste of this black liquid was understandably pacified by the inclusion of cream and sugar. Like other cultures, coffee was enjoyed as an after-meal splurge, a sugary exclamation point, acting more as a dessert than anything else. The popularity of &#8220;Americanos&#8221; and black drip coffee is only recent history on the Peninsula. The lasting impact of said dabangs can still be reminisced by Korea&#8217;s love for instant coffee; convenient one-pack-a-cup sticks with ground coffee, powdered cream, and sugar.</p>
<p><a href="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hawwoondaedrip-e1360781363461.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1138" alt="" src="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hawwoondaedrip-e1360781363461.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Coffee influences where and how we converse with one another. Where once a dabang hosted blind dates, a Starbucks or Coffee Bean stands to host chitchatting college students in Gangnam. A lasting similarity, though, is the relatively muted interest towards the coffee itself; as it was decades ago, one pays for one&#8217;s seat and right to chat in that specific ambiance.</p>
<p>Greeks had their own association with coffee, as painted here by Nikos Kazantzakis:</p>
<p>&#8220;I took a seat in a kafeneion. The coffee and water came. Today is Sunday, services are over, and now the householders proceed to the square. Dressed in their Sunday best, grim and pompous. They sit down, light their cigarettes, sip water and wait with faces turned toward the north. What are they waiting for? The newspapers from Athens. React to the order around you, resist the current, say no! when all those around you are murmuring yes; this is one of the most demanding obligations of a soul that lives in a bankrupt era. Consonance and balance are fertile virtues in creative times; but when the historical moment of dissolution is at hand, a great struggle is needed to keep your soul in order. In order to catch hold, not to be swept away, a good method is to concentrate your mind on a great soul, one which sprang up and blossomed in your native soil. Today as I sit in the Tripolitan coffeehouses watching the people and listening to their talk, I sense that if I were a young man living in Tripolis, I would concentrate &#8211; in order to save myself &#8211; upon the rich, aggressive, cunning and valiant soul of Kolokotronis.&#8221; (Nikos Kazantzakis, Journey to the Morea).</p>
<p>Throughout his account of his travels through Greece, Kazantzakis was intrigued by the the substance of people&#8217;s conversations while they sipped coffee. Not even &#8220;sipped,&#8221; but often his subjects would order a coffee, a couple glasses of water, and converse; the sipping of coffee is rarely mentioned in his narrative. The Greeks of the Peloponnesos, awaiting news from Athens, debated politics and the economy; they spoke of struggle, of resistance, of bleak hope. Coffee was the perfect vehicle to deliver such conversations. In the midst of political chaos and uncertainty, the &#8220;kafeneion&#8221; served as the vehicle of mutual gatherings &#8211; whether or not the coffee was consumed was secondary. And the Greeks seemed fond of their glass of cold water with their coffee; reason not elaborated by the author, but indeed for some purpose. Coffee, water and cigarettes, inseparable trio for conversation, at least for the Greeks.</p>
<p><a href="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/adourcoffee1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1143" alt="AdourCoffee" src="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/adourcoffee1-e1360783519175.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Coffee&#8217;s sense of place, and its vehicular role of delivering conversation, does not always lack a rising truth: the quality of the coffee. One speaks of paying for the coffee shop ambiance, the seat and the lights, a gathering place of political discourse. But now more than ever, the &#8220;taste&#8221; of the coffee itself has a sense of &#8220;place.&#8221;</p>
<p>The cold-brewed coffee transforms one&#8217;s perception of the standard morning buzz or after meal coffee; the art of &#8220;culinary coffee&#8221; should be increasingly appreciated. La Colombe Torrefaction, a personal favorite, steeps its dark Corsica blend for sixteen hours in stainless steel wine tanks, resulting in its Pure Black creation with an ultimate clean and crisp coffee. Its subtle cocoa tones rest profoundly on one&#8217;s tongue &#8211; throughout the meal, and specifically with red meat. Coffee and meat, lamb chops or a bone-in rib eye for instance, are excellent partners in crime. The natural sweetness in cold-brew coffee sublimely tosses around the iron and fat in a bloody steak. A few swings of the steak knife and a chug of coffee transports one&#8217;s senses to Brazil, Colombia, Mexico, wherever the coffee beans have been grown and hand-picked.</p>
<p><a href="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/pureblack-e1360779626361.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1137" alt="" src="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/pureblack-e1360779626361.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Culinary coffee allows a profound shift in the &#8220;place&#8221; of coffee. No longer limited to the dabang, the Starbucks, or kafeneion, coffee now roams freely from table to table, across cuisines, to be enjoyed in conjunction with a culture&#8217;s specialty dish or mom&#8217;s home cooking. Coffee&#8217;s notes and flavors are vast and numerous like the Greek gods, each with a variant fury. Matching a bottle of some French wine with a Chilean sea bass (which is, by the way, endangered) drenched in truffle oil should now be as ancient and antiquated like the ruins of Corinth. Culinary matching now breathes in the fresh wisp of fresh-ground coffee or a &#8220;cold one&#8221; from steel wine tanks. The vast bean varieties from growing regions all across the globe presents an unexplored &#8220;black ocean&#8221; within the art of food.</p>
<p>Some say we are what we eat. One must add that we are what we drink, where we drink, and to what purpose we drink to. Coffee signifies place. Valuation shall not be shortchanged only by the beans&#8217; price tag, or with the real estate associated with the chair one sits in to enjoy such coffee. True valuation, like good coffee, shifts &#8211; from table to counter top to cafes and the streets. Where we drink will always add value. With whom we drink always adds conversation, with its own scale of values. What we drink (region, bean, roast, brewing method) levitates our coffee experience beyond our physical presence and transports coffee&#8217;s sense of place to unseen and unknown plateaus. In all aspects, coffee is the medium in which one finds common ground where none previously existed, orating stories of people and their places, echoing those efforts of Homer himself.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1135/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1135&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://i-am-not-a-lawyer.com/2013/02/13/on-coffee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b6c17b88aba4e03bf9c83ac445b2f4d8?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theoriginalsung</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/hawwoondaedrip-e1360781363461.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/adourcoffee1-e1360783519175.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AdourCoffee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theoriginalsung.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/pureblack-e1360779626361.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Lover&#8217;s Paradise</title>
		<link>http://rodalena.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/book-lovers-paradise/</link>
		<comments>http://rodalena.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/book-lovers-paradise/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 03:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>rodalena</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Larry McMurtry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lonesome Dove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peculiar people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quotes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bookstores]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rodalena.wordpress.com/?p=4588</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In Archer, Texas, there's a dusty wonder with a stupid name not too far from the Dairy Queen...<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4588&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rodalena.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/book-lovers-paradise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>106</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8fafc88dc17c5275be1603e9ed92ef58?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rodalena</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rodalena.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mcmurtry-and-booked-up.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Larry McMurtry opens Booked Up</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rodalena.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5987288775_d670b98797.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Not much to look at, but so much to discover</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rodalena.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mcmurtry003.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Larry relaxes in his cave of wonders.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rodalena.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dscn6654.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Two patrons enjoy the atmosphere.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The Other&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://nikalikesmaps.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/the-other/</link>
		<comments>http://nikalikesmaps.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/the-other/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 02:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nika</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the other]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the self]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world signs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comfort zone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice cube]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rooted]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nikalikesmaps.wordpress.com/?p=289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you enter a small get together and know almost no one, you are &#8220;the other.&#8221; When everyone is on the same page, and you&#8217;re behind, you&#8217;re &#8220;the other.&#8221; When everyone knows the lyrics and you don&#8217;t, you&#8217;re &#8220;the other.&#8221; And when you find yourself wandering in a country where everyone but you knows the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_292" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><a href="http://nikalikesmaps.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/signs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-292" alt="A photo that I took in the center of Bordeaux at Place Gambetta ." src="http://nikalikesmaps.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/signs.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A photo that I took in the center of Bordeaux at Place Gambetta .</p></div>
<p>When you enter a small get together and know almost no one, you are &#8220;the other.&#8221; When everyone is on the same page, and you&#8217;re behind, you&#8217;re &#8220;the other.&#8221; When everyone knows the lyrics and you don&#8217;t, you&#8217;re &#8220;the other.&#8221; And when you find yourself wandering in a country where everyone but you knows the language and the culture, you are, surely, &#8220;the other.&#8221; Only in this case, you can&#8217;t simply get to know the small party of mutual friends, or read ahead when you have a free minute, or memorize the lyrics. So, now what?</p>
<p>Now you wait. Wait and live and learn. You can&#8217;t possibly think you&#8217;ll fit in. You&#8217;re like an ice cube in a pot of boiling water: same substance but from different environments. Only humans aren&#8217;t as pure as water. We are more complex, and while the ice cube will become one with the boiling water, a foreigner will always have those moments where he or she feels a bit different. Even those who immigrated at a young age might feel displaced at times.</p>
<p>Now, what does this have to do with studying abroad? Study abroad students are the foreigners, they are &#8220;the others.&#8221; And like any foreigner, when someone feels &#8220;out of their comfort zone&#8221; (as many people like to call the feeling when recounting their abroad experiences), they are actually doing two things: 1) learning about another culture, and 2) understanding their own culture.</p>
<p>I have recently come to realize that if you grow up in a society, you might not know how rooted in it you really are. Sure, there are certain things you don’t agree with and that you detest, but they are familiar. You may know what is polite, what is unacceptable, and when to say “excuse me.” You know how to exist there. Living in a foreign town, you may see just how rooted you are in your culture. But you realize this through another one. In other words, being “the other” might just help you learn about “the self,” yourself.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nikalikesmaps.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/the-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3df3e6f0483bc94bc33d490b47a33d7c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nikakovach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nikalikesmaps.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/signs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A photo that I took in the center of Bordeaux at Place Gambetta .</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Searchers of the Dead</title>
		<link>http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.com/2013/02/11/silent-voices-in-history-the-searchers-of-the-dead/</link>
		<comments>http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.com/2013/02/11/silent-voices-in-history-the-searchers-of-the-dead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 14:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Chirurgeon's Apprentice</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Casebooks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.com/?p=935</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One could hardly imagine a more vile job than examining the putrid, bloated remains of diseased corpses during the early modern period. Yet that is exactly the task that befell the ‘searchers’ of the dead beginning in the 16th century. Who were they? And why do we know so little about them today?    The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=935&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_937" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 307px"><a href="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/76003136.jpg"><img class="wp-image-937     " title="76003136" alt="" src="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/76003136.jpg?w=297&#038;h=176" width="297" height="176" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>The Great Plague of 1665. Crosses mark the doors of the infected and guards prevent anyone from leaving the houses. On the left, female searchers with staffs visit the houses of the dead. In the centre, a person kills a dog, believing it to be the cause of the epidemic.</em></p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style:normal;">One could hardly imagine a more vile job than examining the putrid, bloated remains of diseased corpses during the early modern period. Yet that is exactly the task that befell the ‘searchers’ of the dead beginning in the 16th century. Who were they? And why do we know so little about them today?   </span></em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The searchers are the silent voices behind one of the most important documents on mortality rates in early modern London: the Bills of Mortality. Begun in 1592 as a way of monitoring outbreaks of plague, the Bills of Mortality quickly became a weekly publication which detailed both the number of dead in each parish as well as the cause of death.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The office of the searcher was typically filled by elderly female pensioners in each parish. During this period, church bells tolled alerting the searchers that a death had occurred.  Once the body had been examined, and the cause of death determined, the searchers then reported their findings to the parish clerk where it was then recorded in the Bills of Mortality.</p>
<div id="attachment_3007" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 256px"><a href="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3007  " alt="Bills of Mortality form February 21 -28, 1664. A plague free week. " src="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1.jpg?w=246&#038;h=346" width="246" height="346" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em> Bills of Mortality form February 21 -28, 1664. A plague free week.</em></p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The searcher’s job was certainly unpleasant, but it could also be dangerous. In 1665, Widows Briggs and Manton were appointed searchers and paid 2 shillings a week for inspecting plague-ridden corpses in St Dunstan in the West.<a href="#f1"> [1]</a> During outbreaks when high volumes of people were dying, searchers would walk through the dank, dirty streets shouting: ‘Bring out your dead!’ Those who had succumbed to the disease were piled in carts and carried off to mass burial pits outside the city’s boundaries.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Little is known about the individual lives of these women, but it is not difficult to imagine that some of them contracted diseases as a result of their roles as parish searchers.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In 1768, the Quaker physician John Fothergill wrote: ‘These searchers are, for the most part, ignorant poor women’ with no medical training whatsoever.<a href="#f1"> [2]</a> Perhaps because of this, peculiar causes of death were recorded in the Bills of Mortality: horseshoehead, stoppage in the stomach, twisting of the guts, eaten by lice, and rising of the lights are but some of the strange descriptions that appear periodically in the publication.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">That said, it is worth remembering that medical diagnoses could often be  varied and inconsistent during this period; and it is not to say that contemporary physicians would have been any better at certifying causes of death than the searchers.<a href="#f1"> [3]</a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The searchers’ role in compiling the Bills of Mortality has remained somewhat hidden in history. In 1662, their reputation came under attack by Britain’s first demographer, John Graunt. Because they were elderly pensioners, he questioned their susceptibility towards bribes, especially with regards to recording deaths caused by venereal diseases.</p>
<blockquote><p>Foreasmuch as by the ordinary discourse of the world it seems a great part of men have, at one time, or other, had some <i>species</i> of this disease [syphilis], I wondering why so few died of it&#8230;<a href="#f1"> [4]</a></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Moreover, Graunt was suspicious of their qualifications. Although women were ‘traditional caretakers of the body’ and granted ‘certain expertise in funeral matters’, they were distrusted as public agents.<a href="#f1"> [5]</a></p>
<div id="attachment_3012" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 263px"><a href="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/11.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3012      " alt=" Plague pit, London. " src="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/11.jpg?w=253&#038;h=169" width="253" height="169" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em> Plague pit, London. </em></p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Because of Graunt’s baseless accusations, the searchers have melted  into the background of history while their legacy—the Bills of Mortality—remains a highly visible reminder of the past in which they lived.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Despite the questions around the validity of their recordings, the searchers are undeniably an important part of what we know about death and disease in the early modern period.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Beyond that, their silenced voices speak volumes about historical perceptions of women in roles of authority.</p>
<p><code> </code></p>
<p><a name="f1"></a>1. <em>Epidemic Disease in London</em>, ed. J.A.I. Champion (Centre for Metropolitan History Working Papers Series, No.1, 1993): pp. 35-52.<br />
<a name="f1"></a>2. Richard Hingston Fox, <em>Dr John Fothergill and His Friends: Chapters in 18th Century Life</em> (1919), p. 228.<br />
<a name="f1"></a>3. Gill Newton, &#8216;Parochial Registration and the Bills of Mortality: case studies in the age structure of causes of death in urban areas between 1583 and 1812&#8242;, Paper for BSPS Mortality Past and Present Symposium (29 November 2012).<br />
<a name="f1"></a>4. John Graunt, <em>Natural and Political Observations made upon the Bills of Mortality</em>, in Charles Henry Hull (ed.), <em>The Economic Writings of Sir William Petty</em>, vol. 2 (1899), pp. 321.<br />
<a name="f1"></a>5. Richelle Munkoff, &#8216;Reckoning Death: Women Searchers and the Bills of Mortality&#8217;, in R<em>hetoric of Bodily Disease and Healthy in Medieval and Early Modern England</em> (2010), p. 131.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/935/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/935/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=935&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.com/2013/02/11/silent-voices-in-history-the-searchers-of-the-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/16987643ba006dcf2f1fd171a325947b?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thechirurgeonsapprentice</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/76003136.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">76003136</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bills of Mortality form February 21 -28, 1664. A plague free week. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechirurgeonsapprentice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html"> Plague pit, London. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Minimum Wage Probably Doesn&#8217;t Help</title>
		<link>http://virtuoussociety.com/2013/02/13/the-minimum-wage-probably-doesnt-help/</link>
		<comments>http://virtuoussociety.com/2013/02/13/the-minimum-wage-probably-doesnt-help/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 23:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tom Stringham</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All Entries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://virtuoussociety.com/?p=94</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few posts ago I alluded to the fact that most economists oppose rises in the minimum wage, while non-economists in general support them. I&#8217;m not an economist. But I think we have to take economists seriously, just in case they know something we don&#8217;t. During the State of the Union address last night, President [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=94&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_97" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://virtuoussociety.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/obama-mw.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-97 " alt="Last night Pres. Obama proposed a federal minimum wage of $9/hr." src="http://virtuoussociety.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/obama-mw.jpg?w=300&#038;h=162" width="300" height="162" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Last night, Pres. Obama proposed a federal minimum wage of $9/hr.</p></div>
<p>A few posts ago I alluded to the fact that most economists <a href="http://epionline.org/studies/epi_minimumwage_07-2007.pdf">oppose rises</a> in the minimum wage, while non-economists in general support them. I&#8217;m not an economist. But I think we have to take economists seriously, just in case they know something we don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>During the State of the Union address last night, President Obama told Congress that he would like the federal minimum wage to be $9/hour, instead of $7.25/hour. His reasoning was that it isn&#8217;t right for full-time workers to earn less than $9/hr. That premise isn&#8217;t a bad one&#8211;I think we&#8217;d all like to see wages rise and the standard of living along with it. But the effect of the minimum wage isn&#8217;t generally to raise wages. What it tends to do is cause unemployment among unskilled workers. This is true especially for teenagers, who are new to the labor market and lack experience and skills. In the US, the minimum wage has also been shown to disproportionately hurt minority workers.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the intuition behind it. Imagine the President had proposed raising the minimum wage to $40/hour. You, like just about everyone, would quickly write the idea off as ridiculous. And it would be. Obviously, the costs of employing people would rise so much that employers couldn&#8217;t afford it. They&#8217;d have to lay people off, starting with the least valuable employees&#8211;in other words, the ones whose labor isn&#8217;t worth more $40 to the company. But while not as drastic, minimum wages at any level work on the same principle. If the minimum wage were raised to $9/hour, then workers whose value to the company was less than $9/hour would over time lose their jobs, and companies would hire fewer low-skilled workers.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve sketched out a really simplistic model of the labor market. I don&#8217;t want to get into the involved, jargony theory behind why the minimum wage is thought to reduce employment. So here&#8217;s the empirical data. In 2008, David Neumark and William Wascher published a book titled &#8220;<a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/minimum-wages">Minimum Wages</a>&#8221; that analyzed data from around 100 studies that included short-run and long-run data from many jurisdictions. They concluded that the minimum wage has a modest, but negative effect on employment, and that it especially makes it harder for teenagers and other new workers to find jobs. It has often been theorized that the minimum wage would delay entry into the labor market for new workers and reduce lifetime income for individuals, and the longitudinal data show just that. In other words, if you eventually want a high-paying job, your prospective employer wants you to have experience. But if you aren&#8217;t able to get experience because your base skills aren&#8217;t enough to justify a minimum wage, then the years you spend looking for a job will delay your wage increases throughout your whole life.</p>
<p>Others have analyzed the data since to check Neumark and Wascher&#8217;s findings. <a href="http://www.irle.berkeley.edu/workingpapers/157-07.pdf">One study</a> argues that Neumark and Wascher didn&#8217;t control enough for the differences in different geographic locations, and so the findings turn out a bit differently. But they also conclude that the minimum wage has a modest negative effect on employment which clearly outweighs any wage gains at the margin.</p>
<p>So when you hear voices from Congress (including some surprised Democrats) and the business sector arguing against this increase in the federal minimum wage, it probably doesn&#8217;t mean they don&#8217;t care about the poor. More likely is that they realize that the minimum wage is a well-intentioned but ineffective anti-poverty tool. A more effective way to promote a basic income would be simply to establish a basic income, via a negative income tax or earned income tax credits.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t help myself from liking Pres. Obama, but I really hope the next president is more competent when it comes to economics, whichever party he represents.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=94&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://virtuoussociety.com/2013/02/13/the-minimum-wage-probably-doesnt-help/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb353b501291cb247f9aa1dd5fe56c73?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tomstringham</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://virtuoussociety.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/obama-mw.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Last night Pres. Obama proposed a federal minimum wage of $9/hr.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heart—Posterior View</title>
		<link>http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/heart-posterior-view/</link>
		<comments>http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/heart-posterior-view/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 17:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ltownsdin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amherst Writers & Artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed media art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetic short fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing groups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/?p=357</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Made up of two halves, the heart is divided by the septum. &#160; Where did the rift between us occur? Left subclavian artery or aortic arch? Perhaps the right atrium, always pulsing, pumping out those feelings. &#160; Or was it the oh so superior vena cava? Most likely the inferior. My inferior vena cava has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=357&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Made up of two halves,</p>
<p>the heart is divided by the septum.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Where did the rift between us occur?</p>
<p>Left subclavian artery or aortic arch?</p>
<p>Perhaps the right atrium, always pulsing,</p>
<p>pumping out those feelings.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Or was it the oh so superior vena cava?</p>
<p>Most likely the inferior.</p>
<p>My inferior vena cava has always felt, well, inferior.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After all our history, your footprints</p>
<p>were all over my pericardium.</p>
<p>How could they not be</p>
<p>after confessing every heartbreak</p>
<p>every fear, every shameful secret?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>And each triumph</p>
<p>when shared with you</p>
<p>more meaningful.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When you abandoned me</p>
<p>my left common carotid artery</p>
<p>bled out.</p>
<p>I was half a person</p>
<p>with half a heart.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I blame the septum.</p>
<p>Always divisive, controlling</p>
<p>what comes in and what goes out.</p>
<p>Published in <i>Soul of the Narrator Anthology</i> Vol. III, Fall 2012</p>
<div id="attachment_359" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://lindatownsdin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/009.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-359" alt="Mixed MediaLinda Townsdin" src="http://lindatownsdin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/009.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mixed Media<br />Linda Townsdin</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/357/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/357/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=357&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/heart-posterior-view/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b2a96dbd5126237bb6d3053e7cfb93c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ltownsdin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lindatownsdin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/009.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mixed MediaLinda Townsdin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Loved By Me</title>
		<link>http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/loved-by-me/</link>
		<comments>http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/loved-by-me/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 14:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>SaneSamantha</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/?p=1794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If, like me, you find yourself alone on Valentine’s Day, please do as I do &#8211; treat yourself well. As the spotlight shines down and reveals that you have yet to end your day looking into the eyes of your life’s love, or even that of a mere lover, use the day to look into [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1795" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://sanesamantha.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/lovedbyme.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1795" alt="http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/" src="http://sanesamantha.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/lovedbyme.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/" rel="nofollow">http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/</a></p></div>
<p>If, like me, you find yourself alone on Valentine’s Day, please do as I do &#8211; treat yourself well. As the spotlight shines down and reveals that you have yet to end your day looking into the eyes of your life’s love, or even that of a mere lover, use the day to look into yourself. And when you do, please do so with kindness. Fall in love with you.</p>
<p>It almost seems like a superfluous concept &#8211; to fall in love with one’s self. And yet, it is your self that will follow you wherever you go. It is yourself that will talk to you when no one is there. Your self will damn you. Your self will love you. The belief you have in yourself can cause you to crumble or it can cause you to reach unprecedented heights. The energy and perspective you put into you &#8211; you will receive from you in the form of inner knowing, conviction and peace.</p>
<p>On this day, instead of giving free rein to a mind that critiques and reminds us of our failures, come to peace with those moments when the outcome for which you had most hoped didn’t manifest. Think about giving yourself credit for having survived something that, at the time, felt like death. When you look in the mirror, instead of seeing the effects of time and stress, see a face that has viewed some of the ugliest of circumstances, and yet can radiantly shine when caught up in laughter. And when you look down at your body, try not to see those things that cause you disappointment. Try to remember that your body is giving you it&#8217;s very best, dependent upon what you are giving it. Furthermore, if your body is like mine, it has moved through hell and back, perhaps more than once. And when the time comes that you are confronted with your life’s love, they will see your beauty &#8211; because doing so is inherent to the nature of who they are. A divine love is divinely given, and thus sees the divine in us even when we falter and struggle to see it for ourselves.</p>
<p>Go easy on you. I would recommend that you take every day to treat yourself well. But if not, then please use tomorrow as a celebration of the love you are cultivating for you. Making peace with yourself. Loving your many attributes, thoughts, hopes and dreams is the beginning of the most important relationship one can have &#8211; the one we have with ourself. You will be with you during your greatest successes, your deepest disappointments and upon your final day. And if you are blessed to meet up with your life’s love, you’ll then be coming from a place not of insecurity, but of acceptance. You’ve accepted you, which will allow you to accept them.</p>
<p>I won’t deny that the favorable ending for tomorrow would be in front of a fire or wrapped in the arms of one’s lover. That would be my chosen route. But instead, I will endeavor to treat myself well. I will remind myself of my own beauty. My triumphs. My successes. My gifts. I will also spend the day spoiling me as I would wish to be spoiled by a partner. I will stop off and enjoy the taste of something delectable; its a fair assumption dark chocolate will be involved. I will peruse my favorite boutiques and I will allow my body to get pampered. Most of all, I will go easy on me. And my hope is that you go easy on you. Whether you are loved by many, loved by one or only loved by you &#8211; never forget &#8211; you are quite special.</p>
<p>Sane</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1794/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1794/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/loved-by-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>117</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/510ff7e2048068f20d718f2414c8333f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sanesamantha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sanesamantha.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/lovedbyme.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
