<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:yt="http://gdata.youtube.com/schemas/2007">
   <channel>
      <title>Copy of Digg top 24 hours</title>
      <description>RSS feed with direct links to popular technology articles. based on superdigg pipe</description>
      <link>http://pipes.yahoo.com/pipes/pipe.info?_id=b3933c52bbea1d38fdea3231463e0f8f</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 20:15:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <generator>http://pipes.yahoo.com/pipes/</generator>
      <item>
         <title>[+3950] BP Station Sign! Yes, the Irony</title>
         <link>http://www.flickr.com/photos/therachelmaddowshow/4667450260/sizes/l/</link>
         <description>Spotted at BP station in Ohio</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/environment/BP_Station_Sign_Yes_the_Irony</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 22:52:27 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1928] Massive Flow Of Bullshit Continues To Gush From BP</title>
         <link>http://www.theonion.com/articles/massive-flow-of-bullshit-continues-to-gush-from-bp,17564/?ref=d</link>
         <description>As the crisis in the Gulf of Mexico entered its eighth week Wednesday, fears continued to grow that the massive flow of bullshit still gushing from the headquarters of oil giant BP could prove catastrophic if nothing is done to contain it.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/comedy/Massive_Flow_Of_Bullshit_Continues_To_Gush_From_BP</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 18:59:20 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1711] Chinese Concept: The Train that Never Stops (VID)</title>
         <link>http://www.walyou.com/blog/2010/06/07/non-stop-future-train-concept/</link>
         <description>There have been many different Train concepts that aim to be the future of transportation, adding more speed, more room, more comfort and more features, but what about a new conceptual design looking to create a train that doesn’t need to stop?</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/odd_stuff/Chinese_Concept_The_Train_that_Never_Stops_VID</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 14:24:52 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1540] Girlfriend killed by lightning minutes before BF's proposal</title>
         <link>http://www.wate.com/Global/story.asp?S=12608668</link>
         <description>A Knoxville man was minutes from proposing to his girlfriend on a hike in Western North Carolina Friday when she was struck and killed by lightning.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/odd_stuff/Girlfriend_killed_by_lightning_minutes_before_BF_s_proposal</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 23:25:57 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1448] Nuclear Physicist Describes Vast UFO Cover-Up</title>
         <link>http://www.aolnews.com/weird-news/article/stanton-friedman-a-scientist-searches-for-the-truth-of-ufos/19503350?sms_ss=digg</link>
         <description>&quot;Some UFOs are intelligently controlled extraterrestrial spacecraft, and this is the biggest story of the millennium.&quot; These words are not the rantings of a deranged individual looking for attention or a comfortable straitjacket. Stanton Friedman is a maverick of sorts.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/space/Nuclear_Physicist_Describes_Vast_UFO_Cover_Up</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 06:07:49 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1428] Obama Says To BP &quot;I want to know Whose Ass to Kick&quot;</title>
         <link>http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/3032619/vp/37561786#37561786</link>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/politics/Obama_Says_To_BP_I_want_to_know_Whose_Ass_to_Kick</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 16:08:01 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1311] 8 Abandoned American Theme Parks “Open” for Exploration</title>
         <link>http://www.nileguide.com/blog/2010/05/26/8-abandoned-american-theme-parks-open-for-exploration/</link>
         <description>Tons of new parks litter the country, but many of the old classics, unable to compete with the snazzy new parks have been shut down. Most have been destroyed to make way for housing developments and malls, but a few still remain. Mostly forgotten and in total disrepair, these abandoned amusement parks are sometimes more interesting in their decay</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/travel_places/8_Abandoned_American_Theme_Parks_Open_for_Exploration</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 10:43:30 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1203] Man Busted by Traffic Camera Gets Unique Revenge on Police</title>
         <link>http://www.autoblog.com/2010/06/08/man-busted-by-traffic-camera-gets-unique-revenge-on-police-depar/</link>
         <description>It goes without saying, but we're gonna go ahead and say it anyway: Nobody likes getting a speeding ticket. And that's especially true when said ticket isn't issued by a human officer, but from a machine set up to catch unwary motorists off guard. If only there was some way to get back that lost sense of justice...</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/autos/Man_Busted_by_Traffic_Camera_Gets_Unique_Revenge_on_Police</guid>
         <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 08:52:38 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1009] BP Buys Search Engine Phrases Redirecting Users - ABC News</title>
         <link>http://abcnews.go.com/Technology/Broadcast/bp-buys-search-engine-phrases-redirecting-users/story?id=10835618</link>
         <description>Be careful where you click, especially if you're looking for news on the BP oil spill. BP, the very company responsible for the oil spill that is already the worst in U.S. history, has purchased several phrases on search engines such as Google and Yahoo so that the first result that shows up directs information seekers to the company's official web</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/environment/BP_Buys_Search_Engine_Phrases_Redirecting_Users_ABC_News</guid>
         <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 12:14:15 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+1001] The 50 Hottest Brazilian Women (Pics)</title>
         <link>http://best.complex.com/lists/The-50-Hottest-Brazilian-Women/alice-braga</link>
         <description>Considering that the World Cup starts this week and many people have Brazil as a favorite, here are some of the hottest women from that country who will be celebrating if they take it this year.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/celebrity/The_50_Hottest_Brazilian_Women_Pics</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 11:53:31 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+975] China's First Astronaut Actually Returned Covered in Blood</title>
         <link>http://www.motherboard.tv/2010/6/5/saving-face-china-s-first-astronaut-was-actually-covered-in-blood-when-he-landed</link>
         <description>When China's Central Television network captured Yang Liwei emerging from his space capsule, the country's first astronaut looked tired but happy, and certainly healthy. But he did not return to Earth safely. As Andrew Jacobs reports in yesterday's New York Times...</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/space/China_s_First_Astronaut_Actually_Returned_Covered_in_Blood</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 08:46:09 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+917] Remembering D-Day, 66 years ago (PICS)</title>
         <link>http://www.boston.com/bigpicture/2010/06/remembering_d-day_66_years_ago.html</link>
         <description>Yesterday was June 6th, the 66th anniversary of the successful 1944 Allied invasion of France. Several operations were combined to carry out the largest amphibious invasion in history - over 160,000 troops landed on June 6th, assisted by over 5,000 ships, aerial bombardment, gliders and paratroopers.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/world_news/Remembering_D_Day_66_years_ago_PICS</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 10:13:48 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+869] Black Doctor Arrested Driving To Hospital To Deliver Baby</title>
         <link>http://www.newschannel5.com/global/story.asp?s=12478062</link>
         <description>Police clocked Dr. Terry Wynn's car going 46 in a 30-mile-per-hour zone last Wednesday night. Wynn is an OB/GYN who was on the way to the hospital to deliver a baby.She pulled over, and told the officer she needed to get to hospital. The officer then arrested her at the hospital. Officer is in prior lawsuit for using force on a black witness.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/politics/Black_Doctor_Arrested_Driving_To_Hospital_To_Deliver_Baby</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 01:39:56 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+819] Why Digg is Better Than Reddit</title>
         <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/diggsbymcdiggerson/why-digg-is-better-than-reddit</link>
         <description>Do you dig Digg? Are you sick and tired of Redditors claiming that Digg is dead? Put your fears at ease with this definitive list of reasons why Digg is better than Reddit.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/tech_news/Why_Digg_is_Better_Than_Reddit_5</guid>
         <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 07:32:51 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+753] Fans Support Reporter Fired Over 'Offensive' Views On Israel</title>
         <link>http://newsjunkiepost.com/2010/06/07/facebook-fans-offer-support-to-white-house-reporter-fired-over-offensive-comments/</link>
         <description>An outpouring of support is reflected on the Facebook wall of Helen Thomas' page. Thomas resigned or was dismissed from working as a reporter in the White House for a 'controversial' comment she made denouncing Zionism. The 89-year-old journalist had been working at the White House since 1960...</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/politics/Fans_Support_Reporter_Fired_Over_Offensive_Views_On_Israel</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 12:29:29 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+697] 2013 Super Solar Storm could send us back into the Dark Ages</title>
         <link>http://gawker.com/5556692/the-newest-threat-to-all-human-life-on-earth-solar-storms</link>
         <description>In 1859, a geomagnetic storm sparked by a huge solar flare swept over the Earth. Telegraph wires shorted out and set houses on fire. A brilliant aurora was seen in Hawaii-so bright that &quot;people could read newspapers by its red and green glow.&quot; Scientists predict that in May 2013, the sun's solar cycle will peak at about the same level as in 1859</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/general_sciences/2013_Super_Solar_Storm_could_send_us_back_into_the_Dark_Ages</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 19:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+623] Mr. T blasts 'The A-Team' movie as too violent</title>
         <link>http://movies.msn.com/movies/article.aspx?news=504325&amp;Gt1=28101</link>
         <description>TV hardman Mr. T has slammed the film remake of &quot;The A-Team&quot; for featuring too much sex and violence. After seeing a preview of the film, he says he's shocked with how graphic it is. Mr. T says, &quot;People die in the film and there's plenty of sex but when we did it, no one got hurt and it was all played for fun and family entertainment.&quot;</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/movies/Mr_T_blasts_The_A_Team_movie_as_too_violent</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 10:02:09 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+610] Afghan War Is Now Longest War in U.S. History - ABC News</title>
         <link>http://abcnews.go.com/Politics/afghan-war-now-longest-war-us-history/story?id=10849303</link>
         <description>Today the Afghan war becomes the longest in U.S. history, surpassing the Vietnam War.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/world_news/Afghan_War_Is_Now_Longest_War_in_U_S_History_ABC_News</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 17:09:40 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+605] 74% Oppose Taxing Internet News Sites To Help Newspapers</title>
         <link>http://www.rasmussenreports.com/public_content/business/general_business/june_2010/74_oppose_taxing_internet_news_sites_to_help_newspapers</link>
         <description>The FTC is considering several ways to help the struggling newspaper industry, but Americans strongly reject several proposed taxes to keep privately-owned newspapers going. A new national telephone survey finds that 84% oppose a 3% tax on monthly cell phone bills to help newspapers and traditional journalism. Also, 76% oppose a proposed 5% tax</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/political_opinion/74_Oppose_Taxing_Internet_News_Sites_To_Help_Newspapers</guid>
         <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 09:14:44 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>[+596] Depression Rates Around The...Wait, What!?</title>
         <link>http://i.imgur.com/fnEbh.png</link>
         <description>Some may call this a New World Order. Some may call it WTF. Neither is wrong.</description>
         <guid isPermaLink="false">http://digg.com/comedy/Depression_Rates_Around_The_Wait_What</guid>
         <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 13:48:23 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>
<!-- fe12.pipes.sp1.yahoo.com uncompressed/chunked Tue Jun  8 20:15:06 PDT 2010 -->
