<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://static.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>New Looney Toons Animation</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/f8vk5/new_looney_toons_animation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/f8vk5/new_looney_toons_animation/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 19:33:44 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/aromero&quot;&gt; aromero &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/18968024&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/f8vk5/new_looney_toons_animation/"&gt;[534 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Re: PBS Super Heroes show for Noah</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8v5m/re_pbs_super_heroes_show_for_noah/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8v5m/re_pbs_super_heroes_show_for_noah/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 19:17:15 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had to make a separate reddit post to work this out. Regarding this post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/tb/f8q07&quot; &gt;http://www.reddit.com/tb/f8q07&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;LeakyPenny has had the brilliant idea of making this into a comic that we could send to Noah. I still have the envelope with the return address on it. I have no artistic ability, but I would gladly print it out and mail it to him with a letter explaining how the internet pitched in to make this happen. If you want to contribute post a link here to what you have made. I'll keep you updated on the progress.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit 1: I don't know that it would actually be possible for everyone to contribute to the same storyline. Of course I've got to wait for the content to start rolling in before I worry about how to put it all together. Maybe people could do their own 3 or 4 panel comics for me to mail him. I agree that it is very important for Noah to be included in the comic, whether it be as a robot, masked hero, or something else. Let Reddit run its course and upvote the best ideas... Of course I'm not going to sign my name as Admiral Ballsack when I mail it to him. In this case my screen name is kinda unfortunate, I can't share the popularity of the original post with my coworkers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT 2: A lot of people are saying something along the lines of &quot;I'm an illustrator, I could contribute if you want, or PM me if you're interested&quot; To all of you: yes, I am interested! Have some fun with it. Draw whatever story you'd like. There is no master storyline, so make your own about Super Heroes to the Rescue featuring Noah. I know that it's gonna take a while for people to draw things, so hopefully some art will start coming in this evening. We also have a subreddit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/totherescue&quot; &gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/totherescue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit 3: Redditor GaryDennisDouglas has given us a fantastic tagline. I propose that the official title be Super Heroes to the Rescue: Network Of Awesome Heroes. If you agree then find his comment and upvote&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The subreddit has been deleted, surely due to an automation error. Thanks everyone for reporting it so quickly to the powers that be. Hopefully it'll be back up soon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/AdmiralBallsack&quot;&gt; AdmiralBallsack &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/f8v5m/re_pbs_super_heroes_show_for_noah/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8v5m/re_pbs_super_heroes_show_for_noah/"&gt;[638 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Level 85 Shaman, you win</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91o1/level_85_shaman_you_win/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91o1/level_85_shaman_you_win/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:30:41 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91o1/level_85_shaman_you_win/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f91o1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Level 85 Shaman, you win&quot; title=&quot;Level 85 Shaman, you win&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Shadow703793&quot;&gt; Shadow703793 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/o9FGq.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91o1/level_85_shaman_you_win/"&gt;[419 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Level 85 Shaman, you win</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f91o1.png" /></item><item><title>Vermont measure calls for constitutional amendment declaring &quot;corporations are not persons under the laws of the United States.&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/f8rii/vermont_measure_calls_for_constitutional/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/f8rii/vermont_measure_calls_for_constitutional/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:36:19 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/johnji&quot;&gt; johnji &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.commondreams.org/headline/2011/01/25-4&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/f8rii/vermont_measure_calls_for_constitutional/"&gt;[441 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>reddit a revolution is starting strongly in Egypt, we need your help to get the word out, the government is controlling the media nothing is going out.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8pts/reddit_a_revolution_is_starting_strongly_in_egypt/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8pts/reddit_a_revolution_is_starting_strongly_in_egypt/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 15:14:09 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will find a lot of info &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/RNN.NEWS&quot; &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, it could be in arabic so you will have to use translate.google.com. Please reddit get the word out, you will find pictures and videos posted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter is blocked right now, probably facebook later that's how people managed to organize this. Right now I am trying to make a guide how to use proxys, if anyone could help me with any other simpler way I would appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit:&lt;/em&gt; The reason why I posted this in the first place was because there wasn't anything mentioned on any news networks local or worldwide, that's including aljazeera, later they all started following news posted by RNN.NEWS on facebook - the link is on top of topic -&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also another reason was that there were threats of live rounds being shot around and I was afraid people would get wiped out without anyone covering it, which is something the Egyptian government is capable of. So I did what I could.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I will try to update as much as I can&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Main demands:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Reconvening of the People's Assembly&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Repealing martial law which is overdue by more than 30 years.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Maximum of 2 terms for the president&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Setting a minimum for wages of 1200 local pounds.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Sacking of minister of interior affairs.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;Excuse my grammar and english, I am pretty tired.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The main protest in &lt;a href=&quot;http://ar.justin.tv/cairowitness?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=like_button_experiment&amp;amp;utm_medium=test#/w/797816992&quot; &gt;AlTahrir Square&lt;/a&gt;(stream is down) is still holding, they cut off all supplies from them, including mobile network. &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/hX6Mo.jpg&quot; &gt;pic1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/eFI9i.jpg&quot; &gt;pic2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmed&lt;/strong&gt; news that food and water and tents are getting through to protestors in AlTahrir.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Live ammunation is being fired in Suez, Alexandria and Ismailya.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;First death in Suez, 20 year old Moustafa Reda Mahmoud.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Second death in suez, 31 year old Soliman Saber Aly.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Sources say army units are being dispatched in Cairo and Alexandria.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmed&lt;/strong&gt; sources that Gamal Moubarak - the president's son - have fled with his wife along with 97 bags of luggage to london, along with Alaa Moubarak(the other son), and Moubarak's wife Souzan. They are all in London.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;After live ammunation being shot in Alexandaria and crowds were scattered, they are regrouping right now and it's said the numbers are in 7000 right now.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Protests organized for early tomorrow morning everywhere in egypt.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Right now people in Alexandria are gathering at Library of Alexandria &lt;em&gt;unconfirmed&lt;/em&gt; reports say that they are in 15,000.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In Ismailya people are gathering near A stadium there, numbers are in the 30,000.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;A lot of protestors are being captured right now in cairo.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unconfirmed - Curfew announced in cairo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Seems facebook is starting to go down, pictures are starting to not load. Ehm anon, help?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Any protests after 11:15, it's 11:16 right now while writing, live rounds are forced to be shot on civilians. They want to stop the protests before tomorrow morning.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;CNN reports an average of 750,000 were in protests today. A lot more are preparing for tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Kafr ElSheikh overuse of power is being used against protestors, teargas grenades are being fired.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; BREAKING: If protestors refuse to move out of AlTahrir Square live rounds will be shot on them&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Medical aid requested by civilians in AlTahrir Square&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far it seems no rounds shot on people at AlTahrir and protests around the area are gathering to enter the square.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;12 AM and no news for about 30 minutes from AlTahrir Square.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Overuse of force in Mahla, reports of injuries and no clear numbers yet.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;A redditor made a video for how to use proxies here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GTY4uEOtVY0&quot; &gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GTY4uEOtVY0&lt;/a&gt; . He asked for his name not to be mentioned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A lot of updates could be found here as well: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frequency.com/topic/egypt?raw=true&quot; &gt;http://www.frequency.com/topic/egypt?raw=true&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Police forces waited till it's late night and talk shows are over and most likely people went to sleep and they started using force against civilians in AlTahrir Square, I will update when I have more details.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teargas grenades are raining on people&lt;/strong&gt;, new stream up with an extremely bad quality.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrests everywhere around AlTahrir Square for anyone who was trying to join in&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources say that some of the protestors are getting scattered to nearby streets from the amount of teargas&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unconfirmed&lt;/em&gt; Protestors had to move from AlTahrir Square to another square 400 meters away Abd ElMen'm Reyad Sq, some of them got arrested in that move.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Electric shock rods are being used, people can't see anything from the smoke. Anyone the police lay their hands on is put under arrest.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Protestors trying to organize themselves and gathering in together again.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The arrests the police are doing now is unconstitutional, they are kidnapping civilians who have the right to protest.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excessive use of force against protestors continue. The government have prepared speeches and files that the Muslims brotherhood is behind everything that happened today which is not true. They were a partial part of it, people at AlTahrir Square were normal civilians who had absolutely nothing to do with any party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet is starting to get really dodgy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Reports of usage of rubber bullets.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmed&lt;/strong&gt; Third death 44 years old Ghareeb el sayed.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Protestors regathering at Ramses Square, it's said their numbers are in 15,000.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Reports of live bullets being used.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Street wars in Alexandria between security forces and Civilians, in a major street called Port Said Street.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Suez it's getting heated in streets and reports that civilians started attacking the police.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Ramses Square Protest moving towards a crowded cairo area called Shubra, It's not over.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police are following protestors in armored cars shooting both live and rubber bullets on them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sorry internet connection problems!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Insider sources from police forces soldiers are exhausted both physically and morally&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;More and more people going down the streets.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In AlTahrir people were organised and peacefull, they didn't destroy or burn anything. They were even collecting their garbage.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Unconfirmed news Ministry reform within hours.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;People gathered in front of Ministry of internal affairs building and unconfirmed news they are taking control over the national TV building. (They were airing some show about dolphins an hour ago)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Again internet problems, police can't control anything anywhere right now. Dawn is soon and I can see organized demonstrations happening tomorrow(well today, it's 4am right now) everywhere.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Callmeces&quot;&gt; Callmeces &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/f8pts/reddit_a_revolution_is_starting_strongly_in_egypt/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8pts/reddit_a_revolution_is_starting_strongly_in_egypt/"&gt;[1144 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>This looks healthy.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f8tnz/this_looks_healthy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f8tnz/this_looks_healthy/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/ButtonSmasher&quot;&gt; ButtonSmasher &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/peIIt.gif&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f8tnz/this_looks_healthy/"&gt;[1043 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Seriously, Reddit, who the fuck out there watches Two and a Half Men?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f924y/seriously_reddit_who_the_fuck_out_there_watches/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f924y/seriously_reddit_who_the_fuck_out_there_watches/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:58:09 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's not just a rhetorical question. If you watch and enjoy this program I would like to know why. I just can't wrap my mind around how this show has been so successful for 8 years and the actors, including the &quot;half&quot; man are raking in over a million an episode while brilliant shows are being cancelled all the time. I just don't get it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Caramel_is_God&quot;&gt; Caramel_is_God &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/f924y/seriously_reddit_who_the_fuck_out_there_watches/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f924y/seriously_reddit_who_the_fuck_out_there_watches/"&gt;[515 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tunisia-like riots now breaking out in Egypt</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/f8ppd/tunisialike_riots_now_breaking_out_in_egypt/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/f8ppd/tunisialike_riots_now_breaking_out_in_egypt/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 15:03:34 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/mrajt&quot;&gt; mrajt &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/egyptian-riot-photos-2011-1#&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/f8ppd/tunisialike_riots_now_breaking_out_in_egypt/"&gt;[641 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>What if Visual Studio had Achievements?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/f8phd/what_if_visual_studio_had_achievements/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/f8phd/what_if_visual_studio_had_achievements/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 14:43:54 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/rudib&quot;&gt; rudib &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot;&gt; programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.whiletrue.com/2011/01/what-if-visual-studio-had-achievements/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/f8phd/what_if_visual_studio_had_achievements/"&gt;[407 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Robots that are forced to learn how to 'crawl' before they learn to 'walk' are able to learn to walk faster than robots that begin upright.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/f8t25/robots_that_are_forced_to_learn_how_to_crawl/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/f8t25/robots_that_are_forced_to_learn_how_to_crawl/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 17:45:40 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/vints1&quot;&gt; vints1 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&quot;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.discovery.com/tech/robot-revolution-on-the-way.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/f8t25/robots_that_are_forced_to_learn_how_to_crawl/"&gt;[141 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>&quot;It is awful&quot; to prosecute a 15-year-old girl who told a rape lie that got a boy arrested, says women's rights advocate</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8wq3/it_is_awful_to_prosecute_a_15yearold_girl_who/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8wq3/it_is_awful_to_prosecute_a_15yearold_girl_who/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 20:24:56 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/PierceHarlan&quot;&gt; PierceHarlan &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://falserapesociety.blogspot.com/2011/01/it-is-awful-to-prosecute-15-year-old.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8wq3/it_is_awful_to_prosecute_a_15yearold_girl_who/"&gt;[507 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Relationships &amp; Forever Alone: The Truth</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8zsh/relationships_forever_alone_the_truth/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8zsh/relationships_forever_alone_the_truth/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 22:48:40 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8zsh/relationships_forever_alone_the_truth/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8zsh.png&quot; alt=&quot;Relationships &amp;amp; Forever Alone: The Truth&quot; title=&quot;Relationships &amp;amp; Forever Alone: The Truth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/rscotta&quot;&gt; rscotta &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/P2dDO&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8zsh/relationships_forever_alone_the_truth/"&gt;[202 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Relationships &amp; Forever Alone: The Truth</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8zsh.png" /></item><item><title>The Earth at Night - NASA's Visible Earth</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/f8zkl/the_earth_at_night_nasas_visible_earth/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/f8zkl/the_earth_at_night_nasas_visible_earth/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 22:38:03 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/chbrules&quot;&gt; chbrules &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&quot;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/KICe6.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/f8zkl/the_earth_at_night_nasas_visible_earth/"&gt;[58 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Woot showing Reddit some Love'</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8vlo/woot_showing_reddit_some_love/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8vlo/woot_showing_reddit_some_love/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 19:35:27 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/kENNy95SI&quot;&gt; kENNy95SI &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/MRba6&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/f8vlo/woot_showing_reddit_some_love/"&gt;[146 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Am I being an ass charging my GF rent?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f8t3b/am_i_being_an_ass_charging_my_gf_rent/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f8t3b/am_i_being_an_ass_charging_my_gf_rent/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 17:46:47 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am buying a house next month. My girlfriend of 2 years is going to be living with me. (She's actually lived with me on and off during those 2 years, and helped pay rent for the last 4 months) She's still in school and living off student loans. She works, but not really enough to support her. I can pay the mortgage by myself, but my job is pretty much commission, so some months are dry and others are quite good.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My GF's dad thinks that because she is not on the title to the house, that basically by asking her with help on the mortgage that I'm taking advantage of her. (And that if we break up, she loses all the money she put into the house)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I honestly don't see the problem, because if we weren't living together, she would either be paying $500/mo in rent to live somewhere else (which she wouldn't get back anyway), or living with her parents (impossible because it's 2hrs away from her school).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The only thing I can figure is her dad is still stuck in the &quot;men are supposed to bring home the bacon and be providers&quot; mentality. He is 60ish, so this wouldn't surprise me. I don't know, I honestly feel bad about the situation now, and I don't know why her dad is making these accusations of me taking advantage of her.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Is asking your live-in GF to help pay your mortgage wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/sgtmeow&quot;&gt; sgtmeow &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/f8t3b/am_i_being_an_ass_charging_my_gf_rent/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f8t3b/am_i_being_an_ass_charging_my_gf_rent/"&gt;[2991 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>A girl called me a pedophile for refusing to go down on her until she trimmed or shaved her massive bush.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f8t24/a_girl_called_me_a_pedophile_for_refusing_to_go/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f8t24/a_girl_called_me_a_pedophile_for_refusing_to_go/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 17:45:40 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is she crazy, or am I an asshole?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I don't think it's an unreasonable request since I keep myself trimmed, I expect the same. She was furious though, and called me a pedophile, among other things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: To clarify, she's 20 years old, so it's not like she's got some sexy MILF action going on and an afro-bush is just the style that was popular when she was growing up. And hers is bad. We're talking worse than 70s porn bad. There could be a bird sanctuary in there and I wouldn't know.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: For those interested in the wording of the conversation, she was necking on me and whispered in my ear, &quot;Will you go down on me?&quot; I replied, &quot;No, not until you trim or shave.&quot; Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: In all fairness, I probably didn't need to include the &quot;am I an asshole?&quot; part. I know I am. And there's a lot of repeat stuff in here, but one thing that seems to need clarification is that she is not my girlfriend, nor are we dating, nor is/was she a one night stand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: Seriously, some of you are failing to comprehend the massiveness of the bush I am trying to describe. Imagine Angela David being scalped and having that stitched to this girl's nether regions. This is not an ordinary &quot;au naturale&quot; look. This is going above and beyond the call of bush duty. This thing could replace a small dam, or be substituted as fabric in a suit. This is not some adorable dainty bush. This is a full on monster vag-fro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Sex_Panther&quot;&gt; Sex_Panther &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/f8t24/a_girl_called_me_a_pedophile_for_refusing_to_go/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/f8t24/a_girl_called_me_a_pedophile_for_refusing_to_go/"&gt;[1621 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I work at a PBS station, and this arrived in the mail today</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8q07/i_work_at_a_pbs_station_and_this_arrived_in_the/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8q07/i_work_at_a_pbs_station_and_this_arrived_in_the/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 15:30:02 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8q07/i_work_at_a_pbs_station_and_this_arrived_in_the/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8q07.png&quot; alt=&quot;I work at a PBS station, and this arrived in the mail today&quot; title=&quot;I work at a PBS station, and this arrived in the mail today&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/AdmiralBallsack&quot;&gt; AdmiralBallsack &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/gF7Zq.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8q07/i_work_at_a_pbs_station_and_this_arrived_in_the/"&gt;[784 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>I work at a PBS station, and this arrived in the mail today</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8q07.png" /></item><item><title>Don't forget to collect your heart!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91kv/dont_forget_to_collect_your_heart/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91kv/dont_forget_to_collect_your_heart/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:25:46 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91kv/dont_forget_to_collect_your_heart/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f91kv.png&quot; alt=&quot;Don't forget to collect your heart!&quot; title=&quot;Don't forget to collect your heart!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/kero6661&quot;&gt; kero6661 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://dalia.deviantart.com/art/hearts-194885160&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f91kv/dont_forget_to_collect_your_heart/"&gt;[38 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Don't forget to collect your heart!</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f91kv.png" /></item><item><title>Cool Nintendo facts.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f8u01/cool_nintendo_facts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f8u01/cool_nintendo_facts/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 18:28:10 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f8u01/cool_nintendo_facts/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8u01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cool Nintendo facts.&quot; title=&quot;Cool Nintendo facts.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/dick_hole2&quot;&gt; dick_hole2 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xNubU.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/f8u01/cool_nintendo_facts/"&gt;[511 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Cool Nintendo facts.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8u01.png" /></item><item><title>This isn't exactly the party I had pictured.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f91as/this_isnt_exactly_the_party_i_had_pictured/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f91as/this_isnt_exactly_the_party_i_had_pictured/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:10:08 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/pennNteller&quot;&gt; pennNteller &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/zWk54.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f91as/this_isnt_exactly_the_party_i_had_pictured/"&gt;[54 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Learning the solar system [IMG]</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f9292/learning_the_solar_system_img/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f9292/learning_the_solar_system_img/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 01:04:17 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f9292/learning_the_solar_system_img/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f9292.png&quot; alt=&quot;Learning the solar system [IMG]&quot; title=&quot;Learning the solar system [IMG]&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/thaitea&quot;&gt; thaitea &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/SzD8X.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f9292/learning_the_solar_system_img/"&gt;[60 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Learning the solar system [IMG]</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f9292.png" /></item><item><title>&quot;It is awful&quot; to prosecute a 15-year-old girl who told a rape lie that got a boy arrested, says women's rights advocate</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f8wpi/it_is_awful_to_prosecute_a_15yearold_girl_who/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f8wpi/it_is_awful_to_prosecute_a_15yearold_girl_who/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 20:24:27 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/PierceHarlan&quot;&gt; PierceHarlan &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://falserapesociety.blogspot.com/2011/01/it-is-awful-to-prosecute-15-year-old.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f8wpi/it_is_awful_to_prosecute_a_15yearold_girl_who/"&gt;[131 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Egyptian protester faces a water canon vehicle solo.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/f8qus/an_egyptian_protester_faces_a_water_canon_vehicle/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/f8qus/an_egyptian_protester_faces_a_water_canon_vehicle/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:10:17 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/anasqtiesh&quot;&gt; anasqtiesh &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kWr6MypZ-JU&amp;amp;feature=player_detailpage#t=77s&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/f8qus/an_egyptian_protester_faces_a_water_canon_vehicle/"&gt;[171 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>It's a tree with teeth and an axe. It looks fairly angry.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f913k/its_a_tree_with_teeth_and_an_axe_it_looks_fairly/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f913k/its_a_tree_with_teeth_and_an_axe_it_looks_fairly/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 23:58:32 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/aristotle2600&quot;&gt; aristotle2600 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xrzj9.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/f913k/its_a_tree_with_teeth_and_an_axe_it_looks_fairly/"&gt;[28 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>My groom's cake is hereby submitted for your approval.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8ycj/my_grooms_cake_is_hereby_submitted_for_your/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8ycj/my_grooms_cake_is_hereby_submitted_for_your/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 21:40:20 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8ycj/my_grooms_cake_is_hereby_submitted_for_your/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8ycj.png&quot; alt=&quot;My groom's cake is hereby submitted for your approval.&quot; title=&quot;My groom's cake is hereby submitted for your approval.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/yeahhtoast&quot;&gt; yeahhtoast &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/JylaH&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/f8ycj/my_grooms_cake_is_hereby_submitted_for_your/"&gt;[84 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>My groom's cake is hereby submitted for your approval.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_f8ycj.png" /></item></channel></rss>