<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://static.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>Dear Mr. Haberny... Sincerely, Cash4Gold</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eg83m/dear_mr_haberny_sincerely_cash4gold/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eg83m/dear_mr_haberny_sincerely_cash4gold/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:34:58 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eg83m/dear_mr_haberny_sincerely_cash4gold/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_eg83m.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dear Mr. Haberny... Sincerely, Cash4Gold&quot; title=&quot;Dear Mr. Haberny... Sincerely, Cash4Gold&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/tobiasgreenich&quot;&gt; tobiasgreenich &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/or2dv&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eg83m/dear_mr_haberny_sincerely_cash4gold/"&gt;[774 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Dear Mr. Haberny... Sincerely, Cash4Gold</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_eg83m.png" /></item><item><title>My ideal cast for the next L4D</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/egago/my_ideal_cast_for_the_next_l4d/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/egago/my_ideal_cast_for_the_next_l4d/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 22:35:15 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/egago/my_ideal_cast_for_the_next_l4d/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_egago.png&quot; alt=&quot;My ideal cast for the next L4D&quot; title=&quot;My ideal cast for the next L4D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Knov&quot;&gt; Knov &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/Y9BSN&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/egago/my_ideal_cast_for_the_next_l4d/"&gt;[311 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>My ideal cast for the next L4D</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_egago.png" /></item><item><title>Fuck you Matt Drudge, you right wing shill.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eg7j3/fuck_you_matt_drudge_you_right_wing_shill/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eg7j3/fuck_you_matt_drudge_you_right_wing_shill/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:54:39 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/BeliefSuspended2008&quot;&gt; BeliefSuspended2008 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/sKM1M.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eg7j3/fuck_you_matt_drudge_you_right_wing_shill/"&gt;[529 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I think the hive mind has made us blind to the dowside of what Wikileaks has done and I'd like to have an honest conversation about it.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg7l4/i_think_the_hive_mind_has_made_us_blind_to_the/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg7l4/i_think_the_hive_mind_has_made_us_blind_to_the/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:58:27 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realize I'm going to get a lot of flack for this but after a conversation with my very liberal father last night I think my enthusiasm and respect for what Wikileaks has done is fading. Here's why:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As some of us are willing to accept, politics is a complicated and slow game. We try to elect politicians that we trust and respect like Barack Obama. We give them an amazingly difficult job to do and inevitably they end up in situations in which they have to make bad decisions because there simply aren't any good ones. It's easy for us as inexperienced spectators to say &quot;Well why didn't you just do this? Why didn't you just close Guantanamo? Why didn't you just prosecute Bush and Cheney for war crimes or why didn't you get a backbone and stand up to the Republicans on health care?&quot; But the reality is that these issues are vastly more complicated than we could possibly understand as people who have never been in that type of leadership role. We elect people who are more experienced with these things than us because it is impossible for those who haven't studied politics to see the bigger picture and fully understand and weigh the repercussions of these decisions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The natural argument against that is obviously, well that's why we need to know more information. But I think we're giving ourselves a little too much credit for being able to truly piece together this information. Certainly we needed to know the truth about the Iraq war, about torture and true corruption. But I ask, what have the recently leaked documents told us about that? What revelations did they bring besides things we already pretty much knew? More importantly, what information did they expose that was unnecessary for us to know?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think many would agree that in world politics certain information has to stay at the top not just for national security reasons but because as I said before the general public is simply not qualified to disseminate it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What the leaks have done is put our government in a truly awful diplomatic situation. If we thought foreign relations were tricky before in many places they will be nearly impossible to rectify now. And for what? A little gossip that exposed that at the top people are still just people who gossip? How does this help us? More importantly what are the consequences of this damaged diplomacy? Do we truly understand the significance of our ability to find cooperation in the global community? Do we truly understand the United States importance as a moderator in world conflict? How will our damaged credibility affect our ability to work for peace in foreign regions of the world?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I certainly feel that our media needs to do a much better job of keeping us informed. It's an understatement to say that they dropped the ball during the Bush leadership. But these leaked documents did not serve to make us more informed individuals capable of making better choices in who we elect. If anything they've drawn our attention away from the real issues and further confused our understanding of the political process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Symbolically the leaks seem noble and I honestly do not know what Jullian Assange and his team's intention and beliefs were when they decided to release them. But there is a responsible way to blow whistles and there is a time and place for it. I would certainly argue that Ellsberg releasing the Pentagon Papers was such and that we needed someone like him during the recent mideastern wars. What Wikileaks did was not that however. No matter how much they believed what they were doing was right they have caused significant damage that in my opinion does not outweigh the supposed transparency it brought.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I speak to you as a student of political advocacy. I am just as frustrated as the next person with the seemingly ineffective US government. But I also recognize progress that the Obama administration has made and try my best to put it into historical context while understanding that making policy never has or will be easy nor will it happen overnight. Often times I am disheartened by the knee jerk reactions to politics that happen on reddit, that seems to occur with little debate and spread until we become just as extreme as the extremism we claim to detest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I hope that rather than downvoting my opposing opinion, people will use this as a place to truly think about and articulate why they agree or disagree with me. I am certainly open to the suggestion that perhaps I'm missing something. I just ask that people think before they jump on one bandwagon of thought. We know it happens too often on reddit and we're better than that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: I'd like to mention that within 30 seconds of posting this I've been downvoted twice. That's no where near enough time to read my argument.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT 2: D: dowNside&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT 3: Wow, I'm truly impressed with the response here and people's willingness to support political discourse over their own personal opinions on the topic. I've noticed a couple themes in the responses that I wanted to address. First the top comment suggests that I'm looking at this too much as an American issue. I see now that it did sound that way however my motives come from my fear of the damage these leaks could do to other parts of the world primarily. While right now they may seem harmless, there very well may a butterfly effect that occurs from some of the damaged diplomacy. Things that we can't necessarily measure but will in fact be a result of people not talking to each other over this. Like many others I was initially pleased to see the US government take some heat. They do need to be kept in check and reminded that they cannot get away with as much as they thought. I don't believe however that that embarrassment outweighs the consequences of the leaks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Secondly, and although these are the minority, I am getting a lot of scary responses from people completely unwilling to look at this as an issue up for debate. One user said something like &quot;if you are against wikileaks you are not a true patriot&quot;. This is exactly the type of extremism I was referring too. One of the keystones of Liberalism is a view that the world is not black and white. Too often we claim to be open minded yet we subscribe to the same self serving dogma that our opposition does. These &quot;if you are against this you hate America&quot; arguments are not just conservative they are fascist and many atrocities have happened under their premise. Most issues do not just have two sides but multiple. How can we find the best solution to problems if we close ourselves off to any that we do not immediately understand or see for that matter?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With that said I wanted to mention again how pleased I am that this made it to the front page. I never thought it would get off the ground but it's a testament to reddit's true colors. Thank you all for considering another view point and in some cases questioning what you believe. It's a more difficult and rarer thing than I think we realize.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/madelinecn&quot;&gt; madelinecn &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/eg7l4/i_think_the_hive_mind_has_made_us_blind_to_the/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg7l4/i_think_the_hive_mind_has_made_us_blind_to_the/"&gt;[1354 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Do not Fuck with the electronics rule.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg75k/do_not_fuck_with_the_electronics_rule/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg75k/do_not_fuck_with_the_electronics_rule/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:27:49 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/mangeof&quot;&gt; mangeof &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/mmsH5.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg75k/do_not_fuck_with_the_electronics_rule/"&gt;[703 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>&quot;Reporters Without Borders condemns the blocking, cyber-attacks and political pressure being directed at cablegate.wikileaks.org&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eg7se/reporters_without_borders_condemns_the_blocking/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eg7se/reporters_without_borders_condemns_the_blocking/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:13:08 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/AIMMOTH&quot;&gt; AIMMOTH &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.rsf.org/wikileaks-hounded-04-12-2010,38958.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eg7se/reporters_without_borders_condemns_the_blocking/"&gt;[61 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Best writeup I've seen so far on Arsenic life.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/eg70a/best_writeup_ive_seen_so_far_on_arsenic_life/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/eg70a/best_writeup_ive_seen_so_far_on_arsenic_life/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:17:07 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/kleinbl00&quot;&gt; kleinbl00 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&quot;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://pipeline.corante.com/archives/2010/12/02/life_with_arsenic_whod_have_thought.php&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/eg70a/best_writeup_ive_seen_so_far_on_arsenic_life/"&gt;[108 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Help make my mom's Christmas extra special this year, Reddit. In the 80's my mom was in a commercial that aired on MTV. I am searching, but getting nowhere fast.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg6b2/help_make_my_moms_christmas_extra_special_this/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg6b2/help_make_my_moms_christmas_extra_special_this/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 17:28:13 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;My mom was in a commercial around 1983-1984. It was her only TV appearance ever, and it aired on MTV. She often speaks about how she would REALLY like to see this video again, and she has been so depressed recently due to the cold, winter weather. So I have been on a mad witch hunt to figure this out. Unfortunately, my searching has started leading me in the right direction, but I am still hitting some road blocks. Here is all the relevant information I know:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The commercial was for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nortonsflowers.com/&quot; &gt;Norton's Flowers&lt;/a&gt;, and it aired on MTV&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;It aired around 1983-1984&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In the commercial my mom is holding a planter, and showing it to a customer. She does not say anything, but she does make an appearance. She has curly hair.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The original owner of Norton's Flowers, Dennis Norton, sold the business in 1998.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;I have found Mr. Norton on Facebook, and contacted him. He says the local cable company would have been the one who filmed everything, but he does not remember the name of the company it was filmed with.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Mr. Norton is [currently] searching his old records for any information, since he remembers my mom very well, but so far nothing has turned up that will help.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;That's all the necessary information I can recall right now, but if there is something else I can provide that will help, just tell me. It would really be special if I could find this for my mom. If not a copy I can gift to her, at least a copy I can show to her. It would really be a blast to the past that would make her very happy. If anybody has ANY information, or suggestions, please share so I can perhaps get a little bit closer to maybe at least getting a solid yes/no answer on if this is even possible in the first place.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 1&lt;/strong&gt; Wow, thank you so much Reddit. Your spirit truly never ceases to amaze me. The amount of help I have received so far is without a doubt mind-boggling. I feel like I am getting closer and closer to an answer, and I am still waiting on some outstanding e-mails and chats that I have out right now. Also, I have a couple more ideas and things to check before I even think of resting on this issue.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Reddit, even if I don't find the video, this thread alone will be enough to make my mom swell up with emotion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2&lt;/strong&gt; I sent a message to Mr. Norton with the information Reddit has helped me gather, and he has informed me that the company involved was Mediaone! It went from Columbia Cable, to 4Star, to unknown company, and then Mediaone, right before Comcast bought it out! He guesses it would of been Mediaone that he advertised with during that time. This is great news, since it gives me a concrete lead to go off of.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I APPRECIATE EVERYTHING REDDIT HAS DONE! YOU ALL ARE AMAZING! The search is definitely not over, but I have made some progress! All thanks to you guys/girls/aliens, couldn't have done it without you. Next step is contacting this company and seeing what they can do! Once again, thank you so much Reddit! You lot are fantastic, you really are. There isn't enough karma on the whole of Reddit that would be enough for me to give all of you!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2.5&lt;/strong&gt; The owner, and co-founder of Media One Inc is John Fiksdal. Goal is now to find out contact information for him, since he would have the information I need, I believe. He doesn't have a Facebook, and all the background sites require me to pay money to get any usable information. Might have to wait until Monday to contact him, via his business when it opens. Any information regarding this man would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/TheBlackCracka&quot;&gt; TheBlackCracka &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/eg6b2/help_make_my_moms_christmas_extra_special_this/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg6b2/help_make_my_moms_christmas_extra_special_this/"&gt;[139 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Laptop + Processing[software] + Camera + motorized curtain = store front window curtain that magically follows passersby and confounds them</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/eg4i6/laptop_processingsoftware_camera_motorized/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/eg4i6/laptop_processingsoftware_camera_motorized/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 14:05:52 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/jlpoole&quot;&gt; jlpoole &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot;&gt; programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niklasroy.com/project/88/my-little-piece-of-privacy/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/eg4i6/laptop_processingsoftware_camera_motorized/"&gt;[112 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hey Reddit, I made a clone of reddit to help with the load - redditclone.com</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/egan6/hey_reddit_i_made_a_clone_of_reddit_to_help_with/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/egan6/hey_reddit_i_made_a_clone_of_reddit_to_help_with/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 22:48:35 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/VodkaCranberry&quot;&gt; VodkaCranberry &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redditclone.com/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/egan6/hey_reddit_i_made_a_clone_of_reddit_to_help_with/"&gt;[53 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ron Paul: ‘What we need is more WikiLeaks’</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg4v2/ron_paul_what_we_need_is_more_wikileaks/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg4v2/ron_paul_what_we_need_is_more_wikileaks/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 14:41:26 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/mnbvi&quot;&gt; mnbvi &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2010/12/ron-paul-what-wikileaks/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg4v2/ron_paul_what_we_need_is_more_wikileaks/"&gt;[620 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>So Reddit, I own lieberman2012.com, what should I do with it?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg7qc/so_reddit_i_own_lieberman2012com_what_should_i_do/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg7qc/so_reddit_i_own_lieberman2012com_what_should_i_do/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 19:09:18 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current plan is to redirect to wikileaks but I'm open to other suggestions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: some great ideas so far. Whatever the case, looks like I'm going to need to lawyer up (and maybe hit the gym) so I can avoid any charge of libel. As long as I provide sources for any statements I should be clear right?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT 2: It seems cybersquatting laws center on &quot;bad faith&quot; and an attempt to profit from the value of the name. The question therefore is whether, in terms of &quot;profit&quot;, the law draws a distinction between having regular ads on the site and making a site with the sole intent to sell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/droopydog&quot;&gt; droopydog &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/eg7qc/so_reddit_i_own_lieberman2012com_what_should_i_do/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg7qc/so_reddit_i_own_lieberman2012com_what_should_i_do/"&gt;[330 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I lost 100 pounds...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg93v/i_lost_100_pounds/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg93v/i_lost_100_pounds/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 20:50:54 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently made it past this amazing milestone and I'm wanting to mark it with a tattoo. I have been looking for ideas for how it should be presented but haven't found anything that isn't ridiculously tacky. Any ideas?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some photographic proof: &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/MHqlf&quot; &gt;http://imgur.com/MHqlf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit: Thanks for all your amazing comments. They mean a lot! I am starting to rethink the tattoo idea just because I'm still losing! I just feel like I need to commemorate this amazing milestone! Any ideas?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/hearingnotlistening&quot;&gt; hearingnotlistening &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/eg93v/i_lost_100_pounds/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eg93v/i_lost_100_pounds/"&gt;[255 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>fuck yeah</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg5fh/fuck_yeah/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg5fh/fuck_yeah/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 15:39:46 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/the_awesome_face&quot;&gt; the_awesome_face &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/W1Aye.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg5fh/fuck_yeah/"&gt;[219 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Your move, kittens.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg9f2/your_move_kittens/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg9f2/your_move_kittens/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 21:17:48 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/dudewithpants&quot;&gt; dudewithpants &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/POU2X.gif&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/eg9f2/your_move_kittens/"&gt;[128 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Senate Republicans Block Attempt To Give Tax Cuts To 98% of Americans.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eg5rm/senate_republicans_block_attempt_to_give_tax_cuts/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eg5rm/senate_republicans_block_attempt_to_give_tax_cuts/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 16:47:12 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/mickeyknoxnbk&quot;&gt; mickeyknoxnbk &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704767804575654713979746760.html?mod=googlenews_wsj&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eg5rm/senate_republicans_block_attempt_to_give_tax_cuts/"&gt;[736 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>This chicken is better than a Steadicam.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eg410/this_chicken_is_better_than_a_steadicam/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eg410/this_chicken_is_better_than_a_steadicam/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 13:06:52 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/autocorrector&quot;&gt; autocorrector &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sXUeO3auRZg&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eg410/this_chicken_is_better_than_a_steadicam/"&gt;[354 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hey Reddit, a trans-gendered friend of mine was assaulted on black friday at a Kohls in Jackson, TN. Her jaw was broken and she had 3 teeth ripped out. The police are refusing to take the assault seriously and Kohls is refusing to take any responsibility, hoping you guys can help put on some heat</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg70p/hey_reddit_a_transgendered_friend_of_mine_was/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg70p/hey_reddit_a_transgendered_friend_of_mine_was/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:18:00 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/AmericasFunnyman&#34;&gt; AmericasFunnyman &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&#34;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://grand-divisions.blogspot.com/2010/12/transwoman-assaulted-at-kohls.html&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/eg70p/hey_reddit_a_transgendered_friend_of_mine_was/"&gt;[299 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>So Reddit, I own GlennBeckNation.com. What should I do with it?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/egcfs/so_reddit_i_own_glennbecknationcom_what_should_i/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/egcfs/so_reddit_i_own_glennbecknationcom_what_should_i/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 01:08:07 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/jrixey&#34;&gt; jrixey &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&#34;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/comments/egcfs/so_reddit_i_own_glennbecknationcom_what_should_i/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/egcfs/so_reddit_i_own_glennbecknationcom_what_should_i/"&gt;[158 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>As a victim of child abuse, I want to scream this at everyone on facebook (warning: This is graphic, don't open if you have a weak stomach)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/egawf/as_a_victim_of_child_abuse_i_want_to_scream_this/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/egawf/as_a_victim_of_child_abuse_i_want_to_scream_this/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 23:09:55 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/redditnoobie&quot;&gt; redditnoobie &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/EX2jh.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/egawf/as_a_victim_of_child_abuse_i_want_to_scream_this/"&gt;[163 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>What my buddy realizes while on vacation</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/eg5vm/what_my_buddy_realizes_while_on_vacation/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/eg5vm/what_my_buddy_realizes_while_on_vacation/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 16:55:06 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/eg5vm/what_my_buddy_realizes_while_on_vacation/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_eg5vm.png&quot; alt=&quot;What my buddy realizes while on vacation&quot; title=&quot;What my buddy realizes while on vacation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/zeelaw&quot;&gt; zeelaw &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/IBcPt.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/eg5vm/what_my_buddy_realizes_while_on_vacation/"&gt;[355 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>What my buddy realizes while on vacation</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_eg5vm.png" /></item><item><title>My WTF meter just exploded into a thousand pieces</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eg6lf/my_wtf_meter_just_exploded_into_a_thousand_pieces/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eg6lf/my_wtf_meter_just_exploded_into_a_thousand_pieces/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 17:49:35 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/nickram81&quot;&gt; nickram81 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.liveleak.com/view?i=5ca_1291431095&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eg6lf/my_wtf_meter_just_exploded_into_a_thousand_pieces/"&gt;[227 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wikileaks Cables - Leading Chinese politician ordered attacks on Google after Googling his own name and finding critical articles</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eg6yx/wikileaks_cables_leading_chinese_politician/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eg6yx/wikileaks_cables_leading_chinese_politician/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:14:27 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Soul2018&quot;&gt; Soul2018 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2010/dec/04/wikileaks-cables-google-china-hacking&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eg6yx/wikileaks_cables_leading_chinese_politician/"&gt;[101 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>The remarkable genius of Kurt Godel: in a lost 1956 letter to John von Neumann, he anticipated the P=NP question some 15 years before its formulation.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/eg77z/the_remarkable_genius_of_kurt_godel_in_a_lost/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/eg77z/the_remarkable_genius_of_kurt_godel_in_a_lost/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 18:32:58 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/gmiwenht&quot;&gt; gmiwenht &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot;&gt; programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://rjlipton.wordpress.com/the-gdel-letter/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/eg77z/the_remarkable_genius_of_kurt_godel_in_a_lost/"&gt;[74 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why do Iraqi women not sleep with American soldiers?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/egd7t/why_do_iraqi_women_not_sleep_with_american/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/egd7t/why_do_iraqi_women_not_sleep_with_american/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 02:15:03 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because they always talk about pulling out but never do.&quot; - Slavoj Zizek&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Zaxis&quot;&gt; Zaxis &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/egd7t/why_do_iraqi_women_not_sleep_with_american/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/egd7t/why_do_iraqi_women_not_sleep_with_american/"&gt;[25 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>