<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>reddit: the front page of the internet</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://www.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit: the front page of the internet</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>What a baller</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/sqojr/what_a_baller/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/sqojr/what_a_baller/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 22:11:03 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/twinsofliberty&#34;&gt; twinsofliberty &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&#34;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/ERmMf&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/sqojr/what_a_baller/"&gt;[266 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>grammar.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqo2w/grammar/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqo2w/grammar/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 22:02:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqo2w/grammar/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://c.thumbs.redditmedia.com/TKadfhMS5sRBLbt2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;grammar. &#34; title=&#34;grammar. &#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/fastr1337&#34;&gt; fastr1337 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/&#34;&gt; AdviceAnimals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://qkme.me/3oy8ze&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqo2w/grammar/"&gt;[204 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>grammar.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://c.thumbs.redditmedia.com/TKadfhMS5sRBLbt2.jpg" /></item><item><title>I want this.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqizs/i_want_this/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqizs/i_want_this/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 20:34:18 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/ElectricD&#34;&gt; ElectricD &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&#34;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/aSuBh&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqizs/i_want_this/"&gt;[73 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>So we just hired a new IT guy</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/sqfu3/so_we_just_hired_a_new_it_guy/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/sqfu3/so_we_just_hired_a_new_it_guy/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 12:38:20 -0700</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/sqfu3/so_we_just_hired_a_new_it_guy/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://d.thumbs.redditmedia.com/LMdpiVfTtB7vqZXE.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;So we just hired a new IT guy&#34; title=&#34;So we just hired a new IT guy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/SimplyZ&#34;&gt; SimplyZ &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/&#34;&gt; aww&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Uq5uB.jpg?1&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/sqfu3/so_we_just_hired_a_new_it_guy/"&gt;[153 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>So we just hired a new IT guy</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://d.thumbs.redditmedia.com/LMdpiVfTtB7vqZXE.jpg" /></item><item><title>I broke up with a girl, and then this happened...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqfm3/i_broke_up_with_a_girl_and_then_this_happened/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqfm3/i_broke_up_with_a_girl_and_then_this_happened/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:34:16 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqfm3/i_broke_up_with_a_girl_and_then_this_happened/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a.thumbs.redditmedia.com/rOb_Lf8FOAZX-E8T.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I broke up with a girl, and then this happened...&#34; title=&#34;I broke up with a girl, and then this happened...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/Eternity42Immensity&#34;&gt; Eternity42Immensity &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&#34;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/UHWqd.png&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqfm3/i_broke_up_with_a_girl_and_then_this_happened/"&gt;[2295 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>I broke up with a girl, and then this happened...</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://a.thumbs.redditmedia.com/rOb_Lf8FOAZX-E8T.jpg" /></item><item><title>Cispa cybersecurity bill opposed by Obama administration</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/spzsr/cispa_cybersecurity_bill_opposed_by_obama/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/spzsr/cispa_cybersecurity_bill_opposed_by_obama/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 14:36:15 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/DrJulianBashir&#34;&gt; DrJulianBashir &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/&#34;&gt; technology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2012/apr/24/cispa-cybersecurity-bill-opposed-obama&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/spzsr/cispa_cybersecurity_bill_opposed_by_obama/"&gt;[1545 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Drug maker Novartis takes legal action in UK to make hospitals use $1,000 eye drug over $97 alternative</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/sq4ns/drug_maker_novartis_takes_legal_action_in_uk_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/sq4ns/drug_maker_novartis_takes_legal_action_in_uk_to/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 16:12:57 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/twolf1&#34;&gt; twolf1 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&#34;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_MED_NOVARTIS_DRUG_LAWSUIT?SITE=AP&amp;amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/sq4ns/drug_maker_novartis_takes_legal_action_in_uk_to/"&gt;[649 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>This is CISPA explained. SOPA was meant to stop piracy. CISPA is going to kill all privacy on the net. Enough Reddit you are waffling.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/spxx4/this_is_cispa_explained_sopa_was_meant_to_stop/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/spxx4/this_is_cispa_explained_sopa_was_meant_to_stop/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 13:53:41 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Action list. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step One.&lt;/strong&gt; Sign this petition. Make sure to Share on Twitter and Facebook. Avaaz Petition. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.avaaz.org/en/stop_cispa/?tta&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Two&lt;/strong&gt; Call your representative. One of these methods. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wfc2.wiredforchange.com/o/9042/p/dia/action/public/?action_KEY=8444&#34;&gt;EFF Message your representative&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://grassroutes.us/cispa&#34;&gt;Call your congressional representatives and urge them to vote against CISPA&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contactingthecongress.org/&#34;&gt;Contact Congress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Three&lt;/strong&gt; Tell the guy that wrote it what you think. Primary Sponsor Mike Rogers (MI) Twitter: @RepMikeRogers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/RepMikeRogers&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Mike-J-Rogers/168209963203416&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; Send them your disapproval&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can also send him a personal &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikerogers.house.gov/Contact/&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; Zip code for MI 8th district is: 48346&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Four&lt;/strong&gt; Appeal directly to the president. He already does not approve of the bill. Let&amp;#39;s make sure we say we agree. We the people petition. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petitions#!/petition/veto-cispa-if-it-makes-it-past-both-houses-congress-legislation-harmful-american-people/fKW3bVhg&#34;&gt;LINK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Five&lt;/strong&gt; Make note of these companies. Here is a list of companies. It is big though. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digitaltrends.com/web/cispa-supporters-list-800-companies-that-could-help-uncle-sam-snag-your-data/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra Credit&lt;/strong&gt; Great Comment Below. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/spxx4/this_is_cispa_explained_sopa_was_meant_to_stop/c4g1zz2&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/evolutionReddit/comments/sjay6/cispa_action_list_we_need_to_hit_up_congress/&#34;&gt;Reddit action list&lt;/a&gt; or Donate to the reddit TestPAC. &lt;a href=&#34;http://testpacpleaseignore.org/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Extra Credit&lt;/strong&gt; Tweeting @barakobama with something like this: Commit to a veto on CISPA or lose my vote. #CISPA #StopCISPA #Obama2012&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Share this &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberspying.eff.org/images/cispa.jpg&#34;&gt;Great Image Explanation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paralegal.net/cispa/&#34;&gt;Another Great Image Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/StopTheCISPA&#34;&gt;Join this Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Youtube video. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=xLjj6RD6-MI&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News on CISPA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/andygreenberg/2012/04/24/the-internets-political-voices-are-lining-up-to-smash-cispa/&#34;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2012/apr/23/ron-paul-cispa-cyberterrorism-bill?newsfeed=true&#34;&gt;The Gaurdian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rt.com/usa/news/ron-paul-against-cispa-753/&#34;&gt;RT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latimes.com/news/politics/la-pn-cispa-draws-closer-to-a-vote-amid-a-flurry-of-amendments-20120424,0,7037771.story?track=rss&#34;&gt;LA Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Original Post:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lofgren.house.gov/images/stories/pdf/042312%20lofgren%20cispa%20concerns.pdf&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I felt this comment needed it&amp;#39;s own thread. I took it from this guy. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/tb/spnsi&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Reddit we need to understand that we are an open community which means there are people posting in these threads that are paid to spin the conversation away from the real issue. It is causing us to waffel on the issue at hand. If you have nothing to add to the conversation then please don&amp;#39;t post so we can see those individuals that are spinning the conversation. Otherwise do everything you can activist wise to help our cause. No cynics, pessimists, detractors please. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA could allow any private company to share vast amounts of sensitive, private data about its customers with the government.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA would override all other federal and state privacy laws, and allow a private company to share nearly anything—from the contents of private emails and Internet browsing history to medical, educational and financial records—as long as it “directly pertains to” a “cyber threat,” which is broadly defined.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA does not require that data shared with the government be stripped of unnecessary personally-identifiable information. A private company may choose to anonymize the data it shares with the government. However, there is no requirement that it does so—even when personally-identifiable information is unnecessary for cybersecurity measures. For example, emails could be shared with the full names of their authors and recipients. A company could decide to leave the names of its customers in the data it shares with the government merely because it does not want to incur the expense of deleting them. This is contrary to the recommendations of the House Republican Cybersecurity Task Force and other bills to authorize information sharing, which require companies to make a reasonable effort to minimize the sharing of personally-identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA would allow the government to use collected private information for reasons other than cybersecurity. The government could use any information it receives for “any lawful purpose” besides “regulatory purposes,” so long as the same use can also be justified by cybersecurity or the protection of national security. This would provide no meaningful limit—a government official could easily create a connection to “national security” to justify nearly any type of investigation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA would give Internet Service Providers free rein to monitor the private communications and activities of users on their networks. ISPs would have wide latitude to do anything that can be construed as part of a “cybersecurity system,” regardless of any other privacy or telecommunications law.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA would empower the military and the National Security Agency (NSA) to collect information about domestic Internet users. Other information sharing bills would direct private information from domestic sources to civilian agencies, such as the Department of Homeland Security. CISPA contains no such limitation. Instead, the Department of Defense and the NSA could solicit and receive information directly from American companies, about users and systems inside the United States.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA places too much faith in private companies, to safeguard their most sensitive customer data from government intrusion. While information sharing would be voluntary under CISPA, the government has a variety of ways to pressure private companies to share large volumes of customer information. With complete legal immunity, private companies have few clear incentives to resist such pressure. There is also no requirement that companies ever tell their customers what they have shared with the government, either before or after the fact. As informed consumers, Americans expect technology companies to have clear privacy policies, telling us exactly how and when the company will use and share our personal data, so that we can make informed choices about which companies have earned our trust and deserve our business.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;**copy pasted from the above linked PDF&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CISPA really is the Big Brother law.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/LastPriority&#34;&gt; LastPriority &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&#34;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/spxx4/this_is_cispa_explained_sopa_was_meant_to_stop/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/spxx4/this_is_cispa_explained_sopa_was_meant_to_stop/"&gt;[1130 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>A skeleton crawled out of my closet and asked me to attend his wedding. The skeleton is a multiply-convicted sex offender and child rapist. He's also my brother. What do I do?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/sqdxw/a_skeleton_crawled_out_of_my_closet_and_asked_me/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/sqdxw/a_skeleton_crawled_out_of_my_closet_and_asked_me/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:04:23 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a phone call that fucked my whole world up this weekend. About 12 years ago my older brother was arrested for sexual assault while away at college. As part of the investigation his computers were confiscated and the detectives discovered my brother was running a pedophilia server. He went to prison, served his time uneventfully, and was released into a group home. Several years later, as part of his court-ordered therapy, he admitted to his therapist and ultimately to law enforcement that for a period of years prior to his arrest he had molested and raped my baby sister. I found out when the men in my family sat down with my brother, his PO, and therapist for him to tell us what he had done. He looked me, my other brother, and my father in the eye and told us about how he had raped my sister several hundred times when he was between 16 and 18 and she was between 9 and 11.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That was over a decade ago. I never spoke to my brother again. I&amp;#39;ve spent most of my adult life dealing with the rage over what he had done, the guilt over the fact that I had no idea, and the overpowering shame that I was unable to protect my sister. Myself, my other brother, and my sister all moved away and never looked back. We went to college together and are generally inseparable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So fast forward to last weekend and I get a call from the area code where I grew up. I didn&amp;#39;t answer and let it go to voicemail. I&amp;#39;ve had the same cell phone number all this time and I guess my brother held onto it. He told me he was getting married and wanted me to be there. He said he loved and missed me. I don&amp;#39;t know how long it took me to feel anything, or have any kind of conscious thought, but when I finally did it was a torrent of conflict. I was enraged, I wanted to explode and tear something apart. I was disgusted, I wanted to throw up everything I had ever eaten. I was painfully saddened, I wanted to cry until I had nothing left in me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My brother destroyed my family. He destroyed the innocence of my best friend. He ripped the soul of his own little sister to shreds. I&amp;#39;ve hated him so thoroughly for so long that I almost forgot he is my brother. When he called it reminded me of all the times he stood up and took a beating for me because he didn&amp;#39;t want my drunken sack of shit step father to get his hands on me. I remembered all the high school football games when no one was there but him because my mother was somewhere face down in her own vomit after taking too many Xanax again. I remembered that he&amp;#39;s my blood, my brother.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But he&amp;#39;s a monster. My sister still can&amp;#39;t talk about him, the only thing she can say is that he is dead to her. She will hate him until the day she dies. I could never go to his wedding. It would be a betrayal of my sister that I won&amp;#39;t even contemplate. But I feel like my brother deserves a no. He&amp;#39;s my brother, I should be man enough to call him and tell him no. But I don&amp;#39;t know if I can.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What do I do? What should I do?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/Tase_Me_Bro&#34;&gt; Tase_Me_Bro &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&#34;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/sqdxw/a_skeleton_crawled_out_of_my_closet_and_asked_me/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/sqdxw/a_skeleton_crawled_out_of_my_closet_and_asked_me/"&gt;[1830 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Are you FUCKING KIDDING me? This is REAL.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sqofc/are_you_fucking_kidding_me_this_is_real/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sqofc/are_you_fucking_kidding_me_this_is_real/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 22:08:44 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sqofc/are_you_fucking_kidding_me_this_is_real/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://d.thumbs.redditmedia.com/-1GeocwK1KIfgZ9u.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Are you FUCKING KIDDING me? This is REAL.&#34; title=&#34;Are you FUCKING KIDDING me? This is REAL.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/endscene&#34;&gt; endscene &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/&#34;&gt; videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/40110285&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sqofc/are_you_fucking_kidding_me_this_is_real/"&gt;[220 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Are you FUCKING KIDDING me? This is REAL.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://d.thumbs.redditmedia.com/-1GeocwK1KIfgZ9u.jpg" /></item><item><title>TIL a Hungarian psychologist wrote a book on how to raise a genius. He proposed his ideas to a teacher. They married and raised three chess grandmasters, two of them became record-breakers and one even became the first female to beat the top ranked male (Gary Kasporov).</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/sq0dg/til_a_hungarian_psychologist_wrote_a_book_on_how/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/sq0dg/til_a_hungarian_psychologist_wrote_a_book_on_how/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 14:48:21 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/lightsaberon&#34;&gt; lightsaberon &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/&#34;&gt; todayilearned&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psychologytoday.com/print/23195&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/sq0dg/til_a_hungarian_psychologist_wrote_a_book_on_how/"&gt;[952 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I am Dan Bull - pro-filesharing geek rapper. I'm on the front page of The Pirate Bay, aiming to hijack the pop charts. AMA</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sqayu/i_am_dan_bull_profilesharing_geek_rapper_im_on/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sqayu/i_am_dan_bull_profilesharing_geek_rapper_im_on/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 18:10:45 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDIT - thanks for all the questions everyone, I&amp;#39;ve been typing for five hours now so it&amp;#39;s time to stop. I may come back tomorrow and reply to any new unanswered posts. Thanks for taking the time to talk to me&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Dan Bull. I am a British rapper, diagnosed with Asperger Syndrome. As a result, I love playing computer games, questioning the logic of everything I see, and assembling words into aurally pleasing sequences. I have an oversized vocabulary, which I regularly use to protest about digital rights. I have rapped about everything from SOPA to Skyrim to a musical explanation of how glaciers are formed. My most popular videos are &amp;quot;SOPA Cabana&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Epic Skyrim Rap&amp;quot;. You can see my videos here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/douglby&#34;&gt;http://youtube.com/douglby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My latest campaign, which is being backed by The Pirate Bay, is to get a free torrent into the UK and US singles charts (amongst others) by making it available for sale and promoting it as hard as I can. I am going to make a video personally thank by name everybody who buys the complete single. More about that here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://itsdanbull.com/single&#34;&gt;http://itsdanbull.com/single&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have a subreddit here: &lt;a href=&#34;/r/danbull&#34;&gt;/r/danbull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EDIT: Proof that this is actually me - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/itsDanBull/status/194851010185932800&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/#!/itsDanBull/status/194851010185932800&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/itsDanBull&#34;&gt; itsDanBull &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/&#34;&gt; IAmA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sqayu/i_am_dan_bull_profilesharing_geek_rapper_im_on/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sqayu/i_am_dan_bull_profilesharing_geek_rapper_im_on/"&gt;[626 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>A quick shot of Daniel Day-Lewis as President Lincoln.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/sq20g/a_quick_shot_of_daniel_daylewis_as_president/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/sq20g/a_quick_shot_of_daniel_daylewis_as_president/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 15:22:00 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/RumpledForeskin13&#34;&gt; RumpledForeskin13 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/&#34;&gt; movies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/KikPp.jpg&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/sq20g/a_quick_shot_of_daniel_daylewis_as_president/"&gt;[291 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Junior Senior - Move Your Feet</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/sqpgq/junior_senior_move_your_feet/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/sqpgq/junior_senior_move_your_feet/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 22:27:31 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/upvote_deez_nutz&#34;&gt; upvote_deez_nutz &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/&#34;&gt; Music&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch%3Fv%3DSPlQpGeTbIE&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/sqpgq/junior_senior_move_your_feet/"&gt;[35 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Engineers create flying object that propels itself by flipping inside out</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/spyfz/engineers_create_flying_object_that_propels/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/spyfz/engineers_create_flying_object_that_propels/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 14:06:07 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/ammcurious&#34;&gt; ammcurious &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&#34;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newscientist.com/blogs/nstv/2012/04/flying-object-propels-itself-by-flipping-inside-out.html?cmpid=NLC%7CNSNS%7C2012-2304-GLOBAL%7Cflyingobjects&amp;amp;utm_medium=NLC&amp;amp;utm_source=NSNS&amp;amp;utm_content=flyingobjects&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/spyfz/engineers_create_flying_object_that_propels/"&gt;[262 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>&quot;Just box this up, we're leaving.&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/sqpu8/just_box_this_up_were_leaving/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/sqpu8/just_box_this_up_were_leaving/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 22:34:34 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/dingofarmer2004&#34;&gt; dingofarmer2004 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/&#34;&gt; bestof&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/sq3zj/throwaway_time_what_is_the_one_illegal_immoral/c4g60r8?context=3&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/sqpu8/just_box_this_up_were_leaving/"&gt;[20 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Russell Brand talking to Britain's Home Affairs Committee about drug addiction.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sq1vh/russell_brand_talking_to_britains_home_affairs/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sq1vh/russell_brand_talking_to_britains_home_affairs/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 15:19:25 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sq1vh/russell_brand_talking_to_britains_home_affairs/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://c.thumbs.redditmedia.com/mniKTYdy5-KoMYph.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Russell Brand talking to Britain&#39;s Home Affairs Committee about drug addiction.&#34; title=&#34;Russell Brand talking to Britain&#39;s Home Affairs Committee about drug addiction.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/rich186&#34;&gt; rich186 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/&#34;&gt; videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7BNNMpkM8AE&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/sq1vh/russell_brand_talking_to_britains_home_affairs/"&gt;[666 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Russell Brand talking to Britain's Home Affairs Committee about drug addiction.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://c.thumbs.redditmedia.com/mniKTYdy5-KoMYph.jpg" /></item><item><title>Meanwhile in a Russian metro</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqb2v/meanwhile_in_a_russian_metro/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqb2v/meanwhile_in_a_russian_metro/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 18:12:57 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/trololbaus&#34;&gt; trololbaus &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&#34;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/tJ8N9&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqb2v/meanwhile_in_a_russian_metro/"&gt;[200 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I approve of the &quot;Good guy VHS&quot; meme.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqm5t/why_i_approve_of_the_good_guy_vhs_meme/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqm5t/why_i_approve_of_the_good_guy_vhs_meme/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 14:28:50 -0700</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqm5t/why_i_approve_of_the_good_guy_vhs_meme/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/H-YWeMe6ptv5yVlM.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Why I approve of the &amp;quot;Good guy VHS&amp;quot; meme.&#34; title=&#34;Why I approve of the &amp;quot;Good guy VHS&amp;quot; meme.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/clydefrog11&#34;&gt; clydefrog11 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/&#34;&gt; AdviceAnimals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quickmeme.com/meme/3oy83v/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/sqm5t/why_i_approve_of_the_good_guy_vhs_meme/"&gt;[66 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Why I approve of the &quot;Good guy VHS&quot; meme.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/H-YWeMe6ptv5yVlM.jpg" /></item><item><title>My friend told me to draw Gabe Newell.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqf2g/my_friend_told_me_to_draw_gabe_newell/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqf2g/my_friend_told_me_to_draw_gabe_newell/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:24:58 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqf2g/my_friend_told_me_to_draw_gabe_newell/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://c.thumbs.redditmedia.com/wM_C_1e16BDZjfOJ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My friend told me to draw Gabe Newell.&#34; title=&#34;My friend told me to draw Gabe Newell.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/beardbeck&#34;&gt; beardbeck &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&#34;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/L2o3B&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/sqf2g/my_friend_told_me_to_draw_gabe_newell/"&gt;[134 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>My friend told me to draw Gabe Newell.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://c.thumbs.redditmedia.com/wM_C_1e16BDZjfOJ.jpg" /></item><item><title>I am Phil Plait, astronomer/author/blogger/some time TV host. AMA.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sq1id/i_am_phil_plait_astronomerauthorbloggersome_time/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sq1id/i_am_phil_plait_astronomerauthorbloggersome_time/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 15:11:19 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow redditors. I figured it was about time I did this. I&amp;#39;ve been here for over four years, after all. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oh yeah: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/BadAstronomer/statuses/194805545465683968&#34;&gt;I&amp;#39;m me.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#39;m ready to answer questions. Please be aware that a lot of astronomy-type queries can take forever to answer, so try to avoid things like &amp;quot;Explain quantum chromodynamics to me&amp;quot; (which is easy anyway, since all I can do is spell it). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;BTW, today is a bit crazy with the asteroid mining and the Hubble birthday and of course the glavin, so please bear with me if it takes a while for me to answer stuff. I&amp;#39;m trying. I also asked Woody Harrelson to fill in if needed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[UPDATE 1 (17:20 UTC): I need to take off for a while and listen to the asteroid mining press conference. I&amp;#39;ll be back in hopefully an hour or so, but I&amp;#39;ll have to take off again after that. I&amp;#39;ll do what I can to keep up! Thanks!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[UPDATE 2 (21:00 UTC): OK, I was back, but now I need to go run some errands. Back in an hour!]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/BadAstronomer&#34;&gt; BadAstronomer &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/&#34;&gt; IAmA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sq1id/i_am_phil_plait_astronomerauthorbloggersome_time/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/sq1id/i_am_phil_plait_astronomerauthorbloggersome_time/"&gt;[815 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I just lost ALL respect for my school.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqgbf/i_just_lost_all_respect_for_my_school/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqgbf/i_just_lost_all_respect_for_my_school/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:47:02 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/Hollywoood&#34;&gt; Hollywoood &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&#34;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/bDb1Z&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqgbf/i_just_lost_all_respect_for_my_school/"&gt;[501 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teacher Bullies Autistic kid. Dad finds out by sending kid to school wearing a wire.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqjfy/teacher_bullies_autistic_kid_dad_finds_out_by/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqjfy/teacher_bullies_autistic_kid_dad_finds_out_by/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 13:41:52 -0700</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/seoulbandit84&#34;&gt; seoulbandit84 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&#34;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gawker.com/5904762/father-learns-his-autistic-son-is-being-bullied-by-teacher-aides-after-sending-him-to-school-with-a-wire&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqjfy/teacher_bullies_autistic_kid_dad_finds_out_by/"&gt;[91 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>It's time for a new Social Network.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqtuq/its_time_for_a_new_social_network/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqtuq/its_time_for_a_new_social_network/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 16:49:31 -0700</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/MaZeR4455&#34;&gt; MaZeR4455 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&#34;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/X5SHI&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/sqtuq/its_time_for_a_new_social_network/"&gt;[46 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>So THIS is why my math class' graphing calculator isn't working...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqbww/so_this_is_why_my_math_class_graphing_calculator/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqbww/so_this_is_why_my_math_class_graphing_calculator/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 18:27:52 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqbww/so_this_is_why_my_math_class_graphing_calculator/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/3NqvJMhMJNMv99BY.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;So THIS is why my math class&#39; graphing calculator isn&#39;t working...&#34; title=&#34;So THIS is why my math class&#39; graphing calculator isn&#39;t working...&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/mkiyt&#34;&gt; mkiyt &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&#34;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/ZjRjB&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/sqbww/so_this_is_why_my_math_class_graphing_calculator/"&gt;[276 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>So THIS is why my math class' graphing calculator isn't working...</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/3NqvJMhMJNMv99BY.jpg" /></item></channel></rss>