<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss"><channel><title>reddit.com: what's new online!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://static.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit.com: what's new online!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>A reddit experiment: Help us catch spammers by verifying your email address</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/by0qn/a_reddit_experiment_help_us_catch_spammers_by/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/by0qn/a_reddit_experiment_help_us_catch_spammers_by/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 20:22:50 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T20:22:50.212197+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/by0qn/a_reddit_experiment_help_us_catch_spammers_by/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by0qn.png&quot; alt=&quot;A reddit experiment: Help us catch spammers by verifying your email address&quot; title=&quot;A reddit experiment: Help us catch spammers by verifying your email address&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/raldi&quot;&gt; raldi &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/&quot;&gt; announcements&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.reddit.com/2010/04/reddit-experiment-help-reddit-catch.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/by0qn/a_reddit_experiment_help_us_catch_spammers_by/"&gt;[668 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>A reddit experiment: Help us catch spammers by verifying your email address</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by0qn.png" /></item><item><title>Evolution Timeline, to scale [scroll down and to the right]</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/bxylc/evolution_timeline_to_scale_scroll_down_and_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/bxylc/evolution_timeline_to_scale_scroll_down_and_to/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 18:01:23 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T18:01:23.706603+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/xenocidal&quot;&gt; xenocidal &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&quot;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://andabien.com/html/evolution-timeline.htm?=9738234&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/bxylc/evolution_timeline_to_scale_scroll_down_and_to/"&gt;[450 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>What I learned in Jail. What did you learn?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by00r/what_i_learned_in_jail_what_did_you_learn/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by00r/what_i_learned_in_jail_what_did_you_learn/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 19:32:03 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T19:32:03.002869+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learned that it's ok to use the n-word repeatedly in jail regardless of your race. I personally did not experiment with this as I have some semblance of civility and am not particularly fond of that word. I also was also interested in keeping all my teeth. I use them everyday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that urng is a color, and that urnges are edible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that drug dealers use city jail as a sort of professional forum to discuss the latest trends in selling, the hot spots and to compare notes. They also discuss other dealers and good locations to sell. I also learned and I quote that &quot;selling bundles is the wave of the future&quot; apparently the crack market is too saturated. You would be amazed at how many people know each other in jail. It's like a really really shitty hotel at a professional conference.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that all women are hoes and in order to be gangsta cool you must deride your baby momma at every possible convenience. You also should never let anyone hear you on the jail phone while you are begging said baby momma to bail you out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that Nike is the preferred footwear of inmates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that Obama will give you free money if you go to a place on North Main where for a mere 400 dollar fee you can apply for a 1600 dollar benefit. There was a spirited conversation on methods of getting yo check. I explained that they were getting ripped off and exploited by a predatory company and therefore I was the Antichrist.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that not all Asians are good at math.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that concrete is really hard on your ass, especially if you have a 47 year old Caucasian butt, which is to say no butt at all.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned to respect my shoelaces. Try walking around for two days with no shoelaces.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that the definition of food in an institution is extremely loose. There were some items in the cellophane covered paper trays that were not at all identifiable except for the urnge bit's which were most likely carrots. I learned that Oak Farms distributes a chemical slurry in a small carton labeled orange (urnge) drink and lemon drink with big letters on the side that say zero percent juice and an alchemists pantry of ingredients including ester of wood rosin......which was especially funny to me as there was an inmate there that looked just like Esther of Sanford and Son. A side note I could not find any of these Oak Farms juice products on the web. I do not think normal consumers would ever drink these vile concoctions. I think Oak Farms must be making bank on the prison and educational industrial network and not really giving a shit what people without a choice are quaffing down ignorantly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that after eating jail food for two days you can have an amazingly intelligent conversation about cheese burgers. The quest for a cheeseburger became my holy grail and helped me get through the day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that one hour in jail equals about four hours relatively speaking. Being able to see the city hall clock out a window near my cell did not help.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that trusties do most of the actual work in jail.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that City jail guards are the most despicable people on earth with a few notable exceptions. The female guards were the worst. They are mean, nasty contemptible bitches who deserve to be tied to stakes and fed to fire ants. Does that seem overly harsh and misogynistic? It does? Well before you judge me, spend two days in city jail and get back to me. There was one guard there who was very cool I wish I could remember his name.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that all guards and police officers must be referred to as either &quot;Boss Man&quot; or &quot;Boss Lady&quot; if you want their attention. My refusal to address them in this manner led to my rarely getting any questions answered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that a shy bladder and jail do not mix well. The torture of not being able to pee two feet from another mans head only added to my overall torment. I learned that have a incredibly good bladder for a 47 year old man....man I can really hold it. Seriously I am the zen master of holding my pee.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that whenever you laid your ear to the ground or filthy bunk mats that the jail emitted a very low frequency oscillating hum. I was convinced that this was Cthulus's arcane life support system and he was feeding on negative emotions building up enough dark energy to awaken the ancient ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that cell phones are evil. I learned that I am completely isolated by my reliance on contact lists. I could not recall even one important phone number except my office phone with does not allow collect calls. I therefore worried a lot of people. My office was convinced I was dead and called morgues and jails to no avail. I feel horrible that they worried so much, but I know how much they really care about me now and have a new found respect for my family here.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that loss of freedom is a dehumanizing experience. I only spent two days in jail and it still made eternally thankful for my freedom. I can not imagine what an extended stay would do to my psyche. I can not see how anyone gets out of extended incarceration without some deep damage and complete disregard for authority.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that toilet paper is a commodity in jail and is good for a temporary pillow if you can get it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned that in jail the courtesy flush is of the utmost importance, and is often repeated over and over again until you are finished doing your business. I also learned that jail toilets sound like jet fighters taking off when flushed which made courtesy flushing incredibly annoying. My inability to use these toilets shielded me from actually performing this activity myself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most importantly I learned that even after being dismissed of charges against you by a judge that jailers have no problem holding you for 17 hours before processing you out. This more than anything bothered me as I felt that at that point I was being held prisoner without cause. The guards will actually hold you longer if you give them any attitude whatsoever about this gross injustice. They are simply the most spiteful people on earth. I am going to write a full story on my experiences and do my best to get it in the hands of people who can effect change. This has become a cause.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I learned all of this because I accepted a ride home after drinking at a party. Yea it's good to be an American.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Slofut&quot;&gt; Slofut &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/by00r/what_i_learned_in_jail_what_did_you_learn/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by00r/what_i_learned_in_jail_what_did_you_learn/"&gt;[1199 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Speaking to AZ conservatives in their language, Lev. 19:33-34: 'When an alien lives with you in your land, do not mistreat him. The alien living with you must be treated as one of your native-born. Love him as yourself, for you were aliens in Egypt. I am the LORD your God.'</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/by1d4/speaking_to_az_conservatives_in_their_language/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/by1d4/speaking_to_az_conservatives_in_their_language/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 21:10:48 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T21:10:48.289245+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/mrbroom&quot;&gt; mrbroom &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Leviticus+19%3A33-34&amp;amp;version=NIV&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/by1d4/speaking_to_az_conservatives_in_their_language/"&gt;[283 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>This man, is a badass.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxwec/this_man_is_a_badass/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxwec/this_man_is_a_badass/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 15:54:13 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T15:54:13.519556+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxwec/this_man_is_a_badass/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxwec.png&quot; alt=&quot;This man, is a badass. &quot; title=&quot;This man, is a badass. &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Au70&quot;&gt; Au70 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://img.ffffound.com/static-data/assets/6/bd94853ba0a045bd69fe006453a215c8c6f63368_m.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxwec/this_man_is_a_badass/"&gt;[347 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>This man, is a badass.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxwec.png" /></item><item><title>Egypt uses chemical weapons on Palestinians... no one gives a shit. I wonder how many hundreds of links and thousands of upvotes this would have generated if it were Israel doing it?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/bxxiv/egypt_uses_chemical_weapons_on_palestinians_no/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/bxxiv/egypt_uses_chemical_weapons_on_palestinians_no/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 16:58:31 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T16:58:31.597546+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Jewcifer&quot;&gt; Jewcifer &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.presstv.ir/detail.aspx?id=124862&amp;amp;sectionid=351020202&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/bxxiv/egypt_uses_chemical_weapons_on_palestinians_no/"&gt;[420 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fuck you, Flowers [pic]</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/bxv8b/fuck_you_flowers_pic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/bxv8b/fuck_you_flowers_pic/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 14:47:31 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T14:47:31.953954+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/weisenzahn&quot;&gt; weisenzahn &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_l0kr3ivHU11qbs8kyo1_500.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/bxv8b/fuck_you_flowers_pic/"&gt;[199 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hey Reddit, what are your thoughts on Puerto Rico becoming a state?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/bxys7/hey_reddit_what_are_your_thoughts_on_puerto_rico/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/bxys7/hey_reddit_what_are_your_thoughts_on_puerto_rico/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 18:12:52 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T18:12:52.476883+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the HR2499 bill is being debated in congress. This bill provides for a congress-sanctioned two-part process in which Puerto Rico can finally determine its political status. The first part asks Puerto Ricans if they wish to continue with the status quo (as a non-incorporated commonwealth), or if they wish to change their political status. The second part asks if they wish to become one of three choices: 1) Independence, 2) Statehood, or 3) Free Association.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I would love to hear from you, good or bad.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks, -commenter01&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: I would really appreciate if this could hit the front page. It's really important!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit 2&lt;/strong&gt;: I've been seeing many comments regarding the interaction of Puerto Rico's economy with that of the U.S. As of now, from what I've gathered (and I would welcome numbers and statistics on the subject), I don't think we are a drain on the U.S. economy. Sure, we receive federal aid, but reciprocally we are a captive market for U.S. companies. In this respect (consumerism), and to my constant dismay lol, Puerto Ricans are ridiculous. Take, for example Plaza Las Americas, Puerto Rico's largest mall. Here are some stats pulled from wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;It is the third largest shopping center in Latin America.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The RadioShack store in Plaza is the busiest and highest grossing RadioShack store in the world.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The largest JCPenney store in the world (a full 4 stories) is located at the mall.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The largest Big K-Mart store in the Caribbean is located at the mall.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The first Macy's store to open outside of the continental U.S. is located at the mall.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The mall produces approximately 8,000 local jobs and has a local economic impact of approximately $268 million.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The mall has approximately 11,000 parking spaces.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h1&gt;The Highest grossing Borders &amp;amp; Music store is located in the mall.&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if we obtain statehood, we would be entitled to larger amounts of federal aid. However, I think that this would be counterbalanced by the improved economic position. In other words, I think Puerto Rico's GDP (~80 billion USD as of the past few years) would improve drastically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit 3&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm sorry for the continuous edits... I've received multiple comments concerning the flag. I'd think it would be AWESOME, if some Redditor took it upon themselves and designed a 51 star flag :P I promise I'll give you more than a b-. &lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8f/US_51-star_alternate_flag.svg&quot; &gt;Here's the proposed design.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you to those who have commented. I have a final soon, so I'm gonna go hit the books. I'll reply tomorrow :D Thanks again so much!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit 4&lt;/strong&gt;: The post made Front Page!!!!!!!! I'm overwhelmed at the response. Thanks for getting this issue out in the open and keep posting. I'll read even if I can't respond to every message. Thanks again!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/commenter01&quot;&gt; commenter01 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/bxys7/hey_reddit_what_are_your_thoughts_on_puerto_rico/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/bxys7/hey_reddit_what_are_your_thoughts_on_puerto_rico/"&gt;[1012 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ubuntu 10.04 LTS (Lucid Lynx) Released!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/bxxzx/ubuntu_1004_lts_lucid_lynx_released/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/bxxzx/ubuntu_1004_lts_lucid_lynx_released/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 17:27:07 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T17:27:07.019860+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/endeavormac&quot;&gt; endeavormac &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot;&gt; programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://releases.ubuntu.com/lucid/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/bxxzx/ubuntu_1004_lts_lucid_lynx_released/"&gt;[559 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Race you to the bottom! (GIF)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/bxv17/race_you_to_the_bottom_gif/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/bxv17/race_you_to_the_bottom_gif/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 14:36:08 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T14:36:08.076689+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/JohnnyBanana&quot;&gt; JohnnyBanana &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/4dNrj.gif&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/bxv17/race_you_to_the_bottom_gif/"&gt;[410 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gabe &amp; Tycho Make The Time 100!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/bxtqy/gabe_tycho_make_the_time_100/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/bxtqy/gabe_tycho_make_the_time_100/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 13:38:54 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T13:38:54.051425+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/bxtqy/gabe_tycho_make_the_time_100/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxtqy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gabe &amp;amp; Tycho Make The Time 100!&quot; title=&quot;Gabe &amp;amp; Tycho Make The Time 100!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/alandmoey&quot;&gt; alandmoey &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1984685_1984940_1985513,00.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/bxtqy/gabe_tycho_make_the_time_100/"&gt;[267 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Gabe &amp; Tycho Make The Time 100!</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxtqy.png" /></item><item><title>&quot;Every asshole who ever chanted 'Drill baby drill' should have to report to the Gulf coast today for cleanup duty&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by1um/every_asshole_who_ever_chanted_drill_baby_drill/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by1um/every_asshole_who_ever_chanted_drill_baby_drill/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 21:51:41 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T21:51:41.671836+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/HelloYes&quot;&gt; HelloYes &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/billmaher/status/13089003490&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by1um/every_asshole_who_ever_chanted_drill_baby_drill/"&gt;[252 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lady Gaga 'Telephone' + US Troops = Amazing</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/bxzm3/lady_gaga_telephone_us_troops_amazing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/bxzm3/lady_gaga_telephone_us_troops_amazing/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 19:06:03 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T19:06:03.689727+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/rustysproutz&quot;&gt; rustysproutz &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=haHXgFU7qNI&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/bxzm3/lady_gaga_telephone_us_troops_amazing/"&gt;[124 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Denmark's KFC website hacked by Muslims, look fast before someone fixes it!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/by3ew/denmarks_kfc_website_hacked_by_muslims_look_fast/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/by3ew/denmarks_kfc_website_hacked_by_muslims_look_fast/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:23:20 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-30T00:23:20.762353+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/scoutsiren&quot;&gt; scoutsiren &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://kfc.dk/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/by3ew/denmarks_kfc_website_hacked_by_muslims_look_fast/"&gt;[106 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Valve has finally revealed the official launch date for Steam on the Mac</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/by38k/valve_has_finally_revealed_the_official_launch/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/by38k/valve_has_finally_revealed_the_official_launch/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 00:01:59 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-30T00:01:59.380211+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/by38k/valve_has_finally_revealed_the_official_launch/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by38k.png&quot; alt=&quot;Valve has finally revealed the official launch date for Steam on the Mac&quot; title=&quot;Valve has finally revealed the official launch date for Steam on the Mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/UPSLynx&quot;&gt; UPSLynx &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://gaming.icrontic.com/news/steam-on-mac-gets-official-launch-date/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/by38k/valve_has_finally_revealed_the_official_launch/"&gt;[35 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Valve has finally revealed the official launch date for Steam on the Mac</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by38k.png" /></item><item><title>I wish I was a little bit taller, I wish I was a baller [pic]</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/by0yo/i_wish_i_was_a_little_bit_taller_i_wish_i_was_a/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/by0yo/i_wish_i_was_a_little_bit_taller_i_wish_i_was_a/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 20:38:11 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T20:38:11.665936+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/curtisack&quot;&gt; curtisack &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/33597592@N08/4564094074/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/by0yo/i_wish_i_was_a_little_bit_taller_i_wish_i_was_a/"&gt;[74 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hey reddit, I got my dog fixed yesterday. This is the position he chose to recuperate in as soon as we got home.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxvuh/hey_reddit_i_got_my_dog_fixed_yesterday_this_is/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxvuh/hey_reddit_i_got_my_dog_fixed_yesterday_this_is/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 15:21:57 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T15:21:57.220546+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxvuh/hey_reddit_i_got_my_dog_fixed_yesterday_this_is/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxvuh.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hey reddit, I got my dog fixed yesterday. This is the position he chose to recuperate in as soon as we got home.&quot; title=&quot;Hey reddit, I got my dog fixed yesterday. This is the position he chose to recuperate in as soon as we got home.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/OblioNilsson&quot;&gt; OblioNilsson &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/hW0R8.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxvuh/hey_reddit_i_got_my_dog_fixed_yesterday_this_is/"&gt;[490 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Hey reddit, I got my dog fixed yesterday. This is the position he chose to recuperate in as soon as we got home.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxvuh.png" /></item><item><title>It's a trap!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by2l8/its_a_trap/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by2l8/its_a_trap/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 23:00:22 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T23:00:22.802307+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by2l8/its_a_trap/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by2l8.png&quot; alt=&quot;It's a trap!&quot; title=&quot;It's a trap!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/LexMortis&quot;&gt; LexMortis &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.fokzine.net/upload/100429_97351_its_a_trap.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by2l8/its_a_trap/"&gt;[57 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>It's a trap!</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by2l8.png" /></item><item><title>This is an Accident waiting to happen</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxuhj/this_is_an_accident_waiting_to_happen/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxuhj/this_is_an_accident_waiting_to_happen/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 14:09:54 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T14:09:54.624838+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxuhj/this_is_an_accident_waiting_to_happen/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxuhj.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is an Accident waiting to happen&quot; title=&quot;This is an Accident waiting to happen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/MindVirus&quot;&gt; MindVirus &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/u2n8r.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxuhj/this_is_an_accident_waiting_to_happen/"&gt;[1061 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>This is an Accident waiting to happen</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxuhj.png" /></item><item><title>Remember the cop who body checked the cyclist and then charged him with assault? Cop found guilty, faces up to four years.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by0cn/remember_the_cop_who_body_checked_the_cyclist_and/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by0cn/remember_the_cop_who_body_checked_the_cyclist_and/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 19:54:19 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T19:54:19.299687+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/HMG-CoAReductase&quot;&gt; HMG-CoAReductase &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2010/04/30/nyregion/30pogan.html?hp&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/by0cn/remember_the_cop_who_body_checked_the_cyclist_and/"&gt;[112 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Facebook Group 'Praying' For President Obama's Death Passes 1 Million Members</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/bxxcr/facebook_group_praying_for_president_obamas_death/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/bxxcr/facebook_group_praying_for_president_obamas_death/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 16:49:54 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T16:49:54.391022+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/filmfiend999&quot;&gt; filmfiend999 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/04/28/facebook-group-praying-fo_n_555227.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/bxxcr/facebook_group_praying_for_president_obamas_death/"&gt;[906 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Did I miss it? Or is just not a big deal? Either way, can we please show some collective concern at the 210,000 gallons a day of crude oil pumping out into the Gulf of Mexico.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/bxqxv/did_i_miss_it_or_is_just_not_a_big_deal_either/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/bxqxv/did_i_miss_it_or_is_just_not_a_big_deal_either/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 10:43:39 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T10:43:39.738926+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/feedto_feed&quot;&gt; feedto_feed &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/americas/8650620.stm&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/bxqxv/did_i_miss_it_or_is_just_not_a_big_deal_either/"&gt;[1199 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Steve Jobs: &quot;we strongly believe that all standards pertaining to the web should be open&quot; [...] &quot;What they don’t say is that almost all this video is also available in a more modern format, H.264&quot;... wait what?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/bxyx8/steve_jobs_we_strongly_believe_that_all_standards/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/bxyx8/steve_jobs_we_strongly_believe_that_all_standards/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 18:20:40 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T18:20:40.641810+00:00</dc:date><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/citricsquid&quot;&gt; citricsquid &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot;&gt; programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/?reddit&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/bxyx8/steve_jobs_we_strongly_believe_that_all_standards/"&gt;[446 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I need a taco!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxw2i/i_need_a_taco/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxw2i/i_need_a_taco/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 15:35:11 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T15:35:11.886627+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxw2i/i_need_a_taco/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxw2i.png&quot; alt=&quot;I need a taco!&quot; title=&quot;I need a taco!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/gzoont&quot;&gt; gzoont &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/CzWS6&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/bxw2i/i_need_a_taco/"&gt;[56 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>I need a taco!</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_bxw2i.png" /></item><item><title>&quot;Dear Connie&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by17m/dear_connie/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by17m/dear_connie/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 20:58:23 +0000</pubDate><dc:date>2010-04-29T20:58:23.705708+00:00</dc:date><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by17m/dear_connie/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by17m.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Dear Connie&amp;quot; &quot; title=&quot;&amp;quot;Dear Connie&amp;quot; &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/cyclopath&quot;&gt; cyclopath &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/KYKDK.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/by17m/dear_connie/"&gt;[74 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>&quot;Dear Connie&quot;</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_by17m.png" /></item></channel></rss>