<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://static.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>Fuck all websites that effectively turn the BACK button into another REFRESH button.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/elv21/fuck_all_websites_that_effectively_turn_the_back/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/elv21/fuck_all_websites_that_effectively_turn_the_back/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 22:13:33 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/TheExchangeStudent&quot;&gt; TheExchangeStudent &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/elv21/fuck_all_websites_that_effectively_turn_the_back/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/elv21/fuck_all_websites_that_effectively_turn_the_back/"&gt;[421 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cheaters never win.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/blog/comments/elqgs/cheaters_never_win/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/blog/comments/elqgs/cheaters_never_win/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 17:34:59 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, a rumor spreads that someone has figured out a way to manipulate reddit. Now, we're certainly not going to claim that we're invulnerable to all possible present and future attacks (lest we attract unwanted attention from bored geniuses), but in the five-and-a-half years that we've been running this site, a lot of scummy people have tried a lot of scummy things, and we've gotten pretty good at defending against them. It's been a long time since anyone came up with a trick that we haven't seen ten times before.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it's not enough to thwart the cheaters. The mere &lt;em&gt;rumor&lt;/em&gt; of cheating can itself be dangerous: If enough people believe it, it undermines the trust and cooperation that make our community work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That's why we were annoyed last month when Forbes published &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.forbes.com/elizabethwoyke/2010/11/10/240-to-place-story-on-digg-front-page-one-marketing-firms-pitch/&quot; &gt;a stunningly irresponsible, sensationalist piece&lt;/a&gt; that reads like a press release for one of these manipulation companies. There's a link to their site, they give the name of the sales rep, list their services (e.g., $80-$200 to game your link onto the reddit frontpage), discuss bulk discounts, and describe a client who supposedly saw pageviews rise 5000%. Even their slimy motto made it into the article: &quot;You talk, and we make the world listen.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I wrote to the author the day the piece was published, asking her to actually test the claims she was repeating. She politely declined.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;So why are we talking about this today? Well, last night the company in question wrote to a number of high-karma redditors, trying to tempt them over to the dark side. Fortunately, a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://everything2.com/title/Many+Bothans+died+to+bring+us+this+information&quot; &gt;Bothans&lt;/a&gt; relayed the message on to us, and we've decided to publish an excerpt:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I work with [repugnant company], a social media agency that promotes clients on sites just like Reddit ... The problem is that our accounts suck :( and we don’t know how to promote on Reddit, and as a result our submissions go nowhere with no votes other than our own single vote from submitting it. What I’m asking is if you would be willing to work with us? We would send you something, and if you think it’s great social media quality content, you could help us promote it through your account. We would of course be willing to pay for your time and effort to push it if you’d be interested.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now, as much as we want to avoid insulting redditors' intelligence, we're going to spell out very clearly a number of things you should already know:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;We know of no company that can successfully manipulate reddit, though many advertise that they can. The closest success that comes to mind is the &quot;designer rolex sneakers!&quot; spam that sometimes appears in the comments before being downvoted, reported, and removed from the site.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;If you pay a company to game reddit for you, you're a sucker and you're throwing your money away. Not only will it not work, our anti-cheating code tends to overreact, and you may find it harder than ever to get your links on reddit.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;If you try to sell your vote to such a company, beware that you might not actually get paid. (&quot;Oh, I know these guys are dishonorable toward everyone else in the world, but I'm sure they'll treat &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; fairly!&quot;)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;If we catch you attempting to cheat, particularly by joining a voting ring, you may find your reddit experience... degraded.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, and most importantly of all:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you have something that you want to promote on reddit, and are willing to spend money to do it, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/ad_inq&quot; &gt;just buy a sponsored link!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; It's twenty damn dollars, you won't have a guilty conscience, you'll help support reddit, and most importantly of all, &lt;em&gt;it will actually work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/raldi&quot;&gt; raldi &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/blog/&quot;&gt; blog&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/elqgs/cheaters_never_win/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/blog/comments/elqgs/cheaters_never_win/"&gt;[1326 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Very unfortunate choice of shape for the price tags, really.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elss3/very_unfortunate_choice_of_shape_for_the_price/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elss3/very_unfortunate_choice_of_shape_for_the_price/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:16:01 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elss3/very_unfortunate_choice_of_shape_for_the_price/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_elss3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Very unfortunate choice of shape for the price tags, really.&quot; title=&quot;Very unfortunate choice of shape for the price tags, really.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/bipo&quot;&gt; bipo &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/FAnQG.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elss3/very_unfortunate_choice_of_shape_for_the_price/"&gt;[630 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Very unfortunate choice of shape for the price tags, really.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_elss3.png" /></item><item><title>The Humble Indie Bundle #2: Pay what you want for five awesome games (+ charity)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/elpko/the_humble_indie_bundle_2_pay_what_you_want_for/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/elpko/the_humble_indie_bundle_2_pay_what_you_want_for/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 16:47:36 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/parsap&quot;&gt; parsap &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humblebundle.com/?live&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/elpko/the_humble_indie_bundle_2_pay_what_you_want_for/"&gt;[776 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Every space mission from the last 50 years on one map.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/eltdi/every_space_mission_from_the_last_50_years_on_one/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/eltdi/every_space_mission_from_the_last_50_years_on_one/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:43:48 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/whothehellispat2&quot;&gt; whothehellispat2 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&quot;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2445/4002050596_0c2b6c4dd2_o.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/eltdi/every_space_mission_from_the_last_50_years_on_one/"&gt;[226 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>If people tried to pay for other services and goods like they try to pay for programming services</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/elq4s/if_people_tried_to_pay_for_other_services_and/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/elq4s/if_people_tried_to_pay_for_other_services_and/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 17:18:06 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/toomuchpineinthecone&quot;&gt; toomuchpineinthecone &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/&quot;&gt; programming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dump.com/2010/12/13/the-vendor-client-relationship-in-real-world-situations-video/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/elq4s/if_people_tried_to_pay_for_other_services_and/"&gt;[705 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I knew it!!! (pic)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/ely2c/i_knew_it_pic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/ely2c/i_knew_it_pic/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 01:13:12 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/SPectrXX&quot;&gt; SPectrXX &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/NUw5B.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/ely2c/i_knew_it_pic/"&gt;[57 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>The secret to trolling</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elqw2/the_secret_to_trolling/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elqw2/the_secret_to_trolling/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 18:00:40 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/catalanfighter&quot;&gt; catalanfighter &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://26.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ld8qgeeG1g1qe11kdo1_500.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elqw2/the_secret_to_trolling/"&gt;[304 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Julian Assange freed on bail</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eloaw/julian_assange_freed_on_bail/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eloaw/julian_assange_freed_on_bail/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 15:41:52 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/undergrounDinosaur&quot;&gt; undergrounDinosaur &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/Reuters/status/14702207505014784&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/eloaw/julian_assange_freed_on_bail/"&gt;[677 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Are you joking me!? Wikileaks shows EPA knew about a pesticide responsible for dramatic decline in the world bee population (crosspost from r/environment)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eloun/are_you_joking_me_wikileaks_shows_epa_knew_about/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eloun/are_you_joking_me_wikileaks_shows_epa_knew_about/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 16:11:36 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/parasitedan&quot;&gt; parasitedan &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/environment/comments/ekt49/mystery_to_dramatic_honey_bee_decline_solved_epa/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/eloun/are_you_joking_me_wikileaks_shows_epa_knew_about/"&gt;[197 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Really stupid question. Don't upvote.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/elz8g/really_stupid_question_dont_upvote/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/elz8g/really_stupid_question_dont_upvote/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 02:27:47 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey guys,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I've got an image I'd like to post that I believe reddit would find amusing but how do I properly post an image with the thumbnail adjacent to the post?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Would the imgur link be in the url section? Direct link or do I need image tags?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Really stupid question, I know. Thanks for the assistance!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit: Well this has been unexpected. All the upvotes and such.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For those curious, here's what I was referring to. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/elzep/used_cover_at_the_gamestop/&quot; &gt;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/elzep/used_cover_at_the_gamestop/&lt;/a&gt; There is in fact, a boob.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Siegfried262&quot;&gt; Siegfried262 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/elz8g/really_stupid_question_dont_upvote/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/elz8g/really_stupid_question_dont_upvote/"&gt;[58 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Are there any Vancouver Doctors here able to perform a miracle? I don't know where else to turn...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eltb8/are_there_any_vancouver_doctors_here_able_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eltb8/are_there_any_vancouver_doctors_here_able_to/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:40:35 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello Reddit, I'm sorry if this is in the wrong spot, I'm at work and trying not to cry after writing all this out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It's sad that I have to turn to the anonymous internet to try and solve this, but the BC medical system continues to fail my mother and we really have expended all other options. This is my last option, and I hope we can find a solution here. If not, I don't know where else to turn or what we will do...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I've removed the original OP to a seperate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eltb8/are_there_any_vancouver_doctors_here_able_to/c193kw8&quot; &gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; as it had some key information wrong and was detracting attention. What follows is the situation in my mothers own words:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MY STORY.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2003, I fell off my kid's skateboard, after successfully rolling down a driveway. I had on all the proper gear but a butt protector. I fell so hard I cracked my back teeth, and the top of my head hurt for over a week; I felt disoriented and strange. I went to the clinic and was given an odd look by the doctor who said he had no idea why I felt like that but &quot;I was walking so I must be fine&quot;. I was never checked physically. I went back about a month later as I had an odd aching in both my lower legs which i could not relieve, and was told I was depressed!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I changed my job (and doctor) and started my own housecleaning service to boarding houses, pensioners trying to stay in their homes and foster parents. The pain was moving to encompass all of my legs and lower back, so much pain that i could not pinpoint an exact location. I saw Dr. A at this time, about 4 weeks into my new job, who wanted me to come back in a few weeks to &quot; review my symptoms.&quot; Please note- &lt;em&gt;I had never had a back problem in my life, until I fell.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I never made it that long, I collapsed from the pain about 6 weeks into my new job.&lt;/em&gt; I could not stand on my legs, the pain was so severe I fell apart completely. I was taken to the clinic by 2 friends who between them carried me out to the car and into the office. I was given a &quot;touch your toes&quot; exam and then told I had something like MS, even though I said, &quot; I fell in the summer and I did something to my back&quot;. Dr. A, I was with for only a few months as he sent me to 1 neurologist, an appointment I waited 3 months for, who had me touch my toes and then told me I was &quot;just depressed&quot; and to go get a job, ignoring that I had been working, I had just lost my business. I went back and changed doctors. I hadn't much selection as we were in a small community with only one clinic and a few doctors, and I could not afford to seek a physician in another town on a limited income and in such pain. (Even today I dread sitting in a vehicle, or anywhere for that matter, for even a short length of time.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Dr. B- I was with for the next 5 years or so as he was the only doctor at our only clinic who said he would send me for tests, but each time I went for a CT or MRI I found out no request for imaging of the tailbone had been requested. The doctors felt that anything below the S-1 level was inconsequential and not worth looking at. I was sent to another neurologist, again, (as the doctors seemed to think I had something like MS, refusing to listen to my cries of &quot; I fell and hurt my back!&quot;) who also had me touch my toes then said I was just depressed, and needed more exorcise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was given many different anti-depressants and anti-inflammatories, gabapentin, and steroids, for more than 2 years, while in such severe pain that I finally turned to alcohol for relief after 1 &amp;amp; 1/2 years, it was that or lose my mind from the pain. The car had died and life was so much harder from the pain. I wanted my legs cut off. No one would listen. There was no help. I needed relief from the pain every 1-2 days, I can go no longer than that without breaking down completely and utterly. I could not lay around in bed to ease the horrible pain, I had children to raise. Someone needed to get them up and going, manage the household, get them to events, get food in. There was no one else. If I had not kept going, I would have lost them both to foster care. So I used alcohol at the end of the day to ease the horrible pain before I lost my mind. I almost lost my kids. I lost their respect for years, but I am still here.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As far as the medical community was concerned I had no reason to say I was in pain; as &lt;em&gt;they had refused to image the injured area they decided it was all in my head.&lt;/em&gt; So I had no reason to rest from the pain. I was told I was &quot;out of shape&quot;, and to excersise more. &lt;em&gt;I was refused the right to see a back doctor&lt;/em&gt; as I was told I &quot;just had arthritis&quot; showing up on CT and MRI, and nothing could be done. As my Rheumatiod factor came back negative, it was decided I had &quot;old-age arthritis&quot;, at 44!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After using alcohol for pain relief, as I did not want to use street drugs ever, we had a horrible climax, as a single parent is not allowed to drink around their children, whereupon I was required to speak with a psychiatrist who told me although I was likely depressed by now, it was what is called &quot;situational depression&quot;, in other words, address the situation causing the problem and the depression will likely ease or leave. I was at this time allowed to have pain relief, which is when I started on the morphine. I took the 2nd lowest dose possible. &lt;em&gt;I was told from there that imaging my tailbone was a waste of time and money&lt;/em&gt; because I couldn't have a problem there, and even if I did, nothing could be done.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was refused the right to see a rheumatologist&lt;/em&gt; because I was told i just had &quot;old-age&quot; arthritis, at 44, and nothing could be done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was told I was not likely to improve but forget retraining for work as I was too old to get a job, but.... I was refused support for disability as I was told there was nothing wrong with me but &quot;old-age arthritis&quot; and that I wasn't worth supporting. His words.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was told by Dr. B that if I went to another doctor I would not receive my pain medication, and lo and behold, if Dr. B was unavailable and I had to see another doctor I was treated like a drug-seeker and lectured for taking it, told to see my primary physician if I wished to have this prescription.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was given a 2-year &quot; temporary excuse from seeking work&quot; chit for welfare every 2 years for 5 years even though I begged to be sent to a specialist, anyone, but was refused. This gave me no rights for disability, no bus passes, ect. It was simply a stop-gap measure while I was repeatedly told to &quot;live with it&quot;. I saw a chiropractor during this time who clicked down my back and set off a sharp pain in my side that has remained for over 5 years, all I have been told is-&quot; we don't know why that would happen&quot;. I went back again but he made it worse and I had to stop, I was holding my side when standing or walking, from the pain. In the spring of 2009 I was finally allowed to see a rheumatologist who told me that none of my previous history was applicable, we were to ignore all that, and as I was now 49 I had osteoporosis, which according to him does not cause pain, so the pain was all in my head and I was &quot;just depressed&quot;. He based this on a number of incorrect facts which disturbed me greatly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I saw my doctor after this and asked why on earth this rheumatologist would have a record of events that did not coincide with my history, my assumption being my doctor had provided this incorrect info. &lt;em&gt;He laughed it off, and was fired a month later for putting his own blood in patient's tests.&lt;/em&gt; ( This disiplinary action is on the College's website, I was never told why he just disappeared from his practice.) Enter a new doctor to our clinic. This doctor agreed to xray my tailbone, was done finally in April of 2010, 7 YEARS AFTER I FELL. When I came in to review the results in June ( I was never called) I was told my tailbone was bent to the left, but this could not possibly be causing the pain. He then turned the screen slightly so I could read it, and I saw the words Spina Bifida Occulta. I asked what that was and was given a lecture on the common occurrence of such ( it occurs in 10% of the population) and how it was not related to the pain. I asked- but what if one FALLS on it?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; No, it is irrelevant, I was told. I asked to what degree my tailbone was bent. I was told it must not be much or the radiologist would have put numbers in. I went up to the hospital and spoke with the imaging dept, they told me that Xrays don't show enough, and my doctor should be sending me for a sit/stand mri to determine more about the tailbone out of place. At this time I was preparing to move, and my doctor said that I could pursue it here if I wished but likely nothing could be done, nor would I be able to receive the pain medication any more. We came to Vancouver in Sept 2010 and I firstly found a clinic nearby hoping to negate long travel and parking fees. This was a bad experience as I was told I would be re-imaged, they preferred their own xrays. I was xrayed then CT'd. The scans all stopped, once again, at the S-1 level, the doctors telling me nothing below there was important. I am now wondering if the coccyx and sacrum are even studied? I was told quite firmly that under no circumstances would I receive any morphine, although after much begging and pleading I was allowed one last month in order to get the rest of my stuff here on Oct 8th. I was told the addiction rate to this is high so I must be an addict and cannot have it anymore. I DEPEND on it to relieve the pain, as I DEPEND on my cane to stop me from hunching over like a gnome from severe pain, as I DEPEND on water when I am thirsty. I tried 2 doctors there and left. I have been refused the pain medication since. I am now out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I then went to a walk-in hoping to find a physician with knowledge of the coccyx and the related area. &lt;em&gt;The first doctor wanted to readjust my tailbone internally without seeing any images of the area.&lt;/em&gt; I ran. The second doctor sent for the report on the xray of my tailbone. &lt;em&gt;What was sent was not the actual report but a summary stating I &quot;might have something there, possibly due to an old injury, and that there was some small abnormality of the sacrum&quot;, no mention of what or where.&lt;/em&gt; The doctor who reviewed that said I should have seen a back doctor years ago. He said he would send me to one. I tried to explain the &quot;sit/stand MRI&quot; which determines whether or not the tailbone is solidly bent or floating around in there. He said he had never heard of such a thing and doubted there was such a thing. I requested a name I had come across, not a surgeon but an osteopath, but he specified I &quot;needed&quot; to see a back surgeon, and I am at the mercy of going where ever he decides to send me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been here almost 4 months and still cannot get imaging done for this area.&lt;/strong&gt; I feel that as I am the one who fell, and as I am the one living with this pain, I should be listened to, however this is not happening, still. I have no more pain relief as nothing else works. I will not drink. I therefor do little as minimal sitting and standing cause pain and exhaust me. I am required to look for work but have no idea whom would want me as I am. I have no training for anything but physical labour. I was not allowed to retrain while on the temporary exemption, the view being if one can take a course one can work. My small fund I have been living on for a year is almost gone, and I am losing hope. I dared not spend it on training as we needed to move, our town had gone resort. I have missed half of my children's life so far struggling to cope with this, and my teen still at home deserves better than a mom who has to keep lying down on her side from the pain. Without pain relief I am too exhausted to search further, &lt;em&gt;I need to search a knowledgable doctor but am in such pain I dread even going for groceries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is a vicious loop I cannot break out of in time to prevent what is coming&lt;/em&gt;- we will be evicted at the end January as I will be out of funds and no longer able to pay my rent. I have been told by welfare that without a doctors' support I am to get a job. I so wish I could find something I could do but.......My son has been a wonderful support for the past year since he obtained good employment but I feel sick to my stomach having his help. He helped us move and keep the vehicle on the road so he can get his license and drive for me, but he is now drained. It makes me feel such a failure as a parent. I am shunned by my father and sister for accepting my son's support. I do not socialize, as many people find it awkward to converse with someone who needs to stand or lay down. I have issues from the fall such as saddle numbness, incontinence, vision disturbance, I don't know what else to say, or do. I can be seen at a pain clinic, next fall. I can see a neurologist, next summer. I do not know yet how long I will wait to see the back clinic. Sometimes I am sent to private doctors and have to refuse. I have to keep within my msp coverage. This waiting and searching all takes time and I am almost out. I am very, very scared and wonder how a simple fall could have resulted in such chaos, why have I been continually ignored,when I keep saying- &quot;I fell and I did something to my back&quot;. Why am I denied pain relief that improves my life and gets me up and moving, because of what others may have done? If anyone out there has, or knows someone with a simalar experience I am DESPERATELY seeking a physician who is familiar with the coccyx, sacrum, Spina Bifida Occulta, and trauma to this area.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tl;Dr Version:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mother has issues from the severe fall such as saddle numbness, incontinence, and vision disturbance. She can neither sit nor stand for long periods without severe pain, and bending over is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;She's seeking a physician who is familiar with the coccyx, sacrum, possibly Spina Bifida Occulta, and trauma to this area (lower back). Especially a physician who will refer her for imaging below the S-1 level and not deny it based on &quot;irrelevance&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soonest to see a Neurologist is 7 months, a pain clinic is a year. If we do not find a doctor who will at least support a disability claim in the short term based on existing symptoms, her and my sister will be homeless by the early spring. I will be bankrupt trying to support them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Medical record is contaminated as her longtime doctor was suspended for severe medical malpractice by the College of Physicians. Among other reasons: &lt;em&gt;submitting his own urine and blood samples in lieu of his patients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Medicallyirrelevant&quot;&gt; Medicallyirrelevant &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/eltb8/are_there_any_vancouver_doctors_here_able_to/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/eltb8/are_there_any_vancouver_doctors_here_able_to/"&gt;[531 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fox News Won't Admit That Republicans Voted Against 9/11 Rescue Workers | The Nation</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/elsrb/fox_news_wont_admit_that_republicans_voted/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/elsrb/fox_news_wont_admit_that_republicans_voted/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:15:05 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Graefaxe&quot;&gt; Graefaxe &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenation.com/blog/157076/fox-news-wont-admit-republicans-voted-against-911-rescue-workers&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/elsrb/fox_news_wont_admit_that_republicans_voted/"&gt;[88 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yes, a bunch of us like M*A*S*H but a friend of mine built this in his back yard.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eltdw/yes_a_bunch_of_us_like_mash_but_a_friend_of_mine/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eltdw/yes_a_bunch_of_us_like_mash_but_a_friend_of_mine/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:44:29 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/relocopter&quot;&gt; relocopter &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/ztcon&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/eltdw/yes_a_bunch_of_us_like_mash_but_a_friend_of_mine/"&gt;[286 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I'm Posting Bail Money for Julian Assange (by Michael Moore)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/ellhp/why_im_posting_bail_money_for_julian_assange_by/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/ellhp/why_im_posting_bail_money_for_julian_assange_by/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 12:37:43 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Tyroneshoolaces&quot;&gt; Tyroneshoolaces &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.michaelmoore.com/words/mike-friends-blog/why-im-posting-bail-money&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/ellhp/why_im_posting_bail_money_for_julian_assange_by/"&gt;[992 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to destroy your company cred with one lame/douchy CEO photo.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elqpi/how_to_destroy_your_company_cred_with_one/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elqpi/how_to_destroy_your_company_cred_with_one/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 17:50:18 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/lolstuff&quot;&gt; lolstuff &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visualtargeting.com/stevenkronick.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elqpi/how_to_destroy_your_company_cred_with_one/"&gt;[333 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>That poor robot...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elwu7/that_poor_robot/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elwu7/that_poor_robot/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 23:55:10 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Happysin&quot;&gt; Happysin &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/R9xNm.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elwu7/that_poor_robot/"&gt;[18 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hatred … [pic]</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/elmou/hatred_pic/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/elmou/hatred_pic/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 14:07:55 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/rqwe&quot;&gt; rqwe &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://abnlive.tumblr.com/post/2312391991/hatred&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/elmou/hatred_pic/"&gt;[1796 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>The future of DJing is here...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eltst/the_future_of_djing_is_here/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eltst/the_future_of_djing_is_here/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 21:06:15 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Zankou911&quot;&gt; Zankou911 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frequency.com/video/tken-experience/273449?embed=true&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/eltst/the_future_of_djing_is_here/"&gt;[167 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Check out this adult link.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elmm7/check_out_this_adult_link/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elmm7/check_out_this_adult_link/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 14:02:55 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/scottcmu&quot;&gt; scottcmu &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/zTItf.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elmm7/check_out_this_adult_link/"&gt;[162 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Do you have a family and are finding that your financial situation may prevent you from buying your kid(s) a Christmas present?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/elmpf/do_you_have_a_family_and_are_finding_that_your/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/elmpf/do_you_have_a_family_and_are_finding_that_your/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 14:09:01 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit - I really am doing my best to respond to everyone. If you haven't heard from me, don't worry, I will get to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/Favors/comments/el4s0/offer_have_a_family_and_money_is_tight_this/&quot; &gt;I asked this same question in r/favors.&lt;/a&gt; With Christmas fast approaching, it seems there are an ever increasing amount of people expressing discouragement to what will be a bleak holiday for them and their family; even the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/Favors/ek6gv&quot; &gt;mods in r/favors had taken notice&lt;/a&gt;, and I've &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/el523&quot; &gt;seen them in the comments of r/askreddit as well&lt;/a&gt;. Some of these may be spam, but for the few that are genuine, some fellow redditors and myself would like to help out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We pulled together around $700 to purchase toys for any family who cannot afford them on their own right now (like a mini reddit &quot;Toys for Tots&quot; program?).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We'd also like to support fellow redditor, Hans Masing (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/self/comments/ejj76/&quot; &gt;he gave jmk4422 a job, and gave a bullied girl with Huntington's disease a special day&lt;/a&gt;), by purchasing items from his store: &lt;a href=&quot;http://treetowntoys.com/&quot; &gt;Tree Town Toys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So how are the holidays looking for you and your family? Will things be too tight for gifts this year? Do you need help?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR THOSE WHO WOULD LIKE TO HELP:&lt;/strong&gt; Right now I am still fielding the massive amount of requests I've received. Funds are covered right now, but as they are needed, I will let you know. Thank you for your many generous offers, you are an amazing community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/skitch&quot; &gt;skitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/lemonlament&quot; &gt;lemonlament&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/mchr/&quot; &gt;mchr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/JustAnotherAlien&quot; &gt;JustAnotherAlien&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/LostPuma&quot; &gt;LostPuma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/smonson&quot; &gt;smonson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/nuttyrussian&quot; &gt;nuttyrussian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/human_virus&quot; &gt;human_virus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/bingosherlock&quot; &gt;bingosherlock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/acousticbruises&quot; &gt;acousticbruises&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/LawnChairTime&quot; &gt;LawnChairTime&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/gilageek&quot; &gt;gilageek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/goutmaximum&quot; &gt;goutmaximum&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/the_thinker&quot; &gt;the_thinker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/bingoshark&quot; &gt;bingoshark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/jayco&quot;&gt; jayco &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/elmpf/do_you_have_a_family_and_are_finding_that_your/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/elmpf/do_you_have_a_family_and_are_finding_that_your/"&gt;[580 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rare Honesty About WikiLeaks and American Exceptionalism - ' if America should be permitted to prosecute a non-American like Assange for disclosing American secrets, countries like France, China, or Iran should be able to prosecute Americans for disclosing their secrets'</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/elwip/rare_honesty_about_wikileaks_and_american/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/elwip/rare_honesty_about_wikileaks_and_american/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 23:36:01 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/shallah&quot;&gt; shallah &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://opiniojuris.org/2010/12/14/rare-honesty-about-wikileaks-and-american-exceptionalism/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/elwip/rare_honesty_about_wikileaks_and_american/"&gt;[26 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>16-bit Memories</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elljg/16bit_memories/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elljg/16bit_memories/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 12:41:11 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elljg/16bit_memories/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_elljg.png&quot; alt=&quot;16-bit Memories&quot; title=&quot;16-bit Memories&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/giava&quot;&gt; giava &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/0gZzv.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/elljg/16bit_memories/"&gt;[720 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>16-bit Memories</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_elljg.png" /></item><item><title>The view from the Eiffel Tower, Dec. 10th. Mais Oui!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elk1v/the_view_from_the_eiffel_tower_dec_10th_mais_oui/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elk1v/the_view_from_the_eiffel_tower_dec_10th_mais_oui/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 10:09:59 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/nomdeweb&quot;&gt; nomdeweb &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/7cghx.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/elk1v/the_view_from_the_eiffel_tower_dec_10th_mais_oui/"&gt;[466 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Snow in Australia!!! Oh no, wait...WTF?!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/elxf5/snow_in_australia_oh_no_waitwtf/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/elxf5/snow_in_australia_oh_no_waitwtf/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 00:32:47 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/21000&quot;&gt; 21000 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&quot;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blognator.com/ocean-foam-at-australia%e2%80%99s-beaches/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/elxf5/snow_in_australia_oh_no_waitwtf/"&gt;[47 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>