<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>reddit: the front page of the internet</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://www.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit: the front page of the internet</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>These Christians get it....</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/atheism/comments/rgi88/these_christians_get_it/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/atheism/comments/rgi88/these_christians_get_it/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 21:57:50 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/atheism/comments/rgi88/these_christians_get_it/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://e.thumbs.redditmedia.com/WK21rkp_srI2NBVX.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;These Christians get it....&#34; title=&#34;These Christians get it....&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/oneder&#34;&gt; oneder &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/atheism/&#34;&gt; atheism&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/fkbYo&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/atheism/comments/rgi88/these_christians_get_it/"&gt;[553 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>These Christians get it....</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://e.thumbs.redditmedia.com/WK21rkp_srI2NBVX.jpg" /></item><item><title>Type this into your browser.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/rglrp/type_this_into_your_browser/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/rglrp/type_this_into_your_browser/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 23:04:37 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/rglrp/type_this_into_your_browser/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a.thumbs.redditmedia.com/GkSDCDlHvolNx88N.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Type this into your browser.&#34; title=&#34;Type this into your browser.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/victoryian&#34;&gt; victoryian &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/&#34;&gt; AdviceAnimals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://qkme.me/3oi5rs&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/rglrp/type_this_into_your_browser/"&gt;[294 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Type this into your browser.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://a.thumbs.redditmedia.com/GkSDCDlHvolNx88N.jpg" /></item><item><title>This semester is now ruined</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/rgl3z/this_semester_is_now_ruined/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/rgl3z/this_semester_is_now_ruined/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 22:52:17 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/rgl3z/this_semester_is_now_ruined/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/O0iOIJ1BHtIvdPdA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This semester is now ruined&#34; title=&#34;This semester is now ruined&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/McBurger&#34;&gt; McBurger &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&#34;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/mDtSE.jpg&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/rgl3z/this_semester_is_now_ruined/"&gt;[147 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>This semester is now ruined</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/O0iOIJ1BHtIvdPdA.jpg" /></item><item><title>Bill Cosby on grandmothers</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/rga57/bill_cosby_on_grandmothers/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/rga57/bill_cosby_on_grandmothers/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 19:25:18 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/JorgeGarrido&#34;&gt; JorgeGarrido &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&#34;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/rhXh5.jpg&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/rga57/bill_cosby_on_grandmothers/"&gt;[591 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Went hiking today and I found this</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/rggkl/went_hiking_today_and_i_found_this/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/rggkl/went_hiking_today_and_i_found_this/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 21:26:25 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/Madhats19&#34;&gt; Madhats19 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/&#34;&gt; WTF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/kFr8H.jpg&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/WTF/comments/rggkl/went_hiking_today_and_i_found_this/"&gt;[205 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Some Years From Now</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/rgpqj/some_years_from_now/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/rgpqj/some_years_from_now/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:21:27 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/rgpqj/some_years_from_now/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://d.thumbs.redditmedia.com/38Y8UDZOvh_Bbm7-.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Some Years From Now&#34; title=&#34;Some Years From Now&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/e5jhdtn&#34;&gt; e5jhdtn &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&#34;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/zFrTB.jpg&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/rgpqj/some_years_from_now/"&gt;[83 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Some Years From Now</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://d.thumbs.redditmedia.com/38Y8UDZOvh_Bbm7-.jpg" /></item><item><title>Waiting rooms are always more fun with an Irish Wolfhound.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/rgd8a/waiting_rooms_are_always_more_fun_with_an_irish/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/rgd8a/waiting_rooms_are_always_more_fun_with_an_irish/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:22:54 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/rgd8a/waiting_rooms_are_always_more_fun_with_an_irish/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a.thumbs.redditmedia.com/lAqnCo2qVKL1WiGB.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Waiting rooms are always more fun with an Irish Wolfhound. &#34; title=&#34;Waiting rooms are always more fun with an Irish Wolfhound. &#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/FrankieForte&#34;&gt; FrankieForte &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/&#34;&gt; aww&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/iv27u.jpg&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/aww/comments/rgd8a/waiting_rooms_are_always_more_fun_with_an_irish/"&gt;[292 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Waiting rooms are always more fun with an Irish Wolfhound.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://a.thumbs.redditmedia.com/lAqnCo2qVKL1WiGB.jpg" /></item><item><title>Spike Lee tweets Zimmerman's address, was wrong about it, and has endangered an innocent woman's life.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/rgcsa/spike_lee_tweets_zimmermans_address_was_wrong/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/rgcsa/spike_lee_tweets_zimmermans_address_was_wrong/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:14:33 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/JazzNeurotic&#34;&gt; JazzNeurotic &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&#34;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://dailycaller.com/2012/03/27/paper-spike-lee-tweeted-incorrect-george-zimmerman-address-possibly-putting-sanford-woman-in-danger/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/rgcsa/spike_lee_tweets_zimmermans_address_was_wrong/"&gt;[761 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Last words from my father. What did he say?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/rgbyu/last_words_from_my_father_what_did_he_say/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/rgbyu/last_words_from_my_father_what_did_he_say/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 19:59:36 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;My father passed away at home last Wednesday. A few hours before he passed, he motioned to my mom that he wanted to say something. She couldn&amp;#39;t make it out, so she gave him a small whiteboard and marker. He had trouble writing it out and was agitated when she couldn&amp;#39;t understand what he had written. I came out the following day and am still here in Kentucky helping out. It would be great if someone could figure out what he said. I immediately thought of Reddit and figured if there was anyone that could do it, it was the great mind that makes us Reddit. BTW, dad was 85 years old and a WWII Vet. He never reddited, but did give me my first computer. 300 baud dial-up. Those were the days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/cMjKE&#34;&gt;http://imgur.com/cMjKE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;edit: I have talked to my mom and received some clarification. The large letters on the left are my mom&amp;#39;s. She was trying to show him he would need to write big. The first thing he wrote was everything in the red marker. She then gave him a black marker. You can see something above the second set of words there on the right. He wrote smaller, but mom says it looks more like his handwriting. Thanks everyone who is taking a look and trying. We appreciate it. I&amp;#39;m working on new photos now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit: Thank you Reddit. I&amp;#39;ll try to get the higher-res photos up. I&amp;#39;m not at home, so it is a workaround to get photos with the right light, uploaded, etc. I have my dad&amp;#39;s signature and am working to find a sample of his handwriting. My mom says he appeared to be upset when she didn&amp;#39;t understand what he wrote. He made a very strong effort and pushed out the words, &amp;quot;black pen&amp;quot;. Then he wrote the words in black that you see above the second group of red words. Also, I would like to say thank you for everyone offering condolences. I&amp;#39;m grateful he was able to die at home in the arms of his wife. He had been so sick and in and out of the hospital so many years, to not die alone in some hospital or lonely hospital room was a great blessing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/orion44&#34;&gt; orion44 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&#34;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/rgbyu/last_words_from_my_father_what_did_he_say/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/rgbyu/last_words_from_my_father_what_did_he_say/"&gt;[1890 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I am a guy with a rare sexual illness. Its so life-ruining that one sufferer of it decided to be castrated to seek relief and start progressing with his life AMAA</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/rge55/i_am_a_guy_with_a_rare_sexual_illness_its_so/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/rge55/i_am_a_guy_with_a_rare_sexual_illness_its_so/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:42:07 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;md&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Username: 2sexy4mybody&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am a guy with a rare sexual illness. Its so life-ruining that one sufferer of it decided to be castrated to seek relief and start progressing with his life AMAA&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;15 years ago my life was turned upside-down. It was Christmas 1997. I&amp;#39;d just slept for 17 hours straight and when I woke up I still felt like I&amp;#39;d been hit by a truck. My sinuses were blocked, my eyes felt like they were bulging out their sockets, my memory was lagging, I had a sore throat and diarrhoea. I realised I was having difficulty thinking. All I wanted to do was close my eyes and sleep. I thought it was bad flu or some other virus. Doctors couldn&amp;#39;t diagnose me as my lab tests were all ok. I was a hard-working and I suppose high-achieving guy. I don&amp;#39;t think I&amp;#39;d taken a sick day in my life up to that point but I ended up having to have 4 weeks off work. And this was just the beginning&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Over time , I came to realise that the symptoms appeared whenever I ejaculated (sex, masturbation or nocturnal emissions). It turned out that Christmas 15 years ago was my introduction to Post-orgasmic Illness Syndrome, a rare and totally life-altering disorder. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;POIS causes severe tiredness, cognition problems, mood problems, muscle aches and feelings of fever to name just a few symptoms. In the beginning for me it would last about a month from a single ejaculation. Typically it lasts 5-14 days. Abstinence from sex/masturbation gives the only relief but that&amp;#39;s difficult to maintain Some men find they are never symptom-free as even if they abstain from sex or masturbation they get a nocturnal emission in their sleep before their symptoms can subside. This is a life-ruining illness affecting work and relationships. When I am symptomatic I often avoid meeting friends so they don’t see the usual sociable part of me disappear into this quiet,spaced out anti social person who has nothing to contribute to the conversation. In the gaps between my symptoms, I&amp;#39;m a normal, intelligent, motivated and genuinely happy guy. I&amp;#39;ve met some great girls in my life and even started relationships with some but I wasn&amp;#39;t able to sustain them . I&amp;#39;m nearly 40 now. I&amp;#39;d Like to settle and have kids but being more than friends with a girl affects my health and life too much. At least a couple of sufferers have openly contemplated suicide, I can definitely see how it can drive people to this. Sufferers typically feel they can&amp;#39;t talk about their condition and it consumes them with hopelessness and a sense of isolation. It can easily make one depressed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One guy, an educated professional with an advanced degree (which he got before his POIS started) took the drastic measure of castration! He was so disabled by POIS that he had his testicles and seminal vesicles removed and his ejaculatory ducts cauterised. It took him years to find doctors willing to do the procedure and had to travel to multiple countries to complete it. He succeeded in becoming POIS free and with the help of testosterone replacement therapy and other medications has been able to resume his life. The drastic action he took illustrates just how bad POIS can be.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I did countless hours of research trying to figure out what was wrong with me. Doctors weren&amp;#39;t able to help. After a few years, I came across an online forum started by people who had what I had. It was amazing to find out I wasn&amp;#39;t the only one going through this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We still don&amp;#39;t know what causes POIS. A doctor in the Netherlands first described Post-Orgasmic Illness Syndrome in 2002. One theory is that its an auto-immune reaction to our own semen - a sort of allergic reaction. Little research has been done though. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite the suffocating straitjacket of this illness there is some amazing positivity on our forums. We&amp;#39;ve managed to get POIS listed in the most respected rare disease databases - The National Institutes of Health in the USA and Orphanet in Europe and have done much to raise the profile of POIS. The man who underwent the castration was profiled in a tv documentary on The Learning Channel. Another guy is to be the subject of a medical documentary, to be aired on ABC, Australia in the next month. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What we really need is a dedicated medical research programme. Through the National Organisation for Rare Diseases (NORD) we are trying to raise enough money for a research grant for our condition. So far, all the money donated has been from POIS sufferers. We have collected around $6,000 from our personal donations, and a further $17,000 in pledges. The minimum amount required for the research grant is $33,500. All of those pledges will be converted into donations once the combined total reaches that magic $33,500. We have a week left to raise the full $33500 and get a grant this year , otherwise we&amp;#39;ll have to wait until 2013.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of our forum members noticed there have been some incredible life-transforming stories of people using reddit to fundraise. That is the biggest reason I&amp;#39;m here. However, we also need to raise awareness of POIS and reach out to others who must be suffering in silence. So I&amp;#39;m also here to answer your questions and inform about the existence of POIS. By reading this and mentioning POIS to others you are helping. If you feel you can also help us by making a small donation, that would be amazing. The place to do it is the National Organisation of Rare Disorders website here:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rarediseases.org/about/support/research-donations/fg_base_view_p3&#34;&gt;https://www.rarediseases.org/about/support/research-donations/fg_base_view_p3&lt;/a&gt; (Please select &amp;#39;Post-Orgasmic Illness Syndrome&amp;#39; from the drop-down list under &amp;quot;research fund&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can read more about the NORD grant program here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rarediseases.org/medical-professionals/research-grants/policy&#34;&gt;http://www.rarediseases.org/medical-professionals/research-grants/policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Visit our forums are here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thenakedscientists.com/forum/index.php?topic=6576.0&#34;&gt;http://www.thenakedscientists.com/forum/index.php?topic=6576.0&lt;/a&gt; and here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.poiscenter.com/forums/index.php&#34;&gt;http://www.poiscenter.com/forums/index.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To help give more insight into the impact of POIS, here are some quotes from some of our members (these are taken from actual forum posts)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;my professional life is getting wasted (Currently unemployed, I actually fear employment now), my marital life is getting wasted (No wife, not even a possible prospect), my social life is getting wasted and even my Dog has been starting to stare at me in weird manners lately..I feel he&amp;#39;s trying to tell me sometimes....: WHAT THE HECK IS WRONG WITH YOU MASTER?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I look at it this way. POIS took far too many years of my life. I made no progress for about 10 years, following the completion of a graduate degree. Anything I achieved before that was based on near total abstinence. That&amp;#39;s really difficult to maintain in college and shows the kind of iron willpower I had. Then I fell off the wagon and I&amp;#39;ve been in a relationship for many years which has made abstinence impossible (and it was never terribly desirable anyway ). In that time my brother who doesn&amp;#39;t have POIS and started out with about equal intelligence based on IQ tests at the start of puberty (we both scored over 150) learned 3 languages and got 2 masters degrees. It&amp;#39;s not that POIS has made me stupid but it&amp;#39;s taken away the point of trying to learn new things as I&amp;#39;ve known that 1) I would forget the material quickly 2) I&amp;#39;m too tired to apply most of it. So I have a constant reminder of the effects of POIS on my life. When you put a lost decade into perspective, it&amp;#39;s difficult to not feel huge disappointment that my life stalled for so long. When you leave college you don&amp;#39;t believe that the best and most productive years of your life will be written off but that&amp;#39;s how it&amp;#39;s worked out. Anyway, can&amp;#39;t dwell. Onwards we march &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve managed to get myself a job, starting next week, and I&amp;#39;m really worried that either; - I won&amp;#39;t be able to perform, and that I&amp;#39;ll start to fail at the job - I set my sights too low when I applied, and that I&amp;#39;ll feel completely unfulfilled. I program in C++ for some of my uni work, I can just about read and make sense of it and write some basic programs, whilst out POIS, soon as POIS I lose all ability to do any real work and usually sit there gazing at the screen as though I&amp;#39;m reading hebrew.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A message from the moderator of one of our forums:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When I emerged from a suicidal depression (over a lifetime ruined by POIS,) I immersed myself in the POIS forum. The POIS forum gave me MEANING – finally -- a burning passion developed in me to FIGHT this 18-headed monster the only way I knew how. The forum has become a Sacred Mission for me.&amp;quot; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;POIS eats away at your spirit. It destroys your sanity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you decide you can donate a little to our research fund, your money will be handled with complete care, honesty, and respect -- by a most wonderful non-profit organization. And – most importantly – you will have helped the countless men (and their families) whose lives have been utterly broken by POIS.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/2sexy4mybody&#34;&gt; 2sexy4mybody &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/&#34;&gt; IAmA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/rge55/i_am_a_guy_with_a_rare_sexual_illness_its_so/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/rge55/i_am_a_guy_with_a_rare_sexual_illness_its_so/"&gt;[663 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>The most extensive full face transplant to date has been completed, including both jaws, teeth, and tongue.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/rg3gg/the_most_extensive_full_face_transplant_to_date/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/rg3gg/the_most_extensive_full_face_transplant_to_date/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 17:19:03 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/nomdeweb&#34;&gt; nomdeweb &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/science/&#34;&gt; science&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2012/03/120327124904.htm&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/rg3gg/the_most_extensive_full_face_transplant_to_date/"&gt;[593 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>TIL of Franz Stigler, a German WWII pilot who refused to shoot a damaged US bomber piloted by Charlie Brown after seeing how damaged it was and decided to escort it to an allied air base. They both died in 2008 as close friends.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rg211/til_of_franz_stigler_a_german_wwii_pilot_who/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rg211/til_of_franz_stigler_a_german_wwii_pilot_who/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 16:50:22 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/DangerousNewb&#34;&gt; DangerousNewb &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/&#34;&gt; todayilearned&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlie_Brown_and_Franz_Stigler_story&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rg211/til_of_franz_stigler_a_german_wwii_pilot_who/"&gt;[371 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>US Supreme Court Throws Out Human Gene Patents</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/rfx6e/us_supreme_court_throws_out_human_gene_patents/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/rfx6e/us_supreme_court_throws_out_human_gene_patents/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 15:08:18 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/scientologist2&#34;&gt; scientologist2 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/&#34;&gt; technology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.yahoo.com/high-court-throws-human-gene-patents-161634977.html&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/rfx6e/us_supreme_court_throws_out_human_gene_patents/"&gt;[93 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Michael Bay confirms that &quot;Teenage&quot; and &quot;Mutant&quot; will be dropped from &quot;Ninja Turtles&quot; movie</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/rfu2c/michael_bay_confirms_that_teenage_and_mutant_will/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/rfu2c/michael_bay_confirms_that_teenage_and_mutant_will/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 13:52:58 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/mparlevliet&#34;&gt; mparlevliet &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/&#34;&gt; movies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.superherohype.com/news/articles/169997-michael-bay-posts-second-statement-on-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/rfu2c/michael_bay_confirms_that_teenage_and_mutant_will/"&gt;[1901 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>James Cameron releases the first ever video footage of the bottom of the Mariana Trench - seven miles below the ocean's surface.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/rfo3l/james_cameron_releases_the_first_ever_video/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/rfo3l/james_cameron_releases_the_first_ever_video/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 10:07:45 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/DrJulianBashir&#34;&gt; DrJulianBashir &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&#34;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/earthvideo/9168817/James-Camerons-first-footage-from-the-deep.html&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/rfo3l/james_cameron_releases_the_first_ever_video/"&gt;[1143 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creedence Clearwater Revival - Lookin' Out My Backdoor</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/rfrv4/creedence_clearwater_revival_lookin_out_my/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/rfrv4/creedence_clearwater_revival_lookin_out_my/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 12:47:01 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/that_norwegian_guy&#34;&gt; that_norwegian_guy &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/&#34;&gt; Music&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QNczeP33Yk0&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/rfrv4/creedence_clearwater_revival_lookin_out_my/"&gt;[258 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>You_got_it tells a tale of abandonment, no-money, and how karma is not always a bitch.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/rftf9/you_got_it_tells_a_tale_of_abandonment_nomoney/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/rftf9/you_got_it_tells_a_tale_of_abandonment_nomoney/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 13:35:37 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/vote4pedro2011&#34;&gt; vote4pedro2011 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/&#34;&gt; bestof&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/rfg7j/what_are_some_famous_last_words_youve_told_to_an/c45eq4e&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/rftf9/you_got_it_tells_a_tale_of_abandonment_nomoney/"&gt;[79 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skrillex on piano. Actually really enjoyable listening to.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/rgc4m/skrillex_on_piano_actually_really_enjoyable/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/rgc4m/skrillex_on_piano_actually_really_enjoyable/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:02:10 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/Alkzn&#34;&gt; Alkzn &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/&#34;&gt; Music&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.break.com/index/what-skrillex-on-piano-would-sound-like-2312187&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/Music/comments/rgc4m/skrillex_on_piano_actually_really_enjoyable/"&gt;[108 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Best birth control in the world... for men?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/rfv9n/best_birth_control_in_the_world_for_men/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/rfv9n/best_birth_control_in_the_world_for_men/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 14:23:11 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/YesAsInGenghis&#34;&gt; YesAsInGenghis &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/&#34;&gt; technology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcitement.com/culture/the-best-birth-control-in-the-world-is-for-men/?fb_ref=.T3GqGFXuGSY.like&amp;amp;fb_source=home_multiline#.T3HM0tny-Sq&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/rfv9n/best_birth_control_in_the_world_for_men/"&gt;[1155 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Get through this without crying, you have no heart – A comic must earn his living as a clown while suffering the ultimate heartbreak.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rg2hq/get_through_this_without_crying_you_have_no_heart/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rg2hq/get_through_this_without_crying_you_have_no_heart/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 16:59:46 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rg2hq/get_through_this_without_crying_you_have_no_heart/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/vwinCdZWV9w20m5A.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Get through this without crying, you have no heart – A comic must earn his living as a clown while suffering the ultimate heartbreak.&#34; title=&#34;Get through this without crying, you have no heart – A comic must earn his living as a clown while suffering the ultimate heartbreak.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/MeAndMyArmy&#34;&gt; MeAndMyArmy &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/&#34;&gt; videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qdBJ1X33rXM&amp;amp;list=UUxw-YwaBR9lVa1fmreWy94g&amp;amp;index=9&amp;amp;feature=plcp&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rg2hq/get_through_this_without_crying_you_have_no_heart/"&gt;[325 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Get through this without crying, you have no heart – A comic must earn his living as a clown while suffering the ultimate heartbreak.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/vwinCdZWV9w20m5A.jpg" /></item><item><title>Dad hasn't spoken to me since this series of e-mails.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/rgdn3/dad_hasnt_spoken_to_me_since_this_series_of_emails/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/rgdn3/dad_hasnt_spoken_to_me_since_this_series_of_emails/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:31:05 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/stompanie&#34;&gt; stompanie &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&#34;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://imgur.com/DUpsH&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/rgdn3/dad_hasnt_spoken_to_me_since_this_series_of_emails/"&gt;[356 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>R.I.P Edd Gould (Eddsworld)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rgmnr/rip_edd_gould_eddsworld/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rgmnr/rip_edd_gould_eddsworld/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 23:22:09 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rgmnr/rip_edd_gould_eddsworld/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/q-4eLTLuLgSUA-LG.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;R.I.P Edd Gould (Eddsworld)&#34; title=&#34;R.I.P Edd Gould (Eddsworld)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/ReKognito&#34;&gt; ReKognito &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/&#34;&gt; videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jkEvbOsr138&amp;amp;feature=youtube_gdata_player&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rgmnr/rip_edd_gould_eddsworld/"&gt;[50 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>R.I.P Edd Gould (Eddsworld)</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/q-4eLTLuLgSUA-LG.jpg" /></item><item><title>Stephen Fry with a person that suffers tourette syndrome.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rfvsn/stephen_fry_with_a_person_that_suffers_tourette/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rfvsn/stephen_fry_with_a_person_that_suffers_tourette/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 14:36:16 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rfvsn/stephen_fry_with_a_person_that_suffers_tourette/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/Wfisg8KzO23sqKzA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stephen Fry with a person that suffers tourette syndrome.&#34; title=&#34;Stephen Fry with a person that suffers tourette syndrome.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/oppandadardar&#34;&gt; oppandadardar &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/&#34;&gt; videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VEIJJXnhy1U&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/rfvsn/stephen_fry_with_a_person_that_suffers_tourette/"&gt;[604 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Stephen Fry with a person that suffers tourette syndrome.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/Wfisg8KzO23sqKzA.jpg" /></item><item><title>TIL that The North Face clothing company sued a clothing company called The South Butt.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rfwpp/til_that_the_north_face_clothing_company_sued_a/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rfwpp/til_that_the_north_face_clothing_company_sued_a/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 14:58:01 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rfwpp/til_that_the_north_face_clothing_company_sued_a/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/dv5Z7o6Xba8ci2bA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TIL that The North Face clothing company sued a clothing company called The South Butt. &#34; title=&#34;TIL that The North Face clothing company sued a clothing company called The South Butt. &#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/Norva&#34;&gt; Norva &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/&#34;&gt; todayilearned&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_South_Butt&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rfwpp/til_that_the_north_face_clothing_company_sued_a/"&gt;[379 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>TIL that The North Face clothing company sued a clothing company called The South Butt.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://f.thumbs.redditmedia.com/dv5Z7o6Xba8ci2bA.jpg" /></item><item><title>TIL They replaced the original, horrifying artwork in &quot;Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rge54/til_they_replaced_the_original_horrifying_artwork/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rge54/til_they_replaced_the_original_horrifying_artwork/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 20:42:06 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rge54/til_they_replaced_the_original_horrifying_artwork/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://e.thumbs.redditmedia.com/ZqElNcjHC78AJwdp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TIL They replaced the original, horrifying artwork in &amp;quot;Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark&amp;quot;&#34; title=&#34;TIL They replaced the original, horrifying artwork in &amp;quot;Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark&amp;quot;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/user/yusuf_islam&#34;&gt; yusuf_islam &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/&#34;&gt; todayilearned&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adventuresinpoortaste.com/2011/12/18/scary-stories-to-tell-in-the-dark-gammell-vs-helquist/&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/rge54/til_they_replaced_the_original_horrifying_artwork/"&gt;[159 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>TIL They replaced the original, horrifying artwork in &quot;Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark&quot;</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://e.thumbs.redditmedia.com/ZqElNcjHC78AJwdp.jpg" /></item></channel></rss>