<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link><description></description><image><url>http://static.reddit.com/reddit.com.header.png</url><title>reddit: the voice of the internet -- news before it happens</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/</link></image><item><title>White House photo of Obama and his national security team following events in the Bin Laden operation</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/h2ktn/white_house_photo_of_obama_and_his_national/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/h2ktn/white_house_photo_of_obama_and_his_national/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 21:17:06 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/h2ktn/white_house_photo_of_obama_and_his_national/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2ktn.png&quot; alt=&quot;White House photo of Obama and his national security team following events in the Bin Laden operation&quot; title=&quot;White House photo of Obama and his national security team following events in the Bin Laden operation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/likepeterose&quot;&gt; likepeterose &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/&quot;&gt; pics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/tjRP1.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/h2ktn/white_house_photo_of_obama_and_his_national/"&gt;[2880 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>White House photo of Obama and his national security team following events in the Bin Laden operation</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2ktn.png" /></item><item><title>Sang &quot;Still Alive&quot; as a duet with Cleverbot today... It didn't go as well for me as that other guy.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/h2nqb/sang_still_alive_as_a_duet_with_cleverbot_today/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/h2nqb/sang_still_alive_as_a_duet_with_cleverbot_today/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 23:08:45 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/h2nqb/sang_still_alive_as_a_duet_with_cleverbot_today/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2nqb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sang &amp;quot;Still Alive&amp;quot; as a duet with Cleverbot today... It didn't go as well for me as that other guy.&quot; title=&quot;Sang &amp;quot;Still Alive&amp;quot; as a duet with Cleverbot today... It didn't go as well for me as that other guy.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/FlamingDonut&quot;&gt; FlamingDonut &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/&quot;&gt; gaming&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/BWD0H&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/h2nqb/sang_still_alive_as_a_duet_with_cleverbot_today/"&gt;[192 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>Sang &quot;Still Alive&quot; as a duet with Cleverbot today... It didn't go as well for me as that other guy.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2nqb.png" /></item><item><title>The girl married the prince, and the bad guy died... This week is sponsored by Disney</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2dwn/the_girl_married_the_prince_and_the_bad_guy_died/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2dwn/the_girl_married_the_prince_and_the_bad_guy_died/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 17:09:07 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/kavalec&quot;&gt; kavalec &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2dwn/the_girl_married_the_prince_and_the_bad_guy_died/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2dwn/the_girl_married_the_prince_and_the_bad_guy_died/"&gt;[593 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>This makes sense....wait..</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2f28/this_makes_sensewait/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2f28/this_makes_sensewait/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 17:48:20 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/chutye&quot;&gt; chutye &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/qmzAQ.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2f28/this_makes_sensewait/"&gt;[580 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Here's what the WHOLE world thinks of Osama's death. Bonus Robert Fisk interview goodness.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/h2kw2/heres_what_the_whole_world_thinks_of_osamas_death/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/h2kw2/heres_what_the_whole_world_thinks_of_osamas_death/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 21:19:53 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/itswac&quot;&gt; itswac &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/&quot;&gt; worldnews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://aljazeera.com/news/asia/2011/05/20115241936984209.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/h2kw2/heres_what_the_whole_world_thinks_of_osamas_death/"&gt;[332 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>meanwhile in istanbul..</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/h2c5e/meanwhile_in_istanbul/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/h2c5e/meanwhile_in_istanbul/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/h2c5e/meanwhile_in_istanbul/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2c5e.png&quot; alt=&quot;meanwhile in istanbul..&quot; title=&quot;meanwhile in istanbul..&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/tillwalley&quot;&gt; tillwalley &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/&quot;&gt; videos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=53LN_mWiflY&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/h2c5e/meanwhile_in_istanbul/"&gt;[371 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>meanwhile in istanbul..</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2c5e.png" /></item><item><title>Good point.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2cyr/good_point/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2cyr/good_point/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:35:14 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/papthegreek&quot;&gt; papthegreek &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/V3fvr.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2cyr/good_point/"&gt;[328 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>TIL The United States Marine Corps suggests, for its recruits, a scifi novel called Ender's Game as recommended reading wherein humanity is almost wiped out by a race of insectoids.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/h2bn9/til_the_united_states_marine_corps_suggests_for/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/h2bn9/til_the_united_states_marine_corps_suggests_for/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 15:48:09 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/h2bn9/til_the_united_states_marine_corps_suggests_for/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2bn9.png&quot; alt=&quot;TIL The United States Marine Corps suggests, for its recruits, a scifi novel called Ender's Game as recommended reading wherein humanity is almost wiped out by a race of insectoids. &quot; title=&quot;TIL The United States Marine Corps suggests, for its recruits, a scifi novel called Ender's Game as recommended reading wherein humanity is almost wiped out by a race of insectoids. &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Nidis&quot;&gt; Nidis &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/&quot;&gt; todayilearned&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marines.mil/unit/tecom/mcu/grc/library/Pages/mcrl2.aspx&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/h2bn9/til_the_united_states_marine_corps_suggests_for/"&gt;[1001 comments]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><media:title>TIL The United States Marine Corps suggests, for its recruits, a scifi novel called Ender's Game as recommended reading wherein humanity is almost wiped out by a race of insectoids.</media:title><media:thumbnail url="http://thumbs.reddit.com/t3_h2bn9.png" /></item><item><title>What event or occurrence at work could you have only fathomed happening in 'The Office' or the like?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/h2fn5/what_event_or_occurrence_at_work_could_you_have/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/h2fn5/what_event_or_occurrence_at_work_could_you_have/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 18:10:42 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had one today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Co-worker drops a card on my desk and says 'It's for Wendy, can you get everyone to sign it?' The message says something about being in a circle of caring. I never read the cards anyway, it's 9:05am on a Monday and the Sumatra Reserve hasn't made it to my veins yet. So I scribble &quot;EAT LOTS OF CAKE TODAY!&quot; and pass it along to the next person. 30 minutes later the co-worker returns with the card in hand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&quot;Foxprowl, why did you have everyone sign Happy Birthday on Wendy's card? We wanted to show her we care because her father just got diagnosed with stage 4 lung cancer.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;O_o&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Foxprowl&quot;&gt; Foxprowl &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/&quot;&gt; AskReddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2fn5/what_event_or_occurrence_at_work_could_you_have/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/h2fn5/what_event_or_occurrence_at_work_could_you_have/"&gt;[936 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ann Druyan, co-creator of Cosmos and President of NORML, responds to AMA (Part One)</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/h29ve/ann_druyan_cocreator_of_cosmos_and_president_of/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/h29ve/ann_druyan_cocreator_of_cosmos_and_president_of/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 07:33:28 -0700</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As some of you may or may not recall, I started taking questions from Reddit about a month ago to send to Mrs. Druyan in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/g1ezu/iama_update_ann_druyan_late_wife_of_carl_sagan/&quot; &gt;this original AMA thread&lt;/a&gt;. She has thus far only answered a little under half of the questions I sent, but I thought I would post this collection of responses now, and follow-up with the remaining responses when I get them all in the coming weeks. She has expressed that she is currently traveling, and it has made it difficult to sit down and write as many responses as she'd like.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And so, The following has been taken directly from my correspondence with Mrs. Druyan via email.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dear Reader,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Delighted to be asked to answer these wonderful questions. (Please note that the first question was actually several.) I am currently writing under a couple of pressing deadlines. Want to answer each and every question. So, if it's okay with you guys, I'd like to respond in installments. Here's the first. More coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With best regards, Ann&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Where do you see the future of humanity in 100 years? 1,000 years? 100,000 years? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most wonderful and terrible thing about life is its inherent unpredictability. Too many variables for human brains to crunch and then extrapolate conditions in the distant future-- until, perhaps, someday our computers will have evolved sufficiently to do so. Until then, attempts at prophecy of where we'll be in ten years, let alone 100 or more, are probably exercises in futility. History doesn't move in a straight line. It meanders. And there's so much we never see coming.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Do you think humans need to change their way of doing things to survive long enough to explore the cosmos? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;No limb to go out on here: Yes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; In what ways/steps should we change things to fit this proposition? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Start taking the revelations of science to heart. Give up the infantile notion of our centrality to the vastness of space and time. Take seriously the fragility of our environment and treat it as if it were more precious to us than diamonds, because of course it is. Awaken to the urgency of our need to change our ways. Stop living as if everything were disposable. . .as if heaven was somewhere and somewhen else. Question authority, but don't stop there. Reflect on what great big liars we all are. Next time you hear someone with an investment in, say, nuclear power, tell you that the plant can withstand the worst kind of tsunami, or the country I am itching to invade has weapons of mass destruction, be skeptical. Remember you are a link in a chain of life that stretches all the way across some 4 billion years to its origin on this planet and possibly forward to the stars. Think long term. Remember I, you, all of us, might be wrong.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Do you think it would help humanity focus on more important things if we discovered there was intelligent extraterrestrial life? If yes, then in what way? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Not necessarily. I don't believe that the existence of extra-terrestrial microbes would change our culture in the short term. I believe it would be more like the influence of the Copernican system. Those alert to the implications, in that case, the founders of the modern scientific revolution embraced it relatively quickly. But because, science was then and, tragically, is now, a compartmentalized subset of society, it took centuries for this pivotal insight to penetrate the broader culture. I believe microbial life from another world would take quite some time to have an impact on us generally. Eventually and inexorably it leads to the unraveling of traditional belief systems that hold a central place for us in space and time. But that takes awhile.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now, really big guys with the power to push us around showing up on our doorstep would be another story. We are primates, evolved to respond to hierarchy. This latter scenario would likely be a much more sobering event, commanding our immediate attention. The middle scenario: an enigmatic message detected by a radio-telescope from a world, too far away to actually do anything to us -- would create a sensation, and undoubtedly lead to a whole new set of spiritual doctrines for some of us, but I warrant it would be business as usual for most of us not too long after its receipt.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Do you think that the qualities Carl embodied - selflessness, a sense of social justice, a deep appreciation for science - are lost on today's youth / young adults? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;No, not at all. The younger people I know and those who write to me and blog and tweet from around the world are admittedly still too small and self-selected a sample to qualify as anything but anecdotal, but it doesn't surprise me that we are still as good and bad as we ever were.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If anything, Carl's vision and values harken back to our much longer hunter/gatherer past, say a million years of sharing and cooperating, than to our more recent struggles with post-agricultural and post-Copernican stress syndrome. If the surviving remnants of hunter-gatherer societies are any indication of how we behaved for most of human history when we lived in small wandering bands, Carl would have fit right in beautifully. Perhaps, at some earlier time in his life he was concerned with rising to the top of a dominance hierarchy, but not during the twenty years we were together.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think a partial reason for the phenomenally enduring success of Cosmos is that it is not a series of lectures by someone who is trying to impress us with how much more he knows than we do, but, rather a shamanistic experience, one that might happen around a campfire, where a member of our now much larger human tribe is telling us the great story of how, over 40,000 generations, we began to find our coordinates in space and time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Carl saw human civilization as an organism in the process of becoming conscious, of becoming an inter-communicating whole. If he had lived to witness our degree of connectedness,he would have loved it. I know Carl, with his complete honesty, openness, generosity of spirit as well as his prodigious knowledge and prophetic intelligence and wisdom, will be remembered and appreciated by generations to come.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; How can we reconnect with the profound statements that you both made in works like Cosmos and Demon-Haunted World in a society where many are too lost in their digital devices and the pursuit of money to care about the bigger picture? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;I don't see it that way. From my point of view at 61, we have accomplished so much since I was a child. Think of the racism, sexism and repression, disdain for the physically challenged, that was the rule back then. Deep-seated ancient prejudices have given way to a kind of enlightenment. Not everywhere, but sooner or later those pockets of ignorance and resentment will give way. I see those digital devices as a distribution network for binding up the planet and over-riding the efforts of tyrants and other dominance hierarchy hangers on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall, Do you worry about the state of science education in the United States, and our lack of dedication towards pursuing technological, medical, and other science-based initiatives?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yes, of course. But, the zeitgeist tends to move in the arc of a pendulum. Us baby boomers came of age when the military-industrial complex had plenty of cash and needed engineers and scientists to perfect our weapons of mass destruction and their delivery systems. There were many horrendous by-products of the nuclear arms race as well as great ones -- our mythic journeys to the moon, Mars and our reconnaissance of the outer solar system. You can not artificially create a golden age of science. It has to be woven into the social and economic fabric. We may be due for another one about now because we all recognize the danger of losing our competitive edge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can a person do to spread the joy of science and the universe to the people?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;When a child asks you a question that stumps you, instead of being irritated and embarrassed, thank them, take them by the hand and go with them in search of the answer. Carl's mother, Rachel, did that for him and look where it led.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Learn everything you possibly can about a subject that truly interests you. As Carl used to say, &quot;When you're in love you want to tell the world.&quot; You can't fake it. But if you really feel it, chances are you will infect someone else with the passion to know more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don't lie to children. Don't doom them to perpetual infancy. Nature is wondrous enough as it is. Our pathetic fantasies are not supernatural --they are sub-natural. Lying to your children only really communicates that reality is not good enough. I'm convinced that's how we end up with leaders who tell us that &quot;trees cause pollution&quot; or that &quot;Saddam Hussein has weapons of mass destruction.&quot; They destroy untold lives and are never held accountable for the damage they do because we are inured to lying from childhood.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I'm saying is you can't expect to have a science based society when science is compartmentalized into a boring 45 minutes of class time a couple of days a week, while in our inner lives, we cherish a collection of baseless ideas. Science is a way of thinking. If we instilled the wonder of life, the glory of nature from day one and abjured magical, non-sensical thinking --not humorlessness, mind you, there's plenty of room for that and nobody had a better, fuller, greater laugh than Carl-- but if we could bring ourselves to actually take the revelations of science to heart, we might begin to change in the ways we need to in order to get our species, and many others, through this current phase of our technological adolescence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When do you believe the federal laws against marijuana will be repealed? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am probably the wrong person to ask this question, having foolishly believed for decades that sane national drug policy was just around the corner. You know when Pat Robertson starts asking &quot;Why are we locking people up for having a couple of joints?&quot; that national drug policy is way behind the curve.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the best thing an individual activist can do to help your cause other than writing congressional leaders? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Join and support NORML&amp;lt;norml.org&gt; working tirelessly for you for forty years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many feel that the idea of starting with medicinal marijuana is not the way to go about legalization. Some people want to see marijuana treated as a recreational drug, similar to alcohol, as procuring a prescription drug without a prescription is a crime; What are your thoughts on the matter of legal medicinal versus legal recreational? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our most immediate concern must be with those who are suffering from illnesses and treatments (chemotherapy, radiation) that marijuana has demonstrated efficacy to relieve. Beyond that, I do not believe that the government has the right, nor is it in society's longterm interest to punish people for victimless crimes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given the stigma surrounding marijuana, How do you begin to re-shape the general public's view? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;It would be good for people to be generally more honest about their usage. If you only discover someone's use of marijuana in the context of an arrest, the negative association for people who have no experience with marijuana is a natural one. Lying and hypocrisy are what's shameful. I thought Lady Gaga handled the question recently on &quot;60 Minutes&quot; with exemplary candor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you support the legalization and/or decriminalization of any other drugs besides marijuana? If not, what makes marijuana unique? If so, what drugs and why? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;If governments and schools would disseminate information that scrupulously reflected scientific understanding rather than half-truths and scare tactics, more people, including the young, would take what they have to say seriously. Not everyone, of course, but a much higher percentage. We have failed at teaching people which drugs should truly be avoided and which drugs are least harmful, nor anything regarding the sacramental nature of healthy drug usage along the lines of our ancestors' practices for perhaps the last couple of hundred thousand years. Drug use is bound up with lying, secrecy, fear, hypocrisy, shame--all the things that eat away at human relationships. Just as in the days of alcohol prohibition there has been a parting of the ways between public conduct and government policy. Solid citizens are criminalized and respect for law is systematically undermined. Right now I think the abuse of legal prescription drugs poses a far greater threat to our society, and especially our kids, than those which are forbidden.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time. . .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/humanoideric&quot;&gt; humanoideric &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/&quot;&gt; IAmA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h29ve/ann_druyan_cocreator_of_cosmos_and_president_of/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/h29ve/ann_druyan_cocreator_of_cosmos_and_president_of/"&gt;[129 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I'll Remember May 2, 2011</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2asy/why_ill_remember_may_2_2011/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2asy/why_ill_remember_may_2_2011/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 15:10:56 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm an American who works abroad. Today I woke up earlier than usual and while soberly checking the international news, I saw immediately (and everywhere) that Osama bin Laden had been killed. Good news, I suppose. The almost mythical leader of Al-Qaeda, who nearly everyone had forgotten about, was dead and dumped in the sea. He had been irrelevant for long, I thought, but perhaps his death would lead to some much-needed reflection about the catastrophe that was the last decade. Right.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I will not remember today for Osama's death. I will remember it for the way I felt watching the videos of my countrymen celebrating in the streets of New York and Washington. I don't recognize them, these people waving flags, singing, and pouring their jubilation into the night because we killed someone. And what about all the others that have been killed? During 10 years we spent unbelievable amounts of blood and treasure, enacted unthinkable civil liberties legislation, and turned ourselves into brutes for this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And there we were out on the streets. Brutes. We have become brutes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yes, the world is a better place without Osama bin Laden. But I fear what this has brought out in us. The structural factors that create Osama bin Ladens still exist, and unless we work to change those, we will continue to undermine ourselves by giving our attention to tomorrow's straw man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/HeathenFace&quot;&gt; HeathenFace &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2asy/why_ill_remember_may_2_2011/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2asy/why_ill_remember_may_2_2011/"&gt;[3213 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Damn it! Damn it, damn it, damn it, damn it!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2hxc/damn_it_damn_it_damn_it_damn_it_damn_it/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2hxc/damn_it_damn_it_damn_it_damn_it_damn_it/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 19:30:29 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/kaliku&quot;&gt; kaliku &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/DyZOj.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2hxc/damn_it_damn_it_damn_it_damn_it_damn_it/"&gt;[247 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Anybody else massively looking forward to the Daily Show tonight?</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2axg/anybody_else_massively_looking_forward_to_the/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2axg/anybody_else_massively_looking_forward_to_the/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 08:15:31 -0700</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just have a feeling that tonight is going to be...special.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; Just because someone might be looking forward to the Daily Show doesn't mean that it's because they want to hear Osama jokes, Bush jokes, royal wedding jokes, etc etc etc. It's just been a VERY interesting weekend, and one that should be ripe for the Daily Show to take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/tlr86&quot;&gt; tlr86 &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2axg/anybody_else_massively_looking_forward_to_the/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2axg/anybody_else_massively_looking_forward_to_the/"&gt;[679 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Do you have any idea what we've done? We dumped Bin Laden's moldering corpse into the ocean where it will mix with oil from the BP spill and radiation from Fukushima and we're going to have a radioactive zombie terrorist apocalypse.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2fyq/do_you_have_any_idea_what_weve_done_we_dumped_bin/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2fyq/do_you_have_any_idea_what_weve_done_we_dumped_bin/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 18:21:08 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks a fucking ton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/H7M&quot;&gt; H7M &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2fyq/do_you_have_any_idea_what_weve_done_we_dumped_bin/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2fyq/do_you_have_any_idea_what_weve_done_we_dumped_bin/"&gt;[222 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>D:</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2q9k/d/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2q9k/d/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:54:14 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/ravenrriddle&quot;&gt; ravenrriddle &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bod0E.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2q9k/d/"&gt;[30 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>&quot;I mourn the loss of thousands of precious lives, but I will not rejoice in the death of one, not even an enemy.&quot; - Martin Luther King, Jr</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2i50/i_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious_lives/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2i50/i_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious_lives/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 19:37:50 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Lokonopa&quot;&gt; Lokonopa &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/pennjillette/status/65132242770464769&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h2i50/i_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious_lives/"&gt;[254 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Noooo! Don't bury him in the sea!</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2e0s/noooo_dont_bury_him_in_the_sea/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2e0s/noooo_dont_bury_him_in_the_sea/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 10:13:13 -0700</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/onefingerattack&quot;&gt; onefingerattack &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Co6ap.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2e0s/noooo_dont_bury_him_in_the_sea/"&gt;[122 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I don't think this update was coincidental.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2aa5/i_dont_think_this_update_was_coincidental/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2aa5/i_dont_think_this_update_was_coincidental/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 14:50:24 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/brazen&quot;&gt; brazen &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.explosm.net/comics/2409/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2aa5/i_dont_think_this_update_was_coincidental/"&gt;[70 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>In his last act of terrorism...</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2jfg/in_his_last_act_of_terrorism/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2jfg/in_his_last_act_of_terrorism/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 20:23:49 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/nklotz&quot;&gt; nklotz &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/U6xGa.png&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2jfg/in_his_last_act_of_terrorism/"&gt;[21 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Make Wall St. Pay for the Catastrophe They Caused: A new Bill sponsored by Bob Blumenfield (D, LA) would impose a $20,000 fine on banks for each foreclosure</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h283d/make_wall_st_pay_for_the_catastrophe_they_caused/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h283d/make_wall_st_pay_for_the_catastrophe_they_caused/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 13:10:10 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/maxwellhill&quot;&gt; maxwellhill &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alternet.org/economy/150796/make_wall_st._pay_for_the_catastrophe_they_caused%3A_new_bill_would_fine_banks_%2420%2C000_for_each_forclosure/?page=entire&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h283d/make_wall_st_pay_for_the_catastrophe_they_caused/"&gt;[549 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Before everyone gets lost in the inevitable pro-America media for the next few months, I'd like to post what I've learned about OBL/al-Qaeda in the past few years. |OR| I've researched this and here are my notes.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2djb/before_everyone_gets_lost_in_the_inevitable/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2djb/before_everyone_gets_lost_in_the_inevitable/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:55:23 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd like to preface this by saying that I don't, in any way, support anything Osama did. I just feel like with all of the flag-waving going on, people are going to conveniently forget the United States' support for him in the 1980's. After seeing a picture of the Taliban meeting with President Reagan inside the Whitehouse &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bemge.jpg&quot; &gt;Pic&lt;/a&gt;, I became somewhat interested in the group's history.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After the Soviets invaded Afghanistan in 1979, OBL met up with a former teacher in an effort to join the mujahideen (guerrillas/rebels) and rid the country of its invaders. Using his family's wealth, he eventually created a group to arm and train the rebels. It's important to note that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.proxsa.org/resources/9-11/Brzezinski-980115-interview.htm&quot; &gt;the CIA was already funding the mujahideen at least six months prior to the Soviet invasion&lt;/a&gt; in an attempt to provoke conflict between the nations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Using the BCCI (international bank), the CIA funneled extra funding to the mujahideen in Operation Cyclone. Whether or not bin Laden personally received formal military training from the CIA is still under much debate, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fair.org/index.php?page=1094&quot; &gt;he had opened an account at the BCCI shortly after Operation Cyclone commenced&lt;/a&gt;. The CIA used the BCCI when dealing with funding for covert operations. Anyone familiar with the Iran-Contra scandal might (should) be aware of the fact that the CIA used the now-defunct bank to transfer money/weapons and launder drug money accrued from the import of narcotics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;al-Qaeda was officially formed sometime in the second half of 1988, combining bin Laden's assets with the battle experience of the US-funded resistance groups. After the Soviets left in early 1989, bin Laden went back to Saudi Arabia with much fanfare. Up until this point in time, he was relatively neutral with the United States, although he ultimately had reservations because it was a non-Muslim country. Also of note: Prince Bandar bin Sultan (son of crowned Prince Sultan) once said &lt;a href=&quot;http://transcripts.cnn.com/TRANSCRIPTS/0110/01/lkl.00.html&quot; &gt;&quot;...Saudi Arabia and the United States were supporting the Mujahideen to liberate Afghanistan from the Soviets. He came to thank me for my efforts to bring the Americans, our friends, to help us against the atheists, he said the communists.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. It's hard to say whether his demeanor towards the United States was friendly or neutral-at-best.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 1990, during the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait, the Saudi Royal Family had concerns that Iraq would set sights for Saudi Arabia. bin Laden offered to defend King Fahd's oil fields, but the King instead opted to accept help from the United States, allowing placement of US troops and equipment on Saudi land.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is where shit got sour. bin Laden was angry with the Saudis for allowing non-Muslims near the holy cities of Medina/Mecca and began to condemn the Royal Family. Of course, they punished him for talking smack, but it was something he had already planned for. Prior to the invasion of Kuwait, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.9-11commission.gov/report/911Report_Ch2.htm&quot; &gt;Sudanese Hassan al Turabi was trying to get bin Laden to move al-Qaeda to Sudan&lt;/a&gt;. While he was in the process of moving to Saudi Arabia after the Soviets left Afghanistan, he had agents buy real estate in Sudan. In an attempt to squelch bin Laden, the Royal Family took away his passport. Had it not been for a recusant member of the Royal Family sneaking him out of the country in 1991, this could have been the last anyone heard of him. Reality paints a very different picture.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Over the next few years, al-Qaeda gained a lot of momentum, opening branches all across North Africa/Middle East and parts of Asia. He continued to speak poorly of the United States, primarily because troops and equipment were still stationed near Medina and Mecca even after Iraq left Kuwait. US occupation in Somalia pushed him over the edge and he declared the first fatwa against the occupations. He was also still very angry with King Fahd and spammed the hell out of Saudi fax machines. Eventually, the King had had enough and exiled him.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nationless, bin Laden attempted to purchase weapons-grade uranium from a Sudanese military official. He spent $1.5M on what turned out to be nothing more than a dummy cylinder. I think this is the most interesting thing to come out of the 9/11 report because it's where we find out what bin Laden was attempting to do (the same thing al-Turabi wanted to do): unite the Sunni and Shiite to fight against western powers. With nuclear weapons, it would be much easier to convince Shiite/Sunni to &quot;put aside their divisions and join against the common enemy.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On May 26, 1992, Hashim Bedreddin Mohammed attacked al-Turabi in a Canadian airport. Using karate (seriously), he hospitalized al-Turabi for four weeks. In October of 1993, al-Turabi's ally Omar Hassan al-Bashir appointed took over Sudan. Because Sudan was a hotspot for extremist sects, numerous countries pressured al-Bashir to crack down on extremist activities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In June of 1995, the Egyptian Islamic Jihad (a group bin Laden was now very close to) enlisted the help of other groups (along with al-Bashir/Sudan) to assassinate Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak. The attempt failed, obviously.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 1996, al-Bashir began speaking with other countries to try and calm the area down. He offered to exile bin Laden to Saudi Arabia, but the Royal Family did not want him in the country. After he survived an assassination attempt, bin Ladin left the country and headed to Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;bin Laden co-signed a fatwa with the head of the Egyptian Islamic Jihad, Ayman al-Zawahiri, in 1998. Here, the EIJ and al-Qaeda merged into one unit. According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foia.cia.gov/docs/DOC_0001110635/0001110635_0001.gif&quot; &gt;declassified document&lt;/a&gt;, on December 4, 1998, President Clinton was informed by the Director of Central Intelligence that &quot;Bin Ladin [sic]&quot; was &quot;preparing to hijack US aircraft.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Opinionated, insane ranting below&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the extent of my notes. It's somewhat sad that bin Laden's original intentions were simply to stop the Soviet invasion, but it would be inane to say he wasn't the cause of his own downfall. If the United States had withdrawn forces from Saudi Arabia immediately after Iraq pulled out of Kuwait, things might have been very different. Instead, over a million lives have been lost, trillions of dollars have been spent, people get groped or scanned with incredibly under-researched technology when traveling, &quot;anti-terrorism&quot; laws are being used almost exclusively against drug offenders, there is more civil unrest in the Middle East than has been seen since the fall of the Ottoman Empire, and the wealthiest people on the planet have been becoming almost exponentially wealthier while others go unclothed, unsheltered, and unfed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is absolutely clear that, because of the past few days, there is zero chance for a Republican President-elect in 2012. Please don't let the next few months of media make you forget the past two, ten, or thirty-one years. If there's ever going to be a time to get both Republicans and Democrats out of government offices and return the power to the people, it's next year. Both parties are bound and determined to screw you and just because the Democrats are nice enough to spit on their dicks before sticking it in and breaking it off, it doesn't mean &quot;let's go with the lesser of two evils.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We live in a time of near instantaneous transmission of information and I'm positive it is our only tool against greed. Our country is so heartbreakingly divided and people just pick sides like it's some sort of goddamn sports team. Kill your televisions and stop this nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Neonight&quot;&gt; Neonight &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2djb/before_everyone_gets_lost_in_the_inevitable/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2djb/before_everyone_gets_lost_in_the_inevitable/"&gt;[157 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>I think we're all fucked</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2ojo/i_think_were_all_fucked/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2ojo/i_think_were_all_fucked/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 23:43:24 +0000</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Tytru&quot;&gt; Tytru &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/&quot;&gt; funny&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/es6hd.jpg&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/h2ojo/i_think_were_all_fucked/"&gt;[38 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>&quot;I wish this achievement could mean we get our country back, the one before the Patriot Act, before FISA, before rendition and torture and Guantanamo; before we began giving up the freedom and belief in due process that makes us Americans, out of our fear of totalitarians like bin Laden&quot;</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h27ye/i_wish_this_achievement_could_mean_we_get_our/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h27ye/i_wish_this_achievement_could_mean_we_get_our/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 06:03:37 -0700</pubDate><description>submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/MSkog&quot;&gt; MSkog &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/news/opinion/joan_walsh/politics/2011/05/01/obama_sunday_night_address&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h27ye/i_wish_this_achievement_could_mean_we_get_our/"&gt;[274 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>&quot;I will mourn the loss of thousands of precious lives, but I will not rejoice in the death of one, not even an enemy....&quot; -Martin Luther King Jr.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2j4j/i_will_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2j4j/i_will_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 20:13:13 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;I will mourn the loss of thousands of precious lives, but I will not rejoice in the death of one, not even an enemy. Returning hate for hate multiplies hate, adding deeper darkness to a night already devoid of stars. Darkness cannot drive out darkness: only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate, only love can do that.&quot; -Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/leirariel&quot;&gt; leirariel &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/&quot;&gt; politics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h2j4j/i_will_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/h2j4j/i_will_mourn_the_loss_of_thousands_of_precious/"&gt;[85 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hey Canadians, today is our election day. Go VOTE NOW.</title><link>http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h28w3/hey_canadians_today_is_our_election_day_go_vote/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h28w3/hey_canadians_today_is_our_election_day_go_vote/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 13:48:49 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;You're only allowed to bitch about government if you do so lets get it done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; submitted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/user/Redmushroom&quot;&gt; Redmushroom &lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/&quot;&gt; reddit.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/comments/h28w3/hey_canadians_today_is_our_election_day_go_vote/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/h28w3/hey_canadians_today_is_our_election_day_go_vote/"&gt;[1171 comments]&lt;/a&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>