<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Brand Timelines: 6 Big Changes Every Marketer Needs to Understand</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/&amp;title=Facebook Brand Timelines: 6 Big Changes Every Marketer Needs to Understand&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/facebook-timeline-600.jpg" class="alignright" width="275" height="171" title="Facebook Timeline Image"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Victoria Ransom is founder and CEO of &lt;a href="http://www.wildfireapp.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Wildfire Interactive&lt;/a&gt;, the global leader in social media marketing software. Victoria and Wildfire will host a free &lt;a href="http://lp.wildfireapp.com/WildfireBreakingWebinarTimelineForBrandsMarch2012.html" target="_blank"&gt;webinar&lt;/a&gt; on March 2 at 10 a.m. PT, entitled &#8220;Timeline for Brands: How to Make the Switch,&#8221; further outlining best practices for brands in transitioning to Facebook&#8217;s new Timeline format.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-timeline-brands-prepare/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; to brand marketers the world over that, within the month, everything they knew about fan Pages on Facebook would be overturned. While you get your brand ready for the new &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/facebook-timeline"&gt;Timeline&lt;/a&gt; format, here are six important changes to keep top-of-mind. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Updated Look and Feel&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s new:&lt;/strong&gt; The format of Timeline for brands is quite similar to Timeline for personal profiles. It employs a cover photo at the top of the Page, and the Page is separated into two main columns by a dividing line, which represents the passage of time. This format provides brands with new options for self-expression: They can outline their corporate history with milestones (such as product launches, store openings, etc.) to construct a narrative for their audience. &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; Milestones present an important and dramatic opportunity to educate the public, humanize the brand and remove a perception of corporate anonymity. Our analyses of Page engagement have continually shown that brands posting content that depicts behind-the-scenes activities, exclusive updates or promotions encourages user interactions and promotes higher engagement rates. Using interesting milestones to craft the story of the brand over time (and updating the Timeline with new milestones as they happen) can help to stimulate conversations around major achievements.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Reduced Tab Visibility&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/facebook-coca-cola-640.png" alt="" title="facebook-coca-cola-640" width="640" height="230" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-964265" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s new:&lt;/strong&gt; The new Timeline format does not have the left-side panel of links, which could include hundreds of different tabs. While applications still exist, they&amp;#8217;ll display differently, in rectangular panels underneath the cover photo. The width of the Timeline and the space allocated for native apps like Photos means that only three tab panels are viewable at any given time. To see more, users must expand the tab panel by clicking a drop-down box. &#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; For marketers, this major change means that the three above-fold tab apps need to be considered carefully &#8212; this will be one of the first things users see when interacting with your brand on Facebook. Brands will want to switch up which tabs are visible &#8220;above the fold,&#8221; according to current company objectives or project popularity. A good Page analytics tool will be useful for determining which tab to promote on a day-to-day basis.&#8232;&#8232;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. No Default Landing Page&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8232;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s new:&lt;/strong&gt; With the new Timeline Page format, you will no longer be able to set a default landing Page, a favored feature for many savvy brands. The option was one of the primary ways to control the first (branded) impression a user encountered. Since there are no more tab Pages, there is no way to set one as a default. This will drastically change user impressions when they first visit a brand&amp;#8217;s Timeline Page. &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; You will need to apply new and careful attention to all the top messages in the Timeline, as they will be the first objects seen by visiting users. Likewise, Facebook ads for brands will become ever important, as ads will be one of the major ways brands on Facebook can control a user&#8217;s experience. Setting up an advertising campaign for a Facebook promotion or new application will be the only way to guide new and clicking users directly to that application (as landing on this Page cannot be achieved by default). &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. New Way to Feature Content&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/facebook-red-bull-640.png" alt="" title="facebook-red-bull-640" width="640" height="294" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-964295" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s new:&lt;/strong&gt; One major new feature that marketers will love is the ability to &#8220;pin&#8221; certain posts to the top of the Timeline. Similar to marking a blog post &#8220;sticky,&#8221; so that it remains at the top of a blog for a specified period of time, pinning a post to the top of Timeline allows it to precede any other content. A pinned post is distinguished by a small, orange flag. Brands can pin only one item at a time, and the pinned item then exists in two locations &#8212; as the top item on the Timeline itself, as well as within its chronological place. Once unpinned (which happens automatically when a new item gets pinned, or the item has been pinned for more than seven days), the post remains in the chronology of Timeline posts, but there is no visual history that it was pinned in the past. &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; Since you can no longer create a default landing Page, pinning items to the top of the Timeline will become every marketer&#8217;s go-to strategy for highlighting new and interesting content. We will begin to see savvy brands design posts specifically to be pinned, whether images, a well-designed call-to-action, a statement about brand value, or a message calling for the user to click one of the tab panels under the cover photo. &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Current Tab Content and Applications Become Outdated&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8232;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s new:&lt;/strong&gt; The new Timeline layout displaces Facebook&#8217;s existing Page tab configuration (including a tab&#8217;s 520-pixel width), and replaces it with a new 810-pixel layout. As a result, existing Page tab content will look centered in the middle of the 810-pixel layout without any adjustments. All applications that remain on a brand&#8217;s Page will need new application icons (the new dimensions are 111&amp;#215;74). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8232;&#8232;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; The most pressing updates for brands will be to update the images and tab functionality of the above-fold two apps. As these are the first tabs users will see, they will likely be the first to be interacted with, or entirely ignored if not optimized for the new experience.&#8232;&#8232;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;6. Private Messages Between Brands and Users&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s new:&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, brands will be able to send and receive private messages with users. This allows for much deeper consumer interaction, and will also enable Page managers to take extended customer inquiries off the Timeline and into a private message. &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt; Be mindful of noise in the Timeline. Since the real estate allocated to each post depends on how engaging it is or how much interaction it has received, it can be easy to clutter your Timeline with customer inquiries. When these inquiries can be better serviced in a more one-on-one manner, reach out to the consumer with a private message and resolve her question. It&amp;#8217;s a good opportunity to yield both a happy user and a clean Timeline.&#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Timeline for brands will certainly shake things up for social media marketers who seek to make an impact on Facebook. One thing is for sure though: The way content is shared and viewed within a Timeline Page is incredibly important. Brands that constantly create engaging updates and share important milestones will stay at the forefront of users&#8217; attention. Create and rotate new apps for engagement, pin relevant and timely content, and update the feed with user-friendly dialogues to stay relevant in this new space. &#8232;&#8232;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will you or your company do anything differently, right off the bat? Share your thoughts in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. Cover photo potential&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/#511951-Cover-photo-potential"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. Cover photo potential" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/a-powerful-new-tool-for-organizations/CokeCover.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, Coca Cola uses snazzy design to make a strong visual impression on visitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/#511951-Cover-photo-potential'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/customer-service/"&gt;customer service&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-pages/"&gt;facebook pages&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-timeline/"&gt;facebook timeline&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/marketing/"&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0SE5BOnZ1PguDHL4ABbBr8UEeJQ/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0SE5BOnZ1PguDHL4ABbBr8UEeJQ/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0SE5BOnZ1PguDHL4ABbBr8UEeJQ/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0SE5BOnZ1PguDHL4ABbBr8UEeJQ/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1pQNrVZvO4Y:ehaoE3PW_BU:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/1pQNrVZvO4Y" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Style.com: The Online Home of Fashion: News, Runway Shows, Trends, Fashion Models, Designers, Shopping, Beauty &amp; More</title>
      <description>Style.com: Covering the world of fashion, designers, models, celebrities, beauty, and shopping. Comprehensive runway reviews, images, videos, and insider blogs.</description>
      <link>http://www.style.com/</link>
      <guid>http://www.style.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I tried to watch Game of Thrones and this is what happened</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/game_of_thrones"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/theoatmeal-img/thumbnails/game_of_thrones.png" alt="I tried to watch Game of Thrones and this is what happened" class="border0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;WINTER NEVER CAME. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://theoatmeal.com/comics/game_of_thrones"&gt;View&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/game_of_thrones</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/game_of_thrones</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Products You Can Make From Your Instagram Snapshots [PICS]</title>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. Bangles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/instagram-products-decor/#517311-Bangles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. Bangles" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/instagram-products/instagram-bangle.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/75667427/chunky-bangle-bracelet-out-in-the-stix?ref=sr_gallery_11&amp;sref=&amp;ga_search_submit=&amp;ga_search_query=instagram&amp;ga_view_type=gallery&amp;ga_ship_to=US&amp;ga_search_type=handmade&amp;ga_facet=handmade&amp;show_panel=true" target="_blank"&gt;Instagram'd bangle on Etsy&lt;/a&gt; is made by BuyOurCrap. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We fell in love with the Instagram process and how it allows you to create pieces representative of yesteryear with different tones, filters and effects," says Lainey Bard, who's affectionately known by her customers as Mrs. Crap. "Since we create wearable works of art, we decided to include Instagram inspired pieces in our shop."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Craps access the Instagram API via iPod to pull photos. Bangles are sold for $40.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/instagram-products-decor/#517311-Bangles'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photo-sharing service &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/instagram"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/instagram-tops-25m-users-report/"&gt;25 million users&lt;/a&gt; who have &lt;a href="http://searchenginewatch.com/article/2156228/Instagram-10-Tips-to-Tell-Your-Brands-Story-1000-Words-at-a-Time" target="_blank"&gt;uploaded 500 million photos&lt;/a&gt; since its launch in October 2010. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The app is a go-to for amateur and professional photogs alike, and its filters and tilt-shift functionality have won it a legion of loyal fans &amp;#8212; and it&amp;#8217;s still only available for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ios"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Noting Instagram&amp;#8217;s popularity, opportunistic companies and individuals have realized that these beautiful images shouldn&amp;#8217;t be confined to your smartphone or tablet screen. By plugging into the Instagram API, these savvy entrepreneurs have created products &amp;#8212; and sometimes even entire businesses &amp;#8212; that bring your Instagram images to life. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take a look through the gallery for 13 cool Instagram-based products &amp;#8212; and an exciting bonus item that could spice up your office, a wedding and any event. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want more products, such as mugs or tees, give &lt;a href="http://www.instamaker.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Instamaker&lt;/a&gt; a try. Other Instagram items we&amp;#8217;d love to see: laptop cases, umbrellas, dishes, stationery, postage stamps, dog paraphernalia and charm-style pendants. What would &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; want to see? Let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/canvaspop/"&gt;canvaspop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/etsy/"&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/instagram/"&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/iphoneography/"&gt;iphoneography&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/small-business/"&gt;Small Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/MVRnXbV5YxeJqSZj6NK1aNbr1f4/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/MVRnXbV5YxeJqSZj6NK1aNbr1f4/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/MVRnXbV5YxeJqSZj6NK1aNbr1f4/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/MVRnXbV5YxeJqSZj6NK1aNbr1f4/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=IwPA-D0As6g:ZhOmF6T6LMc:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/IwPA-D0As6g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/instagram-products-decor/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/instagram-products-decor/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SnappSchool Connects Parents With Classrooms</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/&amp;title=SnappSchool Connects Parents With Classrooms&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/parent_600.png" alt="parent" title="parent" width="275" height="" class="alignright" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A startup called SnappSchool is compiling a weekly rundown of the Kindergarten to 6th-grade math curriculum &amp;#8212; for parents.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The idea is that if parents understand more about what and how their children are learning, they can better support their children&amp;#8217;s education. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Each digest contains a &amp;#8220;quick refresher&amp;#8221; about the topic, links to further resources and exercises, and a link to a news story or other information that connects the topic to the real world. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.snappschool.com/" target="_blank"&gt;SnappSchool&lt;/a&gt; hires certified teachers to write the digests, and they&amp;#8217;re based on Common Core Standards that &lt;a href="http://www.corestandards.org/in-the-states" target="_blank"&gt;all but five states&lt;/a&gt; use. Because the emails are not coordinated by your children&amp;#8217;s specific teachers, however, they might be paced slightly ahead or behind their actual classroom lessons. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Parents simply sign up for the appropriate grade level to receive emails each week. The service is free for three weeks and then costs $7.99 to continue the year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/Screen-shot-2012-03-03-at-5.54.32-PM.png" alt="" title="" width="640" height="" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-285526" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;To do long division, I don&#8217;t need the full lesson my fourth grader needs to get through it, but I do need a little reminder. It&#8217;s not something I do every day,&amp;#8221; explains SnappSchool co-founder John Halloran. &amp;#8220;At that level what often also happens is that there may be different ways of teaching things.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are legs to the startup&amp;#8217;s theory that more-involved parents beget better students.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A recent survey by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) found that parental involvement is linked to better student performance.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8220;Just asking your child how was their school day and showing genuine interest in the learning that they are doing can have the same impact as hours of private tutoring,&amp;#8221; Andreas Schleicher, who oversees OECD exams, told The &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/11/20/opinion/sunday/friedman-how-about-better-parents.html?_r=3&amp;#038;emc=eta1" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;SnappSchool&amp;#8217;s first stab at connecting parents with classrooms was a product that allowed teachers to easily SMS or email the parents of students in their classes. It&amp;#8217;s a good idea, but hard to monetize and dependent upon teacher initiative. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Halloran hopes that the new SnappSchool digests will give any parent the opportunity to connect with their children&amp;#8217;s education, even if it&amp;#8217;s just a matter of checking in once in a while.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Everybody asks, &amp;#8216;what did you do in school today?,&amp;#8221; and the kids never answer,&amp;#8221; he says. &amp;#8220;If you can ask, &amp;#8216;I know you&amp;#8217;re doing long division, how is that?,&amp;#8217; then it&amp;#8217;s a little bit easier.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do you have school-aged children? Would you find a weekly digest of their curriculum helpful? Or would it just be another newsletter to ignore? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Image courtesy of iStockphoto, &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=408692" target="_blank"&gt;lisafx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/education/"&gt;education&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/snappschool/"&gt;SnappSchool&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/startups/"&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/U1LY_l3I9IweZWysUHTXP1ef-RI/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/U1LY_l3I9IweZWysUHTXP1ef-RI/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/U1LY_l3I9IweZWysUHTXP1ef-RI/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/U1LY_l3I9IweZWysUHTXP1ef-RI/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=FlA79_xWwaQ:ruHni_7vCRM:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/business/~4/FlA79_xWwaQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/snappschool/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Employers Are Paying in 2012 [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have been working hard for your companies under tight financial constraints during the last few years, a silver lining might be coming your way. Thanks to rosy outlooks of employers in companies of all sizes across the country, it looks as though 2012 is going to be the year of the raise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to the infographic below, which was researched and compiled by &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/" target="_blank"&gt;PayScale.com&lt;/a&gt;, more than 93% of employers surveyed plan to give compensation adjustments to their workforces. That&amp;#8217;s significantly more than the percentage of employers who actually gave their employees salary adjustments in 2011 (60%) and 2010 (about 30%). The good news isn&amp;#8217;t just for the already-employed, either: A large percentage of companies in the business support services, information/telecommunications and retail sectors expect financial growth in 2012 &amp;#8212; a sure sign of new jobs to come.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Check out the infographic, which also maps out employer performance in 2011 in areas such as recruiting, social media and overall growth. Do you think 2012 will be a boom year for employees? Let us know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;title=How Employers Are Paying in 2012 [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/PayScale_Compensation_Infographic_972.jpg" alt="" title="Infographic Final RGB 2" width="972" height="6231" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-966053" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Social Media Job Listings&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every week we post a list of &lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/find-jobs"&gt;social media and web job opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&amp;#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661878" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Public Affairs Special Programs Coordinator, PPA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the British Embassy in New York City&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661959" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Marketing Sales Manager &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at TMG in Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661877" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Director of Marketing &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Found Animals Foundation in Los Angeles&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infographic courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/" target="_blank"&gt;PayScale.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/infographic/"&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-search-series/"&gt;job search series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/salary/"&gt;salary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/VEhsDCIC070" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Employers Are Paying in 2012 [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have been working hard for your companies under tight financial constraints during the last few years, a silver lining might be coming your way. Thanks to rosy outlooks of employers in companies of all sizes across the country, it looks as though 2012 is going to be the year of the raise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to the infographic below, which was researched and compiled by &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/" target="_blank"&gt;PayScale.com&lt;/a&gt;, more than 93% of employers surveyed plan to give compensation adjustments to their workforces. That&amp;#8217;s significantly more than the percentage of employers who actually gave their employees salary adjustments in 2011 (60%) and 2010 (about 30%). The good news isn&amp;#8217;t just for the already-employed, either: A large percentage of companies in the business support services, information/telecommunications and retail sectors expect financial growth in 2012 &amp;#8212; a sure sign of new jobs to come.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Check out the infographic, which also maps out employer performance in 2011 in areas such as recruiting, social media and overall growth. Do you think 2012 will be a boom year for employees? Let us know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;title=How Employers Are Paying in 2012 [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/PayScale_Compensation_Infographic_972.jpg" alt="" title="Infographic Final RGB 2" width="972" height="6231" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-966053" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Social Media Job Listings&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every week we post a list of &lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/find-jobs"&gt;social media and web job opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&amp;#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661878" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Public Affairs Special Programs Coordinator, PPA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the British Embassy in New York City&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661959" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Marketing Sales Manager &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at TMG in Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661877" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Director of Marketing &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Found Animals Foundation in Los Angeles&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infographic courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/" target="_blank"&gt;PayScale.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/infographic/"&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-search-series/"&gt;job search series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/salary/"&gt;salary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/VEhsDCIC070" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Strategies for Non-Profits on Pinterest</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/&amp;title=10 Strategies for Non-Profits on Pinterest&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/pinboard-volunteer-600-275x171.jpg" alt="Volunteer Pinboard" title="Volunteer Pinboard" width="275" height="171" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-966129" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Non-profits are utilizing &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/pinterest"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; as an extension of their organizations, using photography, infographics and other visuals to show supporters more about their missions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pinterest&amp;#8217;s goal is to connect &amp;#8220;people all over the world based on shared tastes and interests.&amp;#8221; Non-profits, then, can use the social site to connect people based on their social passions, and since non-profits work with and for the community, Pinterest can certainly come in handy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Last week, we covered &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/24/pinterest-non-profits/"&gt;10 non-profits&lt;/a&gt; that are particularly awesome at leveraging Pinterest for social good, but how did they get there? What are their strategies?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/27/pinterest-marketing/"&gt;8 Strategies for Launching a Brand Presence on Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are 10 tips from non-profits that are currently using Pinterest. With these suggestions in your back pocket, your own organization can further (or even reinvent) its image in no time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Know Your Audience&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s important to understand &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/28/the-marketers-guide-to-pinterest-infographic/"&gt;who is using Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; before you start branding through the network. Of Pinterest&amp;#8217;s 10 million+ users, 87% are women, and the average age of users spans between 25 and 54. So, what do you do with this information? How do you know what to pin?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Daljit Singh, office manager intern at &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/jolkona/" target="_blank"&gt;Jolkona&lt;/a&gt; and curator of the organization&amp;#8217;s Pinterest, says that a fun project helped. The staff of the non-profit, which is a web platform that connects you with global development projects and shows you the impact of your donation, asked: If Jolkona were a person, who would it be? They decided that Jolkona would be a woman in her mid-to-late 20s with mixed ethnicity. She would also drink coffee, ride the bus and listen to indie rock.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Because so many of our regular online donors match the demographic of users on Pinterest,&amp;#8221; says Singh, &amp;#8220;it wasn&#8217;t really a question of if we should request an invite, but rather when we would receive an invite.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jolkona tries to keep its pins colorful, light, creative and relevant to the non-profit&amp;#8217;s mission. Whenever Singh needs to determine if a pin is relevant, she can think back to the description of Jolkona as a person.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Get Personal&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;When it comes to social media, users respond better to personal influence than widespread branding. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sarah Cohen, communications and development manager at &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/charitywater/" target="_blank"&gt;charity: water&lt;/a&gt;, a non-profit that brings clean and safe drinking water to people in developing nations, says it&#8217;s important for staff members who are pinning to be familiar with Pinterest and really love the site. &amp;#8220;Our staff is young, curious and hungry for information,&amp;#8221; she says. &amp;#8220;We love sharing books we&#8217;ve read, bands we just checked out, the newest gadget or some new gear for the field.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Reveal Yourself&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/hands-donation.jpg" alt="Hands" title="Hands" width="616" height="425" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-966103" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Give your followers a look at your non-profit from behind the scenes. Pin images that show staff and volunteers working with your organization, as well as those who benefit from that work. It&amp;#8217;s a good idea to show supporters the human faces behind your logo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When the Jolkona staff looked at its &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; statistics, they found that the most engagement came from posting visuals. &amp;#8220;At first, Pinterest was a great place to find new infographics and pictures to provide content for Facebook and our blog,&amp;#8221; says Singh. &amp;#8220;However, as we started gaining new followers, our strategy changed and we decided it was best to pin things&amp;#8230;that help show our audience who we really are.&amp;#8221; You can find various campaigns, projects, goals and photos of staff members and volunteers on Jolkona&amp;#8217;s Pinterest page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The folks at charity: water have a board called &amp;#8220;Photo of the Day,&amp;#8221; a concept that founder Scott Harrison came up with in 2009 for the organization&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; page. Mo Scarpelli, the multimedia producer at charity: water, says, &amp;#8220;Many of our followers [on Pinterest and Twitter] look to the POD as a daily source of inspiration and hope, a reminder that we can change (and are already changing) the water crisis.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cohen adds, &amp;#8220;This idea of showing the impact is core to the work we do&amp;#8230;The spirit and the joy of our photography was a perfect fit for the optimistic nature of [Pinterest].&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. Focus on the Achievable&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;It has become a trend for individuals to use Pinterest for dreams &amp;#8212; dream houses, dream weddings, etc. But as a non-profit organization, you&amp;#8217;re all about making things possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/pancan/" target="_blank"&gt;Pancreatic Cancer Action Network&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s mission is to advance research, support patients and create hope. &amp;#8220;Our goal is to provide helpful content for all individuals who have been affected by pancreatic cancer,&amp;#8221; says Laura Behrman, social media manager at the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network, &amp;#8220;whether they are a survivor, have a loved one diagnosed with the disease or have lost a friend. In an effort to attract more support for our efforts, we are educating the general public about the organization and the disease through Pinterest.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For charity: water, Cohen says the staff &amp;#8220;looks to inspire our supporters with images of hope and opportunity that the water crisis is solvable.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Make It a Team Effort&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Get various staff members involved with your organization&amp;#8217;s Pinterest to diversify your boards and flesh them out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A recently added charity: water board is &amp;#8220;Products We Love.&amp;#8221; Cohen says that the board is comprised of brands the staff admires, most of which &amp;#8220;are partnering with a non-profit or have a philanthropic component to their business model, like Feed Projects, TOMS and Falling Whistles.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t necessarily need to have multiple staffers use the Pinterest account directly. At the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network, for example, Behrman is currently the only one pinning, but employees and volunteers contribute ideas and repin on their personal boards.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;6. Fundraise&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/donation-jar.jpeg" alt="" title="donation-jar" width="616" height="368" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-968073" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pinterest makes it extremely simple to sell various items, helping you raise money for your non-profit. Whether it&amp;#8217;s a t-shirt with your company logo or an inspiring poster, all you need to do is pin the image and type the &amp;#8220;$&amp;#8221; sign with the price in the description box. Pinterest automatically adds a nifty banner in the top-left corner of the image, displaying the cost, and the item will be added to the Gifts tab on the Pinterest homepage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;7. Repin/Highlight Other Non-Profits&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like all forms of social media, Pinterest isn&amp;#8217;t a place to over-promote. Avoid this is by mixing original pinning with repins of images from other non-profits within your sphere of influence. Users receive an email notification when their images are repinned and they are credited on your repin, which can increase their following. The non-profit you repin may return the favor, allowing Pinterest to become a channel for valuable, non-disruptive cross-promotion.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;8. Add Pinterest to Your Website/Project Pages&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;This may seem obvious, but it&amp;#8217;s often overlooked with new networks. You can add various Pinterest &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/about/goodies/" target="_blank"&gt;goodies&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; (a &amp;#8220;pin it&amp;#8221; button, follow button, logos, etc.) not only to your homepage, but also to project pages for more exposure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;9. Pin Videos&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/video-camera.jpg" alt="Video Camera" title="Video Camera" width="616" height="425" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-966111" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Videos aren&amp;#8217;t very common on Pinterest, but they&amp;#8217;re on the rise. &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; videos are especially easy to add, and Pinterest even has a special section for pinned videos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/28/pinterest-youtube/"&gt;Need More YouTube Views? Try Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jolkona&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Campaigns&amp;#8221; board consists of numerous videos. Singh says that people are more likely to donate when they&amp;#8217;re asked. &amp;#8220;We wanted to make sure that that happens interactively online, so we offer [the] online campaign feature, which allows our donors to honor a special person, celebrate a birthday or special milestone, or just show the impact you and colleagues or friends can have on the world&amp;#8230;Videos offer an added emotion and call to action that pictures sometimes don&#8217;t.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She admits that Jolkona hasn&amp;#8217;t received many repins for videos, but it has helped to increase traffic to the blog and adds something interesting to the Pinterest page. &amp;#8220;There are far fewer videos than images on Pinterest at this point, so use them to distinguish [your non-profit],&amp;#8221; Singh advises.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;10. Be Inviting&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pinning can sometimes seem like an individualized, solitary action, but it&amp;#8217;s important to interact with others and keep community in mind. For non-profits, Pinterest is more than just posting interesting visuals &amp;#8212; if used properly, it can be an extension of your organization and, when applicable, a support system.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Through the Pancreatic Cancer Action Network&amp;#8217;s Pinterest, says Behrman, &amp;#8220;We create a community that is inviting for others to share their story and connect with not just our organization, but with others going through a similar experience.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images courtesy of &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=1306270"&gt; mattjeacock&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=3177374"&gt;JamesBrey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=3966522"&gt;1stclassphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=5685649"&gt;ContentWorks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/non-profits/"&gt;non-profits&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/pinterest/"&gt;pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-good/"&gt;Social Good&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/XbIJq6ZVU9V_avnC6dPMYfvwk8g/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/XbIJq6ZVU9V_avnC6dPMYfvwk8g/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/XbIJq6ZVU9V_avnC6dPMYfvwk8g/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/XbIJq6ZVU9V_avnC6dPMYfvwk8g/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?i=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?i=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?i=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=xwMawL1UNlE:hn05UCjC1t8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/SocialMedia/~4/xwMawL1UNlE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/pinterest-strategies-non-profits/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mercedes Rolls Out Invisible Car [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZIGzpi9lCck?rel=0&amp;wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When Mercedes wanted to promote its new fuel cell vehicle, instead of placing it squarely in front of everyone in the world, the company decided to make the car invisible. We have video.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this clever publicity stunt, Mercedes wanted to emphasize that its F-Cell vehicle has no omissions, making it virtually invisible to the environment. If you take a look at the gallery below, you&amp;#8217;ll see how these clever dudes did it: by placing a mat of LEDs across one side of the vehicle and mounting a video-shooting &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/04/08/timelapse-aurora-borealis/"&gt;Canon 5D Mark II&lt;/a&gt; digital SLR camera on the other side.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We saw a Halloween costume like this once. Mount an &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ipad"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt; on your belly, surround it with costuming that looks like a hole, place a webcam on your back shooting backward, and then feed that video into the iPad. &lt;em&gt;Voil&#224;!&lt;/em&gt; It looks like you have a gory hole going all the way through you:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/V6p5mbp_M98?rel=0&amp;wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mercedes is doing basically the same trick. As you can see in the Mercedes video, even though people could still tell there was a car going by, they seemed impressed by the &amp;#8220;invisible&amp;#8221; fuel-cell vehicle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mercedes says its hydrogen-powered drive system is &amp;#8220;ready for series production,&amp;#8221; but other reports have its &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercedes-Benz_F-Cell" target="_blank"&gt;commercialization set for 2014&lt;/a&gt;. However, fuel-cell technology is still notoriously expensive, partly because hydrogen is a difficult fuel to store and transport. The materials needed to create a viable fuel-cell are still hovering in the pricey stratosphere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Practicality aside, we applaud Mercedes and its efforts to create a vehicle with zero emissions and less impact on the environment, and admire the lengths to which these artists went to bring home that point. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;By the way, with all the &lt;a href="http://www.coolsupercars.com/category/mercedes/" target="_blank"&gt;ultra-cool cars in the Mercedes stable&lt;/a&gt;, why did the company pick a minivan for this showy demo? Oh, we get it: more surface area to mount that video screen. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Invisible Mercedes: Setup&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/#51965Invisible-Mercedes-Setup"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/&amp;title=Mercedes Rolls Out Invisible Car [VIDEO]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Invisible Mercedes: Setup" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/invisible-mercedes/2_Set-up_2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/#51965Invisible-Mercedes-Setup'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/advertising/"&gt;Advertising&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/cars/"&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/fuel-cell/"&gt;Fuel Cell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mercedes/"&gt;mercedes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/C6JXFyK8TeSMjDPhEFafQ_ygn3M/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/C6JXFyK8TeSMjDPhEFafQ_ygn3M/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/C6JXFyK8TeSMjDPhEFafQ_ygn3M/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/C6JXFyK8TeSMjDPhEFafQ_ygn3M/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=kh3gc9FCBv8:dyWFtz5aDMI:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/kh3gc9FCBv8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/invisible-mercedes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Facebook Pages: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/research/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="social media research" src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/research-pose.png?9d7bd4" alt="social media research" width="110" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Welcome to our weekly edition of what&amp;#8217;s hot in &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/tag/social-media-news/" target="_blank"&gt;social media news&lt;/a&gt;. To help you &lt;strong&gt;stay up-to-date with social media&lt;/strong&gt;, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;#8217;s New This Week?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/about/pages" target="_blank"&gt;New Facebook Business Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: After rolling out Timeline on personal profiles, Facebook is now rolling out Timeline for Business pages. Timeline changes the design and layout of Business pages and makes them look like personal profiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/ck-facebook-timeline-business-pages.png?9d7bd4" alt="Facebook timeline" width="480" height="330" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;All Facebook Business pages will be moved to the new Timeline by the end of March. You can curate the information on your page beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-15764"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some important additions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;new header space provides more branding possibilities&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;But there are restrictions&lt;/em&gt; on the information you share in this new header regarding pricing, promotions, contact information and various calls to action. Be sure to check out these restrictions and &lt;a href="http://www.learnfacebookpages.com/" target="_blank"&gt;learn more about Facebook pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only three Facebook apps can now highlighted directly underneath this new header. Your other apps are still available through a More button.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;People can now message Business pages.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;And &lt;strong&gt;here&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s gone&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Default landing tabs used by many businesses to create a &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/8-powerful-ways-to-use-facebook-landing-tabs/" target="_blank"&gt;Welcome tab&lt;/a&gt; are no longer available with the new Timeline design.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out this &lt;a href="http://www.dreamgrow.com/facebook-cheat-sheet-sizes-and-dimensions/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Cheat Sheet&lt;/a&gt; for the sizes you need to know. And look out for more soon on how Timeline impacts Facebook marketing for businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.linkedin.com/2012/02/27/linkedin-follow-button-for-companies/" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn Rolls Out Follow Company Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Companies can now add a LinkedIn Follow button to their websites, &amp;#8220;making it easier for any consumer on the web to begin following companies of interest on LinkedIn.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="youtube"&gt; &lt;iframe title="YouTube video player" class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="480" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jykqF-neZ2I?color1=d6d6d6&amp;amp;color2=f0f0f0&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=3&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jykqF-neZ2I"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/jykqF-neZ2I/default.jpg" width="130" height="97" border=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jykqF-neZ2I"&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=jykqF-neZ2I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://googleplusplatform.blogspot.com/2012/02/improving-google-plugins-across-web.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google+ Plugins Get Revamped&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: There are a couple of little changes to make it easier to share your content with the +1 button and follow Google+ business pages. People can now &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/+/plugins/badge/personal-config" target="_blank"&gt;create a personal Google+ badge&lt;/a&gt; for their web pages. And be sure to check out the new &lt;a href="http://plusfiledownloads.appspot.com/follow-style-guide.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Google+ Style Guide&lt;/a&gt; for the recommended language to use when promoting your Google+ accounts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/ck-google-icon-recommendations.png?9d7bd4" alt="google+ icon recommendations" width="480" height="259" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Google+ Style Guide shows you which Google+ icons to use and which ones not to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://youtube-global.blogspot.com/2012/02/captions-for-all-more-options-for-your.html" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube Captions Get More Options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Captions have been available for YouTube videos since 2006, but YouTube has been improving caption features. YouTube viewers can now get automatic captions in more languages, search videos with captions and modify how the captions look while viewing videos. And YouTube creators have more options to import files with closed captions to their YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 364px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/ck-youtube-closed-caption-search.png?9d7bd4" alt="youtube closed caption search" width="354" height="311" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;You can search for text in Closed Captions on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.marismith.com/facebook-offers/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Launches &amp;#8220;Facebook Offers&amp;#8221; for Businesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A few select businesses are &lt;a href="http://www.insidefacebook.com/2012/01/10/facebook-continues-coupon-test-with-larger-news-feed-stories/" target="_blank"&gt;testing Facebook coupons&lt;/a&gt; that appear in the Facebook feeds. Facebook also unveiled &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/29/facebook-reveals-reach-generator-to-turn-posts-into-mobile-news-feed-ads-and-logout-page-ads/" target="_blank"&gt;mobile feed ads and logout ads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a social media tool worth noting:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skills.to/" target="_blank"&gt;Skills.to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A place to tag yourself and your Twitter friends with endorsements for skills and search for people with the skills you need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/ck-skillsto.png?9d7bd4" alt="skills.to" width="480" height="266" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Check out Skills.to and see the skills people have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s an interesting infographic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/infographic-who-really-uses-linkedin-2012-2" target="_blank"&gt;Who Really Uses LinkedIn?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 505px"&gt;&lt;img class=" " src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/ck-who-uses-linkedin-infographic.png?9d7bd4" alt="linkedin infographic" width="495" height="790" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Find out more about LinkedIn users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don&#8217;t miss this:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social Media Examiner presents &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/yClJHi" target="_blank"&gt;Social Media Success Summit 2012&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt; (online conference).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/yClJHi" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img title="456x250" src="http://cdn.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/456x250smss12.gif?9d7bd4" alt="" width="456" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join &lt;strong&gt;27 social media experts&lt;/strong&gt; at Social Media Examiner&amp;#8217;s big &lt;em&gt;online&lt;/em&gt; conference! &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/yClJHi" target="_blank"&gt;Go here to learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What social media news caught your interest this week?&lt;/strong&gt; Please share your comments below.&lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Fnew-facebook-pages-this-week-in-social-media%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/new-facebook-pages-this-week-in-social-media/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="New Facebook Pages: This Week in Social Media &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/new-facebook-pages-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/new-facebook-pages-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Someone at Apple Is Surfing the Web on iOS 6</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/&amp;title=Someone at Apple Is Surfing the Web on iOS 6&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/iPad-iOS6-275x171.jpg" alt="iPad-iOS6-600" title="iPad-iOS6-600" width="275" height="171" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-968051" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/apple"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; appears to be testing the next version of its operating system for mobile devices, iOS 6. At least, that's what device access logs to websites, including &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt;, seem to indicate. The &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/news/2012/03/ipads-using-ios-6-high-res-displays-showing-up-in-ars-server-logs.ars" target="_blank"&gt;initial report&lt;/a&gt; came from &lt;i&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/i&gt;, which says it discovered something unusual in its web logs. The technology site recorded several visits from browsers running on devices that claimed to be running iOS 6. There were also devices that were accessing the site on screens with a resolution of 2,048 x 1,536 -- the rumored pixel count of the iPad 3. &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt; checked its own logs and indeed found a few visits from devices claiming to be running iOS 6. Some claim to be iPhones and others iPads. Checking the IP address info of those visits with an &lt;a href="http://www.mxtoolbox.com/SuperTool.aspx?action=arin%3a17.202.39.47" target="_blank"&gt;online database&lt;/a&gt; revealed they came from Apple's headquarters in Cupertino, California. However, the only machines with 2,048 x 1,536 resolution seen in &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt;'s logs were running Google Chrome, so they couldn't be iPads. Here's a sample of some of our logs (apparently the Apple testers liked our compilation of the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/01/27/best-shit-people-say-videos/"&gt;Best Sh*t People Say Videos&lt;/a&gt;): &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;17.202.39.47 - - [24/Feb/2012:14:03:59 -0600] "GET /2012/01/27/best-shit-people-say-videos/ HTTP/1.1" 200 15974 "http://m.digg.com/newsbar/topnews/15_best_sh_t_people_say_videos" "Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; CPU iPhone OS 6_0 like Mac OS X) AppleWebKit/535.8 (KHTML, like Gecko)" 17.202.39.47 - - [22/Feb/2012:12:38:13 -0600] "GET /2012/01/27/best-shit-people-say-videos/ HTTP/1.1" 200 15975 "http://m.digg.com/newsbar/topnews/15_best_sh_t_people_say_videos" "Mozilla/5.0 (iPhone; CPU iPhone OS 6_0 like Mac OS X) AppleWebKit/535.8 (KHTML, like Gecko)"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; The current version of Apple's mobile software is &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ios-5"&gt;iOS 5&lt;/a&gt;. Apple typically previews new versions of its mobile OS at a developers conference in the spring. Apple reps didn't respond immediately to a request for comment. As &lt;i&gt;Ars&lt;/i&gt; notes, there's at least one other product on the market with the so-called "retina" resolution that the iPad 3 is expected to have. But, obviously, nothing runs iOS 6 -- unless it's an Apple employee testing software by browsing the Internet. The most recent version is &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/17/ios-update-rumor-siri-camera/"&gt;iOS 5.1&lt;/a&gt;, but that's only been made available to developers. On Tuesday, Apple sent out invitations to an event on March 7. The company holds upcoming products to the utmost secrecy. Apple almost never reveals product information until it is on the verge of release. It's a big part of the allure the company's brand has cultivated, and why Apple rumors have such currency. &lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/01/apple-ipad-3-event-clues/"&gt;Apple&#8217;s iPad 3 Event Invitation: 7 Clues You Might Have Missed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt; Still, it's impossible for Apple to keep everything it's doing under wraps. It needs to test its products in real-world environments to ensure that the work properly. That can lead to information being released prematurely, which most notoriously happened when an Apple employee lost a prototype iPhone in a bar in 2010 only to have it fall into the hands of tech blog &lt;i&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/i&gt;. Whereas that was a careless accident, the discovery of retina iPads running iOS 6 is more of a natural consequence. After all, Apple must test its software with the real Internet at some point, and that testing will leave tracks. Apple isn't expected to release iOS 6 at Wednesday's event, but is probably testing it now in advance of a spring unveiling. What would you like to see in iOS 6? Give Apple some tips in the comments. &lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;BONUS: Why iPad 3 Might Cost More Than iPad 2&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. Retina Display&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/#510651-Retina-Display"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. Retina Display" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ipad-expensive/1.%20Retina%20Display.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All reports point to an iPad 3 with a screen that doubles the pixel resolution in both directions. While that would be an incredible amount of pixels (more than what's needed to even show 1080p video at full resolution), it's also going to be harder -- and more expensive -- to make such a large-size "&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/retina-display"&gt;retina display&lt;/a&gt;." And if Apple goes with a new kind of LCD tech (like Sharp's IGZO), all bets are off.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/moshy_moshy/5473465894/" target="_blank"&gt;moshy_moshy&lt;/a&gt;, Flickr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/#510651-Retina-Display'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vSW7G4WNQ9qWoWXNT-P9Q18yIzA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vSW7G4WNQ9qWoWXNT-P9Q18yIzA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vSW7G4WNQ9qWoWXNT-P9Q18yIzA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vSW7G4WNQ9qWoWXNT-P9Q18yIzA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:TzevzKxY174"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?d=TzevzKxY174" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=2iQj35Hl--E:qdBIhM-kgH8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/apple/~4/2iQj35Hl--E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/02/ipad-3-ios6/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
