<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Co-Founder Saverin Gives Up U.S. Citizenship Before IPO (Bloomberg)</title>
      <description>FACEBOOK CO-FOUNDER GIVES UP U.S. CITIZENSHIP BEFORE IPO(Main headline, 1st story, link)</description>
      <link>http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-05-11/facebook-co-founder-saverin-gives-up-u-s-citizenship-before-ipo.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-05-11/facebook-co-founder-saverin-gives-up-u-s-citizenship-before-ipo.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foxconn Chief Confirms The Apple iTV</title>
      <description>In an interview published by China Daily today, Terry Gou, chairman of Foxconn, confirms the massive manufacturing company is making preparations for an Apple television set called iTV. Gou also states that neither development nor manufacturing has begun. Apparently, per China Daily at least, the television set will have an aluminum construction, Siri voice controls and FaceTime video calling. This is the most solid report to date of the long-fabled Apple HDTV. The product has been rumored for the last several years. So far both Steve Jobs and now Tim Cook have called the Apple TV, the company&#8217;s set-top box, a hobby. But it seems the company is almost ready to turn its avocation into an occupation. Gou&#8217;s claims published in today&#8217;s China Daily report line up very nicely with previous rumors including Cult Of Mac&#8217;s claims from last week. The iTV, or as I have long called it, the Apple HDTV, seems like it would be an iMac designed for the living room. An Apple HDTV will likely use a very similar branding and design plan as the iMac with near-edgeless glass and aluminum frame. It would also hopefully have a similar I/O port design, allowing consumers the luxury of having all the ports located in one location. China Daily also indicates that Foxconn is teaming up with Sharp to produce this set, which makes sense given Sharp&#8217;s dominance in LCD manufacturing. But as China Daily indicates, production nor development has started on this product yet, seemingly indicating that it won&#8217;t hit the market in 2012. It&#8217;s been also rumored that Apple is trying to line up more content partners to bolster iTunes&#8217;s library or even perhaps cobble together a legitimate alternative to cable TV. Whenever it hits, the iTV, Apple HDTV, or whatever it will be called will likely be the biggest TV news (albeit perhaps not the most popular selling unit) since the Beatles appeared on Carson.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/11/foxconn-chief-confirms-the-apple-itv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/11/foxconn-chief-confirms-the-apple-itv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Are the Top Retailers on Social Media? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s become practically mandatory that brands incorporate social media into their business strategy, causing retailers to compete for popularity in stores and on the Internet, too. Campalyst has provided this infographic, which covers the largest Internet retailers in the U.S., and their presence on the five key social networks: Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Google+ and Pinterest. Victoria&#8217;s Secret is the top retailer on Facebook, with nearly 18.5 million fans, followed by Walmart with about 15 million fans. According to Campalyst, 97% of the Top 250 Internet Retailers are on Facebook, and average number of fans there is close to 1 million. On Twitter, Major League Baseball is the leading Internet retailer account with 1.9 followers. The brand also has the most on Google+, boasting more than 600,000 followers. Retail channels on YouTube do not show numbers as large as the other social platforms. Nike has the most subscribers with more than 200,000. Pinterest is still relatively new to the social media game, which explains why its numbers are the lowest. It may also suggest that the platform is better for user-generated content, rather than retail. Nordstrom leads on Pinterest with more than 14,000 followers. SEE ALSO: 8 Strategies for Launching a Brand Presence on Pinterest The infographic also breaks down what retail industries are leading on each platform. For example, apparel/accessories average 100,000 followers on Twitter, while computers and electronics only average about 62,000 &#8212; yet computers and electronics is the top industry with subscribers on YouTube. Take a look at the stats below and let us know what you think. Do any of the retail brands or industries surprise you? Is retail suitable for all of these platforms? Share your thoughts in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, pressureUSA More About: brands, Facebook, features, Google, infographic, pinterest, retail, Social Media, trending, Twitter, YouTubeFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/retailers-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/retailers-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I see... http://t.co/Qxe9OmcI</title>
      <description>Stilgherrian: I see http://t.co/Qxe9OmcI &#9733; Retweeted by Adam Fletcher Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kb7DvViFgc/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kb7DvViFgc/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stunning cb2 display. #fallpreview http://t.co/wxzS94tC</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Stunning cb2 display. #fallpreview http://t.co/wxzS94tC &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KdHuc5FgIf/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KdHuc5FgIf/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple to Drop Google Maps, Add 3D in iOS 6 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Apple will drop Google Maps in iOS6 for an in-house app that&#8217;s &#8220;cleaner, faster and more reliable,&#8221; according to a report. Citing &#8220;trusted sources,&#8221; 9to5Mac reports that Apple is using its purchases of Placebase, C3 Technologies, and Poly9 to create a &#8220;complete mapping database.&#8221; In addition to better performance, the new feature will also sport a 3D mode. 3D won&#8217;t be standard, but users can click on a button to enable it. &#8220;This 3D mode is said to essentially be technology straight from C3 Technologies: beautiful, realisitic graphics based on de-classified missile target algorithms,&#8221; according to the report. The move comes after Apple ditched Google Maps in its latest version of iPhoto for iPad in early March. Apple could not be reached for comment. A foe of Google on many fronts, Apple has been working on improving its mapping software since it bought Placeware in 2009. The next year, Apple acquired Poly9, a provider of 3D mapping solutions. In 2011, Apple bought C3, which also provides 3D mapping technology and absorbed the principals of the company. The video below shows C3&#8242;s technology in action. The activity represents a focus for Apple on another improvement to its mobile experience. Similarly, when Apple wanted to add voice-recognition functionality to iOS, it bought Siri in 2010 and later incorporated it into iOS 5. The company is expected to introduce iOS 6 in mid-June at its World Wide Developers Conference. More About: apple, Google Maps, ios6</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/apple-to-drop-google-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/apple-to-drop-google-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple to Drop Google Maps, Add 3D in iOS 6 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Apple will drop Google Maps in iOS6 for an in-house app that&#8217;s &#8220;cleaner, faster and more reliable,&#8221; according to a report. Citing &#8220;trusted sources,&#8221; 9to5Mac reports that Apple is using its purchases of Placebase, C3 Technologies, and Poly9 to create a &#8220;complete mapping database.&#8221; In addition to better performance, the new feature will also sport a 3D mode. 3D won&#8217;t be standard, but users can click on a button to enable it. &#8220;This 3D mode is said to essentially be technology straight from C3 Technologies: beautiful, realisitic graphics based on de-classified missile target algorithms,&#8221; according to the report. The move comes after Apple ditched Google Maps in its latest version of iPhoto for iPad in early March. Apple could not be reached for comment. A foe of Google on many fronts, Apple has been working on improving its mapping software since it bought Placeware in 2009. The next year, Apple acquired Poly9, a provider of 3D mapping solutions. In 2011, Apple bought C3, which also provides 3D mapping technology and absorbed the principals of the company. The video below shows C3&#8242;s technology in action. The activity represents a focus for Apple on another improvement to its mobile experience. Similarly, when Apple wanted to add voice-recognition functionality to iOS, it bought Siri in 2010 and later incorporated it into iOS 5. The company is expected to introduce iOS 6 in mid-June at its World Wide Developers Conference. More About: apple, Google Maps, ios6</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/apple-to-drop-google-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/apple-to-drop-google-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erik reliving his youth at @thelandofnod space #fallpreview http://t.co/KfiY43zp</title>
      <description>Crate and Barrel: Erik reliving his youth at @thelandofnod space #fallpreview http://t.co/KfiY43zp &#9733; Retweeted by The Land of Nod Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KdN4Ytsvy4/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KdN4Ytsvy4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Location-Based App Lets You Stand in an Artists&#8217; Shoes [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Visiting a major landmark, one often suspects numerous artists over the years have created paintings from where you stand. Using your smartphone, you may soon be able to find that out more easily than ever before. A new startup app called Geocoded Art aims to connect people with artworks depicting the places they visit to see those images as the artists viewed them. The project is being pitched to the crowdfunding community on Kickstarter. Currently, Geocoded Art is integrated into Google Earth, but the crew at the startup wants to make it available to travelers on their smartphones. The Geocoded Art website lets you peruse art by region, artist name or the name of the artwork, in case you want to pre-plan a trip based on scenes in paintings. You can be a supporter of the project for a minimum of $1. So far, they have raised around $600 of their $7,500 funding goal with 18 days to go before the campaign closes. A video on the Kickstarter page walks you through what it would be like to view the world with this app in your hand. Google recently launched Photo Tours to take users closer to the destinations they search. What do you think of Geocoded Art? Would you use this while traveling? Sound off in the comments. More About: art, travelFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/location-based-app-artist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/location-based-app-artist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today&#8217;s Top Stories: Web Browsing on Xbox 360, Bing&#8217;s Social Search</title>
      <description>Welcome to this morning&#8217;s edition of &#8220;First To Know,&#8221; a series in which we keep you in the know on what&#8217;s happening in the digital world. Today, we&#8217;re looking at three particularly interesting stories. Bing Gets a Big Social Overhaul Microsoft has launched a major overhaul of its search engine Bing, putting a big emphasis on social search and discovery. Important changes include a new social sidebar with Facebook (and, eventually, Twitter, Google+ Quora and LinkedIn) integration and the option to directly ask your social buddies questions on specific topics. Yahoo CEO Claims he Never Provided a Resume to Yahoo Yahoo CEO Scott Thompson claims he never provided a resume or incorrect information to Yahoo, Reuters reports citing sources familiar with the matter. Thompson found himself at the center of a scandal when it was found that he does not have a computer science degree, despite what was stated in his official company biography. A recent report said Thompson would resign from the Yahoo following the incident, though this has not been officially confirmed. Xbox 360 to Get Full Internet Explorer Browsing Microsoft is testing a modified version of IE9 for use on the Xbox 360 console, The Verge reports citing unnamed sources. Xbox 360 users can already perform some limited internet searches, but the new IE browser for Xbox will let them surf the web as they would on a PC. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, mattjeacock More About: bing, features, first to know series, mashable, microsoft, YahooFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/xbox-360-browsing-bing-social-search/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/xbox-360-browsing-bing-social-search/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#8217;s &#8216;Ghostbusters&#8217; Spoof Circa 1984 Hits YouTube</title>
      <description>Just a week after a video featuring a 1984-era Steve Jobs portraying FDR hit the web, even more magic from the vaults of Apple Corporate have hit the web, and this time we have theme music! And not just any theme music, we&#8217;re talking Ghostbusters. NetworkWorld &#8212; which got the original &#8220;1944&#8243; video scoop &#8212; posted an epic opening video from Apple&#8217;s 1984 International Sales Conference. The video is called &#8220;Blue Busters&#8221; and the conceit is a pretty straight Ghostbusters parody, with Apple employees working as &#8220;Blue Busters&#8221; to eradicate the use of IBM machines on the desktop. As Macrumors points out, you can see cameos of Apple founders Steve Wozniak and Steve Jobs in the video at the 2:21, 3:00 and 4:04 marks. Who would have guessed that Jobs was the kind of guy who was into making humorous corporate videos?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/apple-ghostbusters-spoof/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/apple-ghostbusters-spoof/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Millennials the Most Distracted or Engaged Generation?</title>
      <description>Plenty has been penned on the time teenagers and young adults &#8220;waste&#8221; on the Internet. Facebook is often vilified on this account. And while Internet addiction, bullying and diminishing attention spans are certainly of concern, the empowerment these new channels offer may outweigh the drivel. So argues Adora Svitak, the 14-year-old author, educator and speaker who recently discussed millennials and social media on stage at Mashable Connect in Orlando, Fla. Svitak made a compelling case for social empowerment among &#8220;the generation of eye-rollers,&#8221; drawing from recent trends, studies and anecdotes from her own life growing up in the thick of a changing social landscape. Only problem is, adults can have a hard time understanding just how beneficial that engagement can be. Facebook Is the New Study Hall It&#8217;s a challenge for kids to live in a world of constant communication (as we all do), and suddenly turn it off in a classroom of textbooks and blackboards. I&#8217;ve heard it likened to teleporting kids to the 1950s for six hours each day. Take a recent anecdote about how a school administrator disabled Google&#8217;s chat feature, only to find students sharing Google Docs in order to chat in the sidebar. Similarly, Svitak explained how her peers at school use Facebook for fun, but also as a collaborative educational tool. &#8220;We use Facebook as a study hall, posting a lot of resources for upcoming tests,&#8221; she said, pulling up a comment thread full of links, likes and conversations about art history. Indeed, Facebook itself recognized the potential here when it launched Groups for Schools, where students and teachers could collaborate in a sanctioned social environment. Facebook&#8217;s platform just became richer with the ability to share files within groups as well. Whether via &#8220;official&#8221; channels or not, study will happen where students live. For now, that&#8217;s on Facebook, and fighting it will likely be a losing battle for educators. Meme Culture Is the New Rock and Roll There&#8217;s always been a cultural gap between parents and children. It can take the form of music &#8212; rock and roll or hip hop, for example. Or perhaps humor &#8212; The Cosby Show vs. South Park. The divide happening online, according to Svitak, lies in meme culture. Svitak&#8217;s mom is an early tech adopter. Her dad builds Windows Phones for a living. But according to Svitak, when it comes to web culture, they have no idea what&#8217;s going on. They don&#8217;t share the same touchstones she does with her older sister. &#8220;Memes are a world that my parents don&#8217;t quite understand,&#8221; said Svitak, however &#8220;inescapable&#8221; they are in her own Facebook feed. They are a new language &#8212; a way to communicate casually and humorously &#8212; almost like slang. And like all youth vernaculars, they can be a springboard into more topical conversations. When the hilarious Tumblr blog Texts From Hillary spread across the web, it made an impact on young people, said Svitak. &#8220;So many of my peers saw Hillary Clinton&#8217;s cool factor,&#8221; she explained. Kids whom she assumed didn&#8217;t care about news or current events were suddenly talking about it. New Marketing: Contests and Causes are King Young people have access to infinite entertainment, news and social choices, which means traditional marketing tactics won&#8217;t fly. If brands want to reach millennials, they need to wrap their messages in an engaging package. Contests and causes resonate well, according to Svitak. She cited a recent promotion by shoe retailer Vans, in which the brand encouraged fans to design their own shoes and share them on Facebook. One of her friends posted the creation above, and received about 40 &#8220;likes&#8221; within minutes. &#8220;If I pay you $100, will you let me keep them?&#8221; read one of the comments on the post. There&#8217;s no better brand play than a fan creating art around your product and her friends getting excited about it. &#8220;I think that my peers deserve more than products to buy wrapped up in advertising,&#8221; Svitak said. &#8220;We need ideas to share and causes to believe in &#8212; opportunities to lead and teach.&#8221; The idealism of youth is indeed a reckoning force when amplified by social media. &#8220;Teenagers invest themselves deeply in causes,&#8221; said Svitak. When it comes to marketing, &#8220;there&#8217;s a lot of idealism to tap into. Teens don&#8217;t have cash, but they can do good by using their smarts.&#8221; Svitak mentioned microlending website Kiva.org, which empowers people in developing nations with small, low-interest loans. The reach of lending campaigns in her Facebook feed are magnified as kids share and tag friends to get them involved. &#8220;We can use peer pressure in destructive ways, and amazing ways,&#8221; she said. The net benefit of this public discourse about brands and causes is a new era of corporate transparency, according to Svitak. &#8220;Not only do we share things we really like, but we share things that we hate.&#8221; Just as a brand aims to harness the power of social, a public misstep can be equally damaging. Svitak cited clothing retailer Urban Outfitters&#8217; political donations to candidates with anti-gay platforms. The controversy caused a stir on the web after prominent tweeters like Miley Cyrus called the company out. Not only do they steal from artists but every time you give them money you help finance a campaign against gay equality.#SHADYASHELL &#8212; Miley Ray Cyrus (@MileyCyrus) May 26, 2011 Indeed, the most viral video ever &#8212; KONY 2012 &#8212; compelled young social media users to watch and share a 30-minute documentary about atrocities in Uganda. While many have found fault with KONY 2012, or have debated its value, it remains a testament to the unmatched influence of online youth. &#8220;Imagine KONY 2012 with no youth involvement,&#8221; said Svitak. &#8220;It wouldn&#8217;t be possible.&#8221; More About: Adora Svitak, Facebook, features, Marketing, mashable connect, memes, millenials, youth</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/millennials-social-media-adora-svitak/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/millennials-social-media-adora-svitak/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
