<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Popular Social Media Personality Trey Pennington Dies Unexpectedly</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/&amp;title=Popular Social Media Personality Trey Pennington Dies Unexpectedly&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Pennington.jpg" class="alignright" width="275"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Trey Pennington, a well-known social media personality, died Sunday in Greenville, S.C., of an apparent suicide. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pennington ran a consulting practice, blog and online radio show. He maintained presences on all of the top social networks, including &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/treypennington"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/trey.pennington?sk=wall"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101655649240596577615/posts"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The local NBC affiliate, &lt;a href="http://www.wyff4.com/news/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;WYFF&lt;/a&gt;, in Greenville tells us that police had confirmed a man killed himself in a church parking lot earlier Sunday. As of 6:45 p.m. ET, the coroner had not released the identity of the body, but a member of the news staff there said they had heard from multiple sources that it was Pennington. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many of his friends and fans have turned to the web to mourn, as news of his death spreads. People have commented on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/%40treypennington"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and Facebook about the tragic loss and the role of online and offline friends &amp;#8212; a sentiment Pennington himself mentioned in his last tweet. It was sent late Sunday morning. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Picture-23.png" width="640"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/trey-pennington/"&gt;Trey Pennington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ya15SY3iELr3MySLBAPUGt58U7I/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ya15SY3iELr3MySLBAPUGt58U7I/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ya15SY3iELr3MySLBAPUGt58U7I/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ya15SY3iELr3MySLBAPUGt58U7I/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=jxCdF3TseUs:5ZB0YSwMsuI:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/jxCdF3TseUs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/trey-pennington/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 stories of life-changing social media connections</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="520" height="245" src="http://cdn.thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/Social-Media-Connections-520x245.jpg" alt="People contact network" title="People contact network" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we think about social media, it&amp;#8217;s very easy to keep it sectioned off into nice, little containers. A thought passed along on Twitter might elicit a response, perhaps even a retweet. A Facebook status message is passed along and it gets a like or two.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But what about when it becomes something much more than the sum of its parts? What happens when lives change because of social media interaction? That was the question on my mind this week, so I turned (naturally) to social media in order to find some answers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The responses that came my way ran the gamut from lighthearted and entertaining to truly heart-wrenching and difficult to read. I&amp;#8217;ve condensed a few of them down and I thought I&amp;#8217;d share them with you here.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;The Social Media Job Boards&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve all heard the stories of the world&amp;#8217;s job markets. They&amp;#8217;re tough to say the least and many people are turning toward more entrepreneurial ventures in order to find what they&amp;#8217;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Marga Deona is one such person. Deona relates her story of working as a publicity and campaign strategist, dating back to the earliest days of social media via LiveJournal, Friendster and Internet message boards. After spending years building her own network, she took the leap to working on her own.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;My breakthrough came when I, along with a group of people, took charge of the PR direction of a Presidential campaign last year. The reach of our efforts was phenomenal, with people rapidly sharing and retweeting every single [piece of] content we posted in support of the Presidential candidate.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/jurgen-freund-split-level-shot-of-coral-reef-and-shore-phillippines.jpeg" &gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-22147" title="jurgen-freund-split-level-shot-of-coral-reef-and-shore-phillippines" src="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/jurgen-freund-split-level-shot-of-coral-reef-and-shore-phillippines-220x165.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="165" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Because of the impact of the highly-social campaign in the Philippines, Deona found more doors opening. Companies were sending her messages via Twitter, Facebook and email to do their PR strategies, she was invited to speak at seminars, on radio and elsewhere. But the most interesting twist to the story is how she began curating a businesses musical selection:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;One guy who added me on Facebook because of our common interest in triathlon sent me a message saying he found my musical taste &amp;#8220;exquisite&amp;#8221; and asked me to curate tracks for his shop. Turns out his family owns one of the biggest mall chains in the country, and he got me to do it for a sports arena that he was opening independent from the family business.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Deona is far from alone. Though we often times hear about people making job connections via Twitter, Facebook and the like (heck, even my job at TNW began with a tweet), Alexis Lamster found his connection via Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had emailed a few times with this guy from Tumblr because we had common interests in food and photography. One day he emailed me to say he&amp;#8217;d be in the neighborhood around my office and that we should meet up for coffee. Well, sort of thankfully I had just finishing pitching a big set of changes to my boss. I worked at a wedding website managing the advertising and sales department and suggested we make a set of changes to become the best website out there. My boss effectively said &amp;#8220;These are great ideas but we don&amp;#8217;t care enough to make them.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lamster was crushed, he said, but the coffee meeting with his friend Dave from Tumblr was like a perfectly-timed gift.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#8217;t help but talk about what had just happened, how I wanted to work for a company where they wanted to make real change and be the best. He spoke a bit about his startup (&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://postling.com/" &gt;Postling&lt;/a&gt;) and how they were just starting out. We realized that our wants were very much in line &#8212; I wanted to work for a startup and feel like I could make a great impact on a company, while they needed someone to help them get to MVP [minimum viable product] and find their target market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;So while many people turn to LinkedIn or some other, dedicated network for finding jobs, others are stumbling upon success in places that they might have never thought the would. We see it here on TNW quite often. A simple tweet, a Facebook status update, maybe a blog post&amp;#8230;any of these can start off simply enough, but then snowball into a story that was never intended to have been told.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Social Travels&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/airbnb.jpeg" &gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-22145" title="airbnb" src="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/airbnb-220x122.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="122" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Oh sure, we have &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.airbnb.com/" &gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;, which allows anyone to rent out their unused space. &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.couchsurfing.org/" &gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/a&gt; has been around for ages and we&amp;#8217;re quite used to the social aspect of that. But what about other travels? Those stories are out there, too.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I asked for stories on Twitter, one of the most common ones that I heard about were people who traveled to the different campuses of NASA in order to take part in a NASA Tweetup. We covered the story of NASA&amp;#8217;s social media strategy in depth &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/08/13/the-history-and-future-of-nasas-social-media-strategy/" &gt;a couple of weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;, so that wasn&amp;#8217;t necessarily surprising to see such a response from the faithful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But I knew that there had to be more, and that&amp;#8217;s when I got the story that I was hoping to find.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-22143" title="Screen Shot 2011-09-03 at 2.23.45 PM" src="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/Screen-Shot-2011-09-03-at-2.23.45-PM-520x258.png" alt="" width="520" height="258" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You might have heard of Paul Smith, also known as &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://twitter.com/#!/twitchhiker" &gt;@Twitchhiker&lt;/a&gt;. Smith set out on a mission in 2009 to travel from the UK to New Zealand, using only Twitter to find his methods of travel and accommodation. Along the way, he would raise money for charity, document his trip in video and on Twitter (of course) and he even &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/1849530742?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=twitchhiker-21&amp;amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1849530742" &gt;wrote a book&lt;/a&gt; about his travels. Smith now maintains &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://twitchhiker.com/" &gt;his own website&lt;/a&gt; where he continues to tell stories of travels, encouraging his readers to take part in them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Social Entrepreneurship&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is a final side to the unexpected results from social connections. It&amp;#8217;s one that, even though my entire premise was based on the unexpected, I certainly didn&amp;#8217;t expect to hear. When it comes to entrepreneurship, social networking seems to be the tie that not only binds, but also enables.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/Screen-Shot-2011-09-03-at-2.58.39-PM.png" &gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-22146" title="Screen Shot 2011-09-03 at 2.58.39 PM" src="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/files/2011/09/Screen-Shot-2011-09-03-at-2.58.39-PM-520x201.png" alt="" width="520" height="201" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Megan Hargroder relates to us the story of her findings in New Orleans, which helped her to launch her project called &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://conversations.be/" &gt;conversations.be&lt;/a&gt;. Oh, and there&amp;#8217;s another twist to the story, too:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I moved here 2 years ago not knowing anyone, quickly identified the movers and shakers (and total badasses) that I wanted to be friends with, followed them on Twitter, started engaging in conversations and met up with them at tech-related networking events. These offline/online connections led to personal offline relationships, and then my previous job as community manager of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://launchpadnola.com/" &gt;Launch Pad&lt;/a&gt; (a creative coworking space) which literally launched my own social media and new business online setup company and where I met my now girlfriend of 9 months.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;So while Hargroder&amp;#8217;s goals are set high for conversations.be, there are still others who hope to have an even more wide-reaching impact, and they&amp;#8217;re utilizing social media to help them accomplish their goals.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Raiyan Laksemana relates the ale of trying to create jobs in film and media in his native Indonesia:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Before social media, learning from the best was like trying to fly from Earth to Mars. Everybody is milking everyone else by commoditizing connections. With social media, anyone is just a few pages away.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Laksamana tells me that the more leveled playing field of social media is enabling him to not only find jobs for himself, but to also create jobs for others.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;In Indonesia, we were clueless as to how to create jobs in the film and media industry. All of the major companies and studios were taking the profits and setting barbaric pricing. What we found is that Indonesia has tens of millions of mobile Internet users and our mobile growth is actually ranked 8th in the world.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Laksamana took that information, then created a marketing and regulatory platform for the smaller, independent producers. The hope is that, in doing so, the money will go back to where it needs to go, rather than to those who are not directly involved in the creation of content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If this works as we have planned, it will trigger a thriving, egalitarian media ecosystem in Indonesia and it&amp;#8217;s all thanks to social networking. The system of learning and the opening of a new market would not have been possible without it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Now, It&amp;#8217;s Your Turn&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any time that we ask for stories to be able to pass them on to the rest of our readers, we inevitably miss out on some great ones. So now it&amp;#8217;s your turn. If you have a story to tell, we want to hear it. Let us know in the comments how social media has opened opportunities for you that you might not have had otherwise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?a=cUXJYNR9lp4:FLnqdPoScWY:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?i=cUXJYNR9lp4:FLnqdPoScWY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?a=cUXJYNR9lp4:FLnqdPoScWY:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?a=cUXJYNR9lp4:FLnqdPoScWY:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?i=cUXJYNR9lp4:FLnqdPoScWY:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNextWeb/~4/cUXJYNR9lp4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/09/03/6-stories-of-life-changing-social-media-connections/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/09/03/6-stories-of-life-changing-social-media-connections/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hootsuite launches advanced facebook functionality - pages, events, groups and walls http://j.mp/nmHIUp</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a0.twimg.com/profile_images/1166013646/thedrum_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/peterjblack"&gt;Peter Black&lt;/a&gt;: hootsuite launches advanced facebook functionality - pages, events, groups and walls &lt;a href="http://j.mp/nmHIUp" target="_blank"&gt;http://j.mp/nmHIUp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/peterjblack/status/108398304555053056"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://hootsuite.com/manage-facebook?utm_source=facebook&amp;utm_campaign=hootbook</link>
      <guid>http://hootsuite.com/manage-facebook?utm_source=facebook&amp;utm_campaign=hootbook</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social media connects farmers with local customers &#8211; USATODAY.com</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/story/2011-09-03/Social-media-connects-farmers-with-local-customers/50243472/1?csp=34money&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+UsatodaycomMoney-TopStories+%28Money+-+Top+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/story/2011-09-03/Social-media-connects-farmers-with-local-customers/50243472/1?csp=34money&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+UsatodaycomMoney-TopStories+%28Money+-+Top+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of the web</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://evolutionofweb.appspot.com/</link>
      <guid>http://evolutionofweb.appspot.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday Google: Making Sense of the Web for 13 Years</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/&amp;title=Happy Birthday Google: Making Sense of the Web for 13 Years&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/happy-birthday-google.jpg" alt="" title="happy birthday google" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-725099" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;What were &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; up to 13 years ago? Maybe you were perfecting the ideal AIM screen name. Or you might have been surfing the &amp;#8220;WestHollywood&amp;#8221; neighborhood of GeoCities. Chances are, you had been using Yahoo! or AOL as your primary search engines. But Google&amp;#8217;s debut on this day in &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/DiamondGB#p/search/0/hWq4DWfrpu8" target="_blank"&gt;1998&lt;/a&gt; would change the World Wide Web forever.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On September 4, 1998, Larry Page and Sergey Brin filed for incorporation as &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; Inc. &amp;#8212; they had received a &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/science/discoveries/news/2007/09/dayintech_0907" target="_blank"&gt;$100,000 check&lt;/a&gt; from an investor made out to Google, Inc., and needed to incorporate that name so they could legally deposit the check. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Prior to the launch, Larry Page and Sergey Brin met at Stanford in 1995, and soon decided to launch a search service called &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/corporate/timeline/#start" target="_blank"&gt;BackRub&lt;/a&gt; in January 1996. They soon reevaluated the name (and the creepy logo) in favor of Google, a play on the mathematical figure, &amp;#8220;googol,&amp;#8221; which represents the number 1 followed by 100 zeroes. The name embodied their mission to create an infinite amount of web resources. And that they did.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since then, Google has become a household name to billions of people worldwide. You&amp;#8217;ll overhear senior citizens command their grandchildren to &amp;#8220;google&amp;#8221; the price of foot cream. You&amp;#8217;ll witness toddlers punching the screen of the latest Android phone. And chances are, you&amp;#8217;ve navigated the circles of Google+ (if not, let&amp;#8217;s get you an invite already). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/06/19/10-google-facts/"&gt;10 Fun Facts You Didn&#8217;t Know About Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;d like to guide you on a trip down Google lane, presenting the key products and acquisitions that were born in the first Google garage office, and innovated in the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/googleplex/"&gt;Googleplex&lt;/a&gt;. In the comments below, please share how Google has had an impact on your life, and join us in wishing Google a happy birthday!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1996-1997: BackRub&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#2483319961997-BackRub"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1996-1997: BackRub" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/1_Backrub1996.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google was first launched under the &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/19971210065425/backrub.stanford.edu/backrub.html" target="_blank"&gt;BackRub&lt;/a&gt; nomer. Soon after, founders Larry Page and Sergey Brin registered the Google.com domain name in September 1997. The two arrived at the name as a play on the mathematical figure, "googol," which represents the number 1 followed by 100 zeroes. The name embodied their mission to create an infinite amount of web resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1998: Google's First Homepage&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248351998-Googles-First-Homepage"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1998: Google's First Homepage" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/2.1_Google first homepage1998.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original Google homepage prototype debuted in November 1998. Earlier that year Google received a &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/science/discoveries/news/2007/09/dayintech_0907" target="_blank"&gt;$100,000 check&lt;/a&gt; made out to as-yet-unestablished Google Inc. from first investor Andy Bechtolsheim.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In September 2008, the two founders set up shop in Susan Wojcicki&#8216;s garage in Menlo Park, CA, deposited their check and hired their first employee, &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/19991002122809/www-cs-students.stanford.edu/~csilvers/" target="_blank"&gt;Craig Silverstein&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1999: The Uncle Sam Homepage&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248391999-The-Uncle-Sam-Homepage"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1999: The Uncle Sam Homepage" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/4_Uncle Sam homepage1999.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apart from adding Uncle Sam to its homepage, in 1999 Google outgrew its next office and moved to its first Mountain View, California location. The team announced $25 million in equity funding from Sequoia Capital and Kleiner Perkins in its &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20000309205910/http://google.com/pressrel/pressrelease1.html" target="_blank"&gt;first press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2000: Google Becomes Yahoo's Default Search Provider&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248452000-Google-Becomes-Yahoos-Default-Search-Provider"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2000: Google Becomes Yahoo's Default Search Provider" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/5_Yahoo Google2000.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apart from its partnership with Yahoo, in 2000 Google announced that its index reached the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/press/pressrel/pressrelease26.html" target="_blank"&gt;1 billion-URL mark&lt;/a&gt;, making it the largest search engine in the world. Google also launched &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/press/pressrel/pressrelease39.html" target="_blank"&gt;AdWord&lt;/a&gt;, a self-service ad program that allowed people to purchase keyword advertising that would appear alongside search results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2001: Google Image Search&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248472001-Google-Image-Search"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2001: Google Image Search" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/6.1_Google image search 2001.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image search launched in July 2001 with an index of 250 million images. That same year Google acquired &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/press/pressrel/pressrelease48.html" target="_blank"&gt;Deja Usenet&lt;/a&gt; and archived its index into categories that ultimately made up Google Groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2002: Google Search Appliance&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248632002-Google-Search-Appliance"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2002: Google Search Appliance" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/8-2_google-search-appliance2002.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early in 2002 Google marketed its first hardware, the &lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/Google-aims-search-device-at-companies/2100-1023_3-833905.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google Search Appliance&lt;/a&gt;, a device that plugged into a computer and provided advanced search capabilities for internal documents. In May Google announced &lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/2100-1023-919173.html" target="_blank"&gt;Labs&lt;/a&gt;, a resource for people interested in trying out beta programs emerging from Google's R&amp;D team. Later Google launched its &lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/2100-1023-958927.html" target="_blank"&gt;News tool&lt;/a&gt; that provided links from 4,000 sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2003: AdSense&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248692003-AdSense"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2003: AdSense" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/adsense.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google announced the world's largest &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/press/pressrel/advertising.html" target="_blank"&gt;content-targeted ad program&lt;/a&gt;, later dubbed AdSense after Google acquired Applied Semantics. Earlier in the year Google acquired &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2003/02/17/business/google-deal-ties-company-to-weblogs.html" target="_blank"&gt;Pyra Labs, the creator of Blogger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2004: Gmail&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248672004-Gmail"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2004: Gmail" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/10-1_gmail2004.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google launched &lt;a href="http://searchenginewatch.com/article/2065293/Google-Launches-Gmail-Free-Email-Service"&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt; on April Fool's Day 2004, but the beta version required an invitation to join. In January &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/accounts/ServiceLogin?service=orkut&amp;hl=en-US&amp;rm=false&amp;continue=http://www.orkut.com/RedirLogin?msg%3D0%26page%3Dhttp://www.orkut.com/Home&amp;cd=US&amp;passive=true&amp;skipvpage=true&amp;sendvemail=false" target="_blank"&gt;Orkut&lt;/a&gt; launched as Google's foray into social networking. In August, Google's &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/press/pressrel/ipo.html" target="_blank"&gt;initial public offering&lt;/a&gt; contained 19,605,052 shares of Class A common stock at $85 per share.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2005: Google Maps&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248132005-Google-Maps"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2005: Google Maps" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/11_GoogleMaps2005.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2005/02/mapping-your-way.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt; launched in February 2005, to go live on the first iPhone in 2007. Additionally, &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/" target="_blank"&gt;code.google.com&lt;/a&gt; went live to provide resources for developers, and included all of Google's APIs. The company also acquired &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/pressrel/urchin.html" target="_blank"&gt;Urchin&lt;/a&gt;, whose content optimization service helped create Google Analytics, launched later that year. In June Google released &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2005/06/cover-earth.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth&lt;/a&gt;, a satellite-powered mapping service. In October &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2005/10/feed-world.html" target="_blank"&gt;Reader&lt;/a&gt; was unveiled to help organize and consolidate content into a single feed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2006: YouTube&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248652006-YouTube"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2006: YouTube" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/12_youtube2006.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a $1.65 billion stock transaction, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2006/10/09/confirmed-google-buys-youtube/"&gt;Google acquired YouTube&lt;/a&gt; in October 2006. Google also unveiled &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/trends" target="_blank"&gt;Trends&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that allows a user to evaluate popular searches over a specific timeframe. Earlier that year Google released &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/02/chat-email-crazy-delicious.html" target="_blank"&gt;Gchat&lt;/a&gt;, a Gmail-based instant message service derived from Google Talk. &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/06/find-it-with-google-buy-it-with-google.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google Checkout&lt;/a&gt; emerged later as a way to pay for online purchases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2007: Android&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248172007-Android"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2007: Android" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/13_Android2007.gif" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In November 2007 &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2007/11/05/google-android/"&gt;Google announced its first mobile venture, Android&lt;/a&gt;, which the company called "the first open platform for mobile devices."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2008: Google Chrome&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248192008-Google-Chrome"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2008: Google Chrome" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/14.1_Chrome2008.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September 2008 Google introduced Chrome, its open source browser. The surprise was spoiled when the comic book that was meant to help debut &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2008/09/01/google-chrome/"&gt;Chrome leaked&lt;/a&gt; a day ahead of schedule. Later that month T-mobile announced the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2008/09/23/google-g1/"&gt;G1, Google's first Android-powered mobile device&lt;/a&gt;. That year Google also added &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/09/08/google-instant-predictions/"&gt;Google Suggest&lt;/a&gt; capabilities and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2008/03/23/google-site-search/"&gt;site search&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2009: Google Wave&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248252009-Google-Wave"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2009: Google Wave" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/15_Wave2009.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To much anticipation, Google announced its venture into &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2009/05/28/google-wave-guide/"&gt;real-time communication via the Wave platform&lt;/a&gt;. Little more than a year later, however, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/04/rip-google-wave/"&gt;Wave was no more&lt;/a&gt;. That same year Google launched &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2009/01/05/picasa-for-mac/"&gt;Mac-based photo application Picasa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2010: Google Apps Marketplace&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248272010-Google-Apps-Marketplace"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2010: Google Apps Marketplace" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/16.1_Apps Marketplace 2010.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2010 &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/03/09/google-launches-the-google-apps-marketplace/"&gt;Google launched its Apps Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, an app store that allows third-party developers to sell their creations. That same year &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/02/09/google-buzz-demo-video/"&gt;Google unveiled Google Buzz&lt;/a&gt;, its latest attempt at social sharing that originated in Gmail. The company also &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/05/20/google-tv-3/"&gt;released Google TV&lt;/a&gt; after teaming up with Intel, Sony and Logitech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2011: Google+&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/#248312011-Google"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2011: Google+" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/happy-birthday-google-making-sense-of-the-web-for-13-years/17_GooglePlus2011.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google's most talked-about and participatory social platform thus far, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus/"&gt;Google+ launched in June 2011&lt;/a&gt; with invite-only access. The tech giant also announced its most expensive acquisition to-date when it &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/"&gt;bought Motorola Mobility for $12.5 billion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/media/"&gt;media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/tech/"&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business &amp;amp; Marketing&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business &amp;amp; Marketing on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business &amp;amp; Marketing channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/gZ_fI7vidm0MEcYAK2vDT4qiEqE/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/gZ_fI7vidm0MEcYAK2vDT4qiEqE/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/gZ_fI7vidm0MEcYAK2vDT4qiEqE/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/gZ_fI7vidm0MEcYAK2vDT4qiEqE/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=CXtz7KVpXGs:1qoVeCPjssE:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/CXtz7KVpXGs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud App Delivery Software Maker Graphon Secures $7.1M In Equity Financing</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/graphon.png?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="graphon" title="graphon" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.graphon.com"&gt;GraphOn&lt;/a&gt;, a developer of cloud application delivery solutions, this morning &lt;a href="http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20110902005090/en/GraphOn-Corp.-Announces-Completion-7.1-Million-Equity"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it has secured $7.1 million in equity financing in a private placement to a group of investors, employing intellectual property investment bank MDB Capital Group as its sole agent. GraphOn sold 35.5 million shares of its common stock at $0.20 per share. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;GraphOn also issued five year warrants to the investors for an additional 17.75 million shares of common stock with an exercise price of $0.26 per share, a 30 percent premium to the sale price of the common stock in the transaction. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Founded in 1996, GraphOn Corporation is a publicly traded company headquartered in Santa Cruz, California. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company offers solutions that enable customers to access applications from a multitude of devices from basically anywhere. Its flagship product is GO-Global, a cloud application delivery and Web-enabling solution that helps &lt;a href="http://www.graphon.com/customer-success"&gt;customers&lt;/a&gt; like AT&amp;amp;T, Warner Music Group and Alcatel-Lucent to extend the reach of their Windows, UNIX and Linux applications to a corporate network or the Web.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most recently, GraphOn announced a private label service for its &lt;a href="http://www.graphon.com/products-and-solutions/mobile-clients"&gt;GO-Global iPad Client&lt;/a&gt;, providing software vendors and application service providers with a quick way to create an iPad&lt;br /&gt; app that makes their Windows applications fully accessible to iPad users. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415257/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/V0kP5JV720pfwjZEsNk5Pda9-9E/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/V0kP5JV720pfwjZEsNk5Pda9-9E/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/V0kP5JV720pfwjZEsNk5Pda9-9E/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/V0kP5JV720pfwjZEsNk5Pda9-9E/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yfdHIwV40M4:wBi_E91Q0kg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/yfdHIwV40M4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/cloud-app-delivery-software-maker-graphon-secures-7-1m-in-equity-financing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/cloud-app-delivery-software-maker-graphon-secures-7-1m-in-equity-financing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Objects Vets Raise $6 Million For Business Analytics Software Startup Visier</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/visier.png?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="visier" title="visier" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.visier.com"&gt;Visier&lt;/a&gt;, which builds &amp;#8216;analytic applications for human resources&amp;#8217;, has raised &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/visier"&gt;$6 million&lt;/a&gt; in funding according to an &lt;a href="http://sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1529096/000152909611000001/xslFormDX01/primary_doc.xml"&gt;SEC filing&lt;/a&gt; published this morning. It&amp;#8217;s the startup&amp;#8217;s first institutional venture funding round since its inception in 2010.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Notably, Visier was &lt;a href="http://www.visier.com/visier-blog/why-visier-and-why-now/"&gt;co-founded&lt;/a&gt; by ex-Business Objectives chief and SAP exec &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/john-schwarz"&gt;John Schwarz&lt;/a&gt; (CEO) and &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/ryan-wong"&gt;Ryan Wong&lt;/a&gt; (CTO), who held senior engineering roles at Business Objects and, after their acquisition by SAP, was the VP of Engineering for the SAP Business Objects BI platform and tools. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Furthermore, former SAP SVP &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/dave-weisbeck"&gt;Dave Weisbeck&lt;/a&gt; (CSO) is also part of Visier&amp;#8217;s management team.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Basically, Visier&amp;#8217;s mission is to help companies identify important insights about their business and deliver them to human resources decision makers in an enjoyable way using nifty visualization techniques (see video below to get an idea). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Visier describes it as building &amp;#8216;&lt;a href="http://www.visier.com/visier-blog/what-is-an-analytic-application/"&gt;analytic applications&lt;/a&gt; for people&amp;#8217; on its website.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The business analytics firm invites companies to sign up for a &lt;a href="http://www.visier.com/request-a-demo/"&gt;free demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;span style="text-align:center; display: block;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/business-objects-vets-raise-6-million-for-business-analytics-software-startup-visier/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;div class="module-crunchbase"&gt; &lt;div class="configuration-neighbor"&gt; &lt;h2 class="global-module-header-black"&gt; &lt;span class="line-2"&gt; &lt;div class="cb-home-header cb-stack-home-header"&gt; &lt;a href="http://crunchbase.com"&gt;Crunchbase&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cb-entity-header"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/visier" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;VISIER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel-container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel current"&gt; &lt;div class="leftgreen"&gt; &lt;div class="info-container info-container-stack-view"&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;VISIER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.visier.com" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;http://www.visier.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Launch Date:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;3/2010&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="body-copy"&gt; &lt;p&gt;At Visier we build analytic applications for human resources. Complete, end-to-end solutions are hosted on-demand and deployed in days. Unlike traditional business intelligence which aims to provide powerful tools for...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="profile-image"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/visier"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;a class="learn-more" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/visier" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/415277/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Tx3c8HsCZd_pykbqAoCiR-HrtwA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Tx3c8HsCZd_pykbqAoCiR-HrtwA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Tx3c8HsCZd_pykbqAoCiR-HrtwA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Tx3c8HsCZd_pykbqAoCiR-HrtwA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G8kZNIsYdXI:0OAgj7jms5I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/G8kZNIsYdXI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/business-objects-vets-raise-6-million-for-business-analytics-software-startup-visier/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/business-objects-vets-raise-6-million-for-business-analytics-software-startup-visier/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Clear And Present Danger</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/clearandpresentdanger.jpeg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="clearandpresentdanger" title="clearandpresentdanger" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I often think about how my computing life would be different if I weren&amp;#8217;t a professional blogger. I mean, I have my laptop on me at basically all times just in case I have to duck away and write something at a moment&amp;#8217;s notice (it has happened more than I care to admit). But if I wasn&amp;#8217;t a blogger, what would I use? And more broadly, if I wasn&amp;#8217;t in the neck-deep in the tech sphere that currently controls my life, what would I use?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The answer is simple: an iPad.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ahh! Fanboy alert! Ahhh! Run for the hills! Stop reading! Comment immediately! I know. &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/06/14/fanboy/"&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve been through this&lt;/a&gt;. I would say that you could replace &amp;#8220;iPad&amp;#8221; with &amp;#8220;tablet&amp;#8221;, but the problem is that there aren&amp;#8217;t any other tablets that are worth a damn. So iPad it is.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the thing: at first, &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/01/27/ipad/"&gt;I wasn&amp;#8217;t completely sold&lt;/a&gt; on the iPad as a PC replacement. And for my current line of work, I&amp;#8217;m still not. It&amp;#8217;s simply too hard to type more than a hundred words on the thing. You hear this refrain over and over again in the press. But it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;paradoxical. The press has to write about and review the iPad because that&amp;#8217;s what they do. But they&amp;#8217;re also the worst possible candidates for iPad usage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve slowly come to realize this over time. When I went on vacation a few months ago, I brought both my laptop and my iPad. I promised myself I wouldn&amp;#8217;t do any work during the trip &#8212; as a result, the laptop never came out. Not once. The iPad? I used it every single day, for hours.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s important. The key is that I love computing and the web. Even during my off time, I love it. Yes, disconnect &#8212; blah, blah, blah. &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/02/21/phones-at-dinner/"&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll do what I want&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;But I&amp;#8217;ve been trained over time to think that the traditional PC is the way to do these things whether it&amp;#8217;s for work or play. That&amp;#8217;s simply not true. The tablet form factor is so. much. better. when you don&amp;#8217;t have to do an excessive amount of typing. And during downtime, when I use a computer like a more regular human being, I&amp;#8217;ve found that&amp;#8217;s often.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today. I was boarding a plane. In front of me in the security line was a family of four. Between them, they had four iPads. How do I know? Two were using them in line, and the other two (mom and dad) took them out to be scanned (even though, as it turns out after a brief discussion with security, they didn&amp;#8217;t have to).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;About 20 minutes later, I boarded my plane. Guess what I noticed? In the seats around me, another half dozen or so people using iPads. Yes, there were still more people using laptops on the plane, but not many.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Computing is changing. That&amp;#8217;s just about the most obvious statement ever. We&amp;#8217;ve been seeing this for years with the rise of the smartphones. But&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; computing is changing as well. As in, people are abandoning PCs for these newer devices. And this will keep happening.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m writing this post from the heart of the PC world: Seattle, Washington, about 15 miles west of Redmond &#8212; home of &lt;a href="http://microsoft.com"&gt;you-know-who&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft and I have been at odds for about six years now. I&amp;#8217;ve told this story before; I used to be a diehard Windows guy. Then I jumped to the Mac, and I haven&amp;#8217;t looked back. Now I write &lt;a href="http://parislemon.com/post/9558558373/apples-vision-for-the-future-of-computing-versus"&gt;incendiary things&lt;/a&gt; about Microsoft, while praising Apple. Many readers seem to think I have some ulterior motive in doing this. My motive is simple and&amp;nbsp;straightforward: I now prefer Apple products to Microsoft ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;m one person, I don&amp;#8217;t matter. What should matter to Microsoft is this feeling spreading. &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.time.com/time/business/article/0,8599,2091333,00.html"&gt;The PC Isn&amp;#8217;t Dying &#8212; It&amp;#8217;s Just Evolving&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, writes Harry McCracken for Time tonight. That&amp;#8217;s nice. What an innocuous story. It&amp;#8217;s pussyfooting around what&amp;#8217;s really going on, and I think he knows it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not that the traditional PC is dying &#8212; it will never fully &amp;#8220;die&amp;#8221; in our lifetimes. But it will become something that is primarily a business machine, or a &amp;#8220;truck&amp;#8221; as Steve Jobs puts it. And it will eventually be just a small segment of business computing too. Just look at the business penetration that iPads are getting in this sector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The real issue is that with the decay of the traditional PC market, Microsoft is the big loser. Sure the &amp;#8220;PC&amp;#8221;, meaning the term &amp;#8220;personal computer&amp;#8221;, is evolving, but it&amp;#8217;s evolving to a world beyond Microsoft. The iPad, more than any other computing device, presents a clear and present danger to the Redmond-based juggernaut.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s why we&amp;#8217;re seeing all this action and talk around Windows 8. &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/31/microsofts-compromise-is-to-not-compromise-or-something/"&gt;It will be tablet-friendly but also PC-friendly&lt;/a&gt; &#8212; yadda yadda yadda. Microsoft is in full-on scramble mode. Individuals at the company admit this privately, but the company can never display such weakness publicly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And the truth is that they don&amp;#8217;t need to. If the PC business (again, the one we all think of now) started to rapidly decay tomorrow, Microsoft could still coast for another ten years, no problem. But internally, I do believe they know what is going on and what they need to do. Again, hence, Windows 8.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t agree with &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/30/we-need-an-invert-selection-button/"&gt;the strategy for Windows 8&lt;/a&gt; (at least what I&amp;#8217;ve heard and seen so far). I think bifurcation will only confuse users and push more towards the iPad. But we&amp;#8217;ll see. Metro looks good, there&amp;#8217;s no denying that. I just wish Microsoft had the balls to go all-in on Metro.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, we&amp;#8217;re getting a lot of nonsense about how the PC isn&amp;#8217;t dead, it&amp;#8217;s just &amp;#8220;evolving&amp;#8221;. I&amp;#8217;m now certain that Microsoft&amp;#8217;s message when they do unveil Windows 8 will be how &amp;#8220;everything is a PC&amp;#8221;. Desktops, laptops, cellphones. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/fxshaw/status/108027320849285120"&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not about the hardware&lt;/a&gt;. Hogwash.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s problem is that the public isn&amp;#8217;t stupid. They&amp;#8217;re not going to start buying Windows 8 tablets because they&amp;#8217;re just like the PCs you know and love. In fact, if anything, people &lt;em&gt;won&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt; buy them for that very reason. Microsoft thinks people love their PCs. They don&amp;#8217;t. They&amp;#8217;ve been chained to them for years. They want to be set free. The iPad allows for that. Tying Windows to their don&amp;#8217;t-call-it-post-pc strategy is dangerous for Microsoft. Disdain is starting to outweigh comfort. Further, there are no more &lt;em&gt;windows&lt;/em&gt; in this world for chrissakes!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/18/apple-wins-without-throwing-a-punch/"&gt;I fully agree with the notion&lt;/a&gt; that HP CEO Leo Apotheker is leaving the PC business because of his roots in enterprise software. But I also believe that if the HP PC business was that great, there is no way he would ever be allowed to float the idea of selling or spinning it off. Things are looking too hot for the number two PC maker, Acer, either.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bluntly: the PC business is a shitty business to be in right now. And as McCracken correctly points out, it has been for a while. The difference is that now there&amp;#8217;s a real alternative: the iPad. And the alternatives from other players are going to keep coming in rapid-fire. Even if one of the Android tablets doesn&amp;#8217;t take off anytime soon, I bet one of the ones &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/17/google-versus-amazon-android/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;based&lt;/em&gt; on Android will&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But the scariest notion for Microsoft has to be that the iPad is still nascent. It will continue to get better &#8212; and fast. Certainly a hell of a lot faster than the PC will. Sorry, I mean the Windows 8 consumer electronics series device for portables homes edition&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&#174;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m writing this on my laptop (a MacBook Air), but I really just want to be browsing the web on my iPad right now. So I&amp;#8217;m ending this post to go do that. Within the next five years, I bet most of you reading this will also have this desire &#8212; even if you think you won&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t be fooled into thinking that just because a tablet can&amp;#8217;t do something right now, it never will. It will. And fast. And Microsoft knows this. That&amp;#8217;s why it&amp;#8217;s a clear and &lt;em&gt;present&lt;/em&gt; danger. Not just a future one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;div class="module-crunchbase"&gt; &lt;div class="configuration-neighbor"&gt; &lt;h2 class="global-module-header-black"&gt; &lt;span class="line-1"&gt; &lt;div class="cb-home-header cb-stack-home-header"&gt; &lt;a href="http://crunchbase.com"&gt;Crunchbase&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cb-entity-header"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/microsoft" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;MICROSOFT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel-container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel current"&gt; &lt;div class="leftgreen"&gt; &lt;div class="info-container info-container-stack-view"&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;MICROSOFT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;http://www.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Launch Date:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;4/4/1974&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;IPO:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt; 13/3/1986, NASDAQ:MSFT &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="body-copy"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Microsoft, founded in 1975 by Bill Gates and Paul Allen, is a veteran software company, best known for its Microsoft Windows operating system and the Microsoft Office suite of...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="profile-image"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/microsoft"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;a class="learn-more" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/microsoft" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;div class="module-crunchbase"&gt; &lt;div class="configuration-neighbor"&gt; &lt;h2 class="global-module-header-black"&gt; &lt;span class="line-2"&gt; &lt;div class="cb-home-header cb-stack-home-header"&gt; &lt;a href="http://crunchbase.com"&gt;Crunchbase&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cb-entity-header"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/product/ipad" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;IPAD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel-container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel current"&gt; &lt;div class="leftgreen"&gt; &lt;div class="info-container info-container-stack-view"&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Product:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;IPAD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipad/" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;http://www.apple.com/ipad/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/apple" onclick="&lt;?php tc_set_omniture_attr("post_widget_crunchbase") ?&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="body-copy"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Apple iPad, formerly referred to as the Apple Tablet, is a touch-pad tablet computer announced in January 2010, and released in April 2010. It has internet...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="profile-image"&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;a class="learn-more" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/product/ipad" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/414451/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/nvAfK9Ne5nd9GN_Nj_iPLBILpvY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/nvAfK9Ne5nd9GN_Nj_iPLBILpvY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/nvAfK9Ne5nd9GN_Nj_iPLBILpvY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/nvAfK9Ne5nd9GN_Nj_iPLBILpvY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Y1zwAjuJU18:_ukxkQLqZTw:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Y1zwAjuJU18" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/post-pc-has-nothing-to-do-with-windows/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/02/post-pc-has-nothing-to-do-with-windows/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Workspace Is Best For Your Startup?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/&amp;title=What Kind of Workspace Is Best For Your Startup?&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/coworking-hive-360.jpg" alt="" title="coworking hive 360" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-703547" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/what-kind-of-workspace-is-best-for-your-startup" target="_blank"&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; originally appeared on the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/" target="_blank"&gt;American Express OPEN Forum&lt;/a&gt;, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Startup life is all about bootstrapping, but you need a place to work, right? Here&amp;#8217;s a breakdown of three workplace styles &amp;#8212; home-working, coworking and traditional office space &amp;#8212; with pros, cons and input from startups utilzing each environment so you can figure which the right choice is for you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Working From Home&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/work-from-home.jpg" alt="" title="work from home" width="640" height="501" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-707005" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Why work from home: For those just starting out for those who are one-man bands, it makes the most sense to work from home. &amp;#8220;There&amp;#8217;s simply no budget for [an office], as I bootstrap the company,&amp;#8221; says Paul Molluzzo, founder of &lt;a href="http://www.babygoesmobile.com" target="_blank"&gt;Baby Goes Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, a web app that lets parents create a private baby book they can view and update from their mobile phones. &amp;#8220;I have the space and tools &amp;#8212; computer, cell phone and coffee machine &amp;#8212; to get my work done, so paying for a space didn&amp;#8217;t make sense.&amp;#8221; Plus, digital tools like email, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/skype"&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt;, screenshares, smartphones and &lt;a href="http://FreeConferenceCall.com" target="_blank"&gt;FreeConferenceCall.com&lt;/a&gt; mean you can do work anytime, anywhere and communicate with just about anyone, so it&amp;#8217;s not a must to splurge on an office. There&amp;#8217;s also the perk of being able to take work breaks and spend time with his wife and son, says Molluzzo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Greg Golkin, co-founder of the in-the-works social learning platform ThinkBinder, takes working from home to a new level &amp;#8212; he &lt;em&gt;lives&lt;/em&gt; with his coworker, Dave Lee. For them, &amp;#8220;working from home is the most efficient situation for us to build our product &amp;#8212; we can be machines over here,&amp;#8221; says Golkin, explaining that the two simply &amp;#8220;work, eat, sleep and gym, all with a constant &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/spotify"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; soundtrack.&amp;#8221; The partners actually welcome the lack of separation between work and personal life &amp;#8212; &amp;#8220;if we are home and not working, we do not feel comfortable, and that is great.&amp;#8221; Plus, for nocturnal types who work late, it&amp;#8217;s pretty convenient to be a few steps from your bed at 4 a.m. instead of having to travel home.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And let&amp;#8217;s not forget that working from home means you don&amp;#8217;t have to pay for office space. David Rostan, cofounder of communications startup &lt;a href="http://twitgram.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Umagram&lt;/a&gt;, says that his decision to work from home (his cofounder works from his own home, so they&amp;#8217;re remote) was financial, but &amp;#8220;less in the &amp;#8216;we can&amp;#8217;t afford it&amp;#8217; sense and more in the &amp;#8216;if we saved that money, we could spend it on something way more important&amp;#8217; way.&amp;#8221; As his company grows, he likes the option of hiring flexibly and being able to consider job candidates from other cities and countries. He and his cofounder John meet a few times a week at a coffee shop to touch base and update one another on their respective worlds and solve problems in real-time, which helps to keep them efficient. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#8217;s not all rainbows and sunshine. As expected, it can be hard to maintain a work-life balance when your living room doubles as your corporate headquarters. &amp;#8220;When your baby son and your developer are vying for your attention, it&amp;#8217;s challenging to work the two out,&amp;#8221; says Molluzzo, admitting that to-dos sometimes get lost in the shuffle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another downside, not surprisingly, is that working from home can be lonely. In an office, there&amp;#8217;s camaraderie and water cooler chit-chat. &amp;#8220;Had I taken a spot at [a coworking space], I&amp;#8217;d have people to go to lunch with to chat about startups and tech, which would have been nice,&amp;#8221; says Molluzzo. &amp;#8220;But that seems more of a luxury than a necessity.&amp;#8221; Rostan agrees &amp;#8212; he thinks coworking spaces can be great for networking, but he says he spends so much time on the phone that he probably wouldn&amp;#8217;t get to network that much. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, a home office can only get you so far &amp;#8212; most homes have a capacity at which things just get chaotic and awkward. &amp;#8220;We&amp;#8217;ve maxed out our capacity, and we&amp;#8217;re beginning to recruit more developers &amp;#8212; it would be quite odd to ask them to sit on the couch to work,&amp;#8221; says Golkin. Once they solidify the next hire, the ThinkBinder team will be moving to their own offices.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you work from home but are finding that your digs aren&amp;#8217;t cutting it for business meetings and interviews, you can always hit up a local coffee shop, but be sure to follow &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/13/coffee-shop-etiquette/"&gt;coffee shop etiquette&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Coworking Space&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/coloft1.jpg" alt="" title="coloft" width="640" height="478" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-703585" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces, like &lt;a href="http://generalassemb.ly" target="_blank"&gt;General Assembly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://coloft.com" target="_blank"&gt;Coloft&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://dogpatchlabs.com" target="_blank"&gt;Dogpatch Labs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://hiveat55.com/" target="_blanK"&gt;Hive at 55&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://coworkchicago.com/" target="_blank"&gt;COOP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.cohabitat.us" target="_blank"&gt;CoHabitat&lt;/a&gt;, are used for office space by many startups.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For a small business with two to three people, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/11/15/signs-coworking-is-for-you/"&gt;coworking is a great option&lt;/a&gt;. The cost is much lower than traditional office space, and you have access to a lot of resources &amp;#8212; conference room, printers, scanners, Wi-Fi, snacks, coffees &amp;#8212; that you&amp;#8217;d otherwise have to pay for all by yourself. And don&amp;#8217;t forget the other coworkers who could become potential partners or clients down the road.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dylan Goelz of &lt;a href="http://roadify.com" target="_blank"&gt;Roadify&lt;/a&gt; works out of Hive at 55 and says he finds the coworking environment to be &amp;#8220;a big plus.&amp;#8221; He says his team&amp;#8217;s focus has benefited from having other work-minded people around, and they&amp;#8217;ve even worked with a design team a few seats away. &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ve learned more about other types and styles of business just by walking to lunch with fellow coworkers than I would have anywhere else,&amp;#8221; says Goelz, adding that the occasional inconvenience (not finding a seat) or distraction (laughter or loud conversations in the room) is &amp;#8220;outweighed by efficiency, cost-effectiveness and camaraderie.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of Goelz&amp;#8217;s fellow coworkers, Michelle Weiss, does systems implementation consulting online at the Hive, and though she admits she could do it from home, she comes to the shared office space because of the people. &amp;#8220;Everyone there is working towards something, and it&amp;#8217;s stimulating to be in that environment,&amp;#8221; she says. So Weiss pays $150 a month to have access to the Hive two days per week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Brian DiFeo, the Hive&amp;#8217;s community manager, says the trend is to be professional but have a sense of humor and be ready for the inevitable group laugh or room-wide joke. Whether that&amp;#8217;s a funny ringtone or an impromptu blast of Rebecca Black&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Friday,&amp;#8221; coworking can be a great way to network, make friends and have a built-in advisory board of people from many different industries. Plus, a lot of coworking spaces offer classes and seminars on new technology and tools. And of course, all of this comes without the burden and risk of finding and paying for your own office space.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Traditional Office Space&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/office-buildout.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/office-buildout.jpg" alt="" title="Office space buildout" width="640" height="305" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-707055" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once your startup has grown to 10 or so people, it might be time to &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/30/how-to-choose-office/"&gt;get your own office space&lt;/a&gt;. And that&amp;#8217;s a good thing, because growing is good, but getting your own office space is not without potential pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://zozi.com" target="_blank"&gt;Zozi&lt;/a&gt;, which sells unique experiences and activities, is headquartered in San Francisco&amp;#8217;s Financial District and has its own pad. The startup launched in CEO and founder TJ Sassani&amp;#8217;s house in Byron Bay, Australia, and then became a coffee-shop-based company when he moved to the U.S. Soon they had grown into a shared space in San Francisco, and finally zozi got its own office space in August 2008. (There&amp;#8217;s also a small New York team that works out of a coworking space.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Having their own office space really enables the various departments to communicate and work together to improve zozi and the customer experience. &amp;#8220;We are one team, and the energy is felt by everyone in the office &amp;#8212; that&amp;#8217;s the gas we run on everyday,&amp;#8221; says Sassani, who describes their office space as an open, collaborative and creative space, in which &amp;#8220;everyone can tangibly interact with zozi&amp;#8217;s vision everyday.&amp;#8221; Also adding that energy are trek road cycles stashed throughout the office and inflatable sharks &amp;#8212; things that might not fly (or float) in a shared-office space &amp;#8230; and probably wouldn&amp;#8217;t fit in an apartment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Zozi&amp;#8217;s growth is admirable and enviable, but startups should realize that getting your own office space is a big commitment. Real estate agent David Goldberg of &lt;a href="http://livingny.com" target="_blank"&gt;Living NY&lt;/a&gt; offers some guidelines and wisdom. First, find an area that matches your companies needs &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; budget. In Manhattan&amp;#8217;s Silicon Alley, for example, commercial office space varies in price from block to block &amp;#8212; highly desirable offices near Union Square and the Flatiron District can be $35 to $50 per square foot, and it&amp;#8217;s estimated that there should be about 100 square feet per person. Goldberg says the challenge with getting office space for a startup is that quality small office spaces (less than 3,500 square feet) are in high demand, and there&amp;#8217;s a very low supply. Most startups anticipate growth, so your first small office likely will not sustain much growth. However, many landlords won&#8217;t consider a lease that is shorter than three years, because the expenses both for landlord and tenant &amp;#8212; lawyer fees, office build-out, vacancies and moving fees &amp;#8212; add up. (Hence, the coworking trend.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you do find a space that fits your needs, you&amp;#8217;ll likely need bank statements, the first three pages of the past two year&#8217;s tax returns, and profit-and-loss statements &amp;#8212; of course, if you&amp;#8217;re just starting out, you might not have much of this paperwork, so you&amp;#8217;ll need to explain to the landlord what your startup is all about so they feel comfortable renting space to a fledgling business. Then there&amp;#8217;s the security deposit, moving fees, good-guy clause, personal guarantee and insurance &amp;#8212; yeah, it can be a costly endeavor. Fortunately, most buildings these days are set up for Internet, phones and other business infrastructure, so you don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about installing those modern amenities. Landlords will also often agree to build-out of a conference room or private offices if your offer is strong enough, Goldberg says. Otherwise, you can do the build-out and eat the costs. Be careful not to ask for too much work, however, which can make the landlord more hesitant to lower the rent in negotiations. One rule of thumb is that the longer the lease is, the more work the landlord will be willing to do.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before you sign on the dotted line and start renovating, make sure that you&amp;#8217;re truly ready for an office of your own. &amp;#8220;The timing really should be right before you decide to move into a space and call it your own,&amp;#8221; says Sassani.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What kind of working environment does your startup call home? Let us know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h3&gt;More Small Business Resources From OPEN Forum:&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/15-keyboard-shortcuts-to-enhance-your-pc-productivity" target="_blank"&gt;15 Keyboard Shortcuts To Enhance Your PC Productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/5-services-for-building-websites-on-a-budget" target="_blank"&gt;5 Services For Building Websites On A Budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/10-accessories-to-boost-office-morale" target="_blank"&gt;10 Accessories To Boost Office Morale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/top-5-foursquare-mistakes-committed-by-small-businesses" target="_blank"&gt;Top 5 Foursquare Mistakes Committed By Small Businesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/how-to-use-social-media-for-recruiting" target="_blank"&gt;How To Use Social Media For Recruiting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Image via Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dwonderwall/" target="_blank"&gt;David Wall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/coworking/"&gt;coworking&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/home-office/"&gt;Home office&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/office-space/"&gt;office space&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/startup/"&gt;startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/startups/"&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/MashStartups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Startups on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Startups channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/yCK9lSJbp-Y6GODX7I3MDtO4iT8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/yCK9lSJbp-Y6GODX7I3MDtO4iT8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/yCK9lSJbp-Y6GODX7I3MDtO4iT8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/yCK9lSJbp-Y6GODX7I3MDtO4iT8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=d0C6-E-fUw8:uOieQPcFymg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/d0C6-E-fUw8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/20/startup-workspace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Android Apps to Turn Your Phone Into a Mobile Document Scanner</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/&amp;title=5 Android Apps to Turn Your Phone Into a Mobile Document Scanner&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/android-document-scan-apps-360.jpg" class="alignright" title="Android Scanning Apps" width="275" height=""&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/5-android-apps-to-turn-your-phone-into-a-mobile-document-scanner" target="_blank"&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; originally appeared on the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/" target="_blank"&gt;American Express OPEN Forum&lt;/a&gt;, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;#8217;ve done everything you can to &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/05/01/small-business-paperless/"&gt;banish paper&lt;/a&gt; from your office, those little white sheets can still creep up on you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll want to digitize those crinkly analog fugitives post haste, but you may not be keen on splurging for a scanner &amp;#8212; especially when you&amp;#8217;re only taming the occasional receipt or intake form.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The solution &amp;#8212; wait for it &amp;#8212; could be in the &lt;em&gt;palm of your hand.&lt;/em&gt; Your &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/android"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; smartphone has all the photographic and processing power you&amp;#8217;ll need to snap up those docs and get them into the cloud where they belong.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are a few mobile document scanning solutions we put through their paces.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.intsig.camscanner" target="_blank"&gt;CamScanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/#240351-CamScanner"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://market.android.com/details?id=com.intsig.camscanner&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;CamScanner&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/android-scan/01-CamScanner.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CamScanner is a breeze to use, and you can test out the free version via the Market link above. Snap a photo of your document and pull up the cropping tool. The app will auto-detect the edges of the paper, but the slick drag-and-snap guides will help you fine tune the dimensions. &lt;p&gt;The processing enhancements are smart, and will compensate for low light and bad focus reasonably well. Though the app generates a cropped and toned image, it will also hang onto the original photo -- handy, in case you accidentally cropped your boss' name off the letterhead. &lt;p&gt;The app has built-in integration with Google Docs, Box.net and Dropbox, but for the less fancy among you, it's easy to pipe scanned docs straight into email. &lt;p&gt;The main issue we encountered was with PDF creation. The original image is stored as a JPEG, but the option to convert it to a PDF simply opened the phone's default PDF viewer. The file is viewable, but we found no apparent way to save or share.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.intsig.lic.camscanner" target="_blank"&gt;paid version&lt;/a&gt; promises to make things easier in this department, but you should see how the free version performs on your device before purchasing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; Free / $4.99 for full license and features&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.pwnwithyourphone.documentscanner.trial" target="_blank"&gt;Document Scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/#240372-Document-Scanner"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://market.android.com/details?id=com.pwnwithyourphone.documentscanner.trial&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Document Scanner&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/android-scan/02-Document-Scanner.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This app scans directly to PDF with ease. The interface couldn't be cleaner, and while the cropping tools aren't as snazzy as CamScanner's, they get the job done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are image enhancement features, but in our testing, they weren't as precise as CamScanner's.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Document Scanner also lets you upload directly to Google Docs, DropBox, and Box.net. It even has Evernote integration -- a nice touch. Scan multiple pages in succession and email them to your heart's content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The trial version will only last you seven days, but that should give you the time to decide if you're ready to throw down four bucks on the &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.pwnwithyourphone.documentscanner" target="_blank"&gt;real deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; Free / $3.98 for full version&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;3. &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.trans_code.android.droidscan" target="_blank"&gt;Droid Scan Pro PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/#240393-Droid-Scan-Pro-PDF"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="3. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://market.android.com/details?id=com.trans_code.android.droidscan&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Droid Scan Pro PDF&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/android-scan/03-droid-scan.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Droid Scan works similarly to the aforementioned apps with one exception -- it'll send you out to the system camera to grab the image. No big deal -- in reality, the other apps are simply wrapping the native camera with their interface.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you're done shooting, Droid Scan picks right back up where you left off and gets down to image processing quickly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The app has smart edge detection, intuitive (if small) color and contrast controls, and a final menu that lets you select the docs you want to save down as either JPEGs or PDFs (though PDF functionality is only available in the paid version).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.trans_code.android.droidscanlite" target="_blank"&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt; / $4.99 for PDF functionality&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;4. &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.scan.to.pdf.trial" target="_blank"&gt;Scan to PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/#240414-Scan-to-PDF"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="4. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://market.android.com/details?id=com.scan.to.pdf.trial&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Scan to PDF&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/android-scan/04-Scan-to-PDF.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scan to PDF scores big on interface simplicity. It's easy to start scanning or adjust the settings right from the first screen.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The app jumps over to the system camera by default (though you can adjust this setting), and offers great image processing and enhancement, even in low light.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The cropping function is intuitive but can be awkward -- rather than dragging and snapping at the corners, you'll have to pull the edges. Occasionally, your fingers will run out of screen or they'll accidentally drag the entire frame away from the edge. However, This quirk is far from a deal breaker, and the excellent gallery viewer more than makes up for it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The free version of Scan to PDF does it all, but if you like it and use it regularly, you can show the devs a little love with a &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.scan.to.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;$.99 upgrade&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; Free / $.99 optional purchase for a job well done&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;5. &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.melonmobile.android.pdfscanner" target="_blank"&gt;PDF Scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/#240435-PDF-Scanner"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="5. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://market.android.com/details?id=com.melonmobile.android.pdfscanner&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;PDF Scanner&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/android-scan/05-pdf-scanner.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those looking for the dead-simple option, PDF Scanner is the way to go. This no-frills app cuts right to the quick.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add pages by hitting scan. The camera viewfinder that appears has no buttons, so you'll have to just tap the screen to focus and snap.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The camera makes use of your phone's flash, which is helpful when scanning in low light. But be sure to frame and focus your image carefully because there's no crop or image enhancement here. Snap away until your document is complete, then email the PDF to its destination.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Regrettably, there's not trial version of this app, but if you're looking for a way to generate PDF scans quickly and easily, have no qualms dropping your coin here. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $1.99&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h3&gt;More Small Business Resources From OPEN Forum:&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/15-keyboard-shortcuts-to-enhance-your-pc-productivity" target="_blank"&gt;15 Keyboard Shortcuts To Enhance Your PC Productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/5-services-for-building-websites-on-a-budget" target="_blank"&gt;5 Services For Building Websites On A Budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/10-accessories-to-boost-office-morale" target="_blank"&gt;10 Accessories To Boost Office Morale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/top-5-foursquare-mistakes-committed-by-small-businesses" target="_blank"&gt;Top 5 Foursquare Mistakes Committed By Small Businesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/how-to-use-social-media-for-recruiting" target="_blank"&gt;How To Use Social Media For Recruiting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/android/"&gt;android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile/"&gt;Mobile 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Mobile on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.mobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/mobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Mobile channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/U4lgDKk5F9w3YyedTbewwrarD7c/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/U4lgDKk5F9w3YyedTbewwrarD7c/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/U4lgDKk5F9w3YyedTbewwrarD7c/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/U4lgDKk5F9w3YyedTbewwrarD7c/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iPVGFEMCME4:e6aIbpbenrc:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/iPVGFEMCME4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/09/03/android-apps-document-scanner-pdf/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Great Google Accessories Offer Eclectic Mix of Coolness</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To mark the 13th anniversary of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-happy-birthday-13-years/"&gt;Google&amp;#8217;s inception&lt;/a&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ve pulled together our top 10 G-themed accessories from all around the web. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From lighting to clothing via art, we think these fantastic bits and bobs are perfect for fans of the Mountain View-based business behemoth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/06/27/android-accessories/"&gt;15 Awesome Android Accessories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take a look though the photo gallery for some fun items made, or inspired by, the world&amp;#8217;s largest search engine. Let us know in the comments which ones &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; like.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/76196618/google-maps-wall-decal-sticker" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Maps Wall Decal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#246891-Google-Maps-Wall-Decal"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/&amp;title=10 Great Google Accessories Offer Eclectic Mix of Coolness&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.etsy.com/listing/76196618/google-maps-wall-decal-sticker&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Maps Wall Decal&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/maps.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit of a statement for your own home, we think this would look great in an office reception area.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $23.99&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2. &lt;a href="http://www.googlestore.com/Accessories/20+oz+Motion+Lamp.axd" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Motion Lamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#246992-Google-Motion-Lamp"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.googlestore.com/Accessories/20+oz+Motion+Lamp.axd&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Motion Lamp&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/lamps.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As featured on Google staffers' desks, these G-themed lava lamps are colorful and fun.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $19.35&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;3. &lt;a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/65187767/google-pillow-2010" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Pillow 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#246913-Google-Pillow-2010"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="3. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.etsy.com/listing/65187767/google-pillow-2010&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Pillow 2010&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/pillow.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This talking-point cushion gives you a list of the top Google searches of 2010. The Etsy shop offers versions all the way back to 2006, so you could collect the set.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $69&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;4. &lt;a href="http://www.artfire.com/ext/shop/product_view/1937694" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google MacBook Decal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#247054-Google-MacBook-Decal"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="4. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.artfire.com/ext/shop/product_view/1937694&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google MacBook Decal&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/google.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make your own Google Doodle on the lid of your Mac with this cool decal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $7.99&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;5. &lt;a href="http://www.google-store.com/product_info.php?products_id=1420" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Stress Bricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#247075-Google-Stress-Bricks"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="5. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.google-store.com/product_info.php?products_id=1420&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Stress Bricks&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/bricks.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take your stress out on these LEGO-like squishy bricks. A set of four boasts the Google colors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; &#163;4.69 (approx $7.60)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;6. &lt;a href="http://www.googlestore.com/Accessories/Chalk+It+Up+Ceramic+Mug.axd" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Chalk It Up Mug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#246956-Google-Chalk-It-Up-Mug"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="6. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.googlestore.com/Accessories/Chalk+It+Up+Ceramic+Mug.axd&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Chalk It Up Mug&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/mug.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We're fans of this mug that you can write, draw or doodle on with chalk -- two pieces of which are included.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $9.10&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;7. &lt;a href="http://www.googlestore.com/Accessories/Google+Neon+Light.axd" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Neon Light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#246977-Google-Neon-Light"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="7. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.googlestore.com/Accessories/Google+Neon+Light.axd&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Neon Light&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/neon.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This neon Google light would be a funky way to brighten up a dark corner of your office.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $26.85&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;8. &lt;a href="http://www.googlestore.com/Doodles/Pack+of+7+Individual+Sesame+Doodle+Stickers.axd" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Sesame Street Google Doodle Stickers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#247018-Sesame-Street-Google-Doodle-Stickers"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="8. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.googlestore.com/Doodles/Pack+of+7+Individual+Sesame+Doodle+Stickers.axd&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Sesame Street Google Doodle Stickers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/sesame.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only problem we can see with this set of Sesame Street Doodle stickers is deciding where to put them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $3.45&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;9. &lt;a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/79045631/google-plus-propaganda-poster-version-1" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google+ Propaganda Poster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#246939-Google-Propaganda-Poster"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="9. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.etsy.com/listing/79045631/google-plus-propaganda-poster-version-1&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google+ Propaganda Poster&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/prop.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the style of Soviet propaganda posters, this print would look striking on your office wall. There are versions for other social networks available on Etsy, so you could create a terrific display.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $8&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;10. &lt;a href="http://brassmonki.wazala.com/" TARGET="_blank"&gt;Google Sneakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/#2470310-Google-Sneakers"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="10. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://brassmonki.wazala.com/&amp;quot; TARGET=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Google Sneakers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-accessories/gooshoe.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the truly hardcore fan, Brass Monki offers Google-themed footwear. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; &#163;180 (approx $290)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/accessories/"&gt;accessories&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/gallery/"&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/geek/"&gt;geek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/lists/"&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZkJ_LLOIT39T-4iUjTDkp6AhDZY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZkJ_LLOIT39T-4iUjTDkp6AhDZY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZkJ_LLOIT39T-4iUjTDkp6AhDZY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZkJ_LLOIT39T-4iUjTDkp6AhDZY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1rjyImiWGp8:XcyPTk8nVMs:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/1rjyImiWGp8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/09/04/google-accessories/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
