<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Glass: One day... - YouTube</title>
      <description>We believe technology should work for you &#8212; to be there when you need it and get out of your way when you don't. A team within our Google[x] group started Pr...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Begins Testing Its Augmented Reality Glasses</title>
      <description>On Wednesday, Google gave people 20/20 vision about a secret augmented-reality project called Project Glass. The glasses are the company's first foray into wearable computing.</description>
      <link>http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/04/04/google-begins-testing-its-augmented-reality-glasses/</link>
      <guid>http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/04/04/google-begins-testing-its-augmented-reality-glasses/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rumor: YouTube Rentals Coming to Google TV Soon</title>
      <description>YouTube is working hard to transition for an amateur video sharing site into a full-blown TV network and first-run movie-consumption destination. It&#8217;s creating its own TV shows and has made big deals, including one this morning with Paramount, for scads of tasty filmic content. But there is one big problem. You can rent YouTube movies in the one place you most want to: your big-screen TV. Obviously, you could hook up your PC to your TV, but the quality and dependability (DRM could block the film from playing over your HDMI connection completely) could be suspect. Wouldn&#8217;t it make far more sense to rent digital movies directly through YouTube parent Google&#8217;s own living room product, the Web content/broadcast TV hybridGoogle TV? Yes it would. Now rumor has it that Google TV will soon support direct YouTube movie rentals. There&#8217;s no timing, official announcement or statement from Google, but sources are telling Mashable this is a possibility. The use of the word &#8220;soon&#8221; is enough to give credence to the possibility that Google and YouTube might finally crack this all-important nut. The reality is that, right now, for all the content YouTube is collecting, it simply is not on a level playing field with Apple and Apple TV, Netflix and Amazon&#8217;s Prime. These services are on set-top boxes (Apple has its own) that plug directly into your HDTV. No concerns about whether or not DRM rights will prevent movie playback. The experience for renting a movie on any of them is seamless. If YouTube does go this route, though, it&#8217;s hard to imagine that it will even be able to introduce a subscription service alongside the premium movie rentals. YouTube&#8217;s legacy is free, bite-sized content supported mostly by ad overlays, no one will want to pay for content that was originally free on, say, broadcast television on YouTube &#8211; unless, of course YouTube offers an ad-free network. Then viewers might pay a monthly fee for the privilege. YouTube has another problem, though. It needs more people to buy Google TV. Logitech walked away from the first Google TV after dumping millions into the program. However, at CES, a bunch of new manufacturers lined up with brand new Google TV hardware, so the future could be bright for YouTube Rentals. On the other hand, Google still has a lot of work to do on Google TV. The Sony Google TVs we have in Mashable&#8217;s office feature a compact, yet often inscrutable remote. I could go into all the myriad issues, but suffice to say that it often switches &#8220;enter&#8221; back and forth between two physical controls. As most know, regular YouTube is, in addition to being on Google TV, already on set-top boxes like the Roku2, but it&#8217;s unclear if these partners will ever get YouTube Movie rentals or if Google wants to save that all for itself. For now, YouTube is still a great platform for finding the best one-minute viral videos. Getting consumers to see it as more, no matter how many content partners and original programing YouTube adds could be a challenge, unless and until YouTube Movies finally arrive on Google TV. Do you own a Google TV? Would the addition of YouTube Movie rentals change how you feel about it? Would you buy a Google TV just to have this feature? Tell us in the comments. More About: Apple TV, Google, google tv, logitech, Movies, netflix, sony, YouTubeFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/rumor-youtube-rentals-coming-to-google-tv-soon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/rumor-youtube-rentals-coming-to-google-tv-soon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>500 Paramount Films Coming to YouTube</title>
      <description>You&#8217;ll soon be able to rent nearly 500 Paramount Pictures films via YouTube and Google Play, thanks to a newly signed licensing agreement between the two companies. Many of those films, including The Godfather trilogy, Ferris Bueller&#8217;s Day Off and Hugo, are now available to Internet users in the U.S. and Canada. Others will be rolled out over the next few months, says Google. Forty-eight hour rentals cost between $2.99 and $3.99 for the standard-definition version, and a dollar more for the HD (720p) edition. You have 30 days from the time of purchase to begin watching a movie, and 48 hours from the time you begin to finish watching it. Viacom-owned Paramount was one of the last big &#8220;gets&#8221; for the tech giant&#8217;s movie rental service: five of the six major film studios, along with ten independent studios, have now agreed to rent films through YouTube and Google Play, bringing the total rental catalog to 9,000. The last holdout? 20th Century Fox, which is owned by News Corp. All six studios &#8212; Paramount, Disney, Sony, Warner Bros., Comcast Universal and 20th Century Fox &#8212; sell films through Apple&#8217;s iTunes service. There&#8217;s still no word about whether Google will begin selling as well as renting films, as Apple does. Rumors indicate that studios are pressuring Google to begin selling films to help make up for declines in DVD sales. More About: Google, Google Play, Paramount, paramount pictures, viacom, YouTubeFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/paramount-youtube-rentals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/paramount-youtube-rentals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When execution gets cheaper, so should planning</title>
      <description>If you're going to build a $10 million skyscraper, by all means, plan and prototype and discuss and plan some more. On the other hand, if the cost of finding out is a phone call, make the call. No need to spend a lot of time planning how to call or when to call or which phone to use when execution is fast and cheap. The digital revolution has, as in so many other areas, flipped the equation here. The cost of building digital items is plummeting, but our habit is to plan anyway (because failure bothers us, and we focus on the feeling of failure, not the cost). The goal should be to have the minimum number of meetings and scenarios and documentation necessary to maximize the value of execution. As it gets faster and easier to actually build the thing, go ahead and make sure the planning (or lack of it) keeps pace.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/04/when-execution-gets-cheaper-so-should-planning.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/04/when-execution-gets-cheaper-so-should-planning.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fisker Atlantic Luxury Hybrid Sedan Revealed</title>
      <description>Fisker has unveiled a new electric hybrid car at the New York Auto Show, the Fisker Atlantic luxury sedan. Unlike Fisker&#8217;s all-electric supercar, the Fisker Karma, the Atlantic is a far more conventional affair, though the details are still very scarce. It&#8217;ll sport Fisker&#8217;s second-generation EVer (Electric Vehicle with extended range) powertrain, which includes a four-cylinder gasoline engine. We don&#8217;t know the exact range on electric power alone, but Fisker claims the EVer technology is designed to reduce the &#8220;range anxiety&#8221; that comes with an all-electric powertrain. The design of the prototype exposed at the New York Auto Show, which Fisker calls &#8220;dramatic,&#8221; should be very close to what the production version of the car looks. Price and date of availability are also unknowns at this point, but Autoblog has heard the car will be priced similarly to an Audi A5 or an upper-end BMW 3. The most important takeaway from this unveiling is Fisker&#8217;s firm commitment to actually bringing the car to the market. Fisker Karma has been receiving a lot of bad press recently: The first 239 units got recalled in December 2011, and a later unit broke down during a Consumer Report test. Fisker would do well to bring a more reliable car to the market as soon as possible. Fisker Atlantic Fisker AtlanticClick here to view this gallery. More About: car, Fisker, Fisker Atlantic, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/fisker-electric/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/fisker-electric/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeremy Lin Holds Post-Surgery Facebook Chat, Throws Up in the Middle of It</title>
      <description>&#8220;just woke up. lets do this Q&amp;A before i get on my video games lol&#8221; That&#8217;s how famed basketball star Jeremy Lin began his online Facebook Q&amp;A just hours after undergoing knee surgery. As of this writing, nearly 50,000 people had liked the status update. An MRI last Monday revealed the New York Knicks point guard, who catapulted into sports superstardom this past February, had a &#8220;chronic, small meniscus tear&#8221; on his left knee. Though Lin waited several days before surgery in hopes that he would still be able to play with the tear, he eventually went under the knife. Not only did numerous media outlets announce the surgery&#8217;s success early Tuesday, but Lin himself took to Facebook and proclaimed his road to recovery with this post-surgery photo: Photo courtesy of Jeremy Lin&#8217;s Facebook page The numbers and demographics of the Facebook chat are pretty astounding. According to The Wall Street Journal, 90% of participants were Asian and 50% were evangelical Christian. The average age of the chatters was 15, with males and females equally represented. And the thousands of participants asked more than 8,000 questions &#8212; a rate of about two per second. Lin answered a range of questions including his biggest pet peeves, the video games he plays, how he stays humble and plans for rehabilitation. With the sheer volume of participants and the rate of participation, the session turned out to be a &#8220;tremendously disorienting experience,&#8221; according to The Wall Street Journal. And it wasn&#8217;t just that way for the viewers. Lin, still reeling after his surgery, had to interrupt his own chat for some post-surgery puking &#8212; which he announced on Facebook as well: &#8220;WOW just threw up in the middle of the Q&amp;A lol. time to get some rest but before i go just wanna say much love to all you fans! thanks to you guys who make MSG the best arena and thanks to all the NY media/beat writers for all your hard work in getting information to the fans. goodnight!&#8221; For someone who initiated his Facebook Timeline a little late in the game, these online interactions reveal a high level of comfort. And Lin&#8217;s fans seem to love his ease as well. More than 43,000 people liked his vomiting update alone. SEE ALSO: Jeremy Lin Gets a Facebook Profile. What Took Him So Long? Lin also maintains a Twitter account, although he has more fans on Facebook than followers on Twitter. It&#8217;s expected he will need about six weeks to recover from his knee operation. That means Lin will be out for the rest of the season, although he did announce during the chat that he&#8217;ll post YouTube videos documenting his recovery. Fans, if you have any ideas for that, he says he wants to know. What do you think of Jeremy Lin&#8217;s online interaction with his fans? Sound off in the comments. More About: Facebook, sportsFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/jeremy-lin-surgery-facebook-chat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/jeremy-lin-surgery-facebook-chat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram for Android: Advanced Camera, But No Tilt Shift [HANDS ON]</title>
      <description>Home View The home view shows a stream of photos your Instagram friends have taken. Click here to view this gallery. Instagram for Android is finally here &#8212; which is welcome news for Android smartphone owners who waited patiently as Instagram&#8217;s iOS user base rose into the millions. Will they be satisfied when they install Instagram for Android? We did a walkthrough of the new app in order to find out. &#8220;The Android app offers an extremely familiar Instagram experience when compared to the iOS app,&#8221; Instagram said in its announcement Tuesday. &#8220;You&#8217;ll find all the same exact filters and community as our iOS version.&#8221; It&#8217;s true that Instagram for Android has most of the same features as the iPhone version. The user interface on the Android version has the same layout. The five tabs on the bottom of the home screen are dedicated to five key functions in the app. Another feature that has not changed is sharing photos out to the same four platforms: Twitter, Facebook, Foursquare, and Tumblr. There are, however, some notable differences. Instagram for Android uses a new camera icon in the camera view. The app also lacks some of the iPhone version&#8217;s image editing features &#8212; most importantly tilt shift, which allows you to focus on one area of the photo while distorting the rest of the image. The Android version does have one feature its iPhone counterpart lacks: &#8220;Advanced Camera.&#8221; When you turn this on, it will automatically resize your photo, so you don&#8217;t have to recrop the image in Instagram&#8217;s interface. In the iPhone version, you can only resize or crop if you select a photo from your photo library. Instagram for Android was tested on a Samsung Galaxy Nexus running Android 4.0. Currently, the Android version of Instagram is compatible with Android 2.2 or higher. You can download the Instagram for Android app for free over at Google Play.. Have you started using Instagram for Android? What are your first impressions? Let us know in the comments below. More About: android, Android apps, instagram, photography</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/instagram-android-hands-on/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/instagram-android-hands-on/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 5 Coming In June, Says Foxconn Employee [REPORT]</title>
      <description>According to a Foxconn recruiter, we&#8217;ll see a new iPhone in June of this year. The recruiter suggested the iPhone would be headed our way this summer in an interview with TV Tokyo&#8217;s &#8220;World Business Satellite&#8221; broadcast Monday. In the interview, a reporter asked the recruiter how many people the company was looking to hire, and he answered &#8220;We&#8217;re looking for 18,000 employees &#8230; for the fifth-generation phone.&#8221; The reporter went on to clarify that the recruiter was talking about the iPhone 5, and the recruiter added that the next generation of the handset will come out in June. The iPhone 5 &#8212; or, if Apple maintains the naming scheme it started with the iPad, the &#8220;new iPhone&#8221; &#8212; will actually be the 6th iPhone released by the company. After the the initial iPhone release, the company launched an iPhone 3G, iPhone 3GS, iPhone 4, and iPhone 4S. The June rumor, of course, should be taken with a grain of salt. Rumors of the iPhone 5 started almost immediately after the announcement of the iPhone 4S last year. Current rumors have the device&#8217;s launch pinned between June and October, with many speculating that the next generation will be LTE-capable to run on carrier&#8217;s new speedy data networks. Are any of you looking forward to the release of the iPhone 5 or &#8220;new iPhone&#8221;? Tell us what you&#8217;d like to see in the next-generation handset in the comments. More About: apple, Foxconn, iphone, iPhone 5</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/foxconn-iphone-5-rumor/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/foxconn-iphone-5-rumor/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter vs. Tornado: Dallas Authorities Tweet Weather Warnings</title>
      <description>As several tornadoes caused significant damage Tuesday afternoon near Dallas and Fort Worth local authorities turned to Twitter to help minimize the disruption. While the severe weather looked to be heading straight to Dallas Fort Worth airport, the major hub is no longer in the direct path of the storm. Dallas flights were shut down and travelers at the airport were told to take shelter. During the storm, the Dallas Fort Worth Red Cross and Dallas Fort Worth International Airport used Twitter to reach out to followers and ensure they were taking the proper precautions. When news of the impending tornado threat hit, the Red Cross also shared safety tips on Twitter &#8212; such as how to best find shelter &#8212; then continued to tweet out locations where people should be alert and take cover. The Dallas Fort Worth Intrnational Airport used Twitter to connect with people in the airport confused about where to seek cover, comfort loved ones of people currently in the airport, and share status updates on flights. To see how the Twitter was used to help people stay safe amid the severe weather, check out the Storify below: [View the story "Dallas Airport &amp; Red Cross Use Twitter To Keep People Safe During Tornado Threat" on Storify] More About: Twitter, Weather</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/dfw-airport-tornado/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/dfw-airport-tornado/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strike a Pose: Rachel Zoe Invests in Fashion App</title>
      <description>Amid the fashion inspiration, advice and bookmarking apps that have wrangled for the attention of shoppers over the past two years, a few leaders are beginning to emerge. Last month, Pinterest-lookalike Fancy stepped more directly into retail by beginning to process transactions directly on its site. Fashism, a style feedback app popular among teenagers, went a step further, opening up an online shop that quickly began selling out of merchandise. Now outfit-sharing app Pose has seen a quick rise in interest &#8212; both from users and investors &#8212; thanks to savvy integrations with Facebook&#8217;s Open Graph and well-known tastemakers. One of those well-known tastemakers, celebrity stylist and designer Rachel Zoe (pictured), is now an investor alongside her husband and business partner, Rodger Berman. Zoe has only been uploading photos to the app, which is available on iOS, Android and Facebook, since the beginning of the year, but has already amassed around 200,000 followers. She&#8217;s also brought many of her existing followers onto Pose&#8217;s platform. It&#8217;s one thing to become involved in the app, another to invest in it. In an interview with Mashable, Berman said he and his wife invested in part because it was a promising business, and in part because they like to support LA-based startups that fuse fashion, technology and media. App developer Mobile Roadie, trip-planning app Trippy and discount retail site 23rd.com are among their other investments in the space. &#8220;Online sharing, a la Pinterest, is obviously a bit trend right now, and we&#8217;re hoping Pose is going to be the leader in fashion for that purpose,&#8221; Berman said of their decision to invest in Pose. &#8220;People are posting what they like and tagging it, and what&#8217;s next, you&#8217;ll buy it. Eventually [Pose] will get into commerce.&#8221; Of Pose&#8217;s push into commerce, CEO Dustin Rosen would only say that the company wants to move &#8220;past inspiration towards actual shopping.&#8221; Whether that will mean driving sales through third-party retailers, developing its own transactional platform or building out a store isn&#8217;t yet clear. &#8220;What we don&#8217;t want to do is push something down people&#8217;s throats. We want it to be a natural progression,&#8221; Rosen added. Rosen wouldn&#8217;t disclose the number of signups Pose has received, although he did point out that the Facebook app had 290,000 registered users and that user signups have increased tenfold since Facebook Timeline was released. He also said that 40 million poses are viewed per month across Pose&#8217;s apps. Several of Pose&#8217;s top users, including blogger Leandra Medine and model Coco Rocha, have followers in the 100,000 range. Image via Rachel Zoe&#8217;s Pose account More About: pose, rachel zoe, rodger berman</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/pose-rachel-zoe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/03/pose-rachel-zoe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
