<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;@DrTomCrick: My tie: the only part of me that appeared on tonight's #bbcqt http://t.co/dZDXojNr&#8221; &lt;- I thought I recognised it! ;)</title>
      <description>Steve Bunce: &#8220;@DrTomCrick: My tie: the only part of me that appeared on tonight's #bbcqt http://t.co/dZDXojNr&#8221; &lt;- I thought I recognised it! ;) &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kvqh_PltWP/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kvqh_PltWP/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Co-Founder: No, I Didn&#8217;t Leave U.S. to Dodge Taxes</title>
      <description>Facebook co-founder Eduardo Saverin denied Thursday that he is renouncing his U.S. citizenship and moving to Singapore to avoid paying capital gains taxes on his approximately $3 billion share in Facebook. Saverin said in a statement following a press conference held earlier by two senators who accused him of &#8220;tax dodging&#8221; that his relocation decision was &#8220;based solely on my interest in working and living in Singapore, where I have been since 2009,&#8221; according to Reuters. The move has drawn ire from Senators Chuck Schumer (D-N.Y.) and Bob Casey (D-Penn.), who accuse Saverin of taking advantage of the United State&#8217;s relative economic strength and stability, only to leave without contributing his fair share back to the country where he built his fortune. &#8220;Mr. Saverin has decided to &#8216;defriend&#8217; the United States of America just to avoid paying his taxes,&#8221; said Sen. Schumer in a statement. &#8220;We aren&#8217;t going to let him get away with it so easily. &#8220;It&#8217;s infuriating to see someone sell out the country that welcomed him and kept him safe, educated him and helped him become a billionaire. This is a great American success story gone horribly wrong.&#8221; The senators introduced a bill under which any expatriate with either a net worth of $2 million, or an average income tax liability of at least $148,000, will be automatically presumed to be leaving the country for tax purposes &#8212; enabling the IRS to impose a tax on any investment gains that person makes in the future. Saverin, who was born in Brazil, denied any wrongdoing. He said he owes and is willing to pay &#8220;hundreds of millions of dollars in taxes to the United States government.&#8221; &#8220;I have paid and will continue to pay any taxes due on everything I earned while a U.S. citizen,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It is unfortunate that my personal choice has led to a public debate, based not on the facts, but entirely on speculation and misinformation.&#8221; Saverin filed to give up his U.S. citizenship in January of 2011, but the news didn&#8217;t surface until late last month when the federal government released the information in a routine report. According to Talking Points Memo, Saverin may be barred from re-entering the U.S. if authorities decide he left the country for tax reasons. What do you think Saverin owes to the U.S. &#8212; and to the IRS? Sound off in the comments below. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, US, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/saverin-denies-leaving-tax/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/saverin-denies-leaving-tax/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Companies That Could Have Been Facebook</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s been a long road for Facebook. What began as an intimate platform has turned into a social networking giant serving more than 900 million users. Facebook may be cashing in on its intial public offering this week, but it wasn&#8217;t the first to introduce the world to online social networking &#8212; many other sites were once recognized as the most popular. What made them fall by the wayside? For some, it was server instability or lack of financial support to hit the ground running. Other formerly popular networks received the necessary monetary backing, but were inhibited by the corporation that had acquired them &#8212; and some went on to morph the company into something broader than just social networking. SEE ALSO: Mark Zuckerberg: Smart or Lucky? [POLL] But perhaps the most important reason why other sites couldn&#8217;t compete with Facebook&#8217;s current growth is timing. Today, the web is stronger, faster and more crowded than ever &#8212; people rely on an Internet connection to communicate, earn revenue and entertain, among many other things. That wasn&#8217;t the case 10 to 20 years ago. Take a look at some of the past social networking kings that existed before Facebook. That&#8217;s not to say all weren&#8217;t successful. Most are still around, but in a different form from which they originated. 1. AOL For many computer users in the mid &#8217;90s, the Internet was AOL. From chat rooms to the ubiqutous AOL Instant Messenger (AIM), AOL was the center of online activity. The company acquired one of the dominant desktop browsers (Netscape), the leading streaming music and MP3 services (WinAmp) and was the king of Web 1.0. SEE ALSO: AOL Founder Warns Zuckerberg: Don&#8217;t Get Distracted by Facebook IPO Then in 2001, AOL acquired Time Warner in its bid to become a media company. The merger was a disaster &#8212; one of the worst in business history. The fallout from the merger prevented AOL from keeping its eye on the evolving nature of technology, including broadband and real-time social channels. AOL tried to compete again in the social space in the mid &#8217;00s, but blunders like 2008&#8242;s $1 billion acquisition prevented success. Today, AOL is known as a media and advertising company and owner of such properties as The Huffington Post. 2. GeoCities GeoCities was originally founded as a web hosting service that let users create communities of homepages on like-minded topics. The pages were hosted by specific &#8220;cities&#8221; &#8212; for example, &#8220;Silicon Valley&#8221; (computers/electronics) or &#8220;Hollywood&#8221; (Entertainment). Near its peak, GeoCities was acquired by Yahoo for $3 billion. New copyright rules upset members and some left in protest. Among other issues, Yahoo was unable to make the site profitable and it was shut down in 2009. 3. SixDegrees.com SixDegrees.com, named after the six degrees of separation concept, was one of the first social networking sites to exist. Users list friends and family, invite external contacts to join, then see if there were connections with other users on the site. At its peak, SixDegrees.com had 1 million members and partnered with NADP. The site simply wasn&#8217;t profitable at the time, and shut down in 2001. It has since been revived, but is only open to former members and those who get an invite. 4. Friendster Friendster was once considered the top online social network. It allowed users to connect, communicate and share online content with other members. Within a few months of launching, it had more than 3 million users. During Friendster&#8217;s peak in 2003, Google offered founder Jonathan Abrams $30 billion, however he chose to be funded by Kleiner, Perkins, Caufield &amp; Byers and Benchmark Capital. The decline is considered one of the biggest blunders in the history of Silicon Valley. The site could hardly keep up with demand, and had trouble serving web pages. It was eclipsed by MySpace in 2004. Friendster shifted in 2011 to focus on its expansion in Asia, and is now a social gaming site. Today, more than 90% of new users are based in Asia, and monthly users have increased by 50%. 5. MySpace In 2003, Tom Anderson, Chris DeWolf and a few other Friendster users saw potential in the site, but felt it was lacking infrastructure. The MySpace team and its resources were supported by eUniverse. The new platform had the programmers it needed as it rapidly grew in popularity. By 2006, MySpace was bought by NewsCorp for $580 million and had 100 million accounts. It peaked in 2007 when it was considered the leading social networking site, valued at $12 billion. The site&#8217;s downfall began in 2008, when Facebook eventually caught up and overtook the Alexa ratings. Among other issues, Myspace struggled with a decline in ad revenue, failure to innovate and Facebook&#8217;s expansive membership to users under 18. The downfall accelerated in 2009, when it lost millions of followers monthly. MySpace was bought for $35 million by advertising network Specific Media, and Justin Timberlake took ownership stake. Recently, Timberlake introduced MySpace TV. The site gained a million new followers in February 2012. 6. Second Life Second Life&#8217;s online virtual world was developed in 2003 by Linden Lab. The service enables users to interact with others, create and trade virtual property, and participate in jobs and activities through an avatar. As of 2011, there were 1 million active users on the site. Though Second Life was not necessarily a direct competitor to Facebook, the site became so popular that people made a living through their avatar. Some quit their jobs and others felt happier in a virtual life instead of reality. Due to Second Life&#8217;s rapid growth rate, its servers struggled with instability. Eventual changes to the terms of service in order to comply with various international laws regulated or banned many Second Life businesses that once thrived. 7. Orkut Orkut was quietly designed by Google in 2004. The social networking site was originally hosted in California, but today it is one of the most popular social networks in Brazil. The site intended to help users connect with new and familiar people. It became popular in Brazil, India and Estonia &#8212; until 2010, when many users in Estonia and India switched over to Facebook. Due to its prominence in Brazil, as well as its legal issues, the company moved its operation and management there to continue business. Today there are 66 million users on orkut. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, blackred More About: aim, aol, Facebook, faceboook ipo, features, friendster, geocities, myspace, orkut, Second Life, Social Media, trendingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/companies-before-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/companies-before-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still a great movie. http://t.co/7HQImvFI @GetGlue #TradingPlaces</title>
      <description>erhys: Still a great movie. http://t.co/7HQImvFI @GetGlue #TradingPlaces &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://m.getglue.com/movies/trading_places/john_landis?ref=erhys&amp;s=tch</link>
      <guid>http://m.getglue.com/movies/trading_places/john_landis?ref=erhys&amp;s=tch</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter: Here&#8217;s How to Hide Your Tweets from Google</title>
      <description>Want to keep your tweets among your tweeps and hidden from any old Google searcher? Twitter has some tips for you. The microblogging company&#8217;s @Support account on Wednesday tweeted out a link to a help center page for Twitter users want to keep their posts a bit more anonymous on Google. Given Twitter&#8217;s high rank in Google Search, it&#8217;s likely that your profile there will be among the top results for your name. The first suggestion for more anonymity? Change your username or listed actual name on Twitter. So, for example, if you use a profane @ handle, but your given name is listed in your profile settings, that could be a problem during your job search as recruiters Google you to see what comes up. You can also protect your tweets in your accounts settings but that may not be a perfect fix, as Twitter points out. All tweets posted before you went private will still remain public in search engines (including Twitter&#8217;s own search). Additionally, Google caches old search results, meaning that your old information can still hang around there &#8212; even if it only links to an error page. Eventually, Google will update its search index and refresh to your new privacy settings. But if you want certain posts removed sooner, Twitter does suggest another option. First, copy the URL for the dead status page you would like removed. Then go to this Google page, which explains how to create a removal request for an outdated link or page. You&#8217;ll then be directed to another page, where you can paste in the link and submit your request, but you may need a Google account to do so. Check out Twitter&#8217;s full list of tips for demurring from Google Search here. Twitter and Google have been feuding ever since Google&#8217;s integration of Google+ into its regular search results back in January, which Twitter called &#8220;bad for people&#8221; &#8212; since news increasingly breaks on Twitter before being reported on other outlets. Is it better to have your Twitter profile and activity be a prominent Google Search result, or to protect your anonymity? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, sodafish More About: Google, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/twitter-google-search-results/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/twitter-google-search-results/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turner Broadcasting Takes a Bite of Funny or Die</title>
      <description>Turner Broadcasting System, Inc., including multi-platform entertainment networks TBS and Adult Swim, is joining forces with Funny Or Die in a strategic partnership that links three of the biggest brands in comedy. TBS, the highest-rated comedy network on television, and Adult Swim, TV&#8217;s leader with young adults, along with select Turner digital properties, will collaborate with Funny Or Die to accelerate the digital content provider&#8217;s sales and cement all three brands&#8217; position as the leading multi-platform destinations for great comedy. The agreement promises to enhance the phenomenal growth of Funny Or Die, which was launched in 2007 by Will Ferrell, writer/director Adam McKay and writer Chris Henchy. Turner Broadcasting is taking a minority equity stake in Funny Or Die, and Turner&#8217;s digital sales force will serve as the exclusive seller of advertising opportunities with Funny Or Die. The reach of TBS and Adult Swim &#8211; coupled with the strength and innovation of the Turner Broadcasting System, Inc. sales division &#8211; will be an ideal pairing for Funny Or Die, which has relationships with many of the top people and brands in entertainment. &#8220;While we are incredibly excited about how this partnership will catalyze our growth and make Funny Or Die an even better place for comedic talent, we are even more excited about the opportunities this will open up to brands and advertisers to create far-reaching, hilariously funny cross-platform content and messaging,&#8221; said Dick Glover, president and CEO of Funny Or Die. &#8220;TBS, Adult Swim, Turner Digital Sales and the rest of the Turner organization are a fantastic fit with us in all ways. Plus, we are instantly gaining an even larger sales staff, something it would take us years to develop. This is very cool.&#8221; &#8220;We&#8217;re thrilled by our acquisition of Turner,&#8221; said Adam McKay, co-founder of Funny Or Die. &#8220;We&#8217;re now taking a long hard look at Viacom. These are heady days over here at Funny Or Die.&#8221; Funny Or Die caught fire immediately after its April 2007 launch, thanks to the popularity of Ferrell&#8217;s now-famous &#8220;The Landlord&#8221; video, which has been viewed about 80 million times. Since then, the company has evolved into a vertically integrated 21st century digital studio that produces high-quality content over numerous platforms, including funnyordie.com. Funny Or Die also attracts some of the most famous and talented people in entertainment, ranging from Justin Bieber to Zach Galifianakis. Turner has already worked extensively with Funny Or Die on the creative side of the business, and the two companies will now partner on content that reaches across all platforms, including television, mobile and tablets. &#8220;We&#8217;re investing in Funny Or Die because we can take their great content and give it a wider audience through the incredible reach of TBS,&#8221; said Steve Koonin, president of Turner Entertainment Networks, which includes TBS. &#8220;TBS and Funny Or Die will give people a laugh anywhere, anytime and on any device.&#8221; Because comedy has proven to be a magnet for young adults, the Turner and Funny Or Die partnership will be attractive to a wide range of ad partners. &#8220;Turner&#8217;s new strategic alliance with Funny Or Die adds another core asset to our unrivaled digital portfolio that will prove to be very attractive to advertisers looking to associate their brands with great content and an engaged, socially savvy audience,&#8221; said David Levy, president of sales, distribution and sports at Turner Broadcasting System. &#8220;Combined with the powerful reach and content of TBS and Adult Swim, the addition of Funny Or Die provides advertisers opportunities to associate their messages with three top brands that attract young demos and engage consumers across a variety of screens.&#8221; &#8220;We&#8217;ve worked with Funny Or Die in the past because their sensibilities and creator-friendly environment matches ours,&#8221; said Stuart Snyder, president/COO Turner&#8217;s Animation, Young Adults &amp; Kids Media Group, which includes Adult Swim. &#8220;This extension of our relationship will now allow us to bring even more great comedy content to our audience.&#8221;</description>
      <link>http://www.deadline.com/2012/05/turner-broadcasting-forges-ad-sales-alliance-with-funny-or-die/</link>
      <guid>http://www.deadline.com/2012/05/turner-broadcasting-forges-ad-sales-alliance-with-funny-or-die/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donna Summer Dead -- Disco Legend Dies After Battle with Cancer</title>
      <description>Donna Summer -- the Queen of Disco -- died this morning after a battle with cancer TMZ has learned. We're told Summer was in Florida at the time of her death. She was 63 years old. Sources close to Summer tell us the singer was trying to&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://www.tmz.com/2012/05/17/donna-summer-dead-last-dance/</link>
      <guid>http://www.tmz.com/2012/05/17/donna-summer-dead-last-dance/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Yahoo Killed Flickr and Lost the Internet [Exclusive]</title>
      <description>Web startups are made out of two things: people and code. The people make the code, and the code makes the people rich. Code is like a poem; it has to follow certain structural requirements, and yet out of that structure can come art. But code is art that does something. It is the assembly of something brand new from nothing but an idea. More &#187;</description>
      <link>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</link>
      <guid>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donna Summer Dead -- Disco Legend Dies After Battle with Cancer</title>
      <description>Donna Summer -- the Queen of Disco -- died this morning after a battle with cancer TMZ has learned. We're told Summer was in Florida at the time of her death. She was 63 years old. Sources close to Summer tell us the singer was trying to&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://www.tmz.com/2012/05/17/donna-summer-dead-last-dance/</link>
      <guid>http://www.tmz.com/2012/05/17/donna-summer-dead-last-dance/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Launch: A Promising, Yet Controversial Job Candidate</title>
      <description>Discuss the show on Twitter: #BehindTheLaunch In Mashable&#8216;s new video series, Behind the Launch, we&#8217;re taking cameras behind the scenes at Vungle, an in-app video advertising startup. Last week, we met the the founders and saw them bring on Colin Behr to head up business development. This week, they courted big-name startup investors, such as 500 Startups&#8216; Dave McClure, DFJ Esprit&#8216;s Krishna Visvanathan and AOL Ventures&#8216; Adam Smith. But Vungle needs to focus more on the core &#8212; developing the product instead of fleshing out press releases and a website update. The team is fielding resumes for iOS developers, and while there are some promising candidates, the Vungle guys quickly find out that there&#8217;s always a catch. When Zain is asked to sum up the week in one word, his response is &#8220;unpredictable.&#8221; Watch today&#8217;s episode to see what happens, and join the conversation on Twitter, #BehindTheLaunch. Missed earlier episodes? Watch them here! Ep. 1: Meet Vungle Ep. 2: Bringing in a Closer Ep. 3: How to Court Startup Investors About Vungle Vungle is a San Francisco-based company that purveys mobile video ads to promote apps. Just last week, Vungle announced that it had raised $2 million from big Silicon Valley and Alley names: Google Ventures, AOL Ventures, Crosslink Capital, Ron Conway&#8217;s SV Angel, Dave McClure&#8217;s 500 Startups, Charles Hudson&#8217;s SoftTechVC&#8217;s, Maynard Webb, Scott McNealy and Tim Draper. Vungle also has offices in the UK and Pakistan. Zain Jaffer, CEO and Co-Founder &#8212; A successful and zany entrepreneur since age 15, Zain launched his first Internet company and built-up an impressive list of clients, including Google, Mozilla Firefox, MTV and Hilary Duff, before his 18th birthday. British. Jack Smith, Co-Founder &#8212; Self-described lunatic marketer and hacker. Started his career as a freelance web designer at age 13, founded a video startup, MediaRoots, in college. Met Zain at King&#8217;s College London University in 2009. British. Bryant Chou, CTO &#8212; Full stack engineer and software architect with more than five years of experience developing mobile apps. He&#8217;s an enthusiastic traveler who&#8217;ll share his travel tales with you over a cold beer. American. Marta Bulaich, Chief Yoga Officer &#8212; Marta&#8217;s first job was with the masterminds behind the TV infomercial legends Chia Pet and Clapper. After a career of working with various startups and venture capital firm, she came to Vungle to do public relations and center their chi in full lotus. American. Ben Lindsey, Senior Software Engineer &#8212; A veteran of four Silicon Valley startups with experience in Internet advertising, large scale databases and agile programming. When not slinging code, you cam find him cooking organic food, listening to electronica, backpacking around the world or running marathons. Colin Behr, Director of Business Development &#8212; Previously founded an Internet company, CyberPlanet Ltd, with Zain in 2004, and then moved to San Francisco to start another venture. Colin eventually went to University but dropped out after speaking with Zain about his new venture, Vungle. Ray Myers, Software Engineer &#8212; 25-year-old Linux geek who loves robotics and has been programming since he was 7. Ray is a Shotokan karate third-degree Black Belt, but you can usually find him at his computer, trying to make robots bend to his will. American. Series presented by Internet Explorer Behind the Launch is presented by Internet Explorer. Learn how IE is building a more beautiful web through hardware accelerated graphics and modern web standards like HTML5. Get IE9 today or download the Windows 8 Consumer Preview, which features the new IE10 to see where we&#8217;re headed. More About: Behind the Launch Series, features, mashable, mashable video, Startups, Vungle</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/vungle-ios-developer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/vungle-ios-developer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Knowledge Graph: things, not strings</title>
      <description>Cross-posted from the Inside Search BlogSearch is a lot about discovery&#8212;the basic human need to learn and broaden your horizons. But searching still requires a lot of hard work by you, the user. So today I&#8217;m really excited to launch the Knowledge Graph, which will help you discover new information quickly and easily. Take a query like [taj mahal]. For more than four decades, search has essentially been about matching keywords to queries. To a search engine the words [taj mahal] have been just that&#8212;two words.But we all know that [taj mahal] has a much richer meaning. You might think of one of the world&#8217;s most beautiful monuments, or a Grammy Award-winning musician, or possibly even a casino in Atlantic City, NJ. Or, depending on when you last ate, the nearest Indian restaurant. It&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve been working on an intelligent model&#8212;in geek-speak, a &#8220;graph&#8221;&#8212;that understands real-world entities and their relationships to one another: things, not strings. The Knowledge Graph enables you to search for things, people or places that Google knows about&#8212;landmarks, celebrities, cities, sports teams, buildings, geographical features, movies, celestial objects, works of art and more&#8212;and instantly get information that&#8217;s relevant to your query. This is a critical first step towards building the next generation of search, which taps into the collective intelligence of the web and understands the world a bit more like people do.Google&#8217;s Knowledge Graph isn&#8217;t just rooted in public sources such as Freebase, Wikipedia and the CIA World Factbook. It&#8217;s also augmented at a much larger scale&#8212;because we&#8217;re focused on comprehensive breadth and depth. It currently contains more than 500 million objects, as well as more than 3.5 billion facts about and relationships between these different objects. And it&#8217;s tuned based on what people search for, and what we find out on the web.The Knowledge Graph enhances Google Search in three main ways to start:1. Find the right thing Language can be ambiguous&#8212;do you mean Taj Mahal the monument, or Taj Mahal the musician? Now Google understands the difference, and can narrow your search results just to the one you mean&#8212;just click on one of the links to see that particular slice of results:This is one way the Knowledge Graph makes Google Search more intelligent&#8212;your results are more relevant because we understand these entities, and the nuances in their meaning, the way you do.2. Get the best summary With the Knowledge Graph, Google can better understand your query, so we can summarize relevant content around that topic, including key facts you&#8217;re likely to need for that particular thing. For example, if you&#8217;re looking for Marie Curie, you&#8217;ll see when she was born and died, but you&#8217;ll also get details on her education and scientific discoveries:How do we know which facts are most likely to be needed for each item? For that, we go back to our users and study in aggregate what they&#8217;ve been asking Google about each item. For example, people are interested in knowing what books Charles Dickens wrote, whereas they&#8217;re less interested in what books Frank Lloyd Wright wrote, and more in what buildings he designed.The Knowledge Graph also helps us understand the relationships between things. Marie Curie is a person in the Knowledge Graph, and she had two children, one of whom also won a Nobel Prize, as well as a husband, Pierre Curie, who claimed a third Nobel Prize for the family. All of these are linked in our graph. It&#8217;s not just a catalog of objects; it also models all these inter-relationships. It&#8217;s the intelligence between these different entities that&#8217;s the key.3. Go deeper and broader Finally, the part that&#8217;s the most fun of all&#8212;the Knowledge Graph can help you make some unexpected discoveries. You might learn a new fact or new connection that prompts a whole new line of inquiry. Do you know where Matt Groening, the creator of the Simpsons (one of my all-time favorite shows), got the idea for Homer, Marge and Lisa&#8217;s names? It&#8217;s a bit of a surprise:We&#8217;ve always believed that the perfect search engine should understand exactly what you mean and give you back exactly what you want. And we can now sometimes help answer your next question before you&#8217;ve asked it, because the facts we show are informed by what other people have searched for. For example, the information we show for Tom Cruise answers 37 percent of next queries that people ask about him. In fact, some of the most serendipitous discoveries I&#8217;ve made using the Knowledge Graph are through the magical &#8220;People also search for&#8221; feature. One my favorite books is The White Tiger, the debut novel by Aravind Adiga, which won the prestigious Man Booker Prize. Using the Knowledge Graph, I discovered three other books that had won the same prize and one that won the Pulitzer. I can tell you, this suggestion was spot on!We&#8217;ve begun to gradually roll out this view of the Knowledge Graph to U.S. English users. It&#8217;s also going to be available on smartphones and tablets&#8212;read more about how we&#8217;ve tailored this to mobile devices. And watch our video (also available on our site about the Knowledge Graph) that gives a deeper dive into the details and technology, in the words of people who've worked on this project:We hope this added intelligence will give you a more complete picture of your interest, provide smarter search results, and pique your curiosity on new topics. We&#8217;re proud of our first baby step&#8212;the Knowledge Graph&#8212;which will enable us to make search more intelligent, moving us closer to the "Star Trek computer" that I've always dreamt of building. Enjoy your lifelong journey of discovery, made easier by Google Search, so you can spend less time searching and more time doing what you love.Posted by Amit Singhal, SVP, Engineering</description>
      <link>http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/05/introducing-knowledge-graph-things-not.html</link>
      <guid>http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/05/introducing-knowledge-graph-things-not.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Twitter&#8217;s &#8216;Do Not Track&#8217; Feature Will Mean For You</title>
      <description>Twitter announced Thursday it will take part in &#8220;Do Not Track,&#8221; a cookie-blocking feature found in Mozilla&#8217;s Firefox browser that&#8217;s promoted by the Federal Trade Commission. What does that mean for you, the user? When a Firefox user enables Do Not Track, the browser prevents websites from using cookies to track the user&#8217;s behavior and personal information. Do Not Track only works on sites that have signed on to the service &#8212; a list which now includes Twitter. Cookies can be used for many purposes, including storing information that some, including Google, argue makes browsing the web easier (a weather site might remember your postal code, for example). However, some believe that cookie-based tracking is a breach of privacy. Facebook has previously come under fire for following users around non-Facebook sites. Cookies are also an essential ingredient for websites serving up advertisements based on user&#8217;s behavior or location, called &#8220;behavioral ads.&#8221; Say, for example, you&#8217;re located in New York City and you often tweet about baseball &#8212; with cookies enabled, Twitter would know to serve you ads and sponsored tweets that have to do with the New York Yankees. Those customized ads are an important moneymaker for social networks such as Facebook and Twitter. Different sites use cookies for different purposes. According to Twitter&#8217;s privacy guide, Twitter uses cookies to learn how users interact with its services, monitor web traffic and improve its products (including advertising). If you enable Do Not Track, you&#8217;re opting out of having your data collected for those purposes, making you, your profile and your tweets more anonymous. You would also be waving goodbye to those personalized ads &#8212; no cookies means no customization data for advertising firms. However, Do Not Track is not an ad-blocking service, and enabling it will translate into receiving generic ads and sponsored tweets in your feed. Enabling Do Not Track will also prevent Twitter&#8217;s web-based service from remembering your user name and password, preventing you from automatically logging in upon arrival. Do Not Track is, at its core, a trade off. It asks of you: Do you prefer ease of use and personalized ads, or more anonymity from web services and online advertising agencies? According to Mozilla, 8.6% of desktop Firefox users and 19% of mobile users are choosing the latter, with nearly half of those users reporting they feel more safe surfing the Internet with Do Not Track enabled. For more information on Do Not Track, visit Mozilla&#8217;s website. We reached out to Twitter for further information about Do Not Track. We will update this post with any response. Which is right for you &#8212; easier surfing or more privacy? Sound off in the comments below. More About: do not track, FTC, Social Media, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/twitter-do-not-track/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/twitter-do-not-track/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
