<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>101 Ways to Be Healthy - Android Apps on Google Play</title>
      <description>Doco: Instagram for Android is here: http://t.co/XbpfZkBz #instagram #android ^KJL &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instagram.android</link>
      <guid>https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instagram.android</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Etsy: A Beginner&#8217;s Guide to the Crafty Ecommerce Site</title>
      <description>Sure, Etsy&#8216;s been around since 2005, but not everyone is hip to the ecommerce site. No worries, we&#8217;ve provided an overview of all the great features Etsy has to offer. Just don&#8217;t blame us when you&#8217;ve logged your fifth straight hour browsing refab couch cushions. It&#8217;s been known to happen. Etsy is an ecommerce site comprised of individual user shops, similar to eBay or Amazon. However, Etsy has the reputation for hosting a very specific genre of products: handmade items, vintage clothing and jewelry, refurbished and upcycled housewares, craft supplies, etc. Basically, Etsy encourages you to launch your small business venture on the site, and the more DIY the better. Even if you&#8217;re not an Etsy shop owner, the site is just as fun. In addition to browsing items from individual sellers all over the world, Etsy users can access an engaging social layer on the site, whether by &#8220;circling&#8221; friends like Google+ or adding &#8220;favorites&#8221; like you would pins on Pinterest. SEE ALSO: 20 Unique &#8216;The Hunger Games&#8217; Items on Etsy It&#8217;s true, Etsy has changed a lot since 2005. Whether you&#8217;re a veteran user or a newbie, take a look at our guide below. You&#8217;ll discover how to search, favorite and purchase some incredibly creative products. And be sure and let us know what you think of Etsy in the comments below. 1. Handpicked Items One of the first things you'll notice about the Etsy homepage is the collage of handpicked items. Often, these items belong to themes distinguished by color, occasion, material or type. Etsy updates the homepage's handpicked items regularly, so you could check back 20 minutes later for an entirely different set. Click here to view this gallery. More About: ecommerce, Etsy, fashion, Gifts, shopping, webFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/etsy-beginners-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/etsy-beginners-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Tuesday&#8217;s Primary Elections on Social Media</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s primary day in Indiana, North Carolina and West Virginia, and politicians, journalists and voters are all over Facebook, Twitter and other forms of social media posting about the elections. Mitt Romney has all but locked up the Republican presidential nomination with the exit of former rivals Rick Santorum and Newt Gingrich. But the show must go on &#8212; voters are still headed to the polls in Tuesday night&#8217;s three primary states. Election watchers are also paying close attention to state-level races across the country Tuesday evening: Indiana voters are poised to vote out Sen. Dick Lugar, the third most senior member of the Senate. Up in Wisconsin, Governor Scott Walker faces a recall election. And in North Carolina, voters are deciding on Amendment 1, which would constitutionally define marriage as taking place between a man and a woman. During all of this, candidates will be taking to social media to influence voters in the battle for public office. Journalists are covering the elections with services such as Facebook, YouTube and Tout. Voters, meanwhile, are posting about their favorite candidates. As Tuesday night&#8217;s primaries and other elections unfold, we&#8217;ll be sharing the best examples of social media&#8217;s use in politics. Follow Mashable to learn how politicians, journalists, media outlets and citizens are using social media during Tuesday&#8217;s elections. We&#8217;ll be updating this continually: [View the story "The Indiana, North Carolina and West Virginia Primaries on Social Media" on Storify] More About: 2012 presidential campaign, Politics, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/indiana-north-carolina-west-virginia-primaries/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/indiana-north-carolina-west-virginia-primaries/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize Your Headlines for Google and Humans</title>
      <description>Jonathan Rick is a director at Levick Strategic Communications. He contributes to Levick&#8217;s Bulletproof Blog. Follow him @jrick. Why do search engines always rank certain websites so highly? Sure, their content might be great, but their search engine optimization is definitely awesome. Indeed, for many sites, the search-engine spiders that crawl the web deliver a third or more of their traffic. So crafting key parts of a page, like a headline, is critical. Perhaps the most famous example comes from the Huffington Post, which in February reeled in readers with the ingenious bait: &#8220;What Time Is the Super Bowl?&#8221; In protest, writers for publications such as The Washington Post, The New York Times, and The Atlantic each took turns slugging the SEO punching bag. The headlines describe their complaint: &#8220;Gene Weingarten Column Mentions Lady Gaga.&#8221; &#8220;This Boring Headline Is Written for Google.&#8221; &#8220;Google Doesn&#8217;t Laugh: Saving Witty Headlines in the Age of SEO.&#8221; In other words, algorithms don&#8217;t appreciate wit, irony, humor, or style. As reporter Steve Lohr put it, they&#8217;re &#8220;numbingly literal-minded.&#8221; Yes, it is one of the definitive 21st century truisms that in addition to writing for eternity, or for one&#8217;s mother, today&#8217;s writer must also write for Google. That, however, doesn&#8217;t mean your headlines have to be stale. You can pen pun-based headlines all day long and maintain your journalistic integrity. Consider these examples from leading news organizations. As with most things in life, the media have adopted tactics that range from bad to the best. Bad Don&#8217;t write the same headline for both the article and the page. The difference is that an article title is what you show your readers, and a page title is what you show search engines. (With a good plug-in, like Page Title for Drupal or WordPress SEO for WordPress, you can rig most content management systems to separate the two.) In the examples below, keywords pertaining to the subject of each article are, well, nowhere. Google doesn&#8217;t know if the Time article involves a beach called &#8220;Force One&#8221; or presidential vacations. Likewise, does &#8220;Hacked&#8221; mean a hacked Gmail password or the Stuxnet virus? And it&#8217;s unclear if &#8220;The Woman Who Knew Too Much&#8221; refers to Alice Stewart, who wrote a landmark biography by that name, or the former chairwoman of the congressional oversight panel monitoring the Troubled Assets Relief Program. Time Article Title: &#8220;Beach Force One&#8221; Page Title: Beach Force One The Atlantic Article Title: &#8220;Hacked!&#8221; Page Title: Hacked! Vanity Fair Article Title: &#8220;The Woman Who Knew Too Much&#8221; Page Title: The Woman Who Knew Too Much Good A better approach employs a single title that blends creativity with SEO punch. The idea is to craft headlines that are both self-explanatory and catchy. The compromise here allows both creativity (integrity) and technology (impact). It kills two birds with one keystroke. Mashable Article Title: &#8220;15 Case Studies to Get Your Client on Board With Social Media&#8221; Page Title: 15 Case Studies to Get Your Client on Board With Social Media Bloomberg Businessweek Article Title: &#8220;Scott Forstall, the Sorcerer&#8217;s Apprentice at Apple&#8221; Page Title: Scott Forstall, the Sorcerer&#8217;s Apprentice at Apple Gawker Article Title: &#8220;What Everyone Is Too Polite to Say About Steve Jobs&#8221; Page Title: What Everyone Is Too Polite to Say About Steve Jobs Better Headline writing crystallizes the writer&#8217;s dilemma. To a writer, a headline is a one-shot first impression that stops a mouse-moving, page-scrolling, attention-deprived user in his pixels and makes him wonder, &#8220;What is this?&#8221; The way to do this is with a two-title approach. True, the two-title technique means extra work. But absent sheer dumb luck, only extra work can deliver the eyeballs your content deserves. And considering the dramatic difference between the number of clicks generated by the first result Google returns vs. the second, the third, and the fourth, you owe it to yourself to play every angle in this ever-changing race to the top. The New Yorker Article Title: &#8220;Changing Times&#8221; Page Title: Jill Abramson, New York Times&#8217; First Woman Executive Editor The Wall Street Journal Article Title: &#8220;White House Party Crashers Cause a Hangover&#8221; Page Title: Obama Asks for Review After Michaele and Tareq Salahi Crash White House State Dinner Slate Article Title: &#8220;Deliverance&#8221; Page Title: U.S. Postal Service: Will It Survive? Best For those looking to wring every drop of SEO juice out of every article, there&#8217;s a fourth arrow in your quiver: the meta description. It is from here that Google often pulls the two-line &#8220;snippet&#8221; displayed for each webpage. Why bother with a meta description? Simple: according to the SEO uber-site, SEOmoz.org, a description induces more clicks. At the same time, SEOmoz offers a caveat: While a description makes sense for an article that targets a few heavily searched terms, if you&#8217;re going after long-tail traffic, &#8220;it can sometimes be wiser&#8221; to forgo the description and let Google work its will. (If a description is missing, Google will create one, scraping the article for pertinent content.) Yet SEOmoz&#8217;s qualifications aren&#8217;t written in stone. &#8220;In some cases,&#8221; search engines will &#8220;overrule the meta description&#8221; altogether.&#8221; But here too, it&#8217;s not always wise to bank on that possibility. Here&#8217;s how some of the best leverage this option. New York Magazine Article Title: &#8220;What&#8217;s Eating the NYPD?&#8221; Page Title: Why the NYPD Is Turning on Ray Kelly Meta Description: Ray Kelly has built the best police force in the country. Now it is turning on him. Newsweek Article Title: &#8220;Citizen Cain&#8221; Page Title: Herman Cain&#8217;s Unlikely Republican Rise Meta Description: Meet the rising GOP star who is confounding the pundits and much of black America. The New York Times Magazine Article Title: &#8220;When Is a Flip Not a Flop?&#8221; Page Title: The Fate of the Republicans Who Supported Gay Marriage Meta Description: The four Republicans who broke with their party on New York&#8217;s gay-marriage law were supposedly marked for electoral death.But that&#8217;s not exactly how it is working out. SEO is an ever-evolving and much-debated field. It&#8217;s full of qualifications and judgment calls, backed by correlation studies and launched by conjecture. Those convoluted meta descriptions notwithstanding, start with the above best practices. With this foundation, you&#8217;ll be able to pull off one of the web&#8217;s hardest acts: you&#8217;ll be able to make Google laugh. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, pressureUA More About: contributor, features, Google, SEO, seo tricksFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/google-seo-headlines/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/google-seo-headlines/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo&#8217;s Fall From Grace, By the Numbers [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Last month, we looked at Google&#8217;s amazing growth over the last few years. This month, a sadder tale. Yahoo, a darling of the dot-com era, has had a rough transition into the social media age. As the following infographic shows, the company&#8217;s performance has suffered particularly in the past eight years. Yahoo is still a powerhouse &#8212; after all, few can claim to control more than 1% of the Internet&#8217;s traffic &#8212; but its grip on the web is loosening. Meanwhile, the company&#8217;s management troubles &#8212; the latest is the controversy over CEO Scott Thompson&#8217;s fudged resume &#8212; continue. Overalll, the trends &#8212; outlined in this infographic from HighTable &#8212; aren&#8217;t good. Here&#8217;s hoping the company can turn things around. More About: Google, infographics, trending, YahooFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/yahoos-fall-from-grace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/yahoos-fall-from-grace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Platform For Doodles Pushes Bounds of Web Creativity</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Doodle.ly Quick Pitch: Doodle.ly is a creative social platform for doodlers. Hand-drawn masterpieces created on Doodle.ly can be shared to social networks. Genius Idea: Doodle.ly artists can draw straight on the website or sketch using the Doodle.ly iPad app. For Doodle.ly co-creators Evan Vogel and Darren Paul, the social platform they dreamed up and launched in July 2011 &#8212; is the place for innovation, creativity and inspiration on the web. The latest user-submitted drawings include doodles of bright flowers, dinosaurs and detailed sketches paying homage to Beastie Boys Rapper MCA, who died last Friday. The current number of doodles on the site stands at 32,000 &#8212; and counting. Doodle.ly is a web application and iPad app that lets users draw whatever they want and effortlessly share creations to the web. It takes under a minute for someone with a Twitter and Facebook to sign into Doodle.ly as a new user. That&#8217;s when the magic happens. There are different pen tools and colors, all free to use, so the boundaries are endless. Once the drawing, sketch or scribble is complete, doodles are shared on Twitter or Facebook automatically. The Doodle.ly team is working on building untethered account log-ins &#8212; to stop forced sharing. But for now, the world gets to experience all doodles created on Doodle.ly. Vogel and Paul say they see most of the doodles that come through. These startup guys have high standards for their &#8220;highly skilled&#8221; userbase. &#8220;We want to see the next Radiohead album or Time magazine cover created by doodlers,&#8221; Vogel told Mashable. An application update released on Tuesday is intended to make the social platform more interactive. New features include a &#8220;like button&#8221; on every doodle. Plus, a resulting &#8220;popular section&#8221; for trending images. These social features were inspired by Instagram&#8217;s internal system of &#8220;likes&#8221; and comments for the app&#8217;s filtered square images. There&#8217;s instant gratification in &#8220;likes,&#8221; Paul says. &#8220;This is really meant to be fun,&#8221; Paul says. &#8220;The new features we are launching are socialization features. What the &#8216;like&#8217; button does is take the app to the next level. You can like the doodle either by clicking the &#8216;like&#8217; button or by double tapping the doodle. This allows the cream to rise to the top.&#8221; The social platform is meant to be playful and positive. The hand-drawn aspect of this medium is special, says the creators. &#8220;We can see people around the world using this as a way to share a love note to a loved one, wish someone condolences or just to doodle a creative idea,&#8221; Paul says. Marketing teams are taking advantage of Doodle.ly&#8217;s simple drawing interface and sharing aspects. NHL team, the New Jersey Devils, recently used Doodle.ly on Fan Appreciation Night as a crowd-sourcing device. Hockey fans were asked to sketch a team-inspired doodle to feature on 17,000 Rally Rags for the first home game of the playoffs. After 10,000 votes were cast, the fan-submitted doodle was announced. The Doodle.ly team says the social platform of doodles is opening up new avenues of marketing and reaching consumers. The team, however, says they are currently not focused on monetization or partnerships. For now, the team is busy beefing up its product and working on releasing its API. Projects they have seen come out of their privately released API include a tool for collaborative doodles and a screen saver app. &#8220;We really want this to be a worldwide platform that is ubiquitous and can live out potential we believe it has,&#8221; Paul said. Are you a fan of web-based doodling? Tell us in the comments if this is a social platform you would use. Images courtesy of Doodle.ly Series Supported by Microsoft BizSpark The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark, a startup program that gives you three-year access to the latest Microsoft development tools, as well as connecting you to a nationwide network of investors and incubators. There are no upfront costs, so if your business is privately owned, less than three years old, and generates less than U.S.$1 million in annual revenue, you can sign up today. More About: bizspark, Business, Facebook, Social Media, social networking, Startups, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/doodle-ly-social-platform/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/doodle-ly-social-platform/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pirates Off Silicon Valley! 133 Startups to Live on This Rogue Boat [PICS]</title>
      <description>If you float it, they will come. That&#8217;s the lesson of Blueseed, a brave new utopia for startups that will be anchored in international waters, 12 miles off the coast of the San Francisco peninsula &#8212; aka Silicon Valley &#8212; sometime in the second half of 2013. The company calls its floating campus the &#8220;Googleplex of the sea.&#8221; Blueseed is funded by Peter Thiel, the billionaire co-founder of PayPal and early investor in Facebook. Famous for his libertarian views, Thiel is eager to create more havens for startups that are free from all government regulation &#8212; indeed, from all laws. (To that end, he has also pledged $1.25 million to the Seasteading Institute.) As laughable as it may sound to some, startups are flocking to fulfill Thiel&#8217;s vision. Blueseed has released the details of a survey on its website, which shows 133 international startups willing and eager to get on board. A plurality are from the US, but there&#8217;s also a lot of interest from India, Australia, Canada, Europe and practically every other area of the world: What&#8217;s the draw? Well, partly, it&#8217;s the fact that no U.S. passport or visa would be required to live and work on board the vessel. (If Blueseed is successful, this could be one way around the dearth of H1-B visas for engineers, something which is much lamented in the tech world.) Mostly, according to Blueseed&#8217;s survey, it&#8217;s the proximity to Silicon Valley, less than half an hour away by helicopter or somewhat more by shuttle boat and bus. But we wonder if the startup founders have been also tempted by the Googleplex-like array of amenities promised: high-speed wifi across the ship, 24-hour cafes, a full-service gym, concierge, medical services and (strangely enough for a libertarian venture) a post office. Blueseed is still very much in the concept stage. Check out the pictures below for renderings of various designs the company is considering, and let us know in the comments: would you live and work here? Here Be Libertarians X marks the spot in international waters where Blueseed intends to moor itself.Click here to view this gallery. More About: blueseed, googleplex, peter thielFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/blueseed-pirates-silicon-valley/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/blueseed-pirates-silicon-valley/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Instagram Took America by Storm [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Have you caught Instagram fever? The flaming hot mobile app and recent $1 billion Facebook acquisition now has more than 40 million users. This Online Colleges infographic shares some impressive stats behind the viral mobile photography app. Instagram gains one new user every second. One billion photos have been taken with the app &#8212; that&#8217;s roughly 58 photos uploaded each second. Instagram&#8217;s on track to hit 100 million users &#8212; joining the ranks of LinkedIn, Tumblr, Twitter and Facebook &#8212; two years after its initial iOS launch in October 2010. The infographic, created by an online university database, focuses on college students&#8217; adoption of the app. It suggests professors and campus professionals use Instagram to foster community through photo contests. It also recommends that students follow professors to learn about their interests outside of the classroom. How have you seen colleges use Instagram? Do you think students and professors should interact on social networks? BONUS: 15 LOL-Worthy Instagram Pics hr&gt; Come to the Dark Side Courtesy @wildchild1182Click here to view this gallery. More About: infographic, instagram</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/instagram-america/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/instagram-america/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Accessories That Celebrate the Iconic Power Symbol</title>
      <description>1. Power Standby Symbol Cufflinks These lovely silver cufflinks feature genuine, upcycled computer keys. Cost: $125.00Click here to view this gallery.With roots based in binary, the IEEE &#8220;power&#8221; symbol (or IEC &#8220;standby&#8221;) is a very familiar icon in consumer electronics. We are celebrating the recognizable design by sharing some accessories that feature the simple symbol. You probably hit several buttons featuring the design every single day, so why not join us and geek out with our collection of 15 powered-up accessories? You&#8217;ll find everything from jewelry and fashion to wall decor. SEE ALSO: 10 Awesome Accessories Featuring the Vintage Apple Logo [RAINBOWS] Take a look through the photo gallery above. Let us know in the comments below which of the items hit your &#8220;on&#8221; button. More About: accessories, fashion, features, geek, TechFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/power-symbol-accessories/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/power-symbol-accessories/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
