<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Videos Tailor-Made to Fascinate Your Cat</title>
      <description>Does your cat show an interest in the images and sounds coming from your computer? Did you know you can take that a step further with videos tailor-made for feline viewing pleasure? YouTube user Meghan Koley has created an entire channel dedicated to videos for cats. We asked Koley what inspired her to curate the content. &#8220;I was inspired to create the channel based on my experience with cats &#8212; [they're] entertained by certain videos just as much as humans are,&#8221; Koley told Mashable. &#8220;There are millions of videos of cute cats doing cute things on YouTube, so I thought why not entertain the YouTube star itself (and the owner) at the same time?&#8221; Koley&#8217;s channel, &#8220;Videos For Your Cat&#8221;, contains footage of various &#8220;cat bait&#8221; creatures to which cats respond best, according to Koley. &#8220;Cats almost seem to be as fascinated watching other animals as we are, but birds are obviously what every cat has evolved to love,&#8221; says Koley. &#8220;They flutter and move unpredictably; it&#8217;s perfect cat bait. Second would have to be fish, likely for the same reason.&#8221; Koley&#8217;s own cat, Ruka, a rescue from The Humane Society, is a fan of bird videos. &#8220;I like to protect the birds, as well as my cat from roaming city streets, so the videos are win-win,&#8221; says Koley. &#8220;Cats are the happiest when they get mental and physical stimulation throughout the day, so it&#8217;s as if he has the luxury of a good window to watch.&#8221; SEE ALSO: The Million Dollar Question: Why Does the Web Love Cats? We have collected seven of Koley&#8217;s videos in the gallery below. Test them on your cat and let us know in the comments if your feline was stimulated by the footage. For extra kudos, link to photos and videos of your cat watching the clips! 1. Spotted Orange Mollies in a Fish Tank "Little orange mollies swim and dart around this bright blue fish tank. Your cat will love the gentle bubbling of a real fish tank to complement these tiny snack-sized live bearing fish."Click here to view this gallery. Thumbnail image courtesy of Paul Sapiano More About: cats, Entertainment, features, gallery, Video, YouTubeFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/08/videos-for-your-cat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/08/videos-for-your-cat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[from heyjude] Know and show what you got! - TwentyFeet - TwentyFeet Wiki</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; The performance post for twitter is a cool way to recap your last week for your followers and friends. &lt;p&gt; It's for free. You can do that with your "forever free" twitter account. It contains the changes in your key twitter metrics. We will only post positive changes (e.g. a growing number of followers). The "My week on twitter"-post is published at the beginning of the week automatically (only for authorized accounts and if you choose so).</description>
      <link>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</link>
      <guid>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mike Wallace, '60 Minutes' Pioneer, Dies</title>
      <description>Mike Wallace, a pioneer of American broadcasting who confronted leaders and liars for the newsmagazine "60 Minutes" for four decades, has died, CBS News said. He was 93.</description>
      <link>http://mediadecoder.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/04/08/mike-wallace-60-minutes-pioneer-dies/</link>
      <guid>http://mediadecoder.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/04/08/mike-wallace-60-minutes-pioneer-dies/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On making a ruckus in your industry</title>
      <description>Bring forward a new idea or technology that disrupts and demands a response Change pricing dramatically Redefine a service as a product (or vice versa) Organize the disorganized, connect the disconnected Alter the speed to market radically Change the infrastructure, the rules or the flow of information Give away what used to be expensive and charge for something else Cater to the weird, bypassing the masses Take the lead on ethics (Or you could just wait for someone to tell you what they want you to do)</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/04/on-making-a-ruckus-in-your-industry.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/04/on-making-a-ruckus-in-your-industry.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Glass: One day... - YouTube</title>
      <description>We believe technology should work for you &#8212; to be there when you need it and get out of your way when you don't. A team within our Google[x] group started Pr...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Smartphone Users Taking Pictures, Updating Statuses at Restaurants [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Playing on your phone might be taboo while out to dinner, but more people are pulling out their mobile devices to snap and share pictures of meals and update their Facebook statuses, a new study suggests. According to an infographic by market research firm Lab42, about 19% of those that use their smartphone while at a restaurant update their status on Facebook. Meanwhile, about 24% said they take pictures of their entrees and 18% check-in to the restaurant on services such as Foursquare. Not surprisingly, smartphone users (20%) are also communicating with others to make dinner plans and 19% use mobile devices to find nearby restaurants. Meanwhile, about one in five people who use their smartphones during their dining out experience do so to view a menu online and find directions. Does it bother your when someone uses a phone while at a restaurant or is it now socially acceptable? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, robynmac More About: Mobile, smartphonesFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/smartphone-pics-restaurants-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/smartphone-pics-restaurants-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Tech This Week [PICS]</title>
      <description>1. Sony SmartWatch How smart is this Sony SmartWatch? Well, if you're an iPhone user it's as dumb as a fencepost, but if you're using an Android smartphone, it interacts via Bluetooth and lets you check your Facebook and Twitter feeds, read texts and email messages, take pictures with your smartphone's camera and check your calendar. It's not half bad-looking either -- look for it by the end of this month for $149. [via DVICE]Click here to view this gallery. It was an exciting week for tech, especially for those of us who can&#8217;t wait for the future to get here. Get this: A flying car arrived at a big auto show, there was a breakthrough in solar cells, we caught a glimpse of the coolest electric car yet, and we found a smart watch that&#8217;s as bright as it is beautiful. SEE ALSO: Previous editions of Top 10 Tech This Week Some of the developments seemed straight out of science fiction, while others will make life easier for us in the present day. Yes, it was a blockbuster week for tech, giving us fertile ground to narrow it all down to the Top 10 Tech This Week. Here&#8217;s last week&#8217;s Top 10 Tech. More About: cars, Gadgets, Tech, Top 10 Tech, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/08/top-10-tech-this-week-24/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/08/top-10-tech-this-week-24/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Look Inside the New Facebook HQ: You&#8217;ll Like This [PICS]</title>
      <description>Facebook HQ. You Like This The company is now completely moved out of its Palo Alto pad, and into the much more spacious Menlo Park facility it broke ground on last year. Click here to view this gallery. It&#8217;s been a little more than a year since Facebook bought a 57-acre campus on the outskirts of Menlo Park in Silicon Valley, and started the slow process of turning it into its headquarters of the future. Well, the future is now. As of last week, every last Facebook staffer has been moved into the Menlo Park facility, which is almost unrecognizable compared to the way it looked a year ago. Mashable checked in on the new Facebook HQ in December, but there&#8217;s been a lot going on since then. The entire campus has a fresh coat of paint &#8212; not to mention fresh graffiti-style spray painted and stenciled artwork everywhere. (Employees are encouraged to &#8220;hack their space.&#8221;) We got an unprecedented behind-the-scenes look at what makes Facebook tick &#8212; the high-tech booking systems, amusingly-named conference rooms, and premium caffeination facilities. (What really makes Facebook so eager to constantly upgrade itself? Two words: Philz Coffee.) We saw plenty of things that make working at the social network so much fun &#8212; including a wall where Jeremy Lin had marked his height, towering above the rest of the staff. Take a look at the pics, and tell us in the comments whether you&#8217;d want to work here. More About: Facebook, Facebook HQ, mark zuckerberg, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/facebook-hq/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/facebook-hq/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Could CISPA Be the Next SOPA?</title>
      <description>A bill introduced to the House of Representatives late last year could become the centerpiece of the next SOPA-style struggle between the tech community and Washington, D.C.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/could-cispa-next-sopa-142911795.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/could-cispa-next-sopa-142911795.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pill offering such bonuses as free shipping and free extra pills http://t.co/Eb1xlJaQ</title>
      <description>Kent Kearney: pill offering such bonuses as free shipping and free extra pills http://t.co/Eb1xlJaQ &#9733; Retweeted by Behaviour Needs Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://twttter.tk/</link>
      <guid>http://twttter.tk/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 25 Most Social CIOs: Who&#8217;s the Most Active in Social Media? [CHART]</title>
      <description>If you thought corporate titans spent all their time ensconced in ivory towers &#8212; too important to engage in social media &#8212; think again. Here&#8217;s a chart based on research that ranks the top 25 most social-media-active chief information officers (CIOs) of the Fortune 250. These social scores, developed by Social Strategist and Forbes columnist Mark Fidelman for cross-platform enterprise software developer harmon.ie, list which CIOs are the most socially active by examining and compiling activity on LinkedIn, Twitter and Google+ accounts, as well as counting mentions on social networks, corporate and individual blogs, Alexa scores, and simply Googling their information. By the way, the two CIOs who got a &#8220;special mention&#8221; aren&#8217;t working for a company in the Fortune 250. Why should we care who the most social CIOs are? Perhaps those C-Suite denizens who are more active in social media instill more trust in their customers. What do you think? Are you more likely to trust a company whose CIO extends a personal relationship through social media?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/08/top-25-social-cios/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/08/top-25-social-cios/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
