<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn&#8217;s Biggest Competitor Is a Facebook App That Just Hit 25 Million Users</title>
      <description>Two years and 25 million registered users after launching its professional network for Facebook, BranchOut is LinkedIn&#8217;s biggest competitor. &#8220;At this point, it&#8217;s Coke and Pepsi,&#8221; BranchOut CEO Rick Marini says of the company&#8217;s relationship with LinkedIn. BranchOut allows users to see which of their Facebook friends (or friends of friends) work at specific companies. Unlike LinkedIn, it doesn&#8217;t require users to build a professional network one person at a time. Rather, they simply connect to their pre-existing Facebook graphs. The interface works a lot like LinkedIn from there: users can fill in their work histories, send messages to their connections, collect endorsements and request introductions to friends of friends. The 45-employee startup&#8217;s business model also looks similar to that of its giant &#8212; and recently public &#8212; competitor. BranchOut hosts about 3 million job listings and has a product for recruiters called RecruiterConnect that works like LinkedIn Recruiter. The development of this latter product, which helps employers source talent, is what LinkedIn cited as a violation of its terms of service when it blocked BranchOut from accessing its API in July. BranchOut has 13 million monthly unique visitors, which according to AppData.com makes it the 31st most popular app on Facebook &#8212; ahead of Instagram, Skype, Twitter and Pinterest. Marini says much of the growth can be attributed to international adoption and new mobile users. About half of new members are from outside of the U.S., due partly to integrations with European career sites StepStone and totaljobs.com. These partnerships, along with a similar relationship with CareerBuilder in the U.S., allow job searchers to see connections who may help them get a particular job from within that job&#8217;s listing. SEE ALSO: Glassdoor Can Mine Your Facebook Friends to Help You Land a Job [VIDEO] BranchOut launched its first mobile app in November. By January, mobile accounted for 25% of the service&#8217;s traffic. Today, it accounts for 45% of all visits. Although reaching 25 million registered users looks less impressive when compared to LinkedIn&#8217;s 150 million, there are 850 million Facebook users for whom joining BranchOut is just a matter of accepting the app&#8217;s permissions. On Thursday, BranchOut announced a $25 million round of funding, bringing its total venture capital backing to $49 million. While building on Facebook is BranchOut&#8217;s greatest differentiator, it also makes the startup vulnerable to its host&#8217;s whims. When Facebook changes its features, the team of 45 needs to change BranchOut just as quickly. And if Facebook decides to launch a career feature, BranchOut will likely be toast. Marini doesn&#8217;t think that&#8217;s likely, though. &#8220;Facebook is a platform company,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Facebook wants to see companies disrupt multi-billion-dollar markets &#8212; like BranchOut disrupting LinkedIn in the professional networking space. They want to see that happen on their network.&#8221; Image courtesy of iStockphoto, narvikk More About: branchout, Facebook, jobs, linkedin</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/branchout-25-million/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/branchout-25-million/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Facebook Wreck Marriages?</title>
      <description>Real-Time Advice: Newlywed CEO Mark Zuckerberg may want to watch his status updates, divorce lawyers say. Facebook often gets blamed for breakups.</description>
      <link>http://blogs.smartmoney.com/advice/2012/05/21/does-facebook-wreck-marriages/?mod=1122</link>
      <guid>http://blogs.smartmoney.com/advice/2012/05/21/does-facebook-wreck-marriages/?mod=1122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coda 2</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://panic.com/coda/</link>
      <guid>http://panic.com/coda/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;My Last Wish&#8217; Is a Social Network Based on Death</title>
      <description>A new social network has an interesting premise: connecting people around the world based on what they want to do before they die. Called My Last Wish, the app encourages users to post wishes on a &#8216;Wish Wall&#8217; and then befriend others who might share their dreams. &#8220;I believed in the possibility that there can be two persons in this world with same hopes, dreams and wishes,&#8221; Kirtan Thaker, co-founder of the White Lotus Corporation, the group behind the app, told Mashable. &#8220;I was confident that if we create a app where this possibility can be turned into reality, people will love this concept and they will get a chance to make friends who are unknown but having just one thing in common which is the last wish.&#8221; When sharing a wish, users can also choose to attach their email address or phone number so others that share their dream can connect with them. Tapping on a person&#8217;s contact information within the app will add their information to the contacts list in your phone. A palm icon appears beside wishes, allowing you to &#8220;aLike&#8221; a wish you share, or &#8220;give a five&#8221; to that person to express your support for their wish and become friends. While definitely a little morbid, and certainly out of the ordinary, the app already has a little bit of a following. Posted wishes range from things such as traveling the world to writing a book. Thaker says that the ultimate goal behind the app is to help people make friends that share similar hopes and dreams, or even help someone potentially find his or her soul mate. White Lotus plans to add a location-based feature to the app in the future to help you find people located physically around you, and if the iOS version of the app does well the company plans to release an Android version as well. What do you think about My Last Wish? Is the app cool, or creepy? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: App, death, iOS, iphone</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/my-last-wish/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/my-last-wish/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HS Student&#8217;s Social-Media-Fueled Campaign Propels Him Into Local Office</title>
      <description>Josh Lafazan, an 18-year-old high school senior from Syosset, New York, shattered all kinds of records when he was elected to his school district&#8217;s board last week. He became the youngest-ever elected official in New York state, and voter turnout was well above normal. How did Lafazan make such an achievement possible? In part, thanks to smart use of the web and social media. While many commentators are marveling at the Internet&#8217;s ability to bring together large swaths of people from across nations, Lafazan&#8217;s campaign did just the opposite: he used his website and social media, such as Facebook and live video service Spreecast, to bring together his nearby friends and neighbors under his campaign&#8217;s banner. &#8220;Josh was the only candidate for school board to have a personal website,&#8221; said Jake Asman, Lafazan&#8217;s campaign manager and fellow Syosset High School student. &#8220;He really went out there and expressed his campaign views. He used his Facebook page and Spreecast the same way.&#8221; On Spreecast, Lafazan engaged in face-to-face town halls with his soon-to-be constituency. Asman credits the video site with a great deal of the campaign&#8217;s success. &#8220;Spreecast was a big one for us,&#8221; said Asman. &#8220;We had more than 2,000 views on our first Spreecast. Josh was able to interact directly, face-to-face with members of the community. It&#8217;s one thing to have a story on [the local news], it&#8217;s another for people to ask questions directly. He answered every question he got, it took almost two hours.&#8221; Lafazan also built up a sizable community of followers on Facebook. A note he posted thanking his supporters gathered more than 400 likes &#8212; an impressive feat for a candidate in a campaign with only a few thousand voters. Social media proved useful when the campaign took a turn for the bizarre. The Syosset school district accused Lafazan&#8217;s father, Jeffery, of stealing information about the district&#8217;s residents. An automated message that went out to voters before the election said that &#8220;Jeffrey Lafazan unlawfully removed district records that contained the names and addresses of residents. He removed the records without permission and ran away,&#8221; according to NBC. Lafazan&#8217;s father later returned the documents, saying he didn&#8217;t know he wasn&#8217;t allowed to take them. Lafazan, meanwhile, labeled the accusations as a &#8220;smear campaign.&#8221; He took to Facebook to explain his side of what happened, and Asman said that move helped Lafazan beat the rumors. &#8220;When the school district tried to pull their smear campaign, Josh hopped on Facebook and sent out a status with what had really happened,&#8221; said Asman. &#8220;It got 250 likes and 200 shares. People very quickly realized what was happening.&#8221; Of course, Lafazan campaigned hard in the offline world, too. &#8220;He was in the community and the high school every day, interacting with neighbors and other seniors that were 18 and could vote,&#8221; said Asman. Lafazan went on to win the election by more than 2,000 votes, or 82% of the total votes &#8212; and it looks like he&#8217;ll be using social media to govern, not just to campaign. &#8220;If anyone has any suggestions to help improve this district,&#8221; wrote Lafazan in a post-victory Facebook post, &#8220;do not hesitate to contact me and share those ideas with me.&#8221; How is social media changing local elections in your neighborhood? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, sjlocke More About: Facebook, Politics, Social Media, spreecast, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/josh-lafazan-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/josh-lafazan-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These Are the Most Engaging Brands on Facebook [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>As Facebook gears up for its initial public offering later this week, there&#8217;s been a lot of speculation about the company&#8217;s valuation. But there&#8217;s no denying that its worth to major and up-and-coming brands is invaluable, allowing Facebook users to interact and engage with companies in unprecedented ways. A new infographic from social marketing firm SocialBakers takes a look at which global brands are making the most of their Facebook presence. With 157 million Facebook users in the U.S. and 901 million on the site in total, about 83% of members are located outside the 50 states. This means there&#8217;s room for brands to grow their global reach. SEE ALSO: 10 Innovative Uses of Facebook Timeline for Brands Coca-Coca is the top global beverages brand on Facebook with 416 million fans, according to SocialBakers. Meanwhile, Starbucks dominates the food retail sector with 29 million users and apparel company Converse has 298 million fans on Facebook. The infographic also reveals the top ten countries in which global brands are engaging their audience, with the U.S. leading the pack with Starbucks, McDonald&#8217;s, Xbox, Walmart and Disneyland. Brazil comes in second &#8212; with L&#8217;Oreal Paris and Trident (Kraft) &#8212; followed by India with Vodafone and Pepsi. SocialBakers also notes that among the fastest moving global brands are Halls, Axe, Nokia and Sony. Which brands&#8217; social media strategies do you believe are most impressive? Let us know your opinion in the comments. More About: brands, Business, Facebook, MarketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/facebook-brands-global/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/facebook-brands-global/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nikola Tesla was the greatest geek who ever lived - The Oatmeal</title>
      <description>An ode to the father of the electric age.View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome overtakes Internet Explorer as the Web&#8217;s most used browser</title>
      <description>Google Chrome has been long expected to leapfrog Microsoft&#8217;s Internet Explorer (IE) to take its position as the Web&#8217;s most used browser and, according to data from Statcounter, the momentous change of leadership happened last week. The firm&#8217;s latest figures &#8212; spotted by Global Nerdy blogger Joey deVilla &#8211; show that Chrome&#8217;s line of usage creeped overtook IE&#8217;s for the first week ever, with Firefox, Safari and Opera completing the top five respectively. Statcounter&#8217;s findings give Google a double win, after the analytics site found that its mobile browser &#8212; Android Robot &#8212; had leapfrogged Opera to become the most popular option for mobile-based Web surfers in March. Measuring the Web is an imprecise science, very often based on scaling up small scale measurement surveys, but the gist of Statcounter&#8217;s data over the last year indicates that Chrome use is rising of Chrome at the expense of IE and Firefox, regardless of the exact precision of the data. Statcounter first found Chrome to be ahead for just one day, back on March 18, and its breakdown of browser usage over May to date puts Chrome and IE almost neck-and-neck at around 33 percent for the month. However, given that last week saw Chrome push ahead, May could become the first month during which the Google-owned browser has been the most popular option. Google Chrome has come on leaps and bounds since launching in 2008. Extensions are a key part of the browser&#8217;s appeal, with the latest additions including a scheduler for Google+, a Pinterest like script and these further 9 recommended extensions. Google is big on internationalising its service and Chrome is now different. For example, its My Chrome Theme social tool just became available in 36 more languages, to help increase its appeal across the planet. Microsoft isn&#8217;t taking the challenge lying down and Statcounter recently suggested that the latest version of IE (9) is making progress, and is seeing particularly marked usage over the weekends. Regardless of whether Chrome can maintain its momentum over the rest of May to top the month&#8217;s use, Chrome is on the up and we&#8217;d expect it to reign supreme in the Web browser world sooner rather than later.</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/google/2012/05/21/google-chrome-overtakes-internet-explorer-as-the-webs-most-used-browser/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/google/2012/05/21/google-chrome-overtakes-internet-explorer-as-the-webs-most-used-browser/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome Now the No. 1 Browser in the World</title>
      <description>If the numbers at StatCounter are accurate then the world has a new Web browser champion: Google Chrome.</description>
      <link>http://www.networkworld.com/news/2012/052112-chrome-browser-259480.html?fsrc=netflash-rss</link>
      <guid>http://www.networkworld.com/news/2012/052112-chrome-browser-259480.html?fsrc=netflash-rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube</title>
      <description>Jeff Pidgeon: SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where's the heat?</title>
      <description>Is that your goal? To find the next hot thing? Do you want to buy it, sell it, use it, eat it? In every industry where there's fashion (which is every industry), people spend an enormous amount of time looking for heat. It defines the cutting edge, determines what's in or out, what's hot or not. Two things worth considering: a. the hot thing isn't always the thing that's aligned with your goals. Sure, sometimes the most profitable item is also the hot item of the moment, but for many companies, market share or profitability or utility has not a lot to do with being on the cutting edge of fashion. And as a user, the hot item of the moment isn't necessarily the thing that will create value or even identify you as truly hip. b. The cycle of hot keeps getting shorter. You can chase this, but it's not free, and it might not get you where you want to go.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/wheres-the-heat.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/wheres-the-heat.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Fascinating Things We Learned From Reddit This Week</title>
      <description>1. What Your PC Is Doing During Shutdown This in-depth explanation of what the computer does when it shuts down is fascinating. For many in the tech world, this may seem like a no-brainer, but there are a lot of people who may believe the PC simply turns off and remains dead until the user turns the power back on. The discussion leads to why hard reboots and stopping software installations half-way are not good for your computer -- something basic users might not realize. Originally, the user posted his question on Google, but could only find information on viruses. Image courtesy of David MastersClick here to view this gallery.Reddit often gets a lot of flack. Under all of the chatter, upcoming memes and viral videos, there are tons of conversations that share at least one new, interesting fact every day. The web is moving past the stigma that crowdsourced sites like Wikipedia are unreliable. On Reddit, as it is with any source, users know that every fact must be carefully scrutinized. But Reddit is getting more credible every day. There are educated conversations happening with professionals in technology, fashion, medicine, science, history and pop culture &#8212; among other fields. Even celebrities and professionals are taking to the platform to hold casual interviews with its users, because let&#8217;s face it, these are some of the smartest people who see through the crap on the Internet. We&#8217;ve gathered five interesting facts you may, or may not, have already known that came from a discussion on Reddit. More About: computer, fact, fashion, features, reddit, Science, TED, water</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/reddit-learning/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/reddit-learning/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
