<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passwords Reset</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today the WordPress team noticed suspicious commits to several popular plugins (AddThis, WPtouch, and W3 Total Cache) containing cleverly disguised backdoors. We determined the commits were not from the authors, rolled them back, pushed updates to the plugins, and shut down access to the plugin repository while we looked for anything else unsavory.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re still investigating what happened, but as a prophylactic measure we&amp;#8217;ve decided to force-reset all passwords on WordPress.org. To use the forums, trac, or commit to a plugin or theme, you&amp;#8217;ll need to &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/support/bb-login.php"&gt;reset your password to a new one&lt;/a&gt;. (Same for bbPress.org and BuddyPress.org.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a user, make sure to never use the same password for two different services, and we encourage you not to reset your password to be the same as your old one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Second, if you use &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/addthis/"&gt;AddThis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/wptouch/"&gt;WPtouch&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/w3-total-cache/"&gt;W3 Total Cache&lt;/a&gt; and there&amp;#8217;s a possibility you could have updated in the past day, make sure to visit your updates page and upgrade each to the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://wordpress.org/news/2011/06/passwords-reset/</link>
      <guid>http://wordpress.org/news/2011/06/passwords-reset/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo&#8217;s 360 Degree Turnaround</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://tctechcrunch.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/turnaround.jpg' class="snap_nopreview shot" alt="" /&gt;Oof, Yahoo. The &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/16/technology/16yahoo.html"&gt;Alibaba dispute&lt;/a&gt;, just the most recent Yahoo trainwreck, is still a fresh wound for shareholders. And things are getting worse.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yahoo CEO Carol Bartz has long promised a turnaround at the lagging company. But we&amp;#8217;ve been digging for new information about the state of Yahoo in advance of the annual &lt;a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Yahoo-Annual-Meeting-of-bw-280507278.html?x=0&amp;amp;.v=1"&gt;shareholder meeting&lt;/a&gt; later this week, and everything we&amp;#8217;re hearing isn&amp;#8217;t good. One investor we spoke with said &amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s a turnaround alright, but it&amp;#8217;s a 360&#176; turnaround. Basically, they&amp;#8217;re spinning in circles.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Things we&amp;#8217;ve learned from multiple sources:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Yahoo is quietly looking at replacement CEO candidates. Fox Digital Chief &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/jonathan-miller"&gt;Jon Miller&lt;/a&gt; has had &amp;#8220;early and unofficial&amp;#8221; discussions with the Yahoo board of directors about taking over as CEO. It&amp;#8217;s thought that Yahoo board member &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/david-kenny"&gt;David Kenny&lt;/a&gt;, who&amp;#8217;s long wanted the job, is also a current candidate. Other names have been whispered. Bartz may know that there&amp;#8217;s an active if unofficial search going on, but only if she&amp;#8217;s hearing it indirectly, says one source.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/prabhakar-raghavan"&gt;Prabhakar Raghavan&lt;/a&gt;, previously head of Yahoo Research, was promoted to Chief Strategy Officer. He is &amp;#8220;responsible for developing the long-term corporate strategy and technical vision for Yahoo.&amp;#8221; His lack of business experience has alarmed some investors, who see it as a poor judgement call by Bartz.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Worst of all, Yahoo&amp;#8217;s financial results are said to be significantly below what the street expects, even after expectations were lowered in May. We expect significant revisions to the guidance Yahoo will be giving analysts going forward based on what we&amp;#8217;ve heard, particularly for the last half of the year. Even so, the stock price may not drop much. &amp;#8220;Investors have already priced the main Yahoo business to zero,&amp;#8221; said one investor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Chairman &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/roy-bostock"&gt;Roy Bostock&lt;/a&gt; seems to be the main target of upset shareholders right now. It would be too disruptive to remove Bartz from the board of directors, our sources say, but sending a clear message that they don&amp;#8217;t support Bostock would be appropriate. There&amp;#8217;s little chance of him actually getting less than a 50% vote, and Yahoo can override a shareholder vote anyway. But if 25% or more of the votes are witheld, it&amp;#8217;s likely he&amp;#8217;ll be forced to step down. Of course, we&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href="http://www.searchengineworld.com/yahoo/3458188.htm"&gt;seen this movie&lt;/a&gt; before and Bostock has survived.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One person we spoke with was willing to go on record. Eric Jackson, who&amp;#8217;s been &lt;a href="http://blogs.forbes.com/ericjackson/2011/04/20/to-unlock-yahoos-value-bartz-should-take-a-hike/?partner=yahootix"&gt;openly critical&lt;/a&gt; of Yahoo for years, said he hopes for a &lt;a href="http://blogs.forbes.com/ericjackson/2011/05/26/why-drastic-change-is-needed-on-june-23rd-for-yahoos-board/"&gt;board level shakeup&lt;/a&gt; at the meeting on June 23. As for Bartz, Jackson threw this zinger: &amp;#8220;Personally I&amp;#8217;d like to see [Softbank CEO] &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/masayoshi-son-2"&gt;Masayoshi Son&lt;/a&gt; or [Alibaba founder] &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/jack-ma"&gt;Jack Ma&lt;/a&gt; become CEO of Yahoo.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;These are really just the raw notes from our discussions. We have a couple of other major stories developing around Yahoo as well. But for now we just have to wait and see how things play out at the shareholder meeting, and whether the Yahoo board can avoid a massive no confidence vote.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cbw snap_nopreview"&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_header"&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/javascripts/widget.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_header_text"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/"&gt;CrunchBase Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_content"&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subheader"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/yahoo"&gt;Yahoo!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subcontent"&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/cbw/company/yahoo.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_footer"&gt;Information provided by &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/"&gt;CrunchBase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/316316/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&amp;amp;blog=11718616&amp;amp;post=316316&amp;amp;subd=tctechcrunch&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/XFz0YzU5_OlpJJiOMlUSv5O0qcg/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/XFz0YzU5_OlpJJiOMlUSv5O0qcg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/XFz0YzU5_OlpJJiOMlUSv5O0qcg/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/XFz0YzU5_OlpJJiOMlUSv5O0qcg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=3sPdCF1jt4U:HUSWrtJhe2Q:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/3sPdCF1jt4U" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/21/yahoos-360-degree-turnaround/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/21/yahoos-360-degree-turnaround/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Confidence</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very few people succeed in business without a degree of confidence. Yet everyone, from young people in their first real jobs to seasoned leaders in the upper ranks of organizations, have moments &amp;#8212; or days, months, or even years &amp;#8212; when they are unsure of their ability to tackle challenges. No one is immune to these bouts of insecurity at work, but they don't have to hold you back. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the Experts Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; "Confidence equals security equals positive emotion equals better performance," says Tony Schwartz, the president and CEO of The Energy Project and the author of &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Be-Excellent-Anything-Four-Transforming/dp/1451610262/ref=sr_1_1"&gt;Be Excellent at Anything: The Four Keys to Transforming the Way We Work and Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. And yet he concedes that "insecurity plagues consciously or subconsciously every human being I've met." Overcoming this self-doubt starts with honestly assessing your abilities (and your shortcomings) and then getting comfortable enough to capitalize on (and correct) them, adds Deborah H. Gruenfeld, the Moghadam Family Professor of Leadership and Organizational Behavior and Co-Director of the Executive Program for Women Leaders at Stanford Graduate School of Business. Here's how to do that and get into the virtuous cycle that Schwartz describes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Your piano teacher was right: practice does make perfect. "The best way to build confidence in a given area is to invest energy in it and work hard at it," says Schwartz. Many people give up when they think they're not good at a particular job or task, assuming the exertion is fruitless. But Schwartz argues that deliberate practice will almost always trump natural aptitude. If you are unsure about your ability to do something &amp;#8212; speak in front of large audience, negotiate with a tough customer &amp;#8212; start by trying out the skills in a safe setting. "Practice can be very useful, and is highly recommended because in addition to building confidence, it also tends to improve quality. Actually deliver the big presentation more than once before the due date. Do a dry run before opening a new store," says Gruenfeld. Even people who are confident in their abilities can become more so with better preparation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get out of your own way&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Confident people aren't only willing to practice, they're also willing to acknowledge that they don't &amp;#8212; and can't &amp;#8212; know everything. "It's better to know when you need help, than not," says Gruenfeld. "A certain degree of confidence &amp;#8212; specifically, confidence in your ability to learn &amp;#8212; is required to be willing to admit that you need guidance or support." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the flip side, don't let modesty hold you back. People often get too wrapped up in what others will think to focus on what they have to offer, says Katie Orenstein, founder and director of The OpEd Project, a non-profit that empowers women to influence public policy by submitting opinion pieces to newspapers. "When you realize your value to others, confidence is no longer about self-promotion," she explains. "In fact, confidence is no longer the right word. It's about purpose." Instead of agonizing about what others might think of you or your work, concentrate on the unique perspective you bring. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get feedback when you need it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; While you don't what to completely rely on others' opinions to boost your ego, validation can also be very effective in building confidence. Gruenfeld suggests asking someone who cares about your development as well as the quality of your performance to tell you what she thinks. Be sure to pick people whose feedback will be entirely truthful; Gruenfeld notes that when performance appraisals are only positive, we stop trusting them. And then use any genuinely positive commentary you get as a talisman. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also remember that some people need more support than others, so don't be shy about asking for it. "&lt;a href="http://www.thewhitehouseproject.org/"&gt;The White House Project&lt;/a&gt; finds, for example, that many women need to be told they should run for office before deciding to do so. Men do not show this pattern of needing others' validation or encouragement," says Gruenfeld. It's okay if you need praise. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take risks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Playing to your strengths is a smart tactic but not if it means you hesitate to take on new challenges. Many people don't know what they are capable of until they are truly tested "Try things you don't think you can do. Failure can be very useful for building confidence," says Gruenfeld. Of course, this is often easier said than done. "It feels bad to not be good at something. There's a leap of faith with getting better at anything," says Schwartz. But don't assume you should feel good all the time. In fact, stressing yourself is the only way to grow. Enlisting help from others can make this easier. Gruenfeld recommends asking supervisors to let you experiment with new initiatives or skills when the stakes are relatively low and then to support you as you tackle those challenges. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principles to Remember&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Be honest with yourself about what you know and what you still need to learn &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Practice doing the things you are unsure about&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Embrace new opportunities to prove you can do difficult things&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Don't:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Focus excessively on whether you or not you have the ability - think instead about the value you provide &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Hesitate to ask for external validation if you need it &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Worry about what others think &amp;#8212; focus on yourself, not a theoretical and judgmental audience&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Case Study #1: Get the knowledge and get out of your own way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; In 2010, Mark Angelo, was asked by the CEO of Hospital for Special Surgery in New York to create and implement a program to improve quality and efficiency. Mark was relatively new to the organization. He had worked as a business fellow for the previous year but had recently taken on the role of director of operations and service lines. Even though he had background in operations strategy from his days as a management consultant, he was not familiar with the Lean/Six Sigma principles he'd need to use for this project and didn't feel equipped to build the program from scratch. He was particularly concerned he wouldn't be able to gain the necessary support from the hospital's physicians and nurses. What would they think of a young administrator with no hospital experience telling them how to improve quality and increase efficiency?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For five months, Mark struggled to get the project on track and his confidence suffered. He knew that his apprehension was in part due to his lack of knowledge of Six Sigma. He read a number of books and articles on the subject, talked to consulting firms that specialized in it, and spoke with hospitals that had been successful in developing and implementing similar programs. This helped but he realized he still didn't know if he would be able to get the necessary people on board. "I was anxious and stressed because I had no idea how I was going to transform the organization. I knew I couldn't do it on my own. It was going to take a collective effort that included our management team and all of our staff," he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He talked with the CEO who had supported him since the beginning. He also looked to his family for emotional support. Through these conversations he realized that his anxiety stemmed from a desire to be liked by his colleagues and therefore to avoid conflict. "After many discussions with my CEO and observing how he handled these situations, I learned that it is better to strive to be well-respected than well-liked," he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This was a turning point for Mark. Instead of worrying so much about what others thought of him, he focused on doing what was best for the patient and the institution. In December, he presented the vision for the program to the entire medical staff. While he was nervous about how it would be received, he knew this was a critical moment. "I was able to get up in front of one our toughest constituencies and present the vision that we had been developing over the past few months," he says. His presentation was met with applause. "In the end, my confidence grew by leaps and bounds and we were able to design a program that has since taken off with great success across the hospital. I was able to overcome my mental blocks and knowledge deficits to build a program that will truly help transform how we approach performance improvement and patient care," he says. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case Study #2: Know the value you bring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Julie Zhou knew she had things to say but she wasn't sure how to get heard. As a product design manager at Facebook, she had developed valuable expertise in the products she worked on. Yet, she lacked the confidence to share her ideas. She was used to being one of very few women in the room. That had been the case when she was studying computer science at Stanford and it was still true now that she was at Facebook. She knew this meant she needed to make a concerted effort to speak up. But being the minority voice wasn't the only reason she felt unsure of herself. She says that she also suffered from "imposter syndrome," feeling as if she hadn't earned a right to her ideas; she had somehow ended up where she was accidently, not through hard work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Last November, she published a &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/11/30/opinion/30zhuo.html"&gt;piece in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the danger of anonymity in online discussions. "It was a matter of someone saying you can do it," she explains. "It had never occurred to me that I could be published. But it actually wasn't hard at all." The reaction she got in the workshop and afterward back at Facebook boosted her confidence. "Since then, she's gotten a lot of support from colleagues, which has emboldened her to speak her mind. "Of course it's still a work in progress, but now I'm a much more confident speaker and writer," she says. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.harvardbusiness.org/~ff/harvardbusiness?a=9QfCOWWYkQk:n2PvEfojNjI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/harvardbusiness?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.harvardbusiness.org/~ff/harvardbusiness?a=9QfCOWWYkQk:n2PvEfojNjI:bcOpcFrp8Mo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/harvardbusiness?d=bcOpcFrp8Mo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/harvardbusiness/~4/9QfCOWWYkQk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://blogs.hbr.org/hmu/2011/04/how-to-build-confidence.html</link>
      <guid>http://blogs.hbr.org/hmu/2011/04/how-to-build-confidence.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final Cut Pro X</title>
      <description>Apple hat soeben Final Cut Pro X vorgestellt, eine neue Version der Videobearbeitungssoftware, die Videoschnitt laut Apple "komplett neu definiert". Final Cut Pro X beinhaltet Funktionen wie Magnetic Timeline, mit der man auf einer flexiblen, spurlosen Leinwand schneiden kann; eine automatische Inhaltsanalyse, die Daten beim Import nach Aufnahmeart, Medium und Personen kategorisiert; und Hintergrund-Rendering welches es erlaubt ohne Unte&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.feedsportal.com/c/32215/f/424463/s/160e69c3/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;div class='mf-viral'&gt;&lt;table border='0'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://res.feedsportal.com/viral/sendemail2_de.html?title=Apple+ver%C3%B6ffentlicht+Final+Cut+Pro+X&amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.mactechnews.de%2Fnews%2Findex.html%3Fid%3D150298" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rss.feedsportal.com/images/emailthis2.gif" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://res.feedsportal.com/viral/bookmark_de.cfm?title=Apple+ver%C3%B6ffentlicht+Final+Cut+Pro+X&amp;link=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.mactechnews.de%2Fnews%2Findex.html%3Fid%3D150298" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rss.feedsportal.com/images/bookmark.gif" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/106213701804/u/0/f/424463/c/32215/s/160e69c3/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/106213701804/u/0/f/424463/c/32215/s/160e69c3/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.mactechnews.de/news/index.html?id=150298</link>
      <guid>http://www.mactechnews.de/news/index.html?id=150298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final Cut Pro X</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2678520"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.apple.com/finalcutpro/</link>
      <guid>http://www.apple.com/finalcutpro/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNN has some fun with Obama's war...</title>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;font size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;CNN has some fun with Obama's war&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font face="Arial" size="1"&gt;&lt;i&gt;(First column, 10th story, &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+rss%2Fcnn_freevideo+%28RSS%3A+Video%29#/video/us/2011/03/21/moos.libya.war.souvenirs.cnn"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;hr style="height: 1px; border-style: none; color: #666666; background-color: #666666;"/&gt;&lt;font face="Arial" size="2"&gt;Related stories:&lt;div class="related-links" id="R:C1:S10"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/news/stories/0311/51736.html"&gt;Kucinich: Defund Libya attack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-1368693/Libya-Obamas-coalition-unwilling-asks-does-West-right-kill-Gaddafi.html"&gt;NATO members squabble; no one wants responsibility for bombing Libya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2011/03/22/eric_holder_gaddafis_presence_in_libya_has_got_to_end.html"&gt;HOLDER: Gadhafi's Presence In Libya 'Has Got To End'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/03/22/libya-russia-putin-idUSLDE72L2CB20110322"&gt;Putin urges all responsible for Libya deaths to pray 'for salvation of their own souls'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/QGPNkXqfD0yMeQbBuV1N_6yjqKg/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/QGPNkXqfD0yMeQbBuV1N_6yjqKg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/QGPNkXqfD0yMeQbBuV1N_6yjqKg/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/QGPNkXqfD0yMeQbBuV1N_6yjqKg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=YUeP6_54aXg:QRhLlMSBTn0:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=YUeP6_54aXg:QRhLlMSBTn0:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?i=YUeP6_54aXg:QRhLlMSBTn0:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=YUeP6_54aXg:QRhLlMSBTn0:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=YUeP6_54aXg:QRhLlMSBTn0:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?i=YUeP6_54aXg:QRhLlMSBTn0:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DrudgeReportFeed/~4/YUeP6_54aXg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.cnn.com/video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+rss%252Fcnn_freevideo+%2528RSS%253A+Video%2529</link>
      <guid>http://www.cnn.com/video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+rss%252Fcnn_freevideo+%2528RSS%253A+Video%2529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazing WebGL demo</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2543628"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.ro.me/film</link>
      <guid>http://www.ro.me/film</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips for Transitioning From College to Startup Life</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/&amp;title=5 Tips for Transitioning From College to Startup Life&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/college-to-startup.jpg" alt="" title="college-to-startup" width="225" height="141" class="alignright size-full wp-image-652101" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elliott Spelman is an intern at &lt;a href="https://www.wepay.com/" target="_blank"&gt;WePay&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to collect payments online without the hassle. You can contact him at elliott.spelman@wepay.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years and three internships later, I&#8217;m a graduate of USC. Like a lot of people my age, I&#8217;ve become pretty comfortable with the fact that I don&#8217;t really know what I want to do in life. Every graduation speaker I&#8217;ve ever listened to, from Steve Ballmer to Mr. Gowen, my elementary school gym teacher, has urged the same advice: Do what you&#8217;re passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For people in my position, though, there seems to be a choice between doing a job you love and doing a job that&#8217;s available to you. We&#8217;re left with the question: If doing something rewarding is the ultimate goal, what if it takes some time to figure it out?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because I&amp;#8217;m not on a prescribed career path doesn&#8217;t mean I&#8217;m not interested in anything. On the contrary, actually. My college resume is a veritable potpourri of potential professions. All three of my college internships were tied to personal interests (non-profits, travel, music). I majored in economics and creative writing. I pledged a fraternity and worked for the geography department one summer. And now I&#8217;m feeding my interests again, picking a summer internship at a tech startup in Silicon Valley over other full-time job offers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People ask me all the time, with genuine concern in their faces: &#8220;Aren&#8217;t you worried about what happens at the end of the summer?&#8221; The honest answer is no. If I have to sacrifice my interests for the sake of long-term financial security at the age of 21, then in the words of professor &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hubert_J._Farnsworth"&gt;Hubert J. Farnsworth&lt;/a&gt;: &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to live on this planet anymore.&#8221; Plus, if for some reason the job isn&#8217;t right, or if something else pops up, it&#8217;s only a three-month commitment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the winding path toward a more permanent career, I&amp;#8217;ve picked up a few pieces of wisdom for my fellow interns out there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 1. Understand How People See Your Generation&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/mr-rogers-640.jpg" title="Mr. Rogers"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#8217;s a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube/"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; clip out there of a few anchors on Fox News talking about how Mr. Rogers&#8217; Neighborhood has &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=29lmR_357rA" target="_blank"&gt;ruined a generation&lt;/a&gt; of young people who now feel special. Entitlement, I&#8217;m afraid, is the knock on our generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you objectively measure something like that? I&#8217;ve been fired for it (&#8220;Your generation needs to learn that you do not give ultimatums to a superior&#8221;), and I&#8217;ve heard it muttered (&amp;#8220;F*****g kids these days&#8221;), but basically, your job is to prove these people wrong. It doesn&#8217;t take much. Show that you are genuinely interested and engaged by the people around you. Learn how to be competent. Make your coworkers trust you, and make them look good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 2. Take Advantage of Your Generation&#8217;s Gifts&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are the first wave of people raised on the Internet. We stay connected. We rely on other people. We understand our constant access to infinite information and we adjust ourselves accordingly. Compared to those for whom the Internet is a struggle, we have the opportunity to be exponentially more productive in a fraction of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My advice is to use the applications that best organize your mind &amp;#8212; the ones that help you develop methods and routines that feel comfortable. When it comes to documents, I&#8217;m a Google Apps kind of guy. Some people prefer Dropbox or MobileMe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone our age should be able to find the answer to any basic question within a minute. &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/google"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/wikipedia"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; should be second nature. After all, part of the reason we&#8217;re seen as entitled is because we have access to a whole array of shortcuts that have never existed before. Use them to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 3. There&#8217;s a Reason for Professionalism&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve worked at an internship where everybody in the office ironed their pants every morning, and I&#8217;ve worked with people in flip-flops. Neither one is intrinsically better than the other. You have to understand that each place you work has its own corporate culture and in order to do well you have to adjust yourself to fit it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If people are going to spend nine hours each day cramped together, they have to find ways to stay sane. Some bosses hand out beers at five, and some require their employees to wear a certain color tie. If you want peoples&#8217; respect, you have to give in to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#8217;s basically what professionalism is: A code of behavior that greases the wheels and keeps everyone out of each other&amp;#8217;s way. You shouldn&#8217;t feel like the code is a burden. If it starts to feel like you&#8217;re wearing a mask to work every day, don&#8217;t be afraid to question if the job is a good fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 4. Enjoy the People You Work With&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/staff-people.jpg" title="Business Team Image"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the single most underrated aspect of career decisions. Granted, it&#8217;s very difficult to know what the person hiring you will turn out to be like, but that&amp;#8217;s where internships come in. Internships give you a taste of what kind of people get drawn to what kind of careers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fact is, even with the mask of professionalism, your coworkers rub off on you. You can&#8217;t avoid them. If you hate who you work with, it can be tough to convince yourself that what you are doing is worthwhile, even if you would normally enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 5. Use Your Education Wisely&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless you studied accounting or architecture as an undergrad (and even if you did), there is a very small chance that your college education will come in particularly handy for your first job. There are, however, unexpected elements of your education that will be tremendously useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At my PR gig, I gave my boss an essay by Georg Simmel that I thought he might find interesting. Working at the tutoring center, I helped format databases of small donors with Excel formulas I&#8217;d learned in ECON317. And now, working for a tech company, I find myself blogging, pulling from all kinds of things I learned in creative writing workshops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess my general piece of advice here would be to never assume it&#8217;s okay to stop learning. There is no direct correlation between your formal education and what you do after, so remember to always stay curious and flexible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/jump/mash.to/btf_j_s/;sec0=;sec1=;sz=600x50;ord=323"&gt;&lt;img src="http://ad.doubleclick.net/ad/mash.to/btf_j_s/;sec0=;sec1=;sz=600x50;ord=323"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/triciawang/" target="_blank"&gt;Tricia Wang &#29579;&#22307;&#25463;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/simonk/2672103736/" target="_blank"&gt;Simon King&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=2704655"&gt;H-Gall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/advice/"&gt;advice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/college/"&gt;college&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/education/"&gt;education&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/how-to/"&gt;how to&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/startup/"&gt;startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/startups/"&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/MashStartups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Startups on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Startups channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VZU8Ek3ov-_Xg9CXDeF8okbtO4g/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VZU8Ek3ov-_Xg9CXDeF8okbtO4g/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VZU8Ek3ov-_Xg9CXDeF8okbtO4g/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VZU8Ek3ov-_Xg9CXDeF8okbtO4g/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Wx1ee91iKq8:u6E57IjIqpA:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/Wx1ee91iKq8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/06/17/college-startup-transition/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startup Seeks to Personalize Content With Artificial Intelligence [INVITES]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://trap.it/"&gt;Trapit&lt;/a&gt; is today launching the beta version of its content recommendation service. The start-up calls itself a &amp;#8220;Pandora for content,&amp;#8221; and it&amp;#8217;s a sister company to the virtual personal assistant app &lt;a href="http://siri.com/"&gt;Siri&lt;/a&gt;, which came out of the same artificial intelligence research project at SRI International &amp;#8212; and was &lt;a href="https://allthingsd.com/20100428/apple-snags-siri/"&gt;bought by Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/files/2011/06/trapit_04_new.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-Hero wp-image-88773" title="trapit_04_new" src="http://allthingsd.com/files/2011/06/trapit_04_new-640x344.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="344" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Trapit users create their own content &amp;#8220;Traps&amp;#8221; with keywords, and subscribe to popular and trending Traps. Then content comes in through 50,000 sources that have been vetted for quality and to screen out SEO bait, content farms, and spammers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once users curate their Trapit sources, they can visit site to scan through news, and click through to read the actual articles on the sites where they were published. Trapit internalizes implicit and explicit signals to train its recommendations to each user.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most of that is pretty normal practive for a personalized news site, but Trapit has an interesting approach to building its source list: human intelligence. That doesn&amp;#8217;t mean adding new sites by hand. What the company does is actively scan social networks for new sources of shared content and add them to its index.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Though &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20110308/zite-launches-even-more-personalized-ipad-magazine-app/"&gt;personalized news sites have a rough track record&lt;/a&gt;, iPad applications like Flipboard and Zite have recently attracted &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20110414/exclusive-flipboard-confirms-50-million-funding-at-200-million-valuation/"&gt;attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20110506/flipboard-triples-daily-usage-in-two-months-after-speed-improvements/"&gt;and usage&lt;/a&gt; by customizing for the consumption environment of the iPad. Trapit, by contrast, is Web-only for now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;With 25 million iPads shipped, even though it&amp;#8217;s an exciting interface, we still believe the vast majority of of consumption is on the browser,&amp;#8221; said Hank Nothhaft, Jr., Trapit&amp;#8217;s chief product officer, in a phone interview. &amp;#8220;Some of the beautiful apps demo well, but on a day-to-day basis they&amp;#8217;re not as great for consuming.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Trapit is more about deep personalization,&amp;#8221; Nothhaft continued. &amp;#8220;The iPad stuff is more about next evolution of the RSS reader.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Palo Alto, Calif.-based Trapit is funded with $2 million in angel funding and has 10 employees. The company eventually plans to make money through premium subscriptions and partnerships with paywalled publishers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://allthingsd.com/20110620/trapit-launches-personalized-content-recommender/</link>
      <guid>http://allthingsd.com/20110620/trapit-launches-personalized-content-recommender/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Day of Rage' Looms...</title>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt; Oil prices are finally retreating from two-and-half year highs but the market is bracing for more volatility as anti-government protests threaten to spread beyond the borders of Libya towards the world's top exporter Saudi Arabia. &lt;a href="http://www.drudgefeed.com/vg2/day_of_rage_looms#disqus_thread"&gt;[Discuss]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.drudgefeed.com/l/scr2Y"&gt;[Link]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/HUKt2V1D6j6_OKsxoIix3zbNChA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/HUKt2V1D6j6_OKsxoIix3zbNChA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/HUKt2V1D6j6_OKsxoIix3zbNChA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/HUKt2V1D6j6_OKsxoIix3zbNChA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Drudgefeedcom-DrudgeReportRssFeed/~4/chUmeNnTrqg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://m.cnbc.com/id/41980666</link>
      <guid>http://m.cnbc.com/id/41980666</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
