<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>O'Brien: Social media has changed the Web, but can it make a buck? - San Jose Mercury News</title>
      <description>Amid the fallout from Facebook's IPO is renewed skepticism about its business model. What looked like a juggernaut when it first filed to go public is now besieged with questions about the effectiveness of its advertising and the impact of mobile computing. Many of those same doubts apply to the cluster of social media and networking companies that went public over the past year. as well as the host of still private, second-tier social companies that are growing fast but generating little or no revenue. That's stunning, really, because a year ago it seemed like the pending run of IPOs by social media and networking companies was poised to put to rest all those doubts about this sector's sustainability. Instead, they still face a fairly fundamental question: Can successful social media companies also be successful businesses? "There was a perception just two weeks ago that when the big boy went public that it would mean these guys were all grown up," said Michael Pachter, an analyst at Wedbush Securities. "The share price pull back tells you investors are not convinced. "These guys need to prove to investors that not only do we really have a wonderful product, but we know how to monetize it." For the record, I believe that Facebook will become a monster of a business in the coming years. Its 900 million users are spending unprecedented amounts of time on the site, allowing the company to amass incredible data about their interests. And don't forget that the bulk of advertising still occurs offline, but is eventually expected to go digital, where Facebook is in a great position to capture a huge share. "Marketers want big audiences," said Tom Bedecarre, CEO of AKQA, a digital marketing firm. "And Facebook has the largest. I just think the most savvy digital people see the huge upside and potential for a platform like Facebook." But many advertisers are still trying to figure out how to effectively leverage these audiences and demonstrate clear returns on their ad dollars. As a result, the jury on social media as a business is still out, especially where investors are concerned. So what's happened is that even social superstars like Facebook, Zynga, Groupon, Pandora and Yelp have all seen their stocks trade well below their IPO prices. Martin Pyykkonen, an analyst with Wedge Partners, said investors are still trying to understand the fundamentals of these businesses, and it will likely take a couple years of strong earnings results for them to be persuaded. "I compare it to Google's early days," he said. "We didn't know a whole lot about the business. And they didn't tell us a whole lot." The lone standout in the social sector is LinkedIn, which remains close to double its IPO price. Investors seem to have a rosier view because LinkedIn is far less dependent on advertising, the mother's milk of just about every other Web 2.0 company. I should note that this generation of startups has defiantly been in no rush to prove themselves as businesses. Almost all decided to build a really cool service that put the user first. Amass a gigantic audience. Figure out the business model later. But having reached critical mass, these companies continue to struggle to convert such large numbers of users into a convincing business model. Yelp just posted a loss about three times as large as the same quarter a year ago in its first quarter as a public company. Analysts are split about whether Groupon can generate profits through its daily deals. The royalties Pandora pays for music cast doubt on its long-term survival. Facebook stands above them all, both because its user base is many times larger and also because it generated $3 billion in revenue last year. But soon after filing its IPO papers, the buzz around its financials shifted from confirmation of its status as juggernaut to clues into its weaknesses. These fears were exacerbated by reports it was lowering its estimates for revenue this quarter and news that GM was pulling its ad spending on Facebook. Debra Aho Williamson, principal analyst at eMarketer in Seattle, noted that when the firm published its most recent forecast for digital advertising back in February, it projected that Facebook revenue would probably double again this year to $6 billion, a number she said is likely now out of reach. "Consumers have adopted social media a whole lot faster than advertisers," Williamson said. "It's taking them a lot longer to figure out how to fit social media into their plans." Compounding the problem is that just as these companies have reached this point, the shift away from desktop PCs to smartphones and tablets seems to be accelerating. And for the most part, their business models are not nearly as effective in the mobile realm, generating little or no revenue. "Mobile comes along and everything they built doesn't fit like a glove," said Keith Teare, founder of Archimedes Lab, an incubator focused on mobile technologies. "That was OK when it was a dribble. But it seems to have grown into a torrent." If anyone is going to figure this out, though, I'm betting on Facebook. I think investors are overreacting to its current revenue estimate changes. Plus, it did just raise a big chunk of money it can use to invest in its business and acquire others. "I go back to the fundamentals," said Charlene Li, founder of the Altimeter Group. "Is the company profitable? Yes. Does it have very enthusiastic cutomers? Yes. Look, people have been predicting the death of Facebook for five years. But I've never seen a company reinvent itself as successfullly as Facebook has again and again." But here's a scary thought: What if Facebook can't turn social into a robust business? What hope is there for a company like Twitter, which has far fewer users and much weaker data? And what about up-and-comers like Quora or Pinterest? These companies can't run on enthusiasm forever. If they sputter, they'll likely be gobbled up by larger companies like Google and Microsoft. Or in some cases, they'll fade away. Either way, social needs to prove its value as a business soon. Otherwise, the era of Silicon Valley that spawned a social media revolution will mainly be remembered for producing a Lost Generation of Startups. Contact Chris O'Brien at (415) 298-0207 or cobrien@mercurynews.com. Follow him on Twitter at obrien and read his blog posts at http://www.siliconbeat.com.</description>
      <link>http://www.mercurynews.com/chris-obrien/ci_20760486/obrien-social-media-has-changed-web-but-can-it-make-buck</link>
      <guid>http://www.mercurynews.com/chris-obrien/ci_20760486/obrien-social-media-has-changed-web-but-can-it-make-buck</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android Angst: Ice Cream Sandwich Adoption Moving Slowly [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>What&#8217;s the holdup with the new version 4.0 of Android, affectionately known as Ice Cream Sandwich? Announced on October 19, 2011, the new version so far only accounts for 7.1% of active Android devices according to Android Developers &#8212; nearly eight months later. Take a look at this video where we examine why this is happening. Even though Android dominates smartphones with an overwhelming 65% market share, it&#8217;s a shame it&#8217;s not capable of putting its best foot forward on a wider scale &#8212; at least not yet. How long do you think it will take before Android 4.0 is installed on a majority of Android handsets? Why do you think this has happened? More About: android, ice cream sandwich, mashable video, smartphonesFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/ice-cream-sandwich-slow/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/ice-cream-sandwich-slow/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Radical Skateboarding Tricks Dazzle in Super Slow-Motion [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>You&#8217;ll have a newfound respect for skateboarders&#8217; skills after watching these two minutes of tricks in super slow-motion. Adam Shomsky shot 13 uncommon flips and twists at 1,000 frames per second with a Redlake N3 high-speed camera and turned it into this rad mix. Check out 10 more slow-motion videos below. 1. Slow Motion Billiards Billiards and pool are games that require a decent knowledge of physics and geometry. This video might help you understand what actually happens when you strike a ball or when the ball strikes a rail, leading you to become a more precise - and accomplished - player. Good luck.Click here to view this gallery. More About: skateboard, Slow Motion, viral videos, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/skateboarding-slow-motion/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/skateboarding-slow-motion/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Finally Lets Page Admins Schedule Posts, Have Different Roles</title>
      <description>Third-party apps like HootSuite just got a little less relevant with an update from Facebook that lets Page admins schedule posts. A new help center page from Facebook also outlines how brand pages can now dole out specific duties to multiple page admins, each with varying degrees of permissions. The chart below outlines the new roles of manager, content creator, moderator, advertiser and insights analyst. A separate help center page from Facebook also provides an answer to one question many Facebook Page admins have been asking for some time: How do I schedule a post to appear later? The answer: Posts can be scheduled up to six months in advance at 15-minute intervals. Facebook Page admins, are these features you&#8217;ve been waiting for? How does this change your Facebook marketing strategy? BONUS: Facebook Promoted Posts: A Step-By-Step Guide Want to Promote a Post? Click "Promote" to open this drop-down menu. Clicking on the denomination pulls up another drop-down menu.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, facebook page, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/facebook-page-schedule-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/facebook-page-schedule-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit 101: Co-Founders Explain the Community [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Reddit&#8216;s culture is enigmatic to many. The social news site started in 2005 as a place for people to find new and interesting things online. Today, the front page consistently tracks the unique and hottest stories by the hour. The Reddit community has shifted from an intimate community of anonymous users to 35 million unique visitors per month. SEE ALSO: Here&#8217;s What Reddit Looked Like 5 Years Ago [PIC] Though anonymity is still a prominent part of the Reddit community, users have shown plenty of heart &#8212; from small gestures for the terminally ill to powerful social good for mainstream media. It&#8217;s rather difficult to sum up all of Reddit &#8212; including its subreddits, community, controversy and culture. But PBS&#8217;s web series Off Book interviewed co-founders Steve Huffman and Alexis Ohanian, and they explain extensively in less than 10 minutes. More About: alexis ohanian, pbs, reddit, viral, viral videos, YouTubeFor more Video coverage:Follow Mashable Video on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Video channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/reddit-101/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/reddit-101/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Adds Admin Roles: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Gives Granularity to Page Admin Roles: Businesses with Facebook Pages can now set five different roles for their admins: Manager, Content Creator, Moderator, Advertiser and Insights Analyst. This is a useful tool for Facebook managers.Businesses on Facebook can now grant page admins varying degrees of permissions, depending on their role.Facebook Adds Post Scheduling: You can now schedule posts directly on your Facebook Page. &#8221;You can prepare a post and schedule it to appear later by adding a date and time in the future before you post it.&#8221;"You can schedule a post up to 6 months in advance in 15-minute intervals," and you can also "choose a date in the past" and your post will appear at the appropriate place on your Page's Timeline.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:How will the switch to Google+ Local impact your business?Has anyone tried the new Facebook Promoted Posts?Share your comments on ghost writing for blogs.Facebook Rolls Out Promoted Posts for Facebook Pages: &#8220;Promoted posts are a simple way to reach more of the people who like your Page and their friends.&#8221; Promoted Posts give your updates more exposure on Facebook.To promote a post, select the Promote button after creating an update on your Page.Google+ Local Replaces Google Places: &#8220;Each place you see in Google+ Local will now be scored using Zagat&#8217;s 30-point scale, which tells you all about the various aspects of a place so you can make the best decisions.&#8221; Google Place pages have been automatically converted into Google+ Local pages. This is Google&#8217;s first step beyond Google Places.Google+ users can see the different scores others give this restaurant.Bit.ly Gets New Look: The new design features &#8220;make it easier and faster to find and share interesting stuff.&#8221; Things have moved around a bit, so if you&#8217;re looking for something specific, check their Knowledge Base for directions.Check out Bit.ly's new bookmarking feature, the Bitmark.Pinterest Rival Fancy Brings Social Commerce to iPhone: The Fancy iPhone app allows people to browse the cool products shared on Fancy and also purchase items directly through their mobile devices.Fancy has nearly one million users who press the Fancy button 3 million times every week.Enhancer Adds Music to Vimeo Videos: Vimeo&#8217;s new Enhancer tool makes it easy for users to find and add music to their videos. The music catalog &#8220;has tracks in tons of genres, with lots for free.&#8221; Here are a couple of social media tools worth noting:Network Updater: A free social network alert service that sends you email alerts for any changes or updates from the Twitter and Facebook friends you select.Network Updater ensures you don't miss the news from the people who matter most to you.Curalate: A paid monitoring and analytics Pinterest tool for both the activity on your Pinterest account and all of the pinning activity from your own website.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X8iVa5gq2lIWhat social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-adds-admin-roles-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-adds-admin-roles-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo Sharing App Picplz to Shut Down on July 3</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;re a fan of the iPhone and Android photo sharing app Picplz, you only have one more month to enjoy its pleasures. In a blog post and email late Friday, developer Mixed Media Labs announced the demise of the app: On July 3, 2012, picplz will shut down permanently and all photos and data will be deleted. We have provided download links for existing users to save their photos. Thank you for your support of picplz and we apologize for any inconvenience this may cause you. Login before July 3, 2012 to download your photos. Picplz was competitive with market leader Instagram when both were new, especially since Picplz was available on both the Android and iPhone platforms while Instagram was only available on the iPhone. In February, 2011, when both Picplz and Instagram launched their APIs, Picplz seemed to gain an edge when it added analytics for its users at the same time, as well as the ability to add Creative Commons licensing to photos. Both apps have the ability to add filters and edges to photos, and can share photos with their own networks as well as friends on Twitter, Flickr and Facebook. But Instagram gained all-important buzz, thus experiencing explosive network growth, making it more desirable than all its competitors. On Saturday, Picplz was no longer available on the Apple App Store. More About: apps, instagram, Mixed Media Labs, photo sharing, picplzFor more Startups coverage:Follow Mashable Startups on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Startups channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/picplz-shut-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/picplz-shut-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Receive GLAAD Award for LGBT Efforts</title>
      <description>Facebook will be the first social media company honored at the GLAAD Media Awards, hosted annually by the Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation (GLAAD). Representatives from Facebook will accept a Special Recognition Award at tonight&#8217;s event, held at the San Francisco Marriott Marquis in California. This will be the 23rd Annual Media Awards for the notable lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) media advocacy and anti-defamation organization, recognizing fair and inclusive representations of the LGBT community in television, journalism, music and more. GLAAD announced in March that Facebook would receive the award, citing the social media company&#8217;s efforts against bullying as well as the inclusion of various options &#8212; such as relationship statuses &#8212; for LGBT users of the social network. Throughout the past two years, Facebook has taken many initiatives to promote and enable LGBT rights and equality. The company worked with GLAAD in October 2010 to monitor a memorial page for LGBT youth after users posted violent anti-gay images and comments. It also launched the Network of Support, a panel of five leading LGBT advocacy organizations with MTV&#8217;s A Thin Line campaign to help Facebook address LGBT issues. More recently, Facebook launched the Stop Bullying: Speak Up campaign with Time Warner, which empowers students, teachers and parents to help prevent bullying. The campaign just launched across Latin America this week. Facebook also added Help Center content that provides guidance on how users can help an LGBT person who has posted suicidal content. &#8220;Facebook has set the bar high for ensuring LGBT people have a safe space to connect with friends and family,&#8221; said GLAAD President Herndon Graddick in a statement on Thursday. &#8220;GLAAD is pleased to present this award to Facebook in recognition of its efforts to make their platform welcoming to everyone.&#8221; Brittany McMillan, the high school student who founded Spirit Day, will present the Special Recognition Award. Facebook was among leading companies that participated in Spirit Day on Oct. 20, 2011, encouraging employees to turn their Facebook profile pictures purple and wear the color to show support for LGBT youth. Andrew Noyes, Facebook&#8217;s manager of public policy and communications, will accept the award on behalf of the company. Noyes, who acts as the liaison between Facebook and LGBT groups, was influential in launching the Network of Support. Although Facebook&#8217;s higher-up executives will not be in attendance, a recorded thank-you video from Chief Operating Officer Sheryl Sandberg will be played at the awards. More About: Facebook, glaad, LGBT, Media, Social Good, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/facebook-glaad-award/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/facebook-glaad-award/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which DSLR Camera Is Right for You?</title>
      <description>The Documenting Your Life Series is presented by Western Digital. We believe your life&#8217;s most valuable moments should always be close and accessible. My Passport 2 TB portable hard drives let you dream big and carry small. Whether you use a smartphone or a point-and-shoot as your primary camera, if you&#8217;re serious about photography, all paths lead toward a digital SLR (single-lens reflex) model. With their large image sensors, interchangeable lenses and a seemingly endless supply of tweakable features, DSLRs maximize both flexibility and mobility. They look pretty hot, too. Since the debut of the Nikon D1 in 1999 &#8212; the world&#8217;s first modern DSLR &#8212; the technology has advanced considerably. Once for still pictures only, almost all DSLRs manufactured today record video, too. Camera makers have enhanced autofocus mechanisms with swarms of extra focus points and added high-tech features, such as face detection. Some even have swiveling LCDs for hard-to-get shots. But those are extras. The reason you get a DSLR is so you can take great pictures. The large image sensors in DSLR cameras capture more light than those in smaller models, and they&#8217;re paired with high-performing image sensors. That lets many DSLRs shoot still photos in RAW format &#8212; which records all light data (except for direction, right Lytro?) with no compression. Shooting in RAW results in very large files, but it also ensures photographers get the most accurate pictures possible. Finally, DLSRs are made to be the center of a photography experience that goes beyond the camera. Almost all have ports and jacks for accessories, and there&#8217;s also a &#8220;hot shoe&#8221; on top, where you can attach powered items, typically an external flash. DSLRs are the gateway to building a photography arsenal, but they&#8217;ll also take great pics on their own. When you desire a new DSLR, the right camera depends mainly on what you&#8217;re looking to do with it. Below, we outline some typical use cases and suggest a model for each situation. The Graduate You&#8217;ve liked the simplicity of point-and-shoots, but their limitations are starting to frustrate you more and more. You need something that performs better in low light and can capture fast motion when needed &#8212; with minimal blur. Still, you don&#8217;t want to get overwhelmed by features. Entry-level DSLRs were made with you in mind. Models like the Canon EOS Rebel T3 and Nikon D3100 have all you need to get started. Although they give the full-manual flexibility of any DSLR, they also have many simplified exposure presets. Just switch the dial to, say, landscape photography, and the camera will automatically configure its settings to capture a crisp shot of that mountain range. Today, even basic DSLR cameras can capture HD video. But if that&#8217;s not important to you, you can still find some cheaper older models, such as the Nikon D3000, which shoots stills only. But the ability to switch is a very handy feature, so there&#8217;s a good chance it&#8217;s well worth the extra coin to get a camera that does both. The Videographer Buying a stand-alone video camera almost seems anachronistic today. However, still cameras don&#8217;t often make for the best video cameras. Because of differences in optics and image processing, cameras that are primarily used for taking stills often don&#8217;t capture high-quality video. Fortunately, DSLRs have tremendous advantages over cameraphones and point-and-shoots in those areas, and can make excellent video cameras &#8212; as long as you know what to look for. The Canon T3i and Nikon D5100 are great choices for budding videographers. Both capture video in full 1080p resolution, and that speedy image processing means they have good &#8220;burst&#8221; modes. Nikon also offers continuous autofocus while shooting video, keeping your target sharp as it moves (however, this usually results in noise from the servos getting captured). Looking beyond the usual suspects, Sony&#8217;s Alpha DSLRs have impressive video-capturing abilities, sometimes at a better price. The Sony Alpha a57 can capture 1080p video at 60 frames per second &#8212; Canon and Nikon cameras in its price range max out at 30. It also has nice bonuses, like a swiveling LCD screen and HDMI output for connecting to a big-screen TV (also available on the D5100). The Upgrader If you have an older or lower-end DSLR and are looking to upgrade, there&#8217;s lots to choose from. Going to a mid-level camera won&#8217;t just improve your photos, but also the overall photography experience. With better image processing and bigger camera bodies, you&#8217;ll enjoy faster burst mode rates and longer-lasting batteries, plus those swiveling LCDs become more common. The Canon EOS 7D is an excellent choice for upgraders, able to capture full HD video and shoot up to eight still photos per second. &#8220;Prosumers&#8221; will love the 19-point autofocus system and the intelligent viewfinder, which is more graphically dynamic than previous models. If the 7D is a little on the pricey side for you, you might want to check out the 60D, which has many of the same features. Nikon&#8217;s mid-level DSLRs start with the D7000, which has two user-definable exposure settings, letting you instantly configure the camera for your most common environments. There&#8217;s a 39-point autofocus system, and it can shoot up to six still pics per second. It also has continuous autofocus when shooting video. Sony gives you great bang for your buck with its mid-level DSLR. The Alpha a65 captures pics with a massive 24.3 megapixels, and its Burst mode is an impressive 10 frames per second. Like the a57, it can record 1080p video at up to 60 frames per second, and you have full control of shutter speed and aperture while recording. The LCD can swivel, and the viewfinder is a high-resolution OLED screen that can show the results of camera adjustments in real time. Finally, if you&#8217;ve broken more than one DSLR while shooting in extreme situations, the Pentax K-30 (due in July) is made with you in mind. It&#8217;s fully weather-sealed, so it&#8217;s up to the task of shooting on the beach or a mountaintop, and it can withstand cold temperatures and dust. It shoots 1080p video (30 frames per second) and can capture six stills per second in burst mode. The Serious Photographer If you want a taste of what it&#8217;s like for pro photographers &#8212; or simply want the best of the best &#8212; you&#8217;ll want a high-end DSLR. These are serious image-capturing devices that pour on the megapixels and customized settings. With so much tweakability, they often do away with some automatic features common on lower-end models (like exposure presets and a built-in flash) entirely. The Canon EOS 5D Mark II is a great step toward true pro photography. Its full-frame image sensor can take 21-megapixel shots, and if your situation is less than ideal, you can improve your pics with features like an &#8220;Auto Lighting Optimizer&#8221; and &#8220;Peripheral Illumination Correction.&#8221; If you have a little more money to burn, there&#8217;s also the more recent 5D Mark III, which has better image processing and a few more tricks. For Nikon, the D300s will get your feet wet with pro features, like in-camera image editing, a 51-point autofocus and nine customizable picture settings. But if its 12.3 megapixels aren&#8217;t enough for you, cast your eyes toward the D800, the highest-resolution full-frame DSLR on the market, at 36.3 megapixels. Both capture 1080p video at 30 frames per second. If you think you&#8217;re ready for the extreme high end, you&#8217;ll want either the Nikon D4 or Canon EOS-1D X. Both have too many features to summarize well here, but each will satisfy the pro within you. Their bulky camera bodies provide lots of extra power and a convenient handgrip for portrait shots, but that also means they&#8217;re not for casual shooting. What&#8217;s Your Shot? Buying a DSLR is a lot like buying a computer or a car &#8212; it&#8217;s a commitment to both a product and a company. It&#8217;s not to be taken lightly, but if you can match the right model with your goals, it&#8217;ll unshackle the shutterbug within you and you&#8217;ll soon be taken better pictures than you ever have. We&#8217;ve covered just some of the options here &#8212; there are lots more to explore, so browse the web, visit your local camera shop and find your perfect model. Once you go DSLR, you&#8217;ll never go back. What&#8217;s your model? Let us know in the comments. Series presented by Western Digital The Documenting Your Life Series is is presented by Western Digital. We believe your life&#8217;s most valuable moments should always be close and accessible. My Passport 2 TB portable hard drives let you dream big and carry small. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, by_nicholas More About: Canon, digital cameras, Documenting Your Life Series, DSLR, features, mashable, Nikon, pentax, sony</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/dslr-camera-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/dslr-camera-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter to Top $1 Billion in Ad Revenue in 2014 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Twitter is expected to bring in more than $1 billion in advertising revenue in 2014, according to a report. Two people &#8220;with knowledge of the matter,&#8221; who are apparently irked at some analysts&#8217; low forecasts, told Bloomberg that ad revenue would be &#8220;at least&#8221; $1 billion before the company&#8217;s ninth birthday. By comparison, eight-year-old Facebook generated more than $3 billion in ad revenue in 2011. A Twitter spokesperson declined to comment. Estimates published by eMarketer earlier this year suggest that the Twitter will only generate $540 million in ad revenue in 2014 &#8212; about double what eMarketer forecasts the San Francisco-based startup will bring in this year. Growth will be driven in part by Twitter&#8217;s self-service advertising platform for small businesses, which launched in November, and by international expansion, eMarketer said. Currently, 90% of ad revenue come from U.S. companies. Unlike many other web-based publishers, Twitter doesn&#8217;t depend on display advertising for the bulk of its ad revenue. Instead, it has launched a suite of &#8220;Promoted&#8221; products that allow companies to increase the visibility of specific accounts, tweets and trending topics. Adam Bain, president of global revenue for Twitter, says Promoted Trends and Promoted Tweets yield engagement rates between 3% and 10% on average &#8212; many multiples higher than the average banner ad. 1. Use Promoted Trends or Promoted Tweets to Publicize an Event Twitter is all about discovering what&#8217;s going on right now. As Bain notes, many users return to Twitter&#8217;s homepage a few times per day just to see what&#8217;s trending. Promoted Trends leverage that phenomenon by giving advertisers a premium position on the page. Bain says that this can yield much higher engagement rates than standard online advertising, for example, banner ads. Introduced in 1993, banners have notoriously low click-through rates, even though such advertising is still growing rapidly. (Proponents of banners also point out that, while the ads work fine for raising awareness, direct sales are still measured by clicks.) Nevertheless, Bain says Promoted Trends and Promoted Tweets yield engagement rates between 3% and 10% on average, and sometimes much higher than that. For instance, Volkswagen got 52% engagement on an April 18 Promoted Tweet for its 2012 New Beetle launch. In this case, engagement is defined by click-throughs (which usually accounts for 80% of the total), retweets and &#8220;favorited&#8221; tweets. The buying process for Promoted Trends and Promoted Tweets and all of Twitter&#8217;s ad products follow a model similar to Google's -- marketers buy them in an auction at a cost-per-engagement rate, and then pay based on engagement. Obviously, if you&#8217;re running a Promoted Trend or Promoted Tweet, it helps if you have some kind of news, product launch, or associated event. For instance, For instance, Coca-Cola earned high engagement during the 2010 World Cup &#8212; whenever a goal was scored, Coke would unleash a celebratory tweet.Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, arakonyunus More About: ads, Advertising, TwitterFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/twitter-ad-revenue/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/twitter-ad-revenue/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Content Marketing Lessons From Obama</title>
      <description>Joe Lazauskas is the co-founder and CCO of Faster Times Media, a content studio and consultancy that helps businesses create exceptional articles, videos, blogs, and social media updates. Say hello on Twitter @joelazauskas or via email at joe@thefastertimes.com. Although politicians and their marketing teams are generally seen as behind the times, President Barack Obama&#8217;s campaign team is a big exception, having effectively leveraged social media to win the 2008 campaign. Now, it looks like they&#8217;re ahead of the curve on advertising&#8217;s latest big trend: content marketing. From slow jamming on Late Night With Jimmy Fallon to making the commencement speech at Barnard College, Obama has been a content marketing wizard of late. Here&#8217;s a look at his most clever moves, and what brands can take away from them. 1. Obama Sings Al Green On January 19, while speaking at a fundraiser at the Apollo Theater in Harlem, Obama mentioned that Al Green was in the house before singing a line from Green&#8217;s classic hit, &#8220;Let&#8217;s Stay Together.&#8221; The line&#8217;s message was a smart move for a man banking on his likeability &#8212; especially among women. The video immediately went viral, garnering more than five million views on YouTube, with a 90% positive rating. Jay-Z even wants to recreate the moment with him at the Made in America festival. It was a brilliantly planned piece of content marketing by the POTUS and his team, and brands can deliver similar moments. Just look at Nascar Driver Brad Keselowski&#8217;s tweet during the Daytona 500, or Audi delivering an Audi R8 to the originator of the #wantanR8 hashtag. Takeaway: Don&#8217;t be afraid to seize expected and unexpected moments to appeal to your base and possibly go viral. 2. Obama Slow Jams the News About a month ago Obama had an important message to get out to young voters: He wanted to stop Congress from allowing interest rates on federal-subsidized student loans to double. Unfortunately, not enough young voters read The New York Times anymore. But they do watch clips from Late Night With Jimmy Fallon. On April 24th, Obama went on Jimmy Fallon to slow jam the news in front of a crowd of students at Chapel Hill. He crooned a concise 30-second speech that garnered nearly six million views on YouTube. That&#8217;s nearly six million people who may not have heard his message otherwise. Takeaway: Deliver your content in a way that specifically targets your intended audience. 3. The Campaign Creates a Fake and Funny Attack Ad Obama earned rave reviews for his performance during this year&#8217;s White House Correspondents&#8217; Dinner, and his 18-minute speech earned more than a million views. Nothing was funnier, though, than a fake Romney SuperPac ad that attacked Obama for not allowing dogs to ride on the roof of cars. It was a great &#8212; and hilarious &#8212; move that reminded the dog-loving country that Romney once strapped his dog to the roof of a car, and left him there even as the dog puked. Takeaway: Use the right kind of humor to get your message across. 4. Obama Gets George Clooney to Host a Dinner Contest When Obama raised $15 million at a May 10th fundraiser at George Clooney&#8217;s house, most assumed that the haul came primarily from big Hollywood donors. That wasn&#8217;t the case. Only $6 million came from Tinseltown folks who shelled out $40,000 for a seat. The remaining $9 million came from small donors who donated to enter a raffle to attend the dinner with a guest. That means that the dream dinner, pushed vigorously by the President&#8217;s team through social media, email, and SMS, likely got hundreds of thousands of small donors reinvested in the campaign. &#8220;We raised a lot of money because people love George,&#8221; the President said at the fundraiser. &#8220;They like me; They love George.&#8221; Takeaway: Give your audience a chance to fulfill a fantasy, tie that fantasy to your company or product, and use your social channels to spread news about it. 5. Obama Delivers the Commencement Speech at Barnard College Commencement speeches are a mainstay of presidential campaigning. Emphasizing the GOP&#8217;s &#8220;War on Women&#8221; is a mainstay of Obama&#8217;s 2012 campaign. With that in mind, there wasn&#8217;t a more perfect place for Obama to deliver a commencement speech than at Barnard College in Manhattan. In front of 600 female graduates and journalists from nearly every major media outlet in the city, Obama delivered a speech emphasizing the power and ability of women to play crucial roles. &#8220;Fight for a seat at the head of the table,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s up to you to stand up and be heard, to write, and to lobby, to march, to organize, to vote&#8230;Don&#8217;t be content just to sit back and watch.&#8221; The young crowd could be seen tweeting and Facebooking updates about the speech throughout the event. Videos of it racked up tens of thousands of views, and more importantly, Obama created a positive association between himself and the elite female graduates in publications across the country. Takeaway: Use public opportunities to connect with attendees and have them spread your message via social networks. More About: barack obama, contributor, features, Marketing, online marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/barack-obama-brilliant-content-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/barack-obama-brilliant-content-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google To One-Up Apple, Announce 3D Maps a Week Earlier [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>We&#8217;ve already seen a few leaks that suggest Apple will be announcing its own 3D mapping service on June 11 at WWDC, its developer&#8217;s conference. Now it looks like Google is trying to beat Apple to the punch by unveiling its own 3D maps a week earlier. At an event entitled &#8220;The Next Dimension of Google Maps&#8221; next Wednesday, Brian McClendon, vice president of Google Maps and Google Earth is slated to give event goers an inside look at what&#8217;s in the works for Google&#8217;s mapping service and &#8220;provide a sneak peek at upcoming features that will help people get where they want to go &#8211; both physically and virtually.&#8221; Apple has used Google Maps in the iPhone since its launch in 2007, the company is rumored to be removing Google&#8217;s mapping service completely from its phone with the release of iOS 6 and replacing it with its own Google Maps alternative. Reports earlier this year indicated that the company will be showing off its own 3D mapping solution at its Worldwide Developers Conference June 11. In recent months Apple has also acquired mapping experts C3 Technologies, Placebase, and Poly9 adding fuel to those rumors. Apple also recently removed Google Maps from the iPad version of iPhoto. Google&#8217;s timing on its announcement suggests that it is being done to directly compete with Apple, and perhaps show users what &#8211;potentially better &#8211; options might exist with Google Maps and Android versus what Apple will be offering with the iPhone and iOS 6. What do you think Apple and Google have in store? More importantly, are you interested in 3D mapping in the first place? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: apple, Google, Google Maps, iOS 6, iphone, wwdc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/google-3d-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/google-3d-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
