<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter to Top $1 Billion in Ad Revenue in 2014 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Twitter is expected to bring in more than $1 billion in advertising revenue in 2014, according to a report. Two people &#8220;with knowledge of the matter,&#8221; who are apparently irked at some analysts&#8217; low forecasts, told Bloomberg that ad revenue would be &#8220;at least&#8221; $1 billion before the company&#8217;s ninth birthday. By comparison, eight-year-old Facebook generated more than $3 billion in ad revenue in 2011. A Twitter spokesperson declined to comment. Estimates published by eMarketer earlier this year suggest that the Twitter will only generate $540 million in ad revenue in 2014 &#8212; about double what eMarketer forecasts the San Francisco-based startup will bring in this year. Growth will be driven in part by Twitter&#8217;s self-service advertising platform for small businesses, which launched in November, and by international expansion, eMarketer said. Currently, 90% of ad revenue come from U.S. companies. Unlike many other web-based publishers, Twitter doesn&#8217;t depend on display advertising for the bulk of its ad revenue. Instead, it has launched a suite of &#8220;Promoted&#8221; products that allow companies to increase the visibility of specific accounts, tweets and trending topics. Adam Bain, president of global revenue for Twitter, says Promoted Trends and Promoted Tweets yield engagement rates between 3% and 10% on average &#8212; many multiples higher than the average banner ad. 1. Use Promoted Trends or Promoted Tweets to Publicize an Event Twitter is all about discovering what&#8217;s going on right now. As Bain notes, many users return to Twitter&#8217;s homepage a few times per day just to see what&#8217;s trending. Promoted Trends leverage that phenomenon by giving advertisers a premium position on the page. Bain says that this can yield much higher engagement rates than standard online advertising, for example, banner ads. Introduced in 1993, banners have notoriously low click-through rates, even though such advertising is still growing rapidly. (Proponents of banners also point out that, while the ads work fine for raising awareness, direct sales are still measured by clicks.) Nevertheless, Bain says Promoted Trends and Promoted Tweets yield engagement rates between 3% and 10% on average, and sometimes much higher than that. For instance, Volkswagen got 52% engagement on an April 18 Promoted Tweet for its 2012 New Beetle launch. In this case, engagement is defined by click-throughs (which usually accounts for 80% of the total), retweets and &#8220;favorited&#8221; tweets. The buying process for Promoted Trends and Promoted Tweets and all of Twitter&#8217;s ad products follow a model similar to Google's -- marketers buy them in an auction at a cost-per-engagement rate, and then pay based on engagement. Obviously, if you&#8217;re running a Promoted Trend or Promoted Tweet, it helps if you have some kind of news, product launch, or associated event. For instance, For instance, Coca-Cola earned high engagement during the 2010 World Cup &#8212; whenever a goal was scored, Coke would unleash a celebratory tweet.Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, arakonyunus More About: ads, Advertising, TwitterFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/twitter-ad-revenue/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/twitter-ad-revenue/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do You Suffer From These 4 Tech Afflictions?</title>
      <description>Quick: How many devices do you have on-hand at this very moment? How often have you checked your social media accounts in the last hour? When was the last time you played a video game? The answers to these questions may seem inconsequential, but tech addiction is real, and it can have dreadful consequences. According to a January study published in PLoS ONE, a journal of the Public Library of Science, people addicted to the Internet may experience chemical changes in their brains similar to those of alcoholics and other drug addicts. And that&#8217;s just the Internet &#8212; think about all the other aspects of technology we succumb to every day. Check out the following ailments that you should avoid at all costs. 1. Phantom Vibration Syndrome Do you ever reach for your cellphone because you feel it vibrating, only to discover that it hadn&#8217;t buzzed at all? This could be what many call &#8220;phantom vibration syndrome,&#8221; the sufferers of which feel vibrations even when their devices are in an entirely different room. The name is most likely based on phantom limb syndrome, a condition in which someone who has lost a limb experiences sensory hallucinations that it is still attached to the body and functioning. Similarly, those with phantom vibration syndrome feel their phones as extensions of themselves. According to Larry Rosen&#8217;s book, iDisorder, 70% of those who say they heavily use mobile devices experience phantom vibrations. It&#8217;s common, and you&#8217;re able to recover from it, based on at least one study. 2. Internet Addiction Disorder Internet addiction disorder (IAD) refers to compulsory use of the Internet, such that it interferes with daily life. Studies show that addiction to the Internet can cause the same type of social problems as other established addictions, such as gambling. It&#8217;s important to note, however, that it is not yet recognized as a disorder in the American Psychiatric Association&#8217;s Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM). It may be included in the DSM-5 (previously known as DSM-V), which is slated for May 2013 publication, though there has been no clear decision. SEE ALSO: The Internet Is Ruining Your Brain [INFOGRAPHIC] In a 2008 editorial in The American Journal of Psychiatry, Dr. Jerald J. Block wrote that IAD can be characterized by excessive use, feelings of withdrawal and negative repercussions, such as arguments and fatigue. Pathological use of the Internet can also cause severe levels of depression. 3. Social Media Addiction Considered a subdivision of Internet addiction, social media addiction is probably one of the more common tech addictions of late. Researchers from the University of Chicago Booth School of Business surveyed 250 participants, fitting them them with devices that logged nearly 8,000 reports on their everyday desires. According to the study, checking social networking sites for updates is a much harder habit to break than alcohol or tobacco. In Norway, researchers came up with the Bergen Facebook Addiction Scale, a test to help you figure out whether you suffer from a social media addiction. The test is based on six metrics, for example, using Facebook to forget about problems or trying to cut down on Facebook use without success. 4. Video Game Addiction Video game addiction, like IAD and other addictions, is characterized by the interference of gaming with other aspects of life. Although it is not yet considered an official addiction by the American Medical Association, video game overuse has led to terrible consequences. In July 2011, a 20-year-old computer programmer died from deep vein thrombosis from sitting for too long. A blood clot started in his calf and eventually caused fatal blockage in his lungs. How much is too much tech? Let us know in the comments where you draw the line. Images courtesy of iStockphoto, PamelaJoeMcFarlane, courtneyk. More About: features, Gaming, health, Mobile, Social Media, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/tech-addiction/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/tech-addiction/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google To One-Up Apple, Announce 3D Maps a Week Earlier [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>We&#8217;ve already seen a few leaks that suggest Apple will be announcing its own 3D mapping service on June 11 at WWDC, its developer&#8217;s conference. Now it looks like Google is trying to beat Apple to the punch by unveiling its own 3D maps a week earlier. At an event entitled &#8220;The Next Dimension of Google Maps&#8221; next Wednesday, Brian McClendon, vice president of Google Maps and Google Earth is slated to give event goers an inside look at what&#8217;s in the works for Google&#8217;s mapping service and &#8220;provide a sneak peek at upcoming features that will help people get where they want to go &#8211; both physically and virtually.&#8221; Apple has used Google Maps in the iPhone since its launch in 2007, the company is rumored to be removing Google&#8217;s mapping service completely from its phone with the release of iOS 6 and replacing it with its own Google Maps alternative. Reports earlier this year indicated that the company will be showing off its own 3D mapping solution at its Worldwide Developers Conference June 11. In recent months Apple has also acquired mapping experts C3 Technologies, Placebase, and Poly9 adding fuel to those rumors. Apple also recently removed Google Maps from the iPad version of iPhoto. Google&#8217;s timing on its announcement suggests that it is being done to directly compete with Apple, and perhaps show users what &#8211;potentially better &#8211; options might exist with Google Maps and Android versus what Apple will be offering with the iPhone and iOS 6. What do you think Apple and Google have in store? More importantly, are you interested in 3D mapping in the first place? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: apple, Google, Google Maps, iOS 6, iphone, wwdc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/google-3d-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/google-3d-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engadget's summer gear guide 2012: home entertainment</title>
      <description>In the interest of keeping cool this summer, we've put together a list of the hottest products out right now. From smartphones to e-readers and everything in between, there's no time like the present to re-up that post-spring-cleaning stash. So grab a popsicle or a cold one and dive in -- the water's just right. If you've been in the market for a new laptop, you've done the wise thing in waiting until now to buy: both Intel and AMD are putting the finishing touches on their newest mobile chips, which means a torrent of fresh notebooks is on the way. (Power users can already pick up a gaming machine or desktop replacement running one of Intel's new quad-core CPUs.) For the widest selection, we suggest waiting until mid-June or so, but in the meantime, we present you three of the best laptops money can buy right now. Enjoy, and do stick it out, if you can, for the inevitable Ivy Bridge refreshes. But if you must pull the trigger immediately, jump down past to the break to read our summertime suggestions.Continue reading Engadget's summer gear guide 2012: laptopsEngadget's summer gear guide 2012: laptops originally appeared on Engadget on Fri, 01 Jun 2012 07:00:00 EDT. Please see our terms for use of feeds.Permalink | | Email this | Comments</description>
      <link>http://www.engadget.com/2012/06/01/laptop-buyers-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+weblogsinc%2Fengadget+%28Engadget%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.engadget.com/2012/06/01/laptop-buyers-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+weblogsinc%2Fengadget+%28Engadget%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pocket-Sized iPhone Accessory Is a Charger and a Tripod [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Inventions on our &#8220;why didn&#8217;t I think of that&#8221; list include the pillow with arm hole, solar-powered iPad keyboard, and now the Twig on Kickstarter. The Twig is described by its creator Jason Hilbourne as an &#8220;amazing ultra-portable cable for your iPhone.&#8221; The team has already raised more than 120% of its initial $50,000 Kickstarter goal. The 4-inch cable is a simple charger cable that connects your phone to your laptop. The Twig is durable enough to bend into a sturdy table stand for your iPhone. In this state, it doubles as an iPhone camera tripod. The Twig stand also makes hands-free FaceTime possible. Other product perks &#8212; it&#8217;s thin enough to fit into your pocket, and comes in a variety of colors. The accessory is also compatible with the Apple iPod touch and iPod nano. The plastic-and-wire gadget easily attaches to a wall plug. The Twig is also perfect for wrapping your earbuds around. Watch the video above to learn how you can get your hands on this problem-solving product. What&#8217;s your must-have Apple iPhone or iPod accessory? Share with us in the comments. More About: apple, iphone, kickstarterFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/the-twig-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/the-twig-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Mobile Tech Can Improve Your Health</title>
      <description>Edna Boone is the senior director of mHIMSS, the mobile health initiative behind HIMSS, the non-profit devoted to the improvement of health through technology. Join the mHIMSS LinkedIn group, and follow her @mHIMSS. Just a decade ago, if someone had said that Steve Jobs would have a huge effect on how medical professionals administer care, that prediction would have been met with an eye roll. But the reality is people increasingly access healthcare services via mobile, or &#8220;mHealth.&#8221; The result: Mobile is having a transformative effect on the way physicians and nurses care for patients. It&#8217;s also impacting how consumers manage their own health and well-being. Unconvinced? The following statistics might change your mind. By the end of 2012 mHealth apps will have been downloaded 44 million times. By 2016, that number is expected to increase to 142 million downloads. By this summer, 13,000 consumer health apps will be available for download on the iPhone. About half of those (6,000) are for medical professionals. More than 80% of physicians own a mobile device, compared to 50% of the general U.S. population. About 30% of physicians are using smartphones and tablets to treat patients. So exactly how are these devices shaping healthcare? Here are five ways companies are adopting mobile technologies to improve healthcare delivery. 1. Tracking Physical Activity We&#8217;ve all been told that losing weight involves taking that extra flight of stairs, walking instead of driving, and cutting back on calories. But who has the time to keep track of all that? Enter health monitoring devices that can be snapped to your belt loop. Mobile apps like FitBit help log workouts, meals and weight. Naturally, weight loss is a key benefit of these apps, which is timely, given that obesity is a serious health epidemic facing the U.S. So much so, that First Lady Michelle Obama has strongly pushed her Let&#8217;s Move campaign. 2. Medical Reference Technology Imagine walking into your local hospital with symptoms of a near-fatal, but perfectly treatable, breathing disorder. However, not one of the attending physicians is able to properly diagnose it, not to mention figure out the exact dose of medicine with which to treat you. In many parts of the world, access to quality healthcare and skilled medical professionals is a hard-won luxury. That means the above scenario is a reality for many patients. Health eVillages is working to fix this global health dilemma. The non-profit organization donates mobile phones and iPads pre-loaded with Skyscape medical reference technology to clinics in at-risk and underserved regions. The organization is currently working to train clinicians on the mobile devices in places such as Kenya, Uganda, Haiti, and China. The goal is to improve patient care where the latest and best medical education is not readily available. 3. Getting to the Right Clinician We&#8217;ve all been to the doctor&#8217;s office on a tight schedule, and have waited through what feels like tedious but necessary check-ins, check-outs, and other administrative tasks. Oftentimes, we just want answers to our most common medical questions: &#8220;What might I have?&#8221; and &#8220;Where should I go for treatment?&#8221; ITriage is a mobile health app designed to enhance the doctor-patient visit. Six million people have downloaded the app, which helps patients identify their symptoms and then directly connect to the most appropriate physician for their medical condition. Patients also have the ability to make medical appointments and check in to the emergency room via their mobile phones. 4. Connected Hospitals More hospitals are adopting mobile as part of their care methods. Take Miami Children&#8217;s Hospital, one of the country&#8217;s top pediatric hospitals, with more than 650 physicians covering 40 pediatric specialties and sub-specialties. The hospital recently signed on PatientPoint&#8217;s HealthSync platform, a mobile care coordination system for patients and staff. The patient engagement mobile tool includes registration functions (check-in and check-out), ways to increase medication compliance, and general health and wellness promotions. Miami Children&#8217;s Hospital also plans to leverage iPads with HealthSync to address potential treatment gaps, and deliver clinical surveys and screenings to patients. 5. VA Telehealth Services The U.S. Department of Veteran Affairs has been at the forefront of providing mobile health services to make veterans&#8217; (and their families&#8217;) lives easier. Just recently, the VA announced plans to give 1,000 family caregivers iPads pre-loaded with health apps. That way, primary caregivers can take better care of their veterans without leaving home. The initiative is also part of a pilot program called Clinic-in-Hand, which is testing distribution through a VA app store set to launch next year. This includes health apps that allow for the exchange of personal data between the VA, veterans, and caregivers, providing greater insight into what veterans need in terms of treatment and at-home care. What mobile technologies do you think are driving the mHealth revolution? Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Lisa-Blue More About: apps, contributor, features, health, lifestyle, Mobile, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/mobile-health-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/mobile-health-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Action Photos That Will Give You Whiplash</title>
      <description>Colin Ochel Click here to view this gallery.One of the purposes of photography is to capture a moment in time. For instance, a portrait preserves a person&#8217;s likeness. A scenic landscape shot encapsulates the environment around you. And an action shot freezes reality for dramatic effect. This week, we asked you to send in your best action shots for the Mashable Photo Challenge. We wanted to see photos that really encapsulated a sense of motion. While life brings constant motion and movement every day, we don&#8217;t often think about capturing motion with our photos. If you were to go through your photos on Facebook or Instagram, odds are you will find more photos of still subjects than those in motion. Mashable readers really stepped up to the challenge of capturing motion, and sent us a colorful range of subjects in motion, like a photo of a sea lion doing a handstand and a snapshot of recent college grads tossing a beer keg. SEE ALSO: 21 Brilliant Reflection Photos From the Mashable Community Be sure to get your cameras ready for this week&#8217;s challenge: homegrown. Stay tuned to Mashable for the next challenge post, coming later today. More About: community, Mashable Photo Challenge, photographyFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/mashable-action-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/mashable-action-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fred Armisen Wants You to Be Serious for 30 Seconds</title>
      <description>Be Serious for 30 Seconds, A Participatory Project by Fred Armisen</description>
      <link>http://links.laughingsquid.com/post/24071284186/be-serious-for-30-seconds-a-participatory-project</link>
      <guid>http://links.laughingsquid.com/post/24071284186/be-serious-for-30-seconds-a-participatory-project</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Companies: A Cheat Sheet [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>So you&#8217;re new to this whole social media thing. Maybe you&#8217;re savvy enough to know your Facebook from your Twitter, your Pinterest from your Spotify. But what about Tagged? Xing? Futubra? Where do they fit into the social media ecosystem? Just learning their names is enough to make your head spin, let alone how large they are or what kind of numbers they&#8217;re pulling down. Never fear. Mashable has got you covered. This comprehensive infographic whipped up by social media strategist firm Hasai, below, serves both as a cheat sheet for the newbies and a scorecard for old hands; there&#8217;s sure to be a stat that surprises even the most jaded social guru. Did you know Club Penguin has more employees than Twitter? That Spotify has larger revenues than Tagged, which in turn has more users than Twitter? That Pinterest may be a hot property, but Foursquare still has more users? (All revenue figures are in U.S. dollars, by the way.) Facebook remains at the top of the social media tree, of course. But as Thursday&#8217;s trending Twitter topic, &#8220;RIP Facebook,&#8221; suggested, that can&#8217;t last forever. So who is best positioned to replace them? Take a look at the chart, and let us know in the comments what you think. More About: club penguin, Facebook, pinterest, spotify, tagged, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/social-media-ranking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/social-media-ranking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Companies: A Cheat Sheet [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>So you&#8217;re new to this whole social media thing. Maybe you&#8217;re savvy enough to know your Facebook from your Twitter, your Pinterest from your Spotify. But what about Tagged? Xing? Futubra? Where do they fit into the social media ecosystem? Just learning their names is enough to make your head spin, let alone how large they are or what kind of numbers they&#8217;re pulling down. Never fear. Mashable has got you covered. This comprehensive infographic whipped up by social media strategist firm Hasai, below, serves both as a cheat sheet for the newbies and a scorecard for old hands; there&#8217;s sure to be a stat that surprises even the most jaded social guru. Did you know Club Penguin has more employees than Twitter? That Spotify has larger revenues than Tagged, which in turn has more users than Twitter? That Pinterest may be a hot property, but Foursquare still has more users? (All revenue figures are in U.S. dollars, by the way.) Facebook remains at the top of the social media tree, of course. But as Thursday&#8217;s trending Twitter topic, &#8220;RIP Facebook,&#8221; suggested, that can&#8217;t last forever. So who is best positioned to replace them? Take a look at the chart, and let us know in the comments what you think. More About: club penguin, Facebook, pinterest, spotify, tagged, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/social-media-ranking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/social-media-ranking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Finally Lets Page Admins Schedule Posts, Have Different Roles</title>
      <description>Third-party apps like HootSuite just got a little less relevant with an update from Facebook that lets Page admins schedule posts. A new help center page from Facebook also outlines how brand pages can now dole out specific duties to multiple page admins, each with varying degrees of permissions. The chart below outlines the new roles of manager, content creator, moderator, advertiser and insights analyst. A separate help center page from Facebook also provides an answer to one question many Facebook Page admins have been asking for some time: How do I schedule a post to appear later? The answer: Posts can be scheduled up to six months in advance at 15-minute intervals. Facebook Page admins, are these features you&#8217;ve been waiting for? How does this change your Facebook marketing strategy? BONUS: Facebook Promoted Posts: A Step-By-Step Guide Want to Promote a Post? Click "Promote" to open this drop-down menu. Clicking on the denomination pulls up another drop-down menu.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, facebook page, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/facebook-page-schedule-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/facebook-page-schedule-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Content Marketing Lessons From Obama</title>
      <description>Joe Lazauskas is the co-founder and CCO of Faster Times Media, a content studio and consultancy that helps businesses create exceptional articles, videos, blogs, and social media updates. Say hello on Twitter @joelazauskas or via email at joe@thefastertimes.com. Although politicians and their marketing teams are generally seen as behind the times, President Barack Obama&#8217;s campaign team is a big exception, having effectively leveraged social media to win the 2008 campaign. Now, it looks like they&#8217;re ahead of the curve on advertising&#8217;s latest big trend: content marketing. From slow jamming on Late Night With Jimmy Fallon to making the commencement speech at Barnard College, Obama has been a content marketing wizard of late. Here&#8217;s a look at his most clever moves, and what brands can take away from them. 1. Obama Sings Al Green On January 19, while speaking at a fundraiser at the Apollo Theater in Harlem, Obama mentioned that Al Green was in the house before singing a line from Green&#8217;s classic hit, &#8220;Let&#8217;s Stay Together.&#8221; The line&#8217;s message was a smart move for a man banking on his likeability &#8212; especially among women. The video immediately went viral, garnering more than five million views on YouTube, with a 90% positive rating. Jay-Z even wants to recreate the moment with him at the Made in America festival. It was a brilliantly planned piece of content marketing by the POTUS and his team, and brands can deliver similar moments. Just look at Nascar Driver Brad Keselowski&#8217;s tweet during the Daytona 500, or Audi delivering an Audi R8 to the originator of the #wantanR8 hashtag. Takeaway: Don&#8217;t be afraid to seize expected and unexpected moments to appeal to your base and possibly go viral. 2. Obama Slow Jams the News About a month ago Obama had an important message to get out to young voters: He wanted to stop Congress from allowing interest rates on federal-subsidized student loans to double. Unfortunately, not enough young voters read The New York Times anymore. But they do watch clips from Late Night With Jimmy Fallon. On April 24th, Obama went on Jimmy Fallon to slow jam the news in front of a crowd of students at Chapel Hill. He crooned a concise 30-second speech that garnered nearly six million views on YouTube. That&#8217;s nearly six million people who may not have heard his message otherwise. Takeaway: Deliver your content in a way that specifically targets your intended audience. 3. The Campaign Creates a Fake and Funny Attack Ad Obama earned rave reviews for his performance during this year&#8217;s White House Correspondents&#8217; Dinner, and his 18-minute speech earned more than a million views. Nothing was funnier, though, than a fake Romney SuperPac ad that attacked Obama for not allowing dogs to ride on the roof of cars. It was a great &#8212; and hilarious &#8212; move that reminded the dog-loving country that Romney once strapped his dog to the roof of a car, and left him there even as the dog puked. Takeaway: Use the right kind of humor to get your message across. 4. Obama Gets George Clooney to Host a Dinner Contest When Obama raised $15 million at a May 10th fundraiser at George Clooney&#8217;s house, most assumed that the haul came primarily from big Hollywood donors. That wasn&#8217;t the case. Only $6 million came from Tinseltown folks who shelled out $40,000 for a seat. The remaining $9 million came from small donors who donated to enter a raffle to attend the dinner with a guest. That means that the dream dinner, pushed vigorously by the President&#8217;s team through social media, email, and SMS, likely got hundreds of thousands of small donors reinvested in the campaign. &#8220;We raised a lot of money because people love George,&#8221; the President said at the fundraiser. &#8220;They like me; They love George.&#8221; Takeaway: Give your audience a chance to fulfill a fantasy, tie that fantasy to your company or product, and use your social channels to spread news about it. 5. Obama Delivers the Commencement Speech at Barnard College Commencement speeches are a mainstay of presidential campaigning. Emphasizing the GOP&#8217;s &#8220;War on Women&#8221; is a mainstay of Obama&#8217;s 2012 campaign. With that in mind, there wasn&#8217;t a more perfect place for Obama to deliver a commencement speech than at Barnard College in Manhattan. In front of 600 female graduates and journalists from nearly every major media outlet in the city, Obama delivered a speech emphasizing the power and ability of women to play crucial roles. &#8220;Fight for a seat at the head of the table,&#8221; he said. &#8220;It&#8217;s up to you to stand up and be heard, to write, and to lobby, to march, to organize, to vote&#8230;Don&#8217;t be content just to sit back and watch.&#8221; The young crowd could be seen tweeting and Facebooking updates about the speech throughout the event. Videos of it racked up tens of thousands of views, and more importantly, Obama created a positive association between himself and the elite female graduates in publications across the country. Takeaway: Use public opportunities to connect with attendees and have them spread your message via social networks. More About: barack obama, contributor, features, Marketing, online marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/barack-obama-brilliant-content-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/barack-obama-brilliant-content-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
