<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a3.twimg.com/profile_images/1592801004/twit_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/BostonBookGirl"&gt;Lauren E. MacLeod&lt;/a&gt;: The dog an I are taking it from here. &lt;a href="http://t.co/xSIvHO1m" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/xSIvHO1m&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/BostonBookGirl/status/131179236118642688"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/BostonBookGirl/status/131179236118642688/photo/1</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/BostonBookGirl/status/131179236118642688/photo/1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For When You Have Too Much to Say</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://tmi.me/hO5bJ</link>
      <guid>http://tmi.me/hO5bJ</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I unlocked the Bootcamp sticker on @GetGlue! http://t.co/rssiRKcP</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a1.twimg.com/profile_images/1409918689/edittwitterprofile_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/Superdaddykw"&gt;Kevin Westerman&lt;/a&gt;: I unlocked the Bootcamp sticker on &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/GetGlue" target="_blank"&gt;@GetGlue&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href="http://t.co/rssiRKcP" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/rssiRKcP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/Superdaddykw/status/133348408894296064"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://m.getglue.com/SuperDaddy/stickers/bootcamp?ref=SuperDaddy&amp;s=ts</link>
      <guid>http://m.getglue.com/SuperDaddy/stickers/bootcamp?ref=SuperDaddy&amp;s=ts</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-Cablevision Exec Gottesman Joins Social Media Firm - Multichannel News</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF51etGD3vjmfb8Vsd3J9OVpxSDCg&amp;amp;url=http://www.mrweb.com/drno/news13184.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://nt3.ggpht.com/news/tbn/lz9tQOMCClkTpM/6.jpg" alt="" border="1" width="80" height="80" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-2"&gt;Daily Research News Online&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGNjQnAgMRIkDbnhyybtClSEvtJKQ&amp;amp;url=http://www.multichannel.com/article/464373-Ex_Cablevision_Exec_Gottesman_Joins_Social_Media_Firm.php"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ex-Cablevision Exec Gottesman Joins &lt;b&gt;Social Media&lt;/b&gt; Firm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Multichannel News&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;by MCN Staff -- Multichannel News, 2/23/2011 4:30:56 PM Patricia Gottesman has been named CEO of Crimson Hexagon, a &lt;b&gt;social media&lt;/b&gt; monitoring company on whose board she has served since December. Gottesman spent 28 years at Cablevision, in marketing, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF48PGGcSxeD6y8y96tv0Pj2UUfIA&amp;amp;url=http://www.bizjournals.com/boston/news/2011/02/23/former-cable-exec-to-run-crimson-hexagon.html"&gt;Former cable exec to run Crimson Hexagon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Bizjournals.com&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF51etGD3vjmfb8Vsd3J9OVpxSDCg&amp;amp;url=http://www.mrweb.com/drno/news13184.htm"&gt;Crimson Hexagon Names CEO for &lt;b&gt;Social Media&lt;/b&gt; Analysis Growth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Daily Research News Online&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFMGVpJVwOZm91HdjUWVp2PMvDxKg&amp;amp;url=http://www.xconomy.com/boston/2011/02/23/new-ceo-for-crimson-hexagon/"&gt;New CEO for Crimson Hexagon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Xconomy&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEvZsxo3tJ4FUiKhSI3ztSY9_OvgA&amp;amp;url=http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20110223005291/en/Crimson-Hexagon-Appoints-Patricia-Gottesman-President-CEO"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Business Wire (press release)&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dFo7_YEABk106MM8B0DhQ5BHcfgnM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;all 13 news articles&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.multichannel.com/article/464373-Ex_Cablevision_Exec_Gottesman_Joins_Social_Media_Firm.php</link>
      <guid>http://www.multichannel.com/article/464373-Ex_Cablevision_Exec_Gottesman_Joins_Social_Media_Firm.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Tech Can Make New Hires Feel Like Part of the Team</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/&amp;title=5 Ways Tech Can Make New Hires Feel Like Part of the Team&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/new-job.jpg" alt="" title="new job" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-729675" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/5-ways-tech-can-make-new-hires-feel-like-part-of-the-team" target="_blank"&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; originally appeared on the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/" target="_blank"&gt;American Express OPEN Forum&lt;/a&gt;, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once an employee is hired, our job isn&#8217;t over. In fact, it&#8217;s just begun. Especially when there are surveys out there that say &lt;a href="http://www.businessnewsdaily.com/84-percent-employees-seek-new-jobs-2011-0858/" target="_blank"&gt;84% of employees&lt;/a&gt; plan to look for a new job this year, we have to make sure all of these new hires feel welcome and are successful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we become a more mobile workforce, it&#8217;s essential to think of orientation and onboarding as more than just a single event that takes place on an employee&#8217;s first day. We have to retool our thinking to help employees become a productive member of the team, and technology is an important factor. Here are five ways that companies are using technology and social media to benefit new hires.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Create a Virtual Bulletin Board for the Community&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first thing any new hire is looking for is information &#8211; about the company, his job, benefits, etc. &lt;a href="http://www.lullabot.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Lullabot&lt;/a&gt;, one of the world&#8217;s top open web development, strategy and training organizations, has developed a special process to fill the information gap. Esther Lee, human resource manager, explains the technology resource they&#8217;ve created for employees. &#8220;We&amp;#8217;ve set up an internal site called the Daily Report where we post &#8216;welcome&#8217; greetings for each new employee, and other employees can add welcoming comments. The Daily Report is also where we post birthday announcements, weekly games (often based around getting employees to know each other better), travel tips (for those doing training or attending conferences), as well as other HR-related information on benefits, vacation, etc. It&amp;#8217;s a go-to resource for new employees as well as those who have been with us for years.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lee added that Lullabot&#8217;s culture encourages its virtual workforce to get to know each other via resources like The Daily Report, but also use it for collaborating and finding better technology solutions. &amp;#8220;We&amp;#8217;re pretty efficient at testing different things and determining what works for us and what doesn&amp;#8217;t. Basically, individually, if we see something we like, we try it. And if it rocks, we will try it as a team. And if we love it, we will keep it as a company practice,&amp;#8221; Lee says.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Train Your Employees With Multimedia&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jakesigal" target="_blank"&gt;Jake Sigal&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO of &lt;a href="http://www.livioradio.com" target="_blank"&gt;Livio Radio&lt;/a&gt;, a company that manufactures simple devices and software to help get Internet radio like &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/pandora"&gt;Pandora&lt;/a&gt;, NPR and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/grooveshark"&gt;Grooveshark&lt;/a&gt; into the home and car, creates video vignettes and saves them for when new hires come onboard. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8220;Anytime part of our crew is learning how to do something new, we take a screen video that captures audio from &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/skype"&gt;Skype&lt;/a&gt; or the phone with our questions/answers, save it and add it to the shared drive under the appropriate folder. When someone new comes onboard, it&amp;#8217;s amazing how much faster they can learn something by watching a 1 to 3 minute video, without taking someone else off a project to teach them. Additionally, when interns leave to go back to school, they make videos to show best practices and send to their supervisors before leaving.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another company using video in a big way for training is &lt;a href="http://www.WaterFilters.net" target="_blank"&gt;WaterFilters.net&lt;/a&gt;, a superstore stocking hundreds of thousands of water filtration systems and replacement cartridges. In keeping with its commitment to environmental sustainability, it operates in a 98% paperless format. Karl Rist, content marketing specialist, explains what that means for the company: &#8220;Our corporate trainer utilizes a large flat-screen monitor to teach new associates the &amp;#8216;ins and outs&amp;#8217; of the company&amp;#8217;s order-processing software used for placing, tracking and shipping orders. Every new associate is issued a laptop to follow along, and to place &amp;#8216;practice orders&amp;#8217; of their own. When the trainees move out into the warehouse for additional product training, they bring their laptops with them in a wireless environment to look up different filter specs on the website while further examining them on the shelves.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;New employees continue their filtration education in a series of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; videos &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/aquamanwisdom#p/u/45/huD6kVeH3xg" target="_blank"&gt;featuring&lt;/a&gt; WaterFilters.net Certified Water Specialist Tony (a.k.a. &#8220;Aquaman&#8221;).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Make Employees More Productive With Communication and Collaboration Tech&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Shortly after coming onboard, employees start learning the daily workflow. Then, it&#8217;s time to share with them the tools they need to be a contributor to the team. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/FeeFighters" target="_blank"&gt;Stella Fayman&lt;/a&gt;, marketing ninja for &lt;a href="http://feefighters.com" target="_blank"&gt;FeeFighters&lt;/a&gt;, a credit card processing marketplace and gateway, says that her company looks to solve problems with technology. &#8220;The extent to which we use technology is usually a bit surprising to new hires, but they get used to it very quickly. Using [&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/37signals"&gt;37Signals&lt;/a&gt;] project management tools like Basecamp and company chat tool Campfire just makes communication and organization much easier. There is usually a bit of a learning curve, but these tools are made with the user in mind, so they end up saving time and effort.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fayman recalls an instance of technology bringing one of her team members closer to the group. &#8220;One of our designers is from Bulgaria &amp;#8212; we&amp;#8217;ve never met him in person but have worked with him extensively for more than two years. Once, we were making a video and really wanted to include him. We used Skype to incorporate him into our video and make him feel part of the team. In the video, everyone is dancing and there is a clear shot of Tisho [the Bulgarian coworker] also dancing in tandem on the screen behind us.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.finedesigngroup.com" target="_blank"&gt;FINE Design Group&lt;/a&gt;, a digital branding agency that creates, designs, builds and manages the touchpoints that connect brands with people in the digital space, also leverages technology to keep employees productive. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/finedesigngroup" target="_blank"&gt;Josh Kelly&lt;/a&gt;, managing partner at FINE, says &#8220;The primary vehicle they use is their internal custom wiki (built on PBWorks) which houses everything from company policies and org charts to impromptu lists of best lunch spots and nicknames. This grew organically from the need to point people to documents and info on policies, and &#8216;at a glance&#8217; info, but became more focused on culture over time. It&amp;#8217;s had the effect of cutting down on mass internal email chains dedicated to novelty ideas, and is a very robust way to generate lists of resources of all kinds.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. Use Software to Show Employees How They Fit Into The Big Picture&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/nerdsoncall" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Bauder&lt;/a&gt;, customer service manager at &lt;a href="http://www.callnerds.com" target="_blank"&gt;Nerds On Call&lt;/a&gt;, a company offering on-site computer and electronic repair services to businesses and consumers, shares how communication was key in the employee and company&#8217;s success. &amp;#8220;NERDS created an open policy to allow staff members to see what everyone else in the company was doing. Anyone can sit down at a workstation and get a feel for how the company is doing &amp;#8212; in real time &amp;#8212; through our self-designed database. NERDS have a &#8216;scoreboard&#8217; running that shows how many appointments have been booked, which location they were booked for and whether or not the customer was a return customer or a new customer. We started this process in 2007, and NERDS still uses it today to help employees and employer keep going strong.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bauder adds that NERDS found a way to extend its communication strategy to field technicians. &#8220;A field technician leads a busy work life, often spending much of his time in the car driving from appointment to appointment, and when our locations are spread as far apart as they are, it tends to be a solitary employee existence. We have a Facebook group that has allowed us to create a community among our employees. It affords us the ability to celebrate achievements, birthdays, weddings and company anniversaries, in addition to providing a forum for company-wide communication. It is even used as a basic training tool for technicians &amp;#8212; if a technician runs into a new virus or computer issue, they can use this forum to tell others how they solved the problem or learn from others.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Capitalize on Social and Gamification to Make Work Fun&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/DoubleDutch" target="_blank"&gt;Lawrence Coburn&lt;/a&gt;, CEO and founder of &lt;a href="http://www.doubledutch.me/" target="_blank"&gt;DoubleDutch&lt;/a&gt;, a builder of mobile productivity apps for enterprises, was able to use the company&amp;#8217;s knowledge of an app suite to create something fun for their internal customers (a.k.a. employees.) &#8220;Our &lt;a href="http://www.doubledutch.me/hyve-knowledge-an-internal-case-study/" target="_blank"&gt;HYVE application&lt;/a&gt; is designed to boost employee productivity and collaboration. It uses geo-location, social, gaming and analytics features to allow employees to &#8216;check in&#8217; to projects, customers and locations in one interface. This knowledge allows our employees to celebrate achievements around customers and projects.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coburn says the employees love the app so much that they decided to make it public &amp;#8212; you can download it for &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/my/app/hyve-public/id456292658?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;free&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes link]. &#8220;It helps employees understand how they fit in the company and what everybody&amp;#8217;s roles are. It&amp;#8217;s a natural way to quickly immerse new hires into the company culture from day one. They quickly see that victories at work, no matter how small, are valued and should be shared with the team on HYVE.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;It&amp;#8217;s All About Culture&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;No matter what kind of company you run or work for, successfully onboarding new hires is important to your business and helps to shape and grow the corporate culture. Employees will always need resources and require training, and they want to be productive and look at the big picture. Lastly, they absolutely love to have fun. Therefore, it&amp;#8217;s the HR department&amp;#8217;s role to create a company culture that supports these things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h3&gt;More Small Business Resources From OPEN Forum:&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/15-keyboard-shortcuts-to-enhance-your-pc-productivity" target="_blank"&gt;15 Keyboard Shortcuts To Enhance Your PC Productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/5-services-for-building-websites-on-a-budget" target="_blank"&gt;5 Services For Building Websites On A Budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/10-accessories-to-boost-office-morale" target="_blank"&gt;10 Accessories To Boost Office Morale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/top-5-foursquare-mistakes-committed-by-small-businesses" target="_blank"&gt;Top 5 Foursquare Mistakes Committed By Small Businesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/idea-hub/topics/technology/article/how-to-use-social-media-for-recruiting" target="_blank"&gt;How To Use Social Media For Recruiting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/37signals/"&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/recruiting/"&gt;Recruiting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/mFHcgeDGkPM1oAa3gxcsoBBE44E/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/mFHcgeDGkPM1oAa3gxcsoBBE44E/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/mFHcgeDGkPM1oAa3gxcsoBBE44E/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/mFHcgeDGkPM1oAa3gxcsoBBE44E/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H0zYKmH8MxY:2KHiokF15_I:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/H0zYKmH8MxY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/10/09/tech-new-hires/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Things Entrepreneurs Don&#8217;t Learn in College</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/college.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="college" title="college" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor&#8217;s note&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Altucher"&gt;James Altucher&lt;/a&gt; is an investor, programmer, author, and entrepreneur. He is Managing Director of Formula Capital and has written 6 books on investing. His latest book is &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005VPXXVM/"&gt;I Was Blind But Now I See&lt;/a&gt;. You can follow him&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/jaltucher"&gt;@jaltucher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve written before on &lt;a href="http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2011/01/10-more-reasons-why-parents-should-not-send-their-kids-to-college/"&gt;10 reasons Parents Should Not Send Their Kids to College&lt;/a&gt; and here is also &lt;a href="http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2011/01/8-alternatives-to-college/"&gt;Eight Alternatives to College &lt;/a&gt;but it&amp;#8217;s occurred to me that the place where college has really hurt me the most was when it came to the real world, real life, how to make money, how to build a business, and then even how to survive when trying to build my business, sell it, and be happy afterwards. Here are the ten things that if I had learned them in college I probably would&amp;#8217;ve saved/made millions of extra dollars, not wasted years of my life, and maybe would&amp;#8217;ve even saved lives because I would&amp;#8217;ve been so smart I would&amp;#8217;ve been like an X-Man.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How to Program -&lt;/strong&gt; I spent $100,000 of my own money (via debt, which I paid back in full) majoring in Computer Science. I then went to graduate school in computer science. I then remained in an academic environment for several years doing various computer programming jobs. Finally I hit the real world. I got a job in corporate America. Everyone congratulated me where I worked, &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8217;re going to the real world,&amp;#8221; they said. I was never so happy. I called my friends in NYC, &amp;#8220;money is falling from trees here,&amp;#8221; they said. I looked for apartments in Hoboken. I looked at my girlfriend with a new feeling of gratefulness&#8212;we were going to break up once I moved. I knew it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In other words, life was going to be great. My mom even told me, &amp;#8220;you&amp;#8217;re going to shine at your new job.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Only one problem: when I arrived at the job, after 8 years of learning how to program in an academic environment&#8212;I couldn&amp;#8217;t program. I won&amp;#8217;t get into the details. But I had no clue. I couldn&amp;#8217;t even turn on a computer. It was a mess. I think I even ruined people&amp;#8217;s lives while trying to do my job. I heard my boss whisper to his boss&amp;#8217;s boss, &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t know what we&amp;#8217;re going to do with him, he has no skills.&amp;#8221; And what&amp;#8217;s worse is that I was in a cluster of cubicles so everyone around me could here that whisper also.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So they sent me to two months of remedial programming courses at AT&amp;amp;T in New Jersey. If you&amp;#8217;ve never been in an AT&amp;amp;T complex it&amp;#8217;s like being a stormtrooper learning how to go to the bathroom in the Death Star where, inconceivably, in six Star Wars movies there is no evidence of any bathrooms. Seriously, you couldn&amp;#8217;t find a bathroom in these places. They were mammoth but if you turned down a random corner then, whallah!&#8212;there might be an arts &amp;amp; crafts show. The next corner would have a display of patents, like &amp;#8220;how to eliminate static on a phone line &amp;#8211; 1947&amp;#8243;. But I did finally learn how to program.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I know this because I ran into a guy I used to work with ten years ago who works at the same place I used to work at. &amp;#8220;Man,&amp;#8221; he says, &amp;#8220;they still use your code.&amp;#8221; And I was like, &amp;#8220;really?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Yeah,&amp;#8221; he said, &amp;#8220;because its like spaghetti and nobody can figure out how to modify it or even replace it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So, everything I dedicated my academic career to was flushed down the toilet. The last time I programmed a computer was 1999. It didn&amp;#8217;t work. So I gave up. Goodbye C++. I hope I never see you and your &amp;#8220;objects&amp;#8221; again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How to Be Betrayed.&lt;/strong&gt; A girlfriend about 20 years ago wrote in her diary. &amp;#8220;I wish James would just die. That would make this so much easier. Whenever I kiss him I&amp;#8217;m thinking of X&amp;#8221;. Where X was a good friend of mine. Of course I put up with it. We went out for several more months. It&amp;#8217;s just a diary, right? She didn&amp;#8217;t really mean it! I mean, c&amp;#8217;mon. Who would think about someone else when kissing my beautiful face? I confronted her of course. She said, &amp;#8220;why would you read through my personal items?&amp;#8221; Which was true! Why would I? Don&amp;#8217;t have I have any personal items of my own I could read through? Or a good book, for instance, to take up my time and educate myself? Kiss, kiss, kiss.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;#8217;t they have a good college course called BETRAYAL 101. I can teach it. Topics we will cover: Betrayal by a business partner, betrayal by investors, betrayal by a girlfriend (I&amp;#8217;d bring in a special lecturer to talk about betrayal by men, kind of like how Gwynneth Paltrow does it in Glee), betrayal by children (since they cleverly push the boundaries right at the limit of betrayal and you have to know when to recognize that they&amp;#8217;ve stepped over the line, betrayal by friends/family (note to all the friends/family that think I am talking about them, &lt;em&gt;I am not&lt;/em&gt;&#8212;this is a serious academic proposal about what needs to be taught in college)&#8212;you help them, then get betrayed &amp;#8211; how to deal with that?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then there are the more subtle issues of betrayal &amp;#8211; self-sabotage. How you can make enough money to live forever and then repeatedly find yourself in soup kitchens, licking envelopes, attending 12 step meetings, taking medications, and finally reaching some sort of spiritual recognition that it all doesn&amp;#8217;t matter until the next time you sink even lower. This might be in BETRAYAL 201. Or graduate level studies. I don&amp;#8217;t know. Maybe the Department of Defense needs to give me a grant to work on this since that&amp;#8217;s who funds much of our education.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;3. Oh shoot, I was going to put Self-Sabotage into a third category and not make it a sub-category of How to Be Betrayed. Hmmm, how do I write myself out of this conundrum. College, after all, does teach one how to put ideas into a cohesive &amp;#8220;report&amp;#8221; that is handed in and graded. Did I form my thesis, argue it correctly, conclude correctly, not diverge into things like &amp;#8220;Kim Kardashian will never be the betrayer, only the betrayed.&amp;#8221; But this brings me to: &lt;strong&gt;Writing.&lt;/strong&gt; Why can&amp;#8217;t college teach people how to actually write. Some of my best friends tell me college taught them how to think. Thinking has a $200,000 price tag apparently and there is no room left over for good writing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And what is&lt;strong&gt; good writing?&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#8217;s not an opinion. Or a rant. Or a thesis with logical steps, a deep cavern underneath, beautiful horizons and mountaintops at the top. It&amp;#8217;s blood. It&amp;#8217;s Carrie-style blood. Where everyone has been fooling you until that exact moment when now, with the psychic power of the written word, you spray pig blood everywhere, at everyone, and most of all you are covered in blood yourself, the same blood that pushed you out of your mother&amp;#8217;s womb, until just the act of writing itself is a birth, a separation between the old you and the new you&#8212;the you that can no longer take the words back, the words that now must live and breathe and mature and either make something of themselves in life, or remain one of the little blips that reminds us of how small we really are in an infinite universe. [See also, &lt;a href="http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2011/03/33-unusual-tips-to-being-a-better-writer/"&gt;33 Unusual Tips to Be a Better Writer&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Dinner Parties&lt;/strong&gt;. How come I never learned about dinner parties in college. Sure, there were parties among other people who looked like me and talked like me and thought like me&#8212;other college students of my age and rough background. But Dinner Parties as an adult are a whole new beast. There are drinks and snacks beforehand where small talk has to disguise itself as big talk and then there&amp;#8217;s the parts where you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; that everyone is equally worried about what people think about them but that still doesn&amp;#8217;t help at those moments when you talk and you wonder what did people think of &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;? Nobody cares, you tell yourself, intellectually rifling through pages of self-help blogs in your mind that told you that nobody gives a sh*t about you. But still, why don&amp;#8217;t we have a class where there&amp;#8217;s Dinner Party after Dinner Party and you learn how to talk at the right moments, say smart things, be quiet at the right moments, learn to excuse yourself during the mingling so you can drift from person to person. Learn how to interrupt a conversation without being rude. Learn how to thank the host so you can be invited to the next party. And so on. Which brings me to:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Networking.&lt;/strong&gt; Did it really take 20 years after I graduated college before someone wrote a book, &amp;#8220;Never Eat Alone.&amp;#8221; Why didn&amp;#8217;t Jesus write that book. Or Plato. Then we might&amp;#8217;ve read it in religious school or it would&amp;#8217;ve been one of those &amp;#8220;big Thinkers&amp;#8221; we need to read in college so we can learn how to think. I still don&amp;#8217;t know how to network properly so this paragraph is small. I&amp;#8217;m classified under the DSM VI as a &amp;#8220;social shut-in&amp;#8221;. I&amp;#8217;d like to get out and be social but when the moment comes, I can only make it out the door about one in ten times. I always say, &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;d love to get together&amp;#8221; but then I don&amp;#8217;t know how to do it. Perhaps because not one dollar of my $100,000 spent on not learning how to program a computer was also not spent on learning how to network with people. [See also, my recent TechCrunch article, "&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/10/23/9-skills-super-connector/"&gt;9 Ways to be a Super-Connector&lt;/a&gt;"]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Politics.&lt;/strong&gt; My very first girlfriend, the girl who first laughed hysterically when I showed her a piece of chewing gum I found on the ground that had sculpted itself into the muddy shape of a heart, took me to a movie called &amp;#8220;Salvador&amp;#8221;. Then there was a discussion group afterwards about how the Contras are bad, or good, I forget, and everyone was nodding and speaking in a Spanish accent. And afterwards my girlfriend was upset, &amp;#8220;why aren&amp;#8217;t you talking?&amp;#8221; Because truth was I was so tired I couldn&amp;#8217;t think but nobody ever taught me how to tell the truth so I lied and said, &amp;#8220;it moved me so much I&amp;#8217;m still absorbing it&amp;#8221; and my girlfriend said, &amp;#8220;yeah, I can see that.&amp;#8221; And nobody ever taught me that there&amp;#8217;s more than one acceptable opinion on a college campus.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My roommate for instance would tell me, &amp;#8220;Reagan is definitely getting impeached &lt;em&gt;this time.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; And I visited his dad&amp;#8217;s mansion over Christmas break and he told me all about Trotskyism and the proletariat and I had to work jobs 40 hours a week while taking six courses so I could A) graduate early and B) pay my personal expenses and when I would run into him he had long hair and would nod about how a lot of the college workers (but not the lowest-paid, poorest treated ones&#8212;the students who worked) were thinking of unionizing and he was helping with that. &amp;#8220;Do you have a job?&amp;#8221; I asked and he said, &amp;#8220;no time&amp;#8221;. And that&amp;#8217;s politics in college.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What about the real politics of how people try to backstab you at the corporate workplace or VCs never properly explained the &amp;#8220;ratchet&amp;#8221; concept to you before they kicked you out of the company and then re-financed. Nobody told me a thing about that in three years of college and two years of graduate school. I wish I would&amp;#8217;ve known that for my $100,000.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Failure.&lt;/strong&gt; Goes without saying they don&amp;#8217;t teach you this. If you are going to pay $100,000, why would you fail? You might think you were wasting your money if the first mandatory elective you had to take was about failure. About wondering how you were going to feed your family after you got fired when something that was not your fault: Post-Traumatic-Lehman-Stress Syndrome, a common medical condition coming up in the DSM VII&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Sales.&lt;/strong&gt; When I was busy learning how to &amp;#8220;not program&amp;#8221; nobody ever taught me how to sell what it was I was programming. Or sell myself. Or sell out. Or sell my ideas and turn them into money. Or sell a product to someone who might need it. Or even better, sell it to someone who doesn&amp;#8217;t need it. Some business programs might have courses on salesmanship but those are BS because everyone automatically gets As in MBA programs so that the schools can demonstrate what good jobs their students get so they then get more applicants and the scam/cycle continues. But sales: how to demonstrate passion behind an idea you had, you built, you signed up for, so that people are willing to pay hard-earned after-tax money for it, is the number one key to any success and I have never seen it taught (properly) in college.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Negotiation.&lt;/strong&gt; You&amp;#8217;ve gotten the idea, you executed, you made the sale and now&amp;#8230;what&amp;#8217;s the price. What part of your body will be amputated in exchange for infinite wisdom. Will you give up one eye? Or your virility? Because something has to go if you are up against a good negotiator? What? You already thought (like most people without any experience do) that you were &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; a good negotiator. A good negotiator will skin your back, tattoo it with &amp;#8220;SUCKA&amp;#8221; and hang it up above the fireplace in his pool house if you don&amp;#8217;t know what you are doing. The funny thing is, the best sales people (who are just aiming for people to say &amp;#8220;Yes!&amp;#8221;) are often the worst negotiators (&amp;#8220;it&amp;#8217;s very hard to say &amp;#8220;No&amp;#8221; when you are trying to get people to &amp;#8220;Yes&amp;#8221;). These are things I wish I had learned in school. I&amp;#8217;ve been beaten in negotiations on at least five different occasions, which fortunately became five valuable lessons I&amp;#8217;ve learned the hard way, instead of studying examples and being forced to think about it for the $100k in debt I got going to college.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;People will say, &amp;#8220;well, that&amp;#8217;s your experience in college. Mine was very different.&amp;#8221; And it&amp;#8217;s true. You joined the sororities and learned how to network and dinner party and be political and know everything there is to know about betrayal. My college experience was sadly unique and probably different from everyone else&amp;#8217;s so you would be completely right to quote me that inane statistic about how college graduates earn 4% more than high school graduates and are consequently 4% happier .&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;(Another thing, &lt;strong&gt;10. Happiness.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2011/02/how-to-be-the-luckiest-guy-on-the-planet-in-4-easy-steps/"&gt;We never learn how it&amp;#8217;s a combination&lt;/a&gt; of the food we eat, our health, our ability to be creative, our ability to have sound emotional relationships, our ability to find something bigger than ourselves and our egos to give up our spiritual virginity to.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I can tell you what I wish I did. I wish I had gone to Soviet Russia, and played chess, and then gone to India and learned yoga and health, and I wish I had gone to South America and volunteered for kids with no arms, and did any number of things. But people then say, &amp;#8220;haha! but that cost money.&amp;#8221; And they would be right. It would cost less than $100,000+ but would still cost some money. I have no idea how much.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But one of these days when the scars of college go away and I truly learn how to think. I might have better comebacks for these people. Or if I truly learn, I would learn not to care at all.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jaltucher"&gt;Follow me on Twitter.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Or, just as good, buy &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005VPXXVM/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Was Blind But Now I See&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, send me the receipt and you get my next self-published book for free (PDF).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: Flickr/&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/herry/3904914700/"&gt;Herry Lawford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/451250/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/12/10-things-entrepreneurs-dont-learn-in-college/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/12/10-things-entrepreneurs-dont-learn-in-college/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Best Practices For Small Business YouTube Marketing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/&amp;title=6 Best Practices For Small Business YouTube Marketing&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/viralvid-youtube.jpg" alt="" title="viral video youtube pic" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-790965" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/articles/6-best-practices-for-small-business-youtube-marketing" target="_blank"&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; originally appeared on the &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.openforum.com/" target="_blank"&gt;American Express OPEN Forum&lt;/a&gt;, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mention &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and most people will picture cats playing piano. But among a certain type of small businessperson, the name conjures another image: Dollar signs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Such entrepreneurs can often sound like brainwashed cult members &amp;#8212; in a good way. For instance, Scott Imbrie, owner of Original Skateboards, a brand that has been built largely on its YouTube presence, says the platform is better for marketers than even &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#8220;YouTube is actually the biggest social media site,&amp;#8221; he says. &amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s bigger than Facebook or &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another YouTube proselytizer is Jeffrey Harmon, chief marketing officer for Orabrush, a Provo, Utah oral care brand that recently parlayed a series of successful YouTube videos into a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/20/orabrush-walmar/"&gt;national distribution deal at Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. Original Skateboards, which joined YouTube in 2005 and Orabrush, which dropped its first YouTube video in 2009, were clearly ahead of the curve, but YouTube is still a great place to launch or grow a brand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Below are some tips from entrepreneurs who have thrived on YouTube, plus some from Lane Shackleton, product manager for YouTube and, yes, a distant relative of polar explorer &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ernest_Shackleton" target="_blank"&gt;Ernest Shackleton&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Don&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;Expect&lt;/em&gt; Your Video to go Viral&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/nFeb6YBftHE?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Are you ready to become the next Orabrush? Maybe it&amp;#8217;s time to reset your expectations. Harmon helpfully points out that 48 hours of video are loaded to YouTube every minute, so you&amp;#8217;re probably better off playing Powerball than waiting for your clip to take off. &amp;#8220;Anyone who thinks they&amp;#8217;re going to have a video go crazy on YouTube is dreaming,&amp;#8221; says Harmon. &amp;#8220;Think base hits, not home runs.&amp;#8221; Raw numbers aren&amp;#8217;t as important as reaching the right customers, so don&amp;#8217;t freak out if you&amp;#8217;re nowhere near a million views.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Buy Some Ads &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since your video is probably not going to go viral on its own (or at all), you should consider buying some ads on YouTube. Fortunately, rates are pretty good compared to &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/03/27/google-adwords-tips/"&gt;AdWords&lt;/a&gt;. Harmon says that right now search ads on YouTube are going for 50 cents per click vs. $1.50 per click on AdWords. That said, you don&amp;#8217;t have to sink a fortune into it. In Orabrush&amp;#8217;s early days, the company spent $30 a day on YouTube search ads. Though Orabrush got a lot more bang for its buck back then, Harmon says you can still do pretty well today buying Promoted Videos, the ads that pop up when you do a YouTube search. However, no matter what you spend on ads, make sure the content is relevant to the search term. Google will base the ad&amp;#8217;s position on that relevance. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Use Comments, Hot Spots and A/B Testing as Your Focus Group &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you hire a Madison Avevue ad agency to run a TV spot, they&amp;#8217;re likely going to want to subject the ad to focus group testing. But if you&amp;#8217;re a small DIY advertiser, your best approximation of a focus group &amp;#8212; aside from your wife and her friends from the Rotary Club &amp;#8212; are the comments below your video. Granted, many will be insipid and/or obscene, but some just may have some insight. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beyond that, YouTube has some other tools to help you gauge how your video is being received. Chief among these is &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2008/09/your-youtube-video-hot-or-not.html" target="_blank"&gt;Hot Spots&lt;/a&gt;, a technology that lets you see when people are tuning in and out of your video. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another option is A/B Testing. Big ad firms do this as well, but you can do this on a smaller scale by running two different versions of your clip as an &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/support/youtube/bin/answer.py?answer=181547" target="_blank"&gt;Unlisted Video&lt;/a&gt; backed by search ads and then watching to see which one gets the better response. Then, you choose the winner.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/24/how-to-use-google-analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, which will at least tell you how much referral traffic you&amp;#8217;re getting from YouTube. Shackleton says on average, people who come to your site from YouTube spend more time there than if they came from somewhere else. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. Watch a Lot of YouTube &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re serious about using YouTube as a marketing platform, then do your research. Forget about watching TV ads and spend a few hours discovering what&amp;#8217;s hot on YouTube. Harmon says he and his staff spend several hours &lt;i&gt;every day&lt;/i&gt; doing just that. Harmon says the goal is to begin to &amp;#8220;recognize good ideas.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Track That ROI &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re spending money on YouTube ads, you will likely want to know what you have to show for it. The fact that people have clicked through your ads is great, but the novelty will wear off quickly if they&amp;#8217;re not actually buying anything. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now here&amp;#8217;s the surprising part: Despite the fact that Google owns YouTube and marketing on YouTube is, by definition, 21st century digital and cutting edge, you still have to rely on a fairly improvisational, analog form of ROI tracking. &amp;#8220;We count the number of views, of course, the combined total for the videos on our YouTube channel was close to a million last time I added them up, and we track the traffic to our sites from the videos, but that&amp;#8217;s about all we&amp;#8217;ve got in terms of hard data,&amp;#8221; says Ed Davis, president of &lt;a href="http://www.ceilume.com" target="_blank"&gt;Ceilume&lt;/a&gt;, a Graton, Calif., company that makes ceiling tiles and has more than 1 million views on its YouTube channel. &amp;#8220;We also rely heavily upon what our customer service people tell us they hear from on the phones every day and what they hear is that customers watch the videos, and the videos help.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;6. Find Your Niche &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OW-J2pQrlsw?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you followed Step 4 and watched copious amounts of YouTube programming, you should be getting a sense of what will and won&amp;#8217;t fly on YouTube. Guess what? No one wants to watch an ad unless it&amp;#8217;s really, really good. But rather than try to crack the code on a spectacular ad (something that the ad industry is generally unable to do with any regularity), Shackleton suggests either positioning yourself as an expert in your particular field (as Ceilume has) or attaching your brand to a particular lifestyle (Original Skateboards&amp;#8217;s approach). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Pick an interesting part of your brand and focus on it,&amp;#8221; Shackleton says. But what if you sell something really boring, like plumbing supplies? Chances are this is interesting to someone, perhaps someone who has to fix their toilet in a hurry. Get inside their head and make a video directed to their likely concerns. Whatever you do, don&amp;#8217;t think like a traditional advertiser. &amp;#8220;The key is creating stuff that helps people, that people connect to and allows them to explore,&amp;#8221; says Imbrie. &amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s not about advertising.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Images courtesy of Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/brightplanet/" target="_blank"&gt;Bright Planet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thegrid-ch/" target="_blank"&gt;TheGrid-ch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/small-business-resources/"&gt;Small Business Resources&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/dO8AiIqQSgptOwLmhrrXHPnh-1Y/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/dO8AiIqQSgptOwLmhrrXHPnh-1Y/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/dO8AiIqQSgptOwLmhrrXHPnh-1Y/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/dO8AiIqQSgptOwLmhrrXHPnh-1Y/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=G8jAx8AN1os:Q4njm9C46AM:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/business/~4/G8jAx8AN1os" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/05/youtube-small-biz-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OCCUPY OAKLAND: Police launch tear gas, flash-bang canisters into crowd of protesters - Video - KTVU San Francisco</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a1.twimg.com/profile_images/1521669219/frog_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/GreenJ"&gt;Jonathan Green&lt;/a&gt;: police move in on Oakland occupiers with explosive devices &lt;a href="http://t.co/bOlzOl9V" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/bOlzOl9V&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/GreenJ/status/129067618949804032"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.ktvu.com/video/29587140/index.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.ktvu.com/video/29587140/index.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Connect to the Local Food Movement Online</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/&amp;title=5 Ways to Connect to the Local Food Movement Online&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/vegetables.jpg" alt="" title="vegetables" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-767733" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The local food movement is taking the world by storm, as more people learn about the numerous benefits of eating locally. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What exactly is local food? Is it hype? In a word, no. It&amp;#8217;s grown nearby, and supports your local economy. It tastes better because your food is often harvested on the day of purchase. It&amp;#8217;s healthier, as local crops are designed to taste good rather than spend weeks in transit and on store shelves. Plus, eliminating that long trip fights climate change. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re interested in learning more about sustainable farming practices, there are plenty of online resources &amp;#8212; and even mobile apps &amp;#8212; that can make eating environmentally sustainable food easy. If you&amp;#8217;re already connected with the local food movement, you can share your expertise with online communities hoping to create extensive databases of farms, shops, butchers, bakers and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In honor of World Food Day (Oct. 16), &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; is participating in &lt;a href="http://blogactionday.org/why-food/" target="_blank"&gt;Blog Action Day&lt;/a&gt;, which is seeking to create an online global conversation about food issues. We&amp;#8217;ve chosen to contribute by sparking a discussion of local farming. We hope this post opens your eyes to ways you can connect with the local food movement, by making your daily food consumption more environmentally and economically sustainable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Are you a subscriber to the local food movement? Please let us know in the comments if you know of other ways to connect online.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;a href="http://www.wholeshare.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Wholeshare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/#300991-Wholeshare"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.wholeshare.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Wholeshare&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/local-food-movement/Picture 11.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wholeshare makes purchasing locally grown food up to 20% more affordable through the power of group buying. Groups of shoppers are automatically joined together by the site and treated like a wholesale client. The site, functioning as the middleman, coordinates delivery directly to your door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/#300991-Wholeshare'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of flickr user &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/65313460@N08/" target="_blank"&gt;wasd38&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/blog-action-day/"&gt;blog action day&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/blogging/"&gt;blogging&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/local-food/"&gt;Local Food&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-good/"&gt;Social Good&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-good/"&gt;Social Good&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/socialgood" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Good on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/socialgood" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialgood" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Good channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EWFrNfs-D4xagyiqfUjwCcQjnpg/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EWFrNfs-D4xagyiqfUjwCcQjnpg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EWFrNfs-D4xagyiqfUjwCcQjnpg/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EWFrNfs-D4xagyiqfUjwCcQjnpg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=9Y4vqSXfjns:Kei4x9Y3gjU:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/9Y4vqSXfjns" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/10/16/local-food-movement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIM CEO on the BlackBerry Outage: &#8220;We&#8217;ve Let Many of You Down&#8221;</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zQ1esvGae_s?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After nearly four full days of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/10/12/blackberry-outages-email-backup/"&gt;global RIM BlackBerry service outages&lt;/a&gt;, RIM founder and co-CEO Mike Lazaridis finally stepped forward to offer his apologies for the service disruptions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;RIM BlackBerry email service, which manages the email system for millions of customers around the world, suffered a failure in Europe four days ago, which eventually caused a significant email backlog. The company&#8217;s failovers also failed unexpectedly and eventually, RIM was forced to throttle service in Europe to try and address the problem. That action led to a mail slow down and disruption of service in other parts of the world, including the U.S., starting Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lazaridis was mostly absent from RIM&#8217;s outage updates until this video. However, this morning he offered a full apology. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&amp;#8217;s been my goal,&#8221; said Lazaridis on a YouTube video, &#8220;to provide reliable real-time communications around the world. We did not deliver on that goal this week. Not even close.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;RIM&#8217;s BlackBerry service is reportedly slowly returning to normal in Europe, the Middle East and Africa, but it has not yet been fully restored here in the U.S. Lazaridis could not offer a timetable for full restoration. &#8220;It&#8217;s too soon to say this issue is resolved.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lazaridis also echoed RIM CTO for Software David Yach&#8217;s comments Wednesday, promising that RIM is &#8220;working tirelessly&#8221; to fix the problem and &#8220;restore your trust in us.&#8221; The CEO, who admitted, &#8220;you expect better from us,&#8221; has had a tough year and these latest woes come at a particularly difficult time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;RIM has been steadily losing market share &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/03/08/android-smartphone-platform-report/"&gt;to Android phones&lt;/a&gt; and Apple and, despite a number of new handsets, is no longer seen as a smartphone leader. The disruption occurs just as Apple introduces its latest handset, the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/iphone-4s/"&gt;iPhone 4S&lt;/a&gt;. RIM&#8217;s highly anticipated PlayBook tablet launched earlier this year without some key features and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/14/rim-490000-playbooks/"&gt;has not sold&lt;/a&gt; particularly well. Plus the CEO notoriously &lt;a href="http://macdailynews.com/2011/04/13/rims-half-ceo-lazaridis-walks-out-of-bbc-interview/" target="_blank"&gt;stormed out&lt;/a&gt; of an interview when he didn&#8217;t like the questions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What do you think of Lazaridis&#8217;s video performance. Is it enough? Tell us in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/blackberry/"&gt;blackberry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mike-lazaridis/"&gt;mike lazaridis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/rim/"&gt;RIM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/smart-phones/"&gt;Smart phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/v-WpD2O8EzznC50a2SgSX4XlRJY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/v-WpD2O8EzznC50a2SgSX4XlRJY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/v-WpD2O8EzznC50a2SgSX4XlRJY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/v-WpD2O8EzznC50a2SgSX4XlRJY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=UvibNtQlXLc:WqrbJBLlpuI:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/tech/~4/UvibNtQlXLc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/10/13/blackberry-outage-rim-response/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/10/13/blackberry-outage-rim-response/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Stops Development of Mobile Browser Flash [REPORT]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/&amp;title=Adobe Stops Development of Mobile Browser Flash [REPORT]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/flash-html5-225-e1297287594566.jpg" alt="" title="Flash-logobig" class="alignright" height="" width="275"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Adobe has ceased the development of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/flash/"&gt;Flash&lt;/a&gt; Player for browsers on mobile devices, ZDNet reports citing an upcoming announcement from Adobe. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Our future work with Flash on mobile devices will be focused on enabling Flash developers to package native apps with Adobe AIR for all the major app stores. We will no longer adapt Flash Player for mobile devices to new browser, OS version or device configurations,&amp;#8221; says Adobe&amp;#8217;s announcement which is reportedly due to be released today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, Adobe will focus its development efforts on mobile apps and HTML5.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is quite a hit for Android and its developers, since Flash support on Android devices was often highlighted as one of the advantages of that platform over Apple&amp;#8217;s iOS. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s also a big victory for Apple, a company that claimed &amp;#8211; most famously in Steve Jobs&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/04/29/steve-jobs-flash-is-no-longer-necessary/"&gt;open letter on Flash&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; that Flash simply isn&amp;#8217;t reliable, secure or fast enough to be used on mobile devices. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re awaiting the official announcement from Adobe and will update this article if necessary. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/adobe/"&gt;adobe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/browser/"&gt;browser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/flash/"&gt;Flash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/smartphones/"&gt;smartphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Mobile on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.mobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/mobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Mobile channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/duOGhZ7sgLKZO7cvNNsvIcswN_o/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/duOGhZ7sgLKZO7cvNNsvIcswN_o/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/duOGhZ7sgLKZO7cvNNsvIcswN_o/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/duOGhZ7sgLKZO7cvNNsvIcswN_o/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=_6IcC9pCURE:2VBwpqX_ThA:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/_6IcC9pCURE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/09/adobe-mobile-browser-flash/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Releases 3 Budget Facebook Phones for Emerging Markets</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/&amp;title=Orange Releases 3 Budget Facebook Phones for Emerging Markets&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/360phones.jpg" alt="phones image" title="phones image" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-801901" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Facebook is about to get a brand new bag with the release of three budget phones aimed at new smartphone users and developing communities. The phones were developed by Alcatel and will be released and supported exclusively by Orange, one of the UK&amp;#8217;s leading mobile providers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The phones will have three tiered prices with more features being offered with more expensive models. The top model, the Alcatel One Touch 908F will cost approximately $130. The middle model, the One Touch 813F, will cost approximately $80 and the cheapest model, the One Touch 585F will cost about $54.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All the phones will come with &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook &lt;/a&gt;pre-loaded and deeply integrated into all their features including a dedicated Facebook button. People can use Facebook to sync their address books and calendar reminders, browse multimedia and send and share messages and photos. The phones feature touch screens, full keyboards and a variety of connectivity options.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While the two more expensive models are aimed at first-time smartphone users, the 585F was built with emerging markets in mind. The phone has GPRS connectivity and limited media functionality. This, however, is to make sure that the phone can be used in remote areas that might not have strong coverage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/640orange.jpg" alt="orange image" title="orange image" width="640" height="307" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-801903" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The three phones mark a big step for &lt;a href="http://www.orange.com/en_EN/" target="_blank"&gt;Orange&lt;/a&gt;, which is touting the new products as a way to spread and democratize the mobile Internet. &amp;#8220;What matters to [our customers] is for them to stay connected to their communities, to their close friends, to their families and Facebook is usually at the center of that,&amp;#8221; says Patrick Remy, Orange&amp;#8217;s VP of Devices. Orange has been working to trim not just the phone cost but the data and mobile plans. Remy says that in Romania, for example, data plans will start as low as $12 a month.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Orange is taking Facebook integration seriously. While data and calls will be subject to standard rates, Remy says that customers will be able to use unlimited Facebook connectivity for free.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a huge deal especially with the lower-price 585F meant for developing communities. Phones are sometimes the only way people in these areas can access the Internet. Not only will this option allow them to access the Internet for free, but it positions Facebook as the de facto portal and lifeline to messaging, information and community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Orange has put in place several safeguards to make sure that emerging markets can reliably access and get the most out of these phones, including a &amp;#8220;Digital Coach Strategy&amp;#8221; to help new users understand their phone&amp;#8217;s features and the ability to sign up to Facebook directly through the phone. &amp;#8220;We are a network operator,&amp;#8221; Remy says. &amp;#8220;We only live and breathe if we provide a good quality service in terms of connectivity.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although the 585F has fewer features, Orange built it to work in low-coverage areas. &amp;#8220;We have to make sure that we don&amp;#8217;t over-promise &amp;#8230; there would be nothing worse than selling these relatively high-market devices and [our customers] were not able to access the wealth of rich information that we offered.&amp;#8221; The 585F, for example, won&amp;#8217;t have the same rich multimedia experience as its more expensive siblings but will come with fast and consistent Facebook messaging and community tools. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The phones are expected to roll out across Europe and Africa as early as December with countries added through early 2012.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will Orange&amp;#8217;s Facebook phones help democratize the Internet? Is Orange milking a new market or providing an invaluable service? Sound off in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ict4d/" target="_blank"&gt;ICT4D.at&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/africa/"&gt;africa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/europe/"&gt;europe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/gadgets/"&gt;Gadgets&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile-phones/"&gt;mobile phones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/phones/"&gt;phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/xsyqnlKVVbh2UB3stOob4zLycfk/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/xsyqnlKVVbh2UB3stOob4zLycfk/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/xsyqnlKVVbh2UB3stOob4zLycfk/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/xsyqnlKVVbh2UB3stOob4zLycfk/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=9CyPTW994yA:FyO8LmdBIcc:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/tech/~4/9CyPTW994yA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/orange-facebook-phones/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
