<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>NBA Brings Twitter Handles to T-Shirts in Pro Sports First</title>
      <description>So you're a big Kevin Durant fan. You watch his games, you wear his jersey -- but do you have his Twitter-handle T-shirt?</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/nba-brings-twitter-handles-t-shirts-pro-sports-184646980.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/nba-brings-twitter-handles-t-shirts-pro-sports-184646980.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sir Richard Branson Unveils &#8216;Virgin Volcanic&#8217;</title>
      <description>Journey to the center of the earth? Virgin CEO Sir Richard Branson would like you to think the famous Jules Verne novel could be a reality. On April 1, Branson&#8217;s Virgin Volcanic program, which will supposedly launch five people into the center of the earth, goes live. If that doesn&#8217;t raise your suspicions of a prank, the news release contains nutty quotes about traveling into live, active volcanos. The Virgin Volcanic website says the vehicle will take a group of people, including Branson, into the earth&#8217;s core through one of five active volcanos (Etna in Sicily, Italy; Stromboli, Aeolian Islands; Yasur, Republic of Vanuatu; Ambrym, Republic of Vanuatu and Tinakula; Solomon Islands) and emerge on the other side of the world. Sound like a joke? It is. No one has ever been to the center of the earth, but scientists have used seismic observations to speculate that the earth&#8217;s mantle is made of liquid iron and nickel. Others say a black hole is at the center of the earth. The press release says the corkscrew-like vehicle is made from &#8220;patented&#8221; carbon carbon. Branson said, &#8220;I have a long held a fascination with volcanoes having read Jules Verne&#8217;s Journey to the Centre of the Earth as a young boy. I decided that one day I would go there too. Alongside our adventures with Virgin Galactic and Virgin Oceanic, volcanoes are the next great unexplored terrain. What can I say, I lava challenge!&#8221; The spiral-shaped probe looks straight out of Austin Powers. Seth Green, the actor who played Dr. Evil&#8217;s son Scott in the movie Austin Powers, is one of the passengers. He is quoted on the site saying, &#8220;Ever since filming Austin Powers, I&#8217;ve had this obsession with underground layers. I&#8217;ve waited patiently for Sir Richard to make the dream of traveling to the Earth&#8217;s core a reality.&#8221; Liquid hot mag-ma, anyone? The other riders include actor Tom Hanks, Will.i.am and documentary filmmaker Barbara Kopple. The post goes even further to say Barbara Kopple will make a documentary about the expedition, along with a soundtrack by Will.i.am that will be recorded inside an active volcano. Some companies just can&#8217;t wait for April Fools&#8217; Day to arrive. Already by Saturday, pranks were hitting the web, with some sharp commenters catching on to the jokes and others taking it very seriously. What do you think about Branson&#8217;s Virgin Volcanic announcement? Did you get a laugh from this prank? Tell us in the comments. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto/Bierchen&#8236; More About: april fools, Google, Google Maps, Virgin</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/richard-branson-virgin-volcanic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/richard-branson-virgin-volcanic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Apps You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss [PICS]</title>
      <description>If you're in a long-distance relationship, then Pair is an app you need to own. The app creates a private shared timeline for couple, allowing them to swap photos and share videos photos and their locations. The app also includes &#8220;thumb kiss&#8221; feature that vibrates the screen when both people touch the same part of their iPhone screen.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/7-apps-dont-want-miss-pics-153213799.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/7-apps-dont-want-miss-pics-153213799.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 New Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>Did you spend this week buying lottery tickets and following the Mega Millions jackpot? Well, now that you know you didn&#8217;t win, it&#8217;s time to throw away your tickets and catch up on the new digital media resources you missed on Mashable. This week we have the most-followed men on Pinterest, tips for how to be more genuinely engaging online, and 15 sessions you can&#8217;t miss at Mashable Connect 2012. We&#8217;ve also covered the evolution of Anonymous, cities that are benefiting from mobile apps, and cases that will make your white iPhone pop. We even have photos from an office tour of GetGlue&#8216;s fun-filled space. Here are the best of this week&#8217;s social media, business and technology resources. Editor&#8217;s Picks The Evolution of Anonymous The evolution of Anonymous, a notorious group of hackers that has acquired a worldwide following. Plus, the group&#8217;s top 10 defining hacks. Stickers Galore: Check Out GetGlue&#8217;s Fun-Filled Office [PICS] GetGlue&#8217;s New York City headquarters are full of stickers, pop culture and fun. The 10 Most-Followed Men on Pinterest Men are influential on Pinterest, too. Find out the top 10 male users on the social network. How do their numbers stack up to the gals? Behind the Scenes of the World&#8217;s First Live-Tweeted Open-Heart Surgery Doctors and digital pros from the hospital that pulled off the world&#8217;s first live-tweeted open-heart surgery give their inside story. 10 Tips for Raising Money on Kickstarter The lessons one Kickstarter participant learned are worth knowing. If you&#8217;re looking to get funded on Kickstarter, here are ten tips to help you succeed. Social Media 9 Free Tumblr Themes That Look Like Pinterest Looking to turn your Tumblr into a Pinterest board? Several themes can help make that happen. How to Make Images Stand Out on Pinterest [INFOGRAPHIC] With more than 12 million users on Pinterest it&#8217;s important to make your images stand out. Here&#8217;s how to optimize your pins. 20 TV Shows With the Most Social Media Buzz This Week [CHART] Which TV shows generate the most buzz on social networks? Find out each week from our social TV chart. Mashable Connect Agenda: 15 Exciting Sessions to Learn From We&#8217;re excited to announce the Mashable Connect 2012 agenda. This year&#8217;s lineup covers a wide range of topics on the state and future of digital. 20 Over-The-Top Tweets About the Mega Millions Jackpot The mind-boggling $540 million Mega Millions jackpot spawned multitudes of entertaining Twitter messages about the lottery. The Evolution of Facebook for Brands Facebook Timeline for businesses is officially here. A look back at the major Facebook milestones that lead to this. For more social media news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s social media channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Business &amp; Marketing 5 Key Talents of Successful Startup Founders Some qualities are essential to becoming a successful startup founder. These five talents, in particular, are vital for entrepreneurs. 4 Tips For Authentic Online Engagement When you think about authenticity as it relates to your brand&#8217;s social media efforts, a key factor is what you stand for and what&#8217;s meaningful to you. Attention Marketers: Back-to-School Season Has Already Started [INFOGRAPHIC] Research from Gen Y-focused marketing agency Mr. Youth shows that conversations about the upcoming school year are already happening. How American Express Grows Its Massive Social Media Presence The credit card company is innovating for both customers and merchants on their social media platforms. Check out how AmEx has gone digital. 6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media Facebook, Twitter and Instagram are great for building your brand &#8212; but how do you find new customers? 10 Ways to Humanize Your Brand On Social Media Humanizing a brand is just that: the attempt to interact with each customer on a personal level. Here are 10 ways companies can work to create a more human brand via social media. Shoptiques Lets You Shop Boutiques Like a Local Shop local boutiques online, city by city. For more business news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s business channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Tech &amp; Mobile 5 Exciting Innovations That Will Change Computing in 2012 Technical innovations are on the way that promise to bridge the gap between the physical and digital worlds like never before. 6 Must-Have Apps for the Samsung Galaxy Note Here are six apps that no Samsung Galaxy Note user should be without. Your Profile Pic Has Nothing on These Guys [VIDEO] Think your vacation album is sweet? Think again. These guys take scrapbooking to a whole new level. 4 Hot Apps for Microvideo Blogging With microvideo blogging apps, you can record short video clips and share them instantly over social platforms. Here are our four faves. 18 Amazing Photos of NASA&#8217;s &#8216;Five Rockets in Five Minutes&#8217; Launch NASA launched five rockets, each 80 seconds apart, into the skies over Virginia early on Tuesday. Will This Adorable Robot Rabbit Be Your Next Digital Media Hub? The Karotz is a little rabbit robot with a big personality. Check out how its creators hope to revolutionize the personalized robotics industry. 10 Ice-Cool White iPhone Cases We&#8217;ve found 10 cases that work brilliantly with the white iPhone. 10 Fun Notepads to Geek Up Your Desk From &#8220;social&#8221; sticky notes to LEGO notebooks to Google Doodle notecards, we think you&#8217;ll find something tempting in our selection. How to Avoid the Common Pitfalls of Mobile App Development We asked several leaders in mobile development to share the common issues that come when creating a new app. Here&#8217;s what they had to say. The Future of Funny: How Old and New Media Collaborate on Comedy How old and new media work together in pursuit of comedy. A History of Hacktivism [INFOGRAPHIC] Learn how hacktivism evolved to become a powerful virtual weapon in today&#8217;s digital age. 10 Classic Gadgets Upcycled Into Fashion Accessories We&#8217;ve collected 10 fashion accessories upcycled from the gadgets of your youth. These 10 Hilarious Podcasts Will Make You LOL If you&#8217;re looking for some of the funniest podcasts, we&#8217;ve rounded up 10 channels. Plug in your headphones and get ready to LOL in public. 5 Cities Benefiting From Mobile Apps Check out how a handful of cities across the U.S. takes advantage of mobile to improve their communities and government efficiency. 3 Reasons Facebook Brand Pages Are Good for Businesses Not everyone is cheering about Facebook Timeline for businesses. The reality is, the new layout will present many great opportunities for companies using it to merchandise their products. Here are three reasons why Facebook&#8217;s new brand pages will benefit sellers and social commerce as a whole. 8 Easy PC Pranks to Trick Your Friends With April Fools&#8217; Day on the horizon, it&#8217;s the perfect time to play some epic pranks on your PC-using co-workers, friends, family and frenemies. 10 Excellent PC Games for Less Than $10 Need a gaming fix on the cheap? Check out these 10 winning PC games, all for less than $10. How to Respond to Any Situation With an Animated GIF There&#8217;s an animated GIF for every occasion! The blog #WhatShouldWeCallMe brilliantly responds to classic situations. 8 Crazy Gadgets to Buy If You Win Mega Millions What would you buy if you won Friday&#8217;s world-record $640 million Mega Millions jackpot? You can purchase plenty of things with the half-a-billion dollar prize, including these eight gems. Tools to Generate Your Random Mega Millions Numbers Can these random number generators help you win the record-high Mega Millions jackpot? Probably not, but it might be worth a try. Top 10 iPhone Word Games Go pick up a dictionary and fortify the ol&#8217; lexicon &#8212; these iPhone word games demand clever wordplay in order to succeed. For more tech news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s tech channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci. More About: Business, COMMUNICATIONS, Features Week In Review, Social Media, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/digital-media-resources-3-31/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/digital-media-resources-3-31/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps 8-bit for NES</title>
      <description>It seems Google has fired the first April Fools Day shot early by introducing their latest product: Google Maps in 8-Bit for Nintendo Entertainment System (NES). For those who want a "sneak peak" at the game before it hits stores, you can click the "Quest" box in the top right corner of Google Maps for a trial. Watch an intro video below, and check out some screen shots above. [ more &#8250; ]</description>
      <link>http://gothamist.com/2012/03/31/video_google_maps_now_available_8-b.php</link>
      <guid>http://gothamist.com/2012/03/31/video_google_maps_now_available_8-b.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 iPhone Word Games</title>
      <description>1. Words With Friends It's an obvious choice for the list, and with good reason. The app features Scrabble-esque gameplay, with online turn-based, multiplayer functionality. The reach of the game is a big part of why it's still so special: It bridges the gaps between iOS, Facebook and Android. Price: $2.99Click here to view this gallery.Time to get wordy! In these iPhone word games, wrangle words and lasso letters to challenge friends, and even yourself. So, go pick up a dictionary and fortify the ol&#8217; lexicon &#8212; these games demand clever wordplay in order to succeed. SEE ALSO: Top 10 Most Amazing iPhone Puzzle Games Which smartphone word play games are you addicted to? Let us know your favorites in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, mbbirdy More About: apps, features, Gaming, iOS, iphone, Mobile</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/iphone-word-games/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/iphone-word-games/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Google Might Be Going to $0</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: James Altucher is an investor, programmer, author, and entrepreneur. He is Managing Director of Formula Capital and has written 6 books on investing. His latest books are I Was Blind But Now I See and FAQ ME. You can follow him on Twitter @jaltucher. Ken Lang could perform miracles. In 1990 we would head off to a bar near where we were going to graduate school for computer science, and we would bring a Go board. Then we would drink and play Go for five hours. At the end of the five hours, after a grueling battle over the board, I remember this one time when magically Ken would show up with two girls who were actually willing to sit down and hang out with two guys who had a GO BOARD in front of them. How did Ken do that? Fast forward: 1991, CMU asks me to leave graduate school, citing lack of maturity. The professor who threw me out still occasionally calls me up asking me when I&#8217;m going to be mature enough. Fast forward: 1994, one of our classmates, Michael Mauldin is working on a database that automatically sorts by category pages his spider retrieves on the Internet. The name of his computer: lycos.cs.cmu.edu. Lycos eventually spins out of CMU, becomes the biggest seach engine, and goes public with a multi-billlion dollar valuation. Fast forward: Ken Lang starts a company called WiseWire. I was incredibly skeptical. I read through what the company is about. &#8220;No way,&#8221; I think to myself, &#8220;that this is going to make any money&#8221;. 1998: Ken files a patent that classified how search results and ad results are sorted based on the number of click-thrus an ad gets. He sells the company to Lycos for $40 million. Ken Lang becomes CTO of Lycos and they take over his patents. $40 million! What? And then Lycos stock skyrockets up. I can&#8217;t believe it. I&#8217;m happy for my friend but also incredibly jealous although later in 1998 I sell my first company as well. Still, I wanted to be the only one I knew who made money. I didn&#8217;t think it was fun when other people I knew made money. And, anyway, weren&#8217;t search engines dead? I mean,what was even the business model? Fast forward: the 2000s. Almost every search engine dies. Excite, Lycos, Altavista. Before that &#8220;the world wide web worm&#8221;. Lycos got bought by a Spanish company, then a Korean company, then an Indian company. To be honest, I don&#8217;t even know who owns it now. It has a breathing tube and a feeding tube. Somehow, in a complete coma, it is being kept alive. One search engine, a little company called Google, figured out how to make money. One quick story: I was a venture capitalist in 2001. A company, Oingo, which later became Applied Semantics, had a technique for how search engines could make money by having people bid for ads. My partner at the firm said, &#8220;we can probably pick up half this company for cheap. They are running out of money.&#8221; It was during the Internet bust. &#8220;Are you kidding me, &#8220; I said. &#8220;they are in the search engine business. That&#8217;s totally dead.&#8221; And I went back to playing the Defender machine that was in my office. That I would play all day long even while companies waited in the conference room. (See: &#8220;10 Unusual Things I Didn&#8217;t Know About Google, Plus How I Made the Worst VC Decision Ever&#8220;) A year later they were bought by Google for 1% of Google. Our half would&#8217;ve now been worth hundreds of millions if we had invested. I was the worst venture capitalist ever. They had changed their name from Oingo to Applied Semantics to what became within Google&#8230;AdWords and AdSense, which has been 97% of Google&#8217;s revenues since 2001. 97%. $67 billion dollars. Don&#8217;t worry. I&#8217;m getting to it. (Yahoo won hundreds of millions from Google on the Overture patent even before Google amassed the bulk of their $67 billion in overall revenues from AdWords) Fast forward. Overture, another search engine company that no longer exists (Yahoo bought it) files a patent for a bidding system for ads on a search engine. The patent office says (I&#8217;m paraphrasing), &#8220;you can file patents on A, B, and C. But not D, E, and F. Because Ken Lang from Lycos filed those patents already.&#8221; Overture/Yahoo goes on to successfully sue Google based on the patents they did win. Google settled right before they went public but long before they achieved the bulk of their revenues. Lycos goes on to being a barely breathing, comatose patient. Fast forward to 2011. Ken Lang buys his patents back from Lycos for almost nothing. He starts a company: I/P Engine. Two weeks ago he announced he was merging his company with a public company, Vringo (Nasdaq: VRNG). Because it&#8217;s Ken, I buy the stock although will buy more after this article is out and readers read this. The company sues Google for a big percentage of those $67 billion in revenues plus future revenues. The claim: Google has willfully infringed on Vringo &#8211; I/P&#8217;s patents for sorting ads based on click-throughs. I remember almost 20 years ago when Ken was working on the software. &#8220;Useless!&#8221; I thought then. Their claim: $67 billion of Google&#8217;s revenues come from this patent. All of Google&#8217;s revenues going forward come from this patent. And every search engine which uses Google is allegedly infringing on the Vringo patent and is being sued. Think: Interactive Corp (Nasdaq: IACI) with Ask.com. Think AOL. Think Target which internally uses Google&#8217;s technologies. Think Gannett, which uses Google&#8217;s technology and is also being sued. Think, eventually, thousands of Google&#8217;s customers who use AdSense. Think: &#8220;willfully&#8221;. Why should you think that? Two reasons. Overture already sued Google. Google is aware of Yahoo/Overture&#8217;s patent history. The patent history officially stated that Ken Lang/Lycos already has patented some of this technology. What does &#8220;willfully&#8221; mean in legal terms? Triple damages. Why didn&#8217;t Lycos ever sue? After Lycos had its massive stroke and was left to die in a dirty hospital room with some uncaring nurse changing it&#8217;s bedpans twice a day, Google was STILL Lycos&#8217;s biggest customer. Why sue your biggest customer? Operating companies rarely sue other operating companies. Then there are countersuits, loss of revenues, and all sorts of ugly things. The breathing tube would&#8217;ve been pulled out of Lycos and it would&#8217;ve been left to die. Think: NTP suing RIMM on patents. NTP had nothing going on other than the patents. Like Vringo/Innovate. NTP won over $600 million from RIMM once Research in Motion realized this is a serious issue and not one they can just chalk up to a bad nightmare. (the beginning of the end for RIMM) Guess who NTP&#8217;s lawyer was? Donald Stout. Guess who Vringo&#8217;s patent lawyer is? Donald Stout. Why is Donald Stout so good? He was an examiner at the US Patent Office. He knows patents. They announced all of this but nobody reads announcements of a small public company like Vringo. It&#8217;s hard enough figuring out how many pixels are on the screen of Apple&#8217;s amazng ipad 3. Well, Google must have a defense? Even though their AdWords results are sorted by click-throughs in the way described by the patent maybe they sorted in a different way (a &#8220;work-around&#8221; of the patent), and didn&#8217;t infringe on the patent. Maybe: But look at Google economist Hal Varian describing their algorithm right here in this video. And compare with the patent claim filed in court by Vringo. You decide. But it looks like the exact same to me. Maybe: But does Google want to risk losing ten billion dollars plus having all of their customers sued. The district the case is getting tried in rules 70% in favor of the plaintiff in patent cases. Most patent trials get settled on the court steps. Maybe: But then there&#8217;s still Microsoft /Yahoo search which, by the way, sorts based on click-throughs and has not been sued yet. Guess what? Google&#8217;s patent lawyer is Quinn-Emmanuel. They are defending Google. Oh, and here&#8217;s something funny. Guess who Yahoo&#8217;s lawyer is? Yahoo is suing Facebook for patent infringement in the search domain. Quinn-Emanuel. So the same lawyer is both defending and accusing in the same domain. Someone&#8217;s going to settle. Everyone will settle. If anyone loses this case then the entire industry is going down in the same lawsuit and the exact same lawyer will be stuck on both sides of the fence. I&#8217;m not a lawyer but that smells. The trial is October 16 in the Eastern District Court of Virginia and will last 2 weeks. An appeal process can take, at most, a year. I&#8217;ve known Ken for 23 years. I&#8217;ve been in the trenches with him when he was writing what I thought was his useless software. I watched his company get bought and we&#8217;ve talked about these technologies through the decades. I&#8217;ve read the patent case. I watched Hal Varian&#8217;s video. Also look at this link on Google&#8217;s site where they describe their algorithm. Compare with the patent claim. I have a screenshot if they decide to take it down. $67 billion in revenues from this patent. Imagine: double that in the next ten years. Imagine: triple damages. Vringo will have an $80 million market capitalization post their merger with I/P. NTP won $600 million from RIMM using the same lawyer. RIMM&#8217;s revenues are a drop in the bucket compared to Google. And compared to 1000s of Google&#8217;s customers who will be embarrassed when the lawyer shows up at their door also. That&#8217;s why I made my investment accordingly. Is Google going to take the risk this happens? I doubt it. You can think to yourself: &#8220;ugh, patent trolls are disgusting&#8221;. But the protection of intellectual property is what America is built on. Smart people invent things. Then they get to protect the intellectual property on what they invents. Other companies can&#8217;t steal that technology. That&#8217;s why we have such a problem outsourcing to China and other countries where we are worried they might steal our intellectual property. Patents are the defense mechanism for capitalism. Ken can perform miracles. But no miracle would save me. At the end of one evening of Go playing and beer drinking in 1990 we gave two girls our phone numbers. I don&#8217;t know if Ken ever got the call. I didn&#8217;t. But I guess I&#8217;m happy where it all ended up.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/31/why-google-might-be-going-to-0/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/31/why-google-might-be-going-to-0/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tax Day On the Way: The 4 Ways You Can Tax Your LLC</title>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the American Express OPEN Forum, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business. The Limited Liability Company (LLC) is a hot business structure for startups right now &#8212; and for good reason. It offers all the personal liability protection without the red tape, paperwork and formalities that can be burdensome for a young startup, digital agency, small business or solo entrepreneur. But after settling on the LLC for the legal structure, many small business owners are surprised to learn there&#8217;s still one more decision to make: how to be taxed. Certainly this is a big decision, as taxes are probably what drove you to select a legal structure in the first place. Because the LLC is an entity created by state statute (and not the federal government), it offers flexibility when it comes to federal tax treatment. A single-member LLC can choose to be taxed as a sole proprietorship or a corporation (either C Corporation or S Corporation). Likewise, a multi-member LLC can choose to be taxed as a partnership or a corporation (either C Corporation or S Corporation). Flexibility is always a good thing &#8212; you just need to know which option is right for you. Read on to learn more about the four different federal tax classifications available for the LLC. 1. Single-Member LLC as a &#8216;Disregarded Entity&#8217; A single-member LLC is essentially taxed as a sole proprietor. As the name implies, you need to be the sole owner of the LLC. This classification falls into the &#8220;pass-through&#8221; taxation category&#8221; &#8212; the business itself doesn&#8217;t file any tax forms. As the owner of the LLC, you report business income or loss on your personal tax forms (Schedule C). In addition, you will need to pay self-employment taxes if you&#8217;re engaged in active trade or business, for example, if you provide a service like copywriting or sell a product. If you formed an LLC for a passive activity such as a real estate investment, then you don&#8217;t need to pay self-employment tax on the profits (rather, you&#8217;d report your passive profits on Schedule E). For example, let&#8217;s say Jonathan is a freelance UI designer who formed an LLC for his business. Through this work, he earned $75,000 in profit in 2011. He will report this income on his personal tax form and pay income taxes on the $75,000 at his individual tax rate, as well as pay self-employment taxes. 2. Multiple-Member LLC as a Partnership For federal tax purposes, if an LLC has two or more members, it will be taxed as a partnership unless it makes an election to be taxed as an S Corp or C Corp (see below). In the case of a multi-member LLC taxed as a partnership, the LLC reports its business income on a separate 1065 partnership tax return. Then, each partner pays self-employment taxes on his share of the partnership profit on the Schedule SE tax form. As with the single-member LLC, self-employment taxes only need to paid if the LLC engages in an active trade or business. 3. LLC as a C Corporation An LLC can elect to be treated as a corporation for tax purposes by filing Form 8832 with the IRS. In this case, the LLC files a corporate tax return 1120 and pays taxes on its profits at its corporate tax rate. If LLC profits are distributed to LLC owners in the form of dividends, those dividends are taxed again at the qualifying dividend rate (this is what&#8217;s known as double taxation). The LLC profits are not subject to self-employment taxes, but an LLC treated as a C Corporation is responsible for payroll taxes on any wages paid to LLC members who work for the business. If you prefer to keep profits in the company (as opposed to distributing any end-of-the-year profits to owners), a C Corporation would work. In this case, only the company is taxed on the profits; individual owners are not responsible for paying taxes on whatever money stays in the business. For example, Judy owns a consulting company that earned $100,000 in profit. As an LLC treated as a C Corporation, the business would pay $34,000 in taxes on this income (assuming a 34% tax rate). If Judy then takes home that profit as a dividend, she would also owe taxes (at the 15% qualifying dividend rate) on the dividend payment. But if she decides to keep that money in the business (perhaps to expand her marketing budget next year), then she personally does not owe any taxes on the profit. 4. LLC as an S Corporation In this last scenario, the LLC elects to be treated as an S Corporation. The S Corp files an 1120S tax return, but the company&#8217;s profits are not subject to corporate income tax like they are in the C Corporation. Instead, individual LLC owners are taxed on their respective shares of the company&#8217;s profits (and profits are not subject to self-employment tax). If an LLC owner works in the business, he must be paid a reasonable wage for his activities, and the LLC must pay payroll taxes on these wages. Let&#8217;s say three friends start a social intranet company, and each owns one-third of the business. They form an LLC and elect to be taxed as an S Corporation. In the first year, the business earns $90,000 in profit. The LLC does not pay income tax on the profit. Instead, each owner includes his or her share of the profit ($30,000) in their taxable income on their individual tax return. And if the business lost $60,000 in the first year, each owner would include a $20,000 loss in his or her individual taxable income. Do Your Homework Choosing the right tax entity for your LLC is a complicated issue and will ultimately depend on all the unique aspects of your particular business needs, vision and circumstances. Investigate your options and stay on top of changing tax developments on both the federal and state levels that could affect your taxes. And since the decision can have significant financial implications, you won&#8217;t go wrong by discussing your particular situation with a tax adviser or CPA. More Small Business Resources From OPEN Forum: - Should Small Businesses Follow Everyone Back on Twitter? - Are You Falling into the Pricing Trap? - How to Innovate for Top Social Media Sites Image courtesy of Image courtesy of iStockphoto, catenarymedia , Flickr, thinkpanama More About: features, LLC, mashable, open forum, taxesFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/tax-llc/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/tax-llc/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Limits TweetDeck Access After Security Fears</title>
      <description>Twitter has shut down access to TweetDeck after a bug appeared to give users access to accounts that are not their own. The TweetDeck web app is currently offline. If you&#8217;re currently logged in to the latest software version, Mashable tests show, you will not be able to get back in after logging out. A Twitter user named Geoff Evason discovered the bug on Friday, and tweeted a message to TweetDeck and Twitter suggesting they look into the issue. Hey @Tweetdeck A bug in your software has given me access to hundreds of accounts. #YouShouldLookIntoThat /cc @Twitter twitter.com/gevason/status&#8230; &#8212; Geoff Evason (@gevason) March 30, 2012 According to Evason the bug gave him access to &#8220;hundreds&#8221; of Twitter and Facebook accounts by simply logging into the service using his own account. In order to prove he wasn&#8217;t lying he also sent out a test message from one of those accounts. test &#8212; Tackleberry Showroom (@gotackleberry) March 30, 2012 TweetDeck has confirmed that the service is down via a Twitter post &#8212; however, the company has not indicated when the service will be back up and running or the reason behind the outage. TweetDeck is currently down while we look into an issue. Apologies for the inconvenience. &#8212; TweetDeck (@TweetDeck) March 30, 2012 We reached out to Twitter for more information on the outage, and a representative indicated the company had nothing more to say at this time other than the tweet acknowledging the outage itself. Twitter recently updated TweetDeck to add better list management, inline media support and improved retweeting support. More About: tweetdeck, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/tweetdeck-outage/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/tweetdeck-outage/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction Begins On World&#8217;s Largest Telescope [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>A new Big Bang occurred last Friday &#8212; albeit not the same magnitude as the original. That&#8217;s what project crews in the Chilean Andes are calling last Friday&#8217;s detonation of Las Campanas Peak to make way for the construction of the Giant Magellan Telescope. Building has commenced on the massive telescope, which will be the largest telescope in the world when finished in 2019. It will feature seven giant mirrors, more than 28 feet in diameter, and be enclosed in a 200-foot tall structure. Adaptive optics will allow the telescope to capture photos of far-away planets orbiting their stars with less glare than other telescopes, and give astronomers the chance to peer into deep space. &#8220;The telescope will be used by scientists at our partner institutions,&#8221; Patrick McCarthy, director at GMTO (Giant Magellan Telescope Organization) tells Mashable. &#8220;Some of the nights will go to small projects led by one person, others will go to &#8216;key&#8217; projects that address big questions line exoplanet atmospheres, dark energy, dark matter and so on.&#8221; The GMT will have a larger field of view and collecting area than any other telescopes currently under construction, he added. &#8220;Contrary to popular lore, telescopes do not benefit astronomers by magnifying distant objects,&#8221; notes a GMTO report. &#8220;Rather they allow us to both collect far more light than is possible with the unaided eye and to resolve finer details. &#8220;The light-gathering power of a telescope is determined by its collecting area and grows as the square of the telescope diameter, while the angular resolving power is determined by the number of wavelengths of light that span the aperture and is thus proportional to the diameter.&#8221; Currently, there are 32 people in the core project team, but there are approximately another 50 other people working on the project at GMTO&#8217;s partner institutions. The telescope project began in 2004-2005, McCarthy said, with work beginning in 2006. The group started the GMTO nonprofit corporation in 2010. The Chilean Andes is a very dry mountain range, making the skies clear for year-round star watching. &#8220;For the first time we have definitive evidence that the Milky Way galaxy is teaming with planetary systems, some like our own solar system, others quite exotic by comparison,&#8221; the GMTO report says. &#8220;We have also learned that the matter that makes up the Earth, stars and other planets is a mere 4% of the total stuff of the Universe &#8211; the rest (96%!) is comprised of dark matter and an unknown &#8220;dark&#8221; energy. &#8220;Telescopes offer a unique way to explore not only the universe as it is today, but to see back to the dawn of time and the formation of the first stars, galaxies and black holes.&#8221; Image courtesy of GMTO More About: chile, Giant Magellan Telescope, Telescope</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/worlds-largest-telescope/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/worlds-largest-telescope/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
