<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>When it comes to buying local, you can't get much closer than in your "Under Pants." http://t.co/mvDAzrxY</title>
      <description>Doug French: When it comes to buying local, you can't get much closer than in your "Under Pants." http://t.co/mvDAzrxY &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kh7baLix8m/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kh7baLix8m/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage neon tote..have to have it #brimfield http://t.co/s0EQ8WDh</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Vintage neon tote..have to have it #brimfield http://t.co/s0EQ8WDh &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kh-EZZFgMS/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kh-EZZFgMS/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU</title>
      <description>Tom Murphy: Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reddit Users Surprise Terminally-Ill Man With Random Acts of Kindness</title>
      <description>Scott Widak and his family recently received the greatest gift anyone in their situation could receive &#8212; a viral act of encouragement and kindness from complete strangers. Widak, 47, has Down syndrome and is terminally ill with liver disease. After frequently checking in and out of the hospital, Widak is now at home with his 85-year-old mother, who&#8217;s helping with his in-home hospice care. To cope with such a challenging situation, Widak&#8217;s nephew, Sean O&#8217;Connor, turned to the Reddit community to see if anyone would be interested in sending a letter to his uncle. &#8220;One of my uncle&#8217;s favorite things to do is open mail, and I thought that if he got a lot of mail it would cheer him up,&#8221; says O&#8217;Connor. Within three hours, the post received more than 1,300 comments, most of which expressed interest in sending mail. O&#8217;Connor then included a link to a news article about Widak and his art, along with two photos of him and his mother, a P.O. box address and a few things he&#8217;s interested in, like Johnny Cash. Due to the amount of personal information, Reddit removed the post four hours later &#8212; which was apparently enough time for most of the commenters to copy the address. Following the post, Widak received hundreds of letters from all over the world, including the United States, Sweden, Finland, Australia, Japan, the United Kingdom and Mexico. According to O&#8217;Connor, there is still mail coming in. In addition to beautifully written letters, Reddit users have sent custom artwork, art supplies, DVDs and personal keepsakes that they wanted to pass on to Widak. Sony Music Entertainment sent him 15 CDs/DVDs, which were mostly by Johnny Cash. &#8220;The mail that&#8217;s arrived has all been extremely positive and thoughtful,&#8221; says O&#8217;Connor. &#8220;My family and I are amazed at how so many strangers could come together for a random act of kindness.&#8221; O&#8217;Connor and his family have shared these images of Widak and the overwhelming amount of mail he&#8217;s received. Take a look and share your thoughts in the comments. Here is just a portion of the letters and packages that Widak has received.Click here to view this gallery. More About: features, Mail, reddit, Social GoodFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/13/reddit-terminally-ill-man/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/13/reddit-terminally-ill-man/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX</title>
      <description>Scary Mommy: I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple readies revamped 15-inch MacBook Pro: Retina Display, ultra-thin design, and super-fast USB 3</title>
      <description>Mockup: New, thinner MacBook Pro on the left. Current model on the right. Apple is putting the finishing touches on an entirely new 15-inch MacBook Pro that is the outcome of years of research and development in ultra-thin mobile computing and super-high-resolution displays. According to trusted sources in Apple&#8217;s supply chain, who have handled prototype components and casings for the new Apple notebook, the computer is currently undergoing test production rounds. The new 15-inch MacBook Pro is coming this summer, and it features an ultra-thin design, a &#8220;jaw-dropping&#8221; Retina Display, and super-fast USB 3. Read on for all of the details! // &lt;![CDATA[ google_ad_client = "ca-pub-9306639021843032"; /* 9to5Mac: Under */ google_ad_slot = "4878594813"; google_ad_width = 300; google_ad_height = 250; // ]]&amp;gt; The revamped design: While many have speculated that the new 15-inch MacBook Pro will pickup the design from the late-2010/mid-2011 MacBook Air, sources familiar with the prototype units say that this is untrue. Instead, the new 15-inch MacBook Pro is described as being an ultra-thin version of the current MacBook Pro. Basically, the prototype design is a flattened, yet more robust, version of the late-2008 design. It has no tapering like the MacBook Airs. This new design serves as an apparent solution to Apple&#8217;s hinge troubles with the cancelled ultra-thin 15-inch notebook for late 2010. As the MacBook Air pioneered, and the latest Mac mini models have followed, the new 15-inch MacBook Pro loses the optical drive in order to reach Apple&#8217;s new standard for notebook thinness. Apple has made it clear that professionals could lose the optical drive in favor of the wildly popular Mac App Store for software installations. Take Final Cut Pro X or Aperture for example. For those few who still need an optical drive, Apple has been selling a USB Superdrive since the first-generation MacBook Air launched. Mockup showing the power button on the keyboard While the new MacBook Pro does not take all of the external design cues from the current MacBook Air, it does adopt the tweaked MacBook Air keyboard design with the power button on the keyboard itself (which replaces the disc eject key). This is according to the sources who are familiar with the components being installed into the new casings. Current MacBook Pros have a round aluminum power button to the top right above the keyboard. The rest of the design is basically what we are all familiar with: charging and connection ports along the sides, and a spacious glass Multi-Touch trackpad (either same or similar in size to the current MacBook Pro and MacBook Air trackpads based on the cutout present in the prototype unibodies). Mockup of the sides The current prototype unibody casings going through test production have spaces for a charging port, two USB ports, two audio in/out-sized ports, and the battery meter on the left side. The right side is said to have cutouts for two Thunderbolt-sized ports, an SD card slot, and another USB port. Notably, these prototype unibodies lack room for Ethernet (Apple sells adapters since the MacBook Air lacks an Ethernet port). We&#8217;re unsure about Firewire but that could also be gone. Introducing the Mac Retina Display: Mockup of the MacBook Pro Retina Display Apple will also introduce the Mac Retina Display in this new MacBook Pro, according to these sources in the far-east. The display is quoted as &#8220;jaw-dropping&#8221; and &#8220;definitely the most important Mac innovation in years,&#8221; by sources familiar with the quality of the screens in test-production. When the Retina Display on the 3.5 inch screen of the iPhone 4 launched in mid-2010, people were shocked at how gorgeous a screen could be. When the third-generation iPad launched earlier this year with its 9.7 inch 2048 x 1536 Retina Display, people were again amazed by how brilliant colors could appear and how sharp text could seem. With that in mind, imagine the sharpness of text and the beauty of images on a 15-inch professional Retina Display-packing notebook. Sources familiar with software strings left behind in OS X Lion 10.7.4 and Mountain Lion betas say that this Retina Display MacBook Pro features multiple Retina resolution modes, so users are able to adjust the sharpness and image sizes to their liking. Unlike Mac display settings of today, these Retina Display settings will not be marked with numbers/resolution sizes, but with descriptions such as big, small, or optimal, according to these software-based findings. The long-awaited &#8220;resolution independence&#8221; is upon us. USB 3 finally making its way to the Mac: USB 2.0 (left) vs. USB 3.0 (right) cables (image via PhotoCitizen) Also a new addition to the MacBook Pro (and actually to the Mac itself) is a USB 3 port. Apple has long been testing Macs with USB 3 ports, but it sounds like the new MacBook Pro will be the first to actually sport the next-generation connector. Our sources in Apple&#8217;s supply chain say the aforementioned USB ports on the left and right sides of the prototype unibody casings have slightly different component cables that attach the ports to the computing components housed inside of the internal structure. While some speculated that Thunderbolt was Apple&#8217;s choice instead of USB 3 (perhaps due to better support from Intel), USB 3 will actually run on these MacBook Pros as a complement to Thunderbolt, as mentioned earlier in this report. While third-party USB 3 cards and Hackintoshes have run &#8220;Super-Speed&#8221; USB 3 and have shown up in the System Profiler previously, sources familiar with Apple&#8217;s software strings in 10.7.4 and 10.8 betas also have provided evidence for USB 3 Macs coming soon. One source identified two new strings pointing to USB 3 Macs (both shown below): one mentions 5Gbps USB transfers (which is the speed of USB 3), and there are actually two explicit mentions of &#8220;USB 3.0.&#8221; These references didn&#8217;t exist before. Video of USB 2.0 vs. USB 3.0 speed test Intel&#8217;s new Ivy Bridge processors come with USB 3 support out of the box, a major upgrade over the aging USB 2.0 technology. USB 3.0 measures in at an average of 5Gbps (gigabytes per second) transfer speeds, which is more than ten times faster than USB 2.0&#8242;s 480Mbps transfer speeds. Users won&#8217;t often find 10X faster than USB 2.0 speeds, but will often find the speed improvements notable. The New York Times published some real-world USB 2 vs USB 3 tests that provide some good insight into average transfer speeds: Next, I created a 10-gigabyte folder comprising Word, PowerPoint, and Excel documents, as well as larger video and JPEG photo files. Using the 3.0 drive, the 10-gigabyte folder transferred to the U.S.B. 3.0 drive in 6 minutes, 31 seconds (write speed). The U.S.B. 2.0 drive took 22 minutes, 14 seconds to copy the same 10-gig folder. In other words, the U.S.B. 3.0 drive copied the data roughly 3.5 times faster than the U.S.B. 2.0 drive. That&#8217;s far short of the touted 10X performance gains, but it&#8217;s an improvement that you&#8217;ll definitely notice. While much faster than USB 2.0, USB 3.0 still trails Thunderbolt&#8217;s maximum of twenty-times better performance than USB 2.0. USB 3.0 is also backwards-compatible to USB 2.0 attachments and products, so users should not fear the change whatsoever. Graphics card information is currently unconfirmed at this point because Apple is prototyping a few different graphics chipsets with the new MacBook Pro bodies, according to sources. However, we&#8217;ve seen direct references to the fairly new NVIDIA GeForce GT 650M graphics card in OS X beta code. kHW_NVidiaGeForceGT650MItem = &#8220;NVIDIA GeForce GT 650M According to NVIDIA, this chip offers incredible dedicated graphics performance for gaming and other tasks, all while apparently being battery-life efficient. A card perfect for a high-end professional notebook. We&#8217;ve also identified references to Ivy Bridge processors in the aforementioned OS X beta code. Ivy Bridge and the aforementioned GeForce 650 graphics chip are coupled together in recent PC hardware releases, so seeing the two chips together in the new MacBook Pro is sensible. The new Intel Ivy Bridge series includes a slew of quad-core i7 processors, including ones with improved power efficiency, so we&#8217;re probably looking at these new MacBook Pros coming mainly in quad-core configurations. This makes sense given that all current-generation 15-inch MacBook Pros run on quad-core chips. Completely separate from our aforementioned information, a new GeekBench reference to a MacBookPro9,1 has appeared. GeekBench is a popular service that measures performance of computers, smartphones, and tablets. This benchmark page says the MacBookPro9,1 has a 2.7GHz Ivy Bridge quad-core processor and 8GB of RAM. The machine is also said to be running a build of the upcoming OS X Mountain Lion. GeekBench scores are easily able to be faked, so we wouldn&#8217;t put too much trust into the benchmarks. However, GeekBench has caught legitimate unreleased Macs in the past. Tim Cook&#8217;s closing statement at Apple&#8217;s early-March Retina Display iPad keynote Precise release information such as launch dates (other than summer) and pricing were not available from these supply chain sources. With WWDC nearing, though, and Apple promising very exciting products for 2012, we hope to see these notebooks in June. In any case, with an ultra-thin design, Retina Display, and new USB 3 port, the new 15-inch MacBook Pro is going to be one of the most exciting mobile computer launches of the year.</description>
      <link>http://9to5mac.com/2012/05/14/apple-readies-revamped-15-inch-macbook-pro-retina-display-ultra-thin-design-and-super-fast-usb-3-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9To5Mac-MacAllDay+%289+to+5+Mac+-+Apple+Intelligence%29</link>
      <guid>http://9to5mac.com/2012/05/14/apple-readies-revamped-15-inch-macbook-pro-retina-display-ultra-thin-design-and-super-fast-usb-3-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+9To5Mac-MacAllDay+%289+to+5+Mac+-+Apple+Intelligence%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This 121-Megapixel Photo of Earth Will Make Your Jaw Drop</title>
      <description>Need something to put things into perspective on a Monday morning? Our suggestion: The largest single-shot photo of Earth ever taken. Eclipsing NASA&#8217;s updated &#8220;Blue Marble&#8221; shot, which is a composite of many satellite images, this image is a single-shot taken from 22,369 miles away by Russian weather satellite Elektro-L No.1. The colors on the 121-megapixel photo are quite different from the ones on NASA&#8217;s photos of Earth. To capture the image, the satellite combines visible and infrared wavelengths of light. Infrared light is used to see plants, which is why the parts of the Earth that would normally be green are seen as rusty brown. Check out a time-lapse video of Earth&#8217;s northern hemisphere taken by Elektro-L below. You can explore the zoomable version of the image here. [via Planet Earth] More About: astronomy, Earth, high resolution, photography, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/14/121-megapixel-photo-of-earth/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/14/121-megapixel-photo-of-earth/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This 121-Megapixel Photo of Earth Will Make Your Jaw Drop</title>
      <description>Need something to put things into perspective on a Monday morning? Our suggestion: The largest single-shot photo of Earth ever taken. Eclipsing NASA&#8217;s updated &#8220;Blue Marble&#8221; shot, which is a composite of many satellite images, this image is a single-shot taken from 22,369 miles away by Russian weather satellite Elektro-L No.1. The colors on the 121-megapixel photo are quite different from the ones on NASA&#8217;s photos of Earth. To capture the image, the satellite combines visible and infrared wavelengths of light. Infrared light is used to see plants, which is why the parts of the Earth that would normally be green are seen as rusty brown. Check out a time-lapse video of Earth&#8217;s northern hemisphere taken by Elektro-L below. You can explore the zoomable version of the image here. [via Planet Earth] More About: astronomy, Earth, high resolution, photography, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/14/121-megapixel-photo-of-earth/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/14/121-megapixel-photo-of-earth/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After a week away, came home to a sick little lady. Poor baby just said "miss you momma." :( http://t.co/7jLvPIdn</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: After a week away, came home to a sick little lady. Poor baby just said "miss you momma." :( http://t.co/7jLvPIdn &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KlirI4lgAh/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KlirI4lgAh/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Still a great movie. http://t.co/7HQImvFI @GetGlue #TradingPlaces</title>
      <description>erhys: Still a great movie. http://t.co/7HQImvFI @GetGlue #TradingPlaces &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://m.getglue.com/movies/trading_places/john_landis?ref=erhys&amp;s=tch</link>
      <guid>http://m.getglue.com/movies/trading_places/john_landis?ref=erhys&amp;s=tch</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Americans Now Spend More Time On Facebook Mobile Than Its Website</title>
      <description>All those minutes reading your news feed in bed, messaging friends over lunch, and browsing photos on the bus really add up. Time spent on Facebook&#8217;s mobile site and apps per month (441 minutes) has finally surpassed usage of its classic website (391 minutes) &#8212; for Americans who use both Facebook interfaces according to the latest report from comScore. And that&#8217;s actually a big problem for the social network. Facebook usually shows four to seven ads per page on its website, but only a few ads per day in its mobile news feed. That means it makes a lot less money when you visit from your little devices. In fact, this week Facebook had to warn potential investors in its IPO that the more people who access it from mobile instead of the web, the worse its business is doing. Can Facebook get away with showing more ads on mobile without turning us off? Way back when Facebook launched in 2004 it was just a website, and it hardly showed ads at all. Over the years it launched a special mobile website called m.facebook.com, and apps for iPhone, Android, BlackBerry, and just about any device you can think of. At first these smaller interfaces were just a way to glimpse Facebook while away from home. But as our phones grew more powerful and Facebook&#8217;s apps got better, we could help but friend, chat, and Like no matter where we were. Now there&#8217;s 78 million Americans age eighteen and older who use Facebook mobile, and they spend 7.3 hours per month there on average, compared to the total 160 million Americans who use Facebook and spend an average of 6.5 hours on its website per month. That&#8217;s a big shift from when the web was king. Facebook realized it had to start making money on mobile, but people hate traditional mobile ads. CEO Mark Zuckerberg didn&#8217;t want annoying banners that took up most of your Facebook screen. so Facebook&#8217;s solution was mobile Sponsored Stories &#8211;stories in your news feed that could appear there anyway, but that companies pay to have appear more prominently and frequently. First showing up in March, these ads are marked &#8220;Sponsored, and could be about a friend Liking a company&#8217;s Page, a game your friend started playing, or a post by a Page you already Like. Seeing them occasionally isn&#8217;t bad, but if Facebook shows too many it could make people angry and less likely to visit. Now Facebook must walk the tightrope. Inject too many ads in the mobile news feed and people will stop visiting, inject too few and it will lose money. No pressure, there&#8217;s just a half a billion mobile users watching.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/11/time-spent-on-facebook-mobile/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/11/time-spent-on-facebook-mobile/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
