<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>10 Uses of Google Earth That Have Made Positive Impacts on the World</title>
      <description>When Google acquired Keyhole &#8212; the tool that would become Google Earth &#8212; in 2004, the company believed it would become the ultimate video game. Google thought travelers could peruse potential vacation destinations and movie makers could use the detailed satellite imagery as a backdrop in films. But Google had no idea the virtual globe and geographic data program had the potential to become a tool for grassroots mobilization, environmental protection and disaster response. Today, through the Google Earth Outreach program, the tool has become a vital instrument for non-profits and public benefit organizations to visually tell their stories. For example, The World Wildlife Fund is using Google Earth to protect Sumatran tiger cubs, and relief workers used the tool for crisis response after Japan&#8217;s 2011 earthquake. Meanwhile, The HALO Trust uses the tool to locate and remove landmines, and Brazil&#8217;s Surui tribe uses Google Earth to map its home in the Amazon Rainforest. The Google Earth Outreach team has created a tool kit of tutorials for organizations looking to create their own storytelling maps. You can add points, lines and polygons and embed YouTube videos to your annotated map. Google Earth Outreach awards non-profits with Developer Grants to help them use mapping technologies to best tell their stories. Previous grant recipients include Water For People, which developed a mapping app to support sanitation-related businesses in African cities, and International Rivers, which created a video showing why dams aren&#8217;t the best response to climate change. Take a look at 10 success stories from Google Earth Outreach. Appalachian Voices Maps Mountaintop Removal Appalachian Voices, a small North Carolina non-profit, used Google Earth to illustrate the scale of mountaintop destruction for coal mining.Click here to view this gallery. How It All Got Started A few weeks before Google Earth Outreach Engineering Manager Rebecca Moore got her start at Google in 2005, she received an &#8220;inscrutable&#8221; notice about tree logging in her community in the Santa Cruz Mountains, with a confusing black-and-white map of the work to be done. Moore took to Keyhole, the tool that would become Google Earth, to begin plotting out the work described in the notice in a more digestible, digital manner. &#8220;It was really striking how much more you could understand and I presented it to the community,&#8221; Moore told Mashable, describing the origins of a group she belongs to Neighbors Against Irresponsible Logging (NAIL). &#8220;As I remapped elements of that logging notice, that&#8217;s where I said there&#8217;s really something here.&#8221; Moore&#8217;s Google Earth map convinced her community to come up with a better alternative than what had initially been proposed. On Moore&#8217;s second day at Google, Hurricane Katrina hit New Orleans. The U.S. government asked Google to publish data, such as Craiglist postings of family whereabouts, on Google Earth, which would be the fastest way to reach the emergency medical responders. Google founder Eric Schmidt spoke with the engineers, Moore recalls, and said, &#8220;Whatever you&#8217;re working on right now isn&#8217;t important compared to saving lives in New Orleans.&#8221; Through Google&#8217;s mapping, the first responders could see where people were stuck and could then decide if boats or helicopters were the best rescue tools in specific cases. The Coast Guard later told the Google team that its technical support helped save 4,000 lives. &#8220;Non profits all over the world started writing to me and we had a feeling it could be used for all sorts of environmental projects,&#8221; Moore says. When Google Earth officially launched in June 2007, Keyhole founder John Hanke saw the non-profit implementations of Google Earth and said the product&#8217;s girth was much more significant than he had realized. Have you ever created a Google Earth map? What stories in your community do you think could be best told through mapping? More About: Google, google earth, non-profits, Social GoodFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/google-earth-positive-impact/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/google-earth-positive-impact/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Lose Your Dream Job During the Interview Process</title>
      <description>Mona Abdel-Halim is the co-founder of Resunate, the makers of the Apply widget for startups. You can start attracting top talent free by getting an Apply widget for your company at Resunate.com/employers. Connect with Resunate on Facebook and Twitter. If you&#8217;ve been on the job search for a while, it&#8217;s likely you have a good idea of things you should be doing to land a new job, such as optimizing your resume or building your personal brand online. Of course, you can&#8217;t get the job if you don&#8217;t make a great impression on your interviewer or potential employer. But there are also plenty of ways you can ruin your chances of getting a new job. It may seem obvious, but you&#8217;d be surprised how many people kill their chances before they&#8217;ve even left their interview. If you&#8217;re hoping to land your dream job, here&#8217;s what not to do during the job hunt. 1. Blow Off the Phone Interview If your resume makes it past an employer&#8217;s applicant tracking system and impresses the hiring manager, it&#8217;s likely you&#8217;ll be invited for a phone interview. This is how employers whittle down their list of applicants to decide who they want to bring in for an in-person interview &#8212; so you need to be prepared and take the opportunity seriously. Here&#8217;s a great example of what not to do (courtesy of an anonymous employer via MyCrappyResume): &#8220;[I] had a couple of phone screens with clearly drunken candidates. Also had a candidate sweating profusely through interviews and going to the bathroom every 5 minutes. (Word to the wise &#8212; if you&#8217;re THAT sick, reschedule!) Needless to say, none of them were hired!&#8221; It&#8217;s also vital that you&#8217;re properly prepared for the interview. Sit in a quiet room without distractions, do your research beforehand and ensure you&#8217;re actually able to speak on the phone for the allotted time. One job candidate learned this the hard way: &#8220;I was asked to participate in a second phone interview while I was on vacation, and because I was very interested in the job, I obliged. Before I started to answer the first question, my phone completely died. I had no way of retrieving the phone number. Needless to say, I did not get the job.&#8221; 2. Talk About Other Job Opportunities It may sound like common sense, but some job seekers feel the need to be overly honest when interacting with potential employers. There&#8217;s always the chance that one opportunity might fall through, so don&#8217;t jeopardize one position because you think you might get another. Obviously, employers don&#8217;t like being rebuffed, particularly when they&#8217;ve spent a lot of time reviewing your material and preparing for the interview. Here are two real stories that are almost hard to believe: &#8220;Someone once started an interview with me by saying &#8216;Okay. So, just to set this straight, I did interview for another job that I&#8217;m probably going to take if I receive an offer.&#8217;&#8221; &#8220;During the interview, an alarm clock went off from a candidate&#8217;s briefcase. He took it out, shut it off, apologized and said he had to leave for another interview.&#8221; 3. Provide TMI Unfortunately, there are a lot of jobseekers who have had a tough time landing a new job. Whether you&#8217;re a new graduate, an older job seeker or one of the long-term unemployed, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve had your fair share of challenges on the hunt for a new position. Sharing these sob stories with employers, however, is not going to get you the job. One employer tells of an awkward interview situation that illustrates the point: &#8220;I once interviewed a woman and asked her standard interview questions, such as &#8216;What do you need from a boss?&#8217; To this question, she replied: &#8216;I need my boss to be my best friend. I&#8217;m so lonely. We just moved here a few months ago, and I haven&#8217;t made any friends. I need a friend.&#8217;&#8221; 4. Talk Negatively About Former Supervisors or Positions It&#8217;s easy to blame your former supervisor for issues you faced in the workplace. Sure, venting to a friend or family member can make you feel less angry, but do not bring it into a new job. Applicants who speak negatively about former positions, management or colleagues are not perceived positively by employers &#8212; it can often raise a red flag in their eyes if you&#8217;re so quick to dish the dirt. In one instance, a candidate spoke badly of customers to his interviewer and ruined his chances of landing the job: &#8220;I was interviewing a young man for a customer service position. He had worked at a hair salon, and in describing his experience there, he said, &#8216;I had to deal with a lot of old biddies.&#8217; Needless to say, that&#8217;s where his candidacy ended.&#8221; 5. Act Cocky Confidence is key on the job search, but cockiness is less than appealing. You certainly don&#8217;t want to sound like this jobseeker: &#8220;One time a candidate said he was so well-qualified that if he didn&#8217;t get the job, it would prove that the company&#8217;s management was incompetent.&#8221; What&#8217;s your biggest interview &#8220;don&#8217;t&#8221;? Let us know in the comments. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Web Designer at Popdust in New York Social Operations Manager at Vivaki Nerve Center in Chicago Manager, Public Relations at New Relic in San Francisco Image courtesy of iStockphoto, PinkTag, gulfix More About: features, job interviews, job search series, mashableFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/job-search-mistakes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/job-search-mistakes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Digital Customer Service Guide</title>
      <description>In our recent Customer Experience Series, Mashable dove deep into the mysterious alchemy of customer service. Those who own their own business will tell you: Getting (and keeping) customers is not easy. There are so many different factors that must work together perfectly within a company to ensure that fans of your brand stay happy. Whether its making sure that your ecommerce platform doesn&#8217;t drive your users crazy or organizing your social media to build your community, forethought is key to a premium customer experience. These articles will give you comprehensive knowledge of many facets of digital customer service, with expert advice from community managers, CEOs and web designers. Here&#8217;s a roundup of all of our articles, brought together into this handy guide. To read more, click through to the full article, and you can access the entire series here. 1. 7 Ways to Lower Your Website&#8217;s Bounce Rate Businesses need to make sure their first impressions reel in the visitor to keep the person on your website and engaged with your brand. To help you combat pesky bounce rates, we&#8217;ve put together a list of usability considerations that can be used to lower your site&#8217;s bounce rate and improve visitor retention. From optimized page layouts to faster loading, there are a number of ways to keep web surfers hooked. Read the full story here. 2. 10 Essential Features of Every Good Business Website So your business has a website &#8212; or you&#8217;re in need of one for your brand new venture. Web design can be an overwhelming process, so we&#8217;ve spoken to a few web designers who told us what you need to have on your site &#8230; and what you can probably do without (like crazy Flash animation). We&#8217;ve gathered 10 website must-haves that will ensure your customers have a positive experience on the site, improve your company&#8217;s digital footprint and increase engagement with your brand. Read the full story here. 3. 8 Killer Web Form Builders for Your Site So you have your website set up with all the necessary features, but what about customer feedback? You have to be prepared to field the questions and concerns of your users, and nothing really does that better than a form. However, not all form builders are created equal. While they all seem to have some basic parts, there are special details and customizable options that make each builder unique. Here are eight great form-building options to choose from &#8212; find the one that fits you and your company&#8217;s needs. Read the full story here. 4. What You Need to Know About Building a Mobile App for Your Brand In case you haven&#8217;t noticed, most of your potential customers have gone mobile. Last June, consumers began spending more time on mobile apps than on the web, according to researcher Flurry. While creating a mobile website seems like an easy, cheap way to maintain visibility in this environment, another option is to create your own app. A few years ago, that wouldn&#8217;t have made any sense. But now prices have come down, the audience has grown and there&#8217;s a good chance that if you don&#8217;t have a mobile app, your competition will offer one. Read the full story here. 5. 10 Ways to Optimize Your Ecommerce Site for Google Search Ecommerce websites have several inherent qualities &#8212; shallow copy, duplicate content and a large product catalog &#8212; that make it challenging to achieve a high Google ranking. But there are some best practices you can employ, in addition to traditional SEO techniques, to help your ecommerce site gain traction on Google. Read the full story here. 6. 4 Ways To Make Your Ecommerce Site More Visually Appealing These days, every thriving retail business needs an ecommerce platform. While consumers flock to major online outlets like Amazon and eBay to get their share of products, smaller stores can benefit from the draw an online storefront can give them. Ecommerce is definitely the future of sales, but there&#8217;s one thing that could send your ecommerce storefront to an early demise: an ugly layout. It&#8217;s plain and simple &#8212; no one wants to shop at an unattractive, dated or unintuitive online storefront. Just as a front window display encourages customers to come into your store and take a peek at your wares, the way that your ecommerce landing and merchandise pages look either will entice users to click the check-out button or drive them to other websites. Read the full story here. 7. 12 Top Community Managers Share Their Tips for Better Engagement Engagement is one of the most talked about metrics for ROI. Some argue that the raw number of Likes, comments and retweets don&#8217;t mean anything. Instead, they point to a fans&#8217; level of investment, loyalty and engagement to determine whether social media is &#8220;paying off.&#8221; Mashable gathered tips from a dozen top community managers to help you boost activity on your social platforms. Read the full story here. 8. 14 Community-Driven Tips for Better Customer Relationships Like any other relationship, the foundation you establish with your client or customer is crucial to how the business relationship will develop over time. It requires taking the time at the start, going the extra mile and paying attention to detail. Customers are more likely to give you their loyalty when they experience consistency and transparency from the initial pitch. They appreciate you being genuine and upfront about your policies &#8212; no one likes a half-hearted response or to feel like they&#8217;ve been tricked. The following are some tips and tricks on how to build relationships with your customers from leaders in communications, PR and social media. Read the full story here. 9. 6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media We all know social media is an important tool for brand awareness and customer acquisition &#8212; but how exactly are you supposed to convert random Twitter and Facebook users into real-life customers? Well, that depends. Whether you&#8217;re a clothing shop, a restaurant or a subscription service, you must tailor your strategy so that it makes sense for your brand. That said, there are a few universal ways to help your company attract new faces on the social web. Read the full story here. 10. 2 Ways to Fix Customer Loyalty Programs Consumers aren&#8217;t as loyal to loyalty programs as they used to be. Why the dissatisfaction? Let&#8217;s call it the Groupon factor. Since 2008, there have been a flood of daily deal merchants, like Groupon and LivingSocial, that have filled customers inboxes with irrelevant offers. (Groupon itself has recently employed a Pandora-like &#8220;thumbs up, thumbs down&#8221; rating system to tackle this problem, which is best illustrated by the example of middle-aged men getting offers for bikini waxes.) Read the full story here. 11. 7 Mistakes to Avoid on Your Ecommerce Site We&#8217;ve all been there. You&#8217;re all set to buy something, credit card in hand, but for one reason or another you never close the deal. Maybe the third time you were asked to enter your credit card number you gave in. Perhaps it was the exorbitant shipping costs. Maybe the site crashed. If you actually want people to stick around and buy stuff from your site, you may want to take note of and avoid these common pitfalls. Read the full story here. Do you have a great customer service story? Tell us in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, ewg3D More About: Customer Experience Series, features, mashable, roundupFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/customer-service-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/customer-service-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I unlocked the Game of Thrones: What Is Dead May Never Die sticker on @GetGlue! http://t.co/eb6xEVcr [del.icio.us]</title>
      <description>I unlocked the Game of Thrones: What Is Dead May Never Die sticker on @GetGlue! http://t.co/eb6xEVcr</description>
      <link>http://m.getglue.com/asktinu/stickers/hbo/game_of_thrones_what_is_dead_may_never_die?ref=asktinu&amp;s=ts</link>
      <guid>http://m.getglue.com/asktinu/stickers/hbo/game_of_thrones_what_is_dead_may_never_die?ref=asktinu&amp;s=ts</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default Email Signature for New Samsung Phone</title>
      <description>This is a joke, right? Right? &#9733;</description>
      <link>https://twitter.com/thinkofthought/status/192967196413149185/photo/1</link>
      <guid>https://twitter.com/thinkofthought/status/192967196413149185/photo/1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven Gmail Add-ons That Make Email Suck Less</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: Sidian M.S. Jones is the founder of OpenSourceReligion.net and does graphic design for BookLamp.org. He has a forthcoming book called The Voice of Rolling Thunder. Follow him on Twitter @SidianMSJones. I think it says a lot about the current state of email that we have so many startups trying to change the way we do it. Gmail has been a key player for many years now. With features like threaded messages and filters, they&#8217;ve kept ahead of the game; but the feeling still seems pretty unanimous. Email sucks! Someone has got to burst this bubble and, when they do, they are going to make a mint. I don&#8217;t know, this legendary &#8220;empty inbox&#8221;, if it does exist, still evades me, have you ever seen one? What happens when when there are zero emails? A win screen? Now there&#8217;s an idea&#8230; While we&#8217;re waiting for the next big disruption, there are services that can make the experience a little better &#8212; and maybe more than that. This is a list of Gmail add-on services that are at the top of the game right now. Rapportive Rapportive has been, more or less, the standard for email sidebars that display the latest social network updates of whomever you are emailing. However, many users are lamenting the recent LinkedIn acquisition, claiming the popular add-on will no longer be updated. You might, like me, be interested in switching to Smartr Inbox for Gmail, or one of the few other alternatives. Either way you go, having the latest on your contacts is a very good way to build meaningful relationships in the digital age. AwayFind You may not be able to escape the tyranny that is email, but you could apply a bit of &#8220;out of sight, out of mind&#8221; technology with AwayFind. It lets you assign parameters to emails like &#8220;push to iPhone if this person emails me within the next week&#8221; in which case AwayFind will notify you on your mobile device with an SMS, Voice call or one of their iPhone or Android apps. With features like this in place, you can finally walk away from the inbox. Just slowly&#8230;back away&#8230; MailPilot This one I&#8217;m most excited about but it&#8217;s also the only one I can&#8217;t get. The Mail-Pilot team leads with &#8220;Your inbox is now a to-do list&#8230;&#8221; It hadn&#8217;t struck me until reading this tagline how much sense this sort of approach makes. Of course my inbox is my to-do list! But then why do I have a Tasks widget sitting in the bottom right corner of my Gmail? Probably because email services haven&#8217;t been treating emails as to-do items; but maybe they should. &#8220;Today&#8217;s email apps mark your email as &#8220;read&#8221; as soon as you open it, even though you still have to act on it. All messages require further action: deleting, replying, or some other activity.&#8221; Again, a slightly different perspective with potentially large consequences. I&#8217;m keeping an eye on this one. If you weren&#8217;t part of the KickStarter funding then you won&#8217;t be getting your hands on a copy, though I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;re working hard on a public release. Find Big Mail Not quite so much an add-on as much as it is a utility, FindBigMail is just too useful to not list here. There isn&#8217;t much explanation needed for this service, you sign up and they give you a rundown of your biggest emails, and therefore what is taking up the most space in your Gmail account. The interface is slick and easy to use, but I will add the caveat that FindBigMail does toss a few new (and unasked for so far as I can tell) folders into your account. Then again, while this surprised me, I&#8217;m not sure what other way they might be able to do it. But just try not clicking that little refresh button over and over as it scans your email! SaneBox SaneBox, which was recently reviewed by TechCrunch, uses algorithms to determine email importance and then moves them into separate folders, something I think Gmail covers in more than one way but maybe SaneBox is better? They do, however, boast social network integration, follow up reminders for when someone hasn&#8217;t gotten back to you, and my favorite, the SaneBlackHole Unsubscribe. &#8220;Drag an email into the SaneBlackHole folder, and you&#8217;ll never hear from that sender again. Unsubscribe from mailing lists with 1 click!&#8221; Something about dropping unsolicited emails into a digital black hole makes me feel so good inside. Boomerang For Gmail Simple and effective. Boomerang For Gmail let&#8217;s you send email later, set follow up reminders, and remind you if you don&#8217;t hear back. Like AwayFind, I think I might categorize Boomerang in the &#8220;out of sight, out of mind&#8221; camp, as you still have to deal with the emails later, but you get the potential solace of an empty inbox. It includes a calendar picker for dates but also understands language such as &#8220;next week&#8221; when telling Boomerang when to send a message. CloudMagic Cloud magic, who competes with Greplin, is a search service that crawls through your Gmail, Google Apps, contacts, calendars, documents, and Twitter updates. Install the extension and CloudMagic will insert a search function in Gmail and Twitter, and It is also now available as a mobile app which, according to Sarah Parez is &#8220;&#8230;really, really, really, fast.&#8221; Advanced Operators like &#8220;content:&#8221; really help you get down to business by searching Gooble Document texts. Yes, you can do that from within a document, but why not just do it all from one search box? Gmail Labs Gmail Labs is one of the best, and first, places you should visit if you are looking to get more out of your Gmail experience. To access Gmail Labs log in to your Gmail account, click the gear in the upper-right of your inbox and then click settings. From here there will be a tab labeled &#8220;Labs&#8221;. The Gmail team describes Labs as &#8220;&#8230;a testing ground for experimental features that aren&#8217;t quite ready for primetime. They may change, break or disappear at any time.&#8221; Despite the warning, Labs features have never disappeared nor drastically changed their functionality on me to the point of stopping my use of one, or even ever frustrating me. And boy is there some awesome stuff in here. To name a few&#8230; Undo send gives you a 5-second panic button, in case you have second thoughts. Email previews of Picasa, Google Docs, Google Maps, Flickr, and Yelp from inside an email. Free SMS messaging to mobile phones with Gmail Chat. Unread Message Icon adds a numeric icon to your Gmail tab indicating your unread emails.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/21/seven-gmail-add-ons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/21/seven-gmail-add-ons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dollars, Sense, And 40 Billion Facebook Credits</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: Dean Alms is the VP of Marketing &amp; Business Development at social entertainment company Milyoni. Follow him on Twitter @deanalms. Roughly 16 billion Facebook Credits were distributed and consumed in 2011. In 2012, I predict that the use of Facebook Credits will soar by three times to over 40 billion Credits spent on virtual goods, digital goods and more. The growth will be fueled by new digital content available on Facebook, use of Facebook Credits to reward brand loyalty and better marketing of a social currency that is still in its infancy. The following chart shows the growth of Facebook Credits revenue reported by Facebook from 2009 to 2011. This chart demonstrates that with a growth rate of 300 percent in 2012 (lower growth rate than in prior years) the number of Facebook Credits in circulation will soon reach 47 billion. If 7 billion remain unused in consumer accounts by the end of the year, then 40 billion will have been spent on social gaming, social entertainment and new innovative applications. At 10 cents per credit, total revenue generated from the Facebook Credits market in 2012 will reach approximately $4 billion. Can Facebook Credits really grow to over 40 billion in circulation in 2012? The answer is yes. Here are some of the key assumptions and business drivers of this new international currency for virtual and digital goods. Facebook, seeing the opportunity and its contribution to the bottom line, will put forth a stronger marketing effort in order to communicate the value this currency brings to both merchants and consumers. Facebook Credits are still new and their value can still be hard to understand. Many don&#8217;t know much about this currency, where to get them, what they can and cannot use them for, and why they matter. This marketing effort will likely leverage mainstream marketing channels: TV, Radio, and Print to simply get the message out&#8212;Facebook Credits are hugely valuable and everyone should use them. Retail efforts will pick up steam. iTunes gift cards will face stiff competition from Facebook as young consumers begin asking for these cards for birthdays and holidays instead of a single-brand card like iTunes. The variety of apps with built-in social interaction will create a strong demand for the next-generation of entertainment. Hundreds of big brands and thousands of smaller brands will use Facebook Credits in 2012 as an incentive tool. Facebook Credits will be the airline miles of the next decade as consumers are rewarded with Facebook Credits for brand loyalty. Companies will encourage customers to visit online stores and reward customers with Facebook Credits in varying amounts because the online world-of-mouth and viral effects are endless. Social Gaming will continue to grow with new games and new audiences playing them. Social Gaming, currently led by Zynga, will make billions of dollars in this market with Facebook taking a fee from every transaction conducted on its social network. Social Entertainment will grow in size and significance. In 2012, thousands of movies and hundreds of live events (concerts, sporting events and more) will be available on Facebook for 30 to 100 Facebook Credits each. Today, 89 of the top 100 Facebook Fan pages are entertainment-oriented &#8211; music, movies, and sports properties or personalities&#8212;and fans always want more content from these pages. In 2012, they&#8217;ll be more and more likely to use Credits to access it. Facebook Credits are a global currency. My company, Milyoni, has created a number of live and video on demand offerings on Facebook. Many of them have reached fans from over 30 countries using Facebook Credits as the only currency. This frictionless currency conversion experience is a key factor in the global adoption &#8211; no need to worry about exchange rates or fluctuating monetary values. Facebook provides seamless currency conversion for 47 currencies, and climbing. The Facebook Open Graph. Less appreciated, but very important, is the open graph API&#8217;s and Facebook&#8217;s support of the platform where people, apps and interactions continuously grow. If Facebook&#8217;s team does not meet a specific need, there are other innovative start-ups that will leverage the Open Graph to produce the apps and services that both consumers and merchants need to make this ecosystem thrive. Given this context, spending 40 billion Facebook Credits or $4 billion in virtual and digital goods is achievable. As music, movies and other entertainment content supplements an already growing base of social gamers, this number may end up being on the low side. The bottom line for all businesses with social media ambitions is: create a strategic initiative to leverage Facebook Credits; ignoring it means missing out on the massive market opportunity they represent.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/22/40-billion-facebook-credits/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/22/40-billion-facebook-credits/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parking Panda Helps You Find, Rent &amp; Rent Out Parking Spaces</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Parking Panda Quick Pitch: Find, rent or rent out a parking space online. Genius Idea: Earn money off your empty driveway. When Nick Miller was a student at Georgetown, he had, by his description, one of the best parking spots in the city. &#8220;If I could have sold that driveway, I probably would have gotten half a million for it,&#8221; he joked. &#8220;But I was in college, it was empty, I never used it.&#8221; It was that driveway that inspired Parking Panda, the three-person company of which he is cofounder and CEO. The site allows you to locate and rent parking spaces, and rent out your own stretch of car-friendly turf, similar to what AirBNB offers for housing. Right now the service is only available in Baltimore, MD, but Miller says his team is working to roll out in Washington, D.C. in the coming weeks, followed by Philadelphia, Boston, Chicago and San Francisco. To find a parking space, simply enter an address. You can sort by distance and price, and view photos of the spot. You can also see how many others have &#8220;liked&#8221; or &#8220;disliked&#8221; a space, which is I suppose marginally helpful &#8212; full-text reviews would be much better. Renting out your own parking spot is a simple process. You can connect to Facebook to import your basic details, then set a price and schedule to announce your spot&#8217;s availability. You&#8217;ll receive an email when someone has made a booking. Parking Panda will take a 20% cut. The startup has raised an undisclosed amount of funding and is still in the process of raising more, Miller tells us. Parking Panda has helped more than 1,000 people park in Baltimore, he adds, and has recently begun working with parking garages to increase its inventory. ParkWhiz, another online startup in the parking space, focuses on helping people find parking in major commercial lots. Series Supported by Microsoft BizSpark The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark, a startup program that gives you three-year access to the latest Microsoft development tools, as well as connecting you to a nationwide network of investors and incubators. There are no upfront costs, so if your business is privately owned, less than three years old, and generates less than U.S.$1 million in annual revenue, you can sign up today. More About: bizspark, parking pandaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/parking-panda/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/parking-panda/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parking Panda Helps You Find, Rent &amp; Rent Out Parking Spaces</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Parking Panda Quick Pitch: Find, rent or rent out a parking space online. Genius Idea: Earn money off your empty driveway. When Nick Miller was a student at Georgetown, he had, by his description, one of the best parking spots in the city. &#8220;If I could have sold that driveway, I probably would have gotten half a million for it,&#8221; he joked. &#8220;But I was in college, it was empty, I never used it.&#8221; It was that driveway that inspired Parking Panda, the three-person company of which he is cofounder and CEO. The site allows you to locate and rent parking spaces, and rent out your own stretch of car-friendly turf, similar to what AirBNB offers for housing. Right now the service is only available in Baltimore, MD, but Miller says his team is working to roll out in Washington, D.C. in the coming weeks, followed by Philadelphia, Boston, Chicago and San Francisco. To find a parking space, simply enter an address. You can sort by distance and price, and view photos of the spot. You can also see how many others have &#8220;liked&#8221; or &#8220;disliked&#8221; a space, which is I suppose marginally helpful &#8212; full-text reviews would be much better. Renting out your own parking spot is a simple process. You can connect to Facebook to import your basic details, then set a price and schedule to announce your spot&#8217;s availability. You&#8217;ll receive an email when someone has made a booking. Parking Panda will take a 20% cut. The startup has raised an undisclosed amount of funding and is still in the process of raising more, Miller tells us. Parking Panda has helped more than 1,000 people park in Baltimore, he adds, and has recently begun working with parking garages to increase its inventory. ParkWhiz, another online startup in the parking space, focuses on helping people find parking in major commercial lots. Series Supported by Microsoft BizSpark The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark, a startup program that gives you three-year access to the latest Microsoft development tools, as well as connecting you to a nationwide network of investors and incubators. There are no upfront costs, so if your business is privately owned, less than three years old, and generates less than U.S.$1 million in annual revenue, you can sign up today. More About: bizspark, parking pandaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/parking-panda/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/parking-panda/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Apps to Help You Go Green for Earth Day and Beyond</title>
      <description>The modern environmental movement began on April 22, 1970, when Gaylord Nelson, a United States Senator from Wisconsin, headed an environmental teach-in with over 20 million participants. This event became known as Earth Day, now in its 42nd year and observed by more than 500 million people in 175 countries. This year&#8217;s Earth Day theme is &#8220;Mobilize the Earth,&#8221; actively encouraging world leaders to put us on the path to sustainability and take the green economy seriously. Earth Day isn&#8217;t just for helping the planet one day out of the year &#8212; it&#8217;s a great way to begin a green, environmentally conscious lifestyle. There are various avenues you can take to support this year&#8217;s Earth Day initiative, and a great way to mobilize the earth is by using mobile devices. Check out these apps that can help you go green in time for Earth Day, and set a precedent for the rest of the year. 1. iRecycle With iRecycle, you get instant access to more than 1 million ways to recycle, plus the latest in green news and tips for improving your own lifestyle. Available on iOS.Click here to view this gallery. More About: android, apps, earth day, features, green, iOS, ipad, iphone</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/apps-earth-day/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/apps-earth-day/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valve&#8217;s Hilarious Employee Handbook Reveals Amusing Secrets [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what it would be like to work for game developer Valve? You might have thought the company was highly unconventional, but a peek inside its employee handbook gives you a better indication of just how deep that insouciant peculiarity goes within the organization. Valve Software is a privately held Kirkland, Washington company, founded in 1996 by Microsoft employees Gabe Newell and Mike Harrington, is best known for its hit games including Half-Life, Counter-Strike, Portal, Left for Dead and Alien Swarm. Valve&#8217;s Handbook for New Employees surfaced on the Flamehaus Forum this week, and you&#8217;ll probably find its contents highly amusing. Is it true that Valve&#8217;s managers don&#8217;t actually exist? Mashable&#8216;s Christian Bryant fills you in on the sordid details. More About: Gaming, valve software, VideoFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/valve-employee-handbook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/valve-employee-handbook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
