<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>People Who Say They're Moving To Canada Because Of ObamaCare</title>
      <description>I'm sure they'll like the healthcare just fine there . View Entire List &#8250; Via: @ohnorosco</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/daves4/people-moving-to-canada-because-of-obamacare</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/daves4/people-moving-to-canada-because-of-obamacare</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People Who Say They're Moving To Canada Because Of ObamaCare</title>
      <description>I'm sure they'll like the healthcare just fine there . View Entire List &#8250; Via: @ohnorosco</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/daves4/people-moving-to-canada-because-of-obamacare</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/daves4/people-moving-to-canada-because-of-obamacare</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlueStacks Now Lets You Run Android Apps On Your Mac</title>
      <description>There&#8217;s no love lost between Android and Apple users, or at least among the fanboys and fangirls. The flamewar between the passionate adopters of the top two mobile operating systems has persisted for awhile now, even in spite of our pleas for a detente. Luckily, one startup is on a mission to bridge the gap between the Open and Walled Gardens, so that we can all join hands and walk off into the sunset. At Google I/O today, BlueStacks staged a mock wedding between Android and Apple as the backdrop for the launch of its Android App Player for Mac &#8212; software that aims to bring 400K+ Android apps to iOS. BlueStacks&#8217; alpha release, which is available for free on the startup&#8217;s website, gives Android users the ability to run their favorite apps on a Mac, so that they can download Angry Birds, Temple Run, Evernote, etc directly into BlueStacks, or sync apps they already have installed using the startup&#8217;s &#8220;Cloud Connect&#8221; app. The Mac release follows BlueStacks&#8217; release of its platform for Windows, which allowed users to download and play their apps on any Windows machines. The PC version went like hotcakes upon its release in March, reaching one million downloads in just nine days. As we said at the time, the real key to BlueStacks&#8217; success was its &#8220;ability to run graphics-intensive Android apps on desktop PCs, using its patent-pending technology called &#8216;Layercake&#8217; &#8230; allowing Android apps to run on x86-based PCs, including apps written for the ARM processor,&#8221; like Angry Birds Space or Fruit Ninja, for example. Shainiel Deo, the CEO of Halfbrick (the makers of Fruit Ninja) also said at the time that, while BlueStacks&#8217; tech has plenty of appeal for everyday users, there&#8217;s a lot of appeal for developers, too, because they don&#8217;t have to port or modify apps to run them on a new operating system &#8212; meaning that those who&#8217;ve already developed apps for Android don&#8217;t have to go through the typical heavy lifting. The same holds true for BlueStacks&#8217; Mac release, and the company pushed its launch today featuring a number of new developer partners, including HandyGames, Creative Mobile, and Pulse. The startup said that its next release, which is coming soon, will expand its partner roster further, and the team has been in full force at I/O wooing developers. For more, find BlueStacks at home here, or check out our prior coverage here.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/27/bluestacks-brings-android-to-mac/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/27/bluestacks-brings-android-to-mac/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIM Collapsing? BlackBerry Maker Loses Third of Revenues, Halts Trading</title>
      <description>Canadian tech giant Research in Motion, the beleaguered maker of BlackBerry phones and tablets, suffered what was arguably its worst hit yet Thursday. The company revealed that its share of the global smartphone market had dropped by half in the first quarter. As a result, sales were down a stunning 43% on the previous quarter -- a loss per share of 28 cents. How bad is that? Analysts, prepared by abstract warnings of bad news from CEO Thorston Heins, had been predicting dire outcomes, but few had gone higher than a 14 cent per share loss. The average was a 3-cent loss. (The company halted trading Wednesday afternoon, after shares had slid 18%.) To get itself back on track, th&#8230; Continue reading... More About: blackberry, BlackBerry 10, RIM, thorston heins</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/rim-collapse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/rim-collapse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome for iPhone, iPad: It&#8217;s Safari with Smart Extras [HANDS ON]</title>
      <description>Chrome for iOS is Here Chrome for iOS is here. Available for the IPhone and iPad, how does it compare to the third-party browser competition?Click here to view this gallery. As promised, Google's Chrome web browser is now available for iOS. We've spent some time playing with the app -- which you can download from the App Store now [iTunes link] -- and trying it out alongside Mobile Safari, iCab Mobile, Opera Mini and others. Understanding the Trade-Offs Because Apple restricts the way third-party web browsers can work with iOS, Chrome isn't substantially different from any other mobile web browser. In fact, it's basically just the UIWebView (geek speak for the basic Mobile Safari rendering engine) with a customized skin. That's not a bad thing -- Mobile Safari is a great mobile web browser -- but it mean that users have to accept a few trade-offs&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Browsers, chrome, chrome ios, Google, iOS apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/chrome-ios-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/chrome-ios-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome for iOS</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chrome/id535886823?mt=8</link>
      <guid>http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chrome/id535886823?mt=8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van Gogh&#8217;s &#8216;Starry Night&#8217; Is Beautifully Recreated From 7,000 Dominoes [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>What would celebrated painter Vincent van Gogh's Starry Night look like if it were constructed out of thousands of dominoes? YouTube video maker FlippyCat found out, successfully recreating the masterpiece on his second try. During the first attempt, a screw from the camera he had affixed overhead fell and sent the dominoes spiraling to the ground. Though he didn't time his first attempt, his second and final go at creating the domino version of "Starry Night" took 11 hours. SEE ALSO: 30,000 Dominoes Capture the History of Nintendo in 3 Minutes [VIDEO] FlippyCat has previously made Leonardo da Vinci's Mona Lisa from dominoes, capturing his creation in a YouTube video since view&#8230; Continue reading... More About: art, Video, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/starry-night-dominoes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/starry-night-dominoes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Glass: One day... - YouTube</title>
      <description>We believe technology should work for you &#8212; to be there when you need it and get out of your way when you don't. A team within our Google[x] group started Pr...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Releases Dedicated iOS Podcasts App</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/podcasts/id525463029?mt=8</link>
      <guid>http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/podcasts/id525463029?mt=8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Granny&#8217;s 50 Tips on Social Media, #Pinterest, Twitter &amp; Content Marketing!</title>
      <description>Wow, it&amp;#8217;s been awhile since Granny stopped by for some good southern social media advice. For those of you who haven&amp;#8217;t met granny, you&amp;#8217;re in for a surprise. Word of warning, she is not shy and will tell you how it is. You can choose to agree with her or not. Either way she&amp;#8217;ll either</description>
      <link>http://www.pammarketingnut.com/2012/06/grannys-50-tips-on-social-media-pinterest-twitter-content-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+PamMarketingNut+%28Pam+Marketing+Nut%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.pammarketingnut.com/2012/06/grannys-50-tips-on-social-media-pinterest-twitter-content-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+PamMarketingNut+%28Pam+Marketing+Nut%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We know what you're doing... A social networking privacy experiment by Callum Haywood</title>
      <description>Disclaimer: All data is pulled directly from Facebook, it is not censored, and it is publicly accessible via the Graph API. I cannot be held responsible for any persons actions as a result of using this experiment. All attempts have been made to ensure the accuracy and reliability of the information provided on this website. However, the information is provided "as is" without warranty of any kind. Callum Haywood does not accept any responsibility or liability for the accuracy, content, completeness, legality, or reliability of the information contained on this website. No warranties, promises and/or representations of any kind, expressed or implied, are given as to the nature, standard, accuracy or otherwise of the information provided in this website nor to the suitability or otherwise of the information to your particular circumstances. We shall not be liable for any loss or damage of whatever nature (direct, indirect, consequential, or other) whether arising in contract, tort or otherwise, which may arise as a result of your use of (or inability to use) this website, or from your use of (or failure to use) the information on this site. This website provides links to other websites owned by third parties. The content of such third party sites is not within our control, and we cannot and will not take responsibility for the information or content thereon. Links to such third party sites are not to be taken as an endorsement by Callum Haywood of the third party site, or any products promoted, offered or sold on the third party site, nor that such sites are free from computer viruses or anything else that has destructive properties. We cannot and do not take responsibility for the collection or use of personal data from any third party site. In addition, we will not accept responsibility for the accuracy of third party advertisements. If you see any posts on here that are yours and you want them removing, delete them from Facebook first, then they will stop appearing here (may take up to an hour), or contact me to block any posts by you from appearing.</description>
      <link>http://WeKnowWhatYoureDoing.com</link>
      <guid>http://WeKnowWhatYoureDoing.com</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
