<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Retina MacBook Pro: The Laptop From the Future [REVIEW]</title>
      <description>When Apple created major buzz around a new product in the past few years, it was almost always an iPhone or iPad. That's why it's so refreshing to see the world ooh and aah about an Apple computer again, the MacBook Pro With Retina Display. It certainly looks great on paper -- a cutting-edge laptop loaded with the latest tech and a jaw-droppingly sharp screen. But does it really deliver the goods? The answer isn't just yes. It's "oh, baby." Within minutes of taking our review sample out of the box here at the Mashable offices, a crowd of staffers gathered around to see what visions the glorious 2,880 x 1,800 retina display would show them. It didn't disappoint. After setting u&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, laptops, Macbook Pro, retina display, reviews</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/retina-macbook-pro-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/retina-macbook-pro-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steve Jobs Vs. Bill Gates in Epic Rap Battle [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>The Epic Rap Battle of History music video series takes on two tech heavyweights -- late Apple innovator Steve Jobs and Microsoft chairman Bill Gates -- in its latest rap-off. Lyrics mock both men and throw jabs at Bill's wife, Melinda, and Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak. And then, holy sh*t, Jobs becomes HAL 9000 from the movie 2001: A Space Odyssey? Yup, Jobs continues the war of words as a "heuristically programmed algorithmic computer." Epic Rap Battle's past matchups include Darth Vader vs. Adolf Hitler, Gandalf vs. Dumbledore, Dr. Seuss vs. Shakespeare, Justin Bieber vs. Beethoven and more. SEE ALSO: Billionaire Tycoon One-Ups Rapper Drake&#8217;s Money Tweet If you lik&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, bill gates, Entertainment, humor, microsoft, Music, parody, rap, steve jobs, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/steve-jobs-bill-gates-rap-battle/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/steve-jobs-bill-gates-rap-battle/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rufus Wainwright&#8217;s New Music Video Features Fans&#8217; Instagrams [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Singer-songwriter Rufus Wainwright's lyric music video for his new song "Out of the Game" is a visual feast full of Instagram photos culled from a crowdsourced contest he launched in April. The clip, shared first with Mashable on Thursday, is the result of Wainwright challenging fans to take Instagram photos that represent a word in the song's lyrics. Participants submitted snaps using hashtag #OutOfTheGame and a second hashtag with the word the image represents. All submissions also became part of a mosaic on instagram.rufaswainwright.com. Some images will be used in a limited-edition print book. BONUS: Jason Mraz Picks Instagram Contest&#8217;s Best Snapshots [PICS] Earlier&#8230; Continue reading... More About: celebrities, Entertainment, instagram, Music, music videos, photography, rufus wainwright</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/rufus-wainwright-out-game-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/rufus-wainwright-out-game-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer 7 'tax' a first</title>
      <description>The Australian online retailer Kogan.com has introduced the world's first "tax" on use of Microsoft's Internet Explorer 7 (IE7) browser.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-18440979</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-18440979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Every Employee Need Social Media Training?</title>
      <description>Has social media become so omnipresent that companies can no longer afford to train just marketers, sales and public relations people in Twitter, Facebook and other networks? That's the premise behind an expansion in service for the social media strategy firm Digital Royalty and its founder Amy Jo Martin. The company is preparing to roll out a new set of online courses meant to train entire corporate workforces -- not just people whose primary tasks are interfacing with customers. Martin says it's a first for the still-emerging industry of social media management. "There's yet to be a comprehensive offering online in this customizable yet automated way," she told Mashable. "Now we're&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Marketing, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/social-media-digital-royalty/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/social-media-digital-royalty/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bloomingdales Will Let You Design Shoes from a Store Window [EXCLUSIVE]</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s a familiar problem; you&#8217;ve scanned the shoe stores for the perfect sandals to match your new bathing suit, but nothing quite goes. What if you could design your own? Havaianas and Bloomingdales in NYC are offering customers the chance to do just that. The store's windows are being turned into interactive displays that let you design and order a pair of the ubiquitous flip flops. Here&#8217;s how it works. Walk up to the window and tap through the ordering process, as you would on the company&#8217;s website. Pick your color sole, straps, and decorations. After you complete the order, you can choose whether you&#8217;d like to get your confirmation number via a QR code or SMS.&#8230; Continue reading... More About: clothing, shopping</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/design-your-own-flip-flops/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/design-your-own-flip-flops/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Set to Unveil Something &#8216;Major&#8217; on Monday</title>
      <description>Well, this is intriguing. Mashable just got an exclusive invite to a major Microsoft "Media Event" for June 18 in Los Angeles. Nothing else -- and we mean nothing -- is known about the 3:30 p.m. event (more details, including the venue, should arrive by early Monday morning), but all indications are that this is not your typical Microsoft product unveiling. In fact, Microsoft is making it 100% clear that this is big: This will be a major Microsoft announcement -- you will not want to miss it. It's hard to recall another Microsoft inviotation like this one. No graphics, no details, no leaks. It sounds, well, almost Apple-esque in its urgency and stringent requirements&#8230; Continue reading... More About: microsoft, Windows, Xbox 360</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/microsoft-media-event-june-18/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/microsoft-media-event-june-18/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FunnyJunk is threatening to file a federal lawsuit against me unless I pay $20,000 in damages</title>
      <description>FunnyJunk's lawyer sent me a letter stating that I owe him $20k in damages. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/blog/funnyjunk_letter</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/blog/funnyjunk_letter</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Engagement is Actually Up, Despite Reuters Poll</title>
      <description>Although a poll circulated the web last week that found one-third of Facebook users are using the social network less than six months ago, statistics show site engagement is actually up. A survey conducted among 1,032 Americans by Reuters and research firm Ipsos found that 35% of Facebook users said they are less engaged on the social network than they have been in the recent past and only 20% of members are spending more time on the site. However, both comScore and Nielson traffic data shows members are accessing Facebook just as much -- if not more -- than six months ago. According to comScore, behavioral data shows that engagement for users is actually up 4% from 364 minutes spe&#8230; Continue reading... More About: engagement, Facebook, poll</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/facebook-engagement-poll/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/facebook-engagement-poll/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Are the Real Online Influencers? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>As the web's capacity for pageviews increases, marketers are becoming less interested in reaching as many people as possible, and more interested in reaching the right people. According to Deanna Brown, the CEO of Federated Media, that's why context is so important -- the ability serve high volumes of advertising continues to expand, but the real value for a brand is to surround its message with the right context so that it reaches the most influential people among customers. Yet, while most marketers agree that reaching influencers is important, they question how to measure influence and how to determine the most influential people online in the first place. Are you influential if you&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, influencers, infographics, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/influence-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/influence-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Day Is June 30. How Will You Celebrate?</title>
      <description>Social Media Day is exactly one month away! On Saturday, June 30, digital enthusiasts will hold meetups across the globe to celebrate the one thing that unites us and keeps us in constant contact: social media. Whether you&#8217;re an obsessed Instagram photographer, an endless Pinterest pinner or a ten-times-an-hour tweeter, Social Media Day is a time to recognize the digital revolution that has changed how we live. How Will You Celebrate? Social Media Day will be a truly international event. Mashable community organizers are already hard at work planning events in hundreds of cities worldwide. The meetup in Swindon, U.K. will feature presentations about social media strategy as well as a speed networking session. Thousands of miles away in the United States, a celebration dedicated to startups will be held in Detroit. We want to know: How are you celebrating Social Media Day? Will you organize a Foursquare scavenger hunt? Attend a fast-paced panel discussion about social media branding? Play Pinterest-inspired hopscotch? The possibilites are endless, and we want you to get creative! Tell us what you&#8217;ve got planned for Social Media Day in the comments below. We look forward to hearing what you have in store! Ways You Can Participate Check out the Social Media Day website for resources and more information. Sign up to attend or organize your own event on the Mashable Meetup Everywhere page. Use the #smday hashtag on Twitter, Instagram, Google+ and any other social network of your choice. Find your Mashable Meetup community: Image courtesy of flickr, ancawonka Social Media Day 2012 Is Presented By Motorola Mobility More About: community, smday, social media dayFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/social-media-day-june-30-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/social-media-day-june-30-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Crowdsourcing the Secret to Creating Innovation in Government?</title>
      <description>Are competitions and crowdsourcing the path to bringing government into the 21st century? The White House's Office of Science and Technology Policy certainly thinks so. It hosted an event this week to discuss prize-based contests and recognize successful examples of their use to spur innovation in the government sector -- not a place typically known as being a haven for early adopters. The idea is simple: If a government agency is presented with a certain challenge (such as, "what do we do with all this data?"), they turn that problem over to the public and say "help us achieve this goal, and win a prize." Prizes can vary, but they're usually some amount of cash to help cover the cost&#8230; Continue reading... More About: crowdsourcing, innovation, open data, open government, Politics, todd park, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/crowdsourcing-government/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/crowdsourcing-government/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
