<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Mouthwatering Instagram Pics [FOOD PORN]</title>
      <description>The Best of Instagram Series is presented by T-Mobile. Its 4G Tweet Race, a week-long campaign launching May 3, pits Twitter users against one another in a daily, frantic race for retweets. There are 7 races, and the winners of each heat win a new HTC One&#8482; S phone with a year of T-Mobile&#8217;s Unlimited Value service, and the final winner takes home $4,000. Instagram users often get a bit of flack for oversharing their food photos. Now that the photo-sharing app is available for iOS, Android and possibly soon Facebook, we expect the user base and the photo uploads to surge. But that&#8217;s not to say all photos aren&#8217;t worth sharing. Sure, maybe there are a swarm of users who like to share photos of their Subway sandwich, but there are also tons of gorgeous pictures of food and beverages that will make your mouth water. We&#8217;ve collected photos from Instagram users, professional photographers and even chefs to present you with 20 of the tastiest photos. (Note: You can&#8217;t actually eat them.) Do you think your food photos have what it takes? Let us know in the comments. 1. Jamie Oliver To celebrate his daughters' birthdays, celebrity chef Jamie Oliver shared this beautiful cake with his followers.Click here to view this gallery. Series presented by T-Mobile The Best of Instagram Series is presented by T-Mobile. The 4G Tweet Race is a week-long campaign starting May 3 that pits Twitter users against one another in a daily, frantic race for retweets. Players register on the official Tweet Race page on T-Mobile&#8217;s Test Drive, and each racer&#8217;s tweets must contain three elements: #4GTweets, http://t-mo.co/4GTweets and @TMobile, and must be submitted during the race to be eligible. There are 7 races over the course of the week, and the winners of all 7 heats will face off in a final race on May 15th to see whose social graph is quickest. The winner of each heat will win a new HTC One&#8482; S phone with a year of T-Mobile&#8217;s Unlimited Value service, and the final winner will take home a cool $4,000. Image courtesy of Jamie Oliver More About: Best of Instagram Series, features, Food And Drink, instagram, mashable</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/food-drink-instagram-pics/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/food-drink-instagram-pics/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shapeways CEO: 3D Printing Will Fuel Creative Commerce</title>
      <description>Although 3D printing has been around since the &#8217;80s, it only recently moved out of specialty prototyping shops. As the technology becomes more accessible &#8212; allowing anybody to design anything they want &#8212; it could revolutionize the way products are made and distributed. &#8220;We think it will give rise to a creative commerce,&#8221; said Shapeways CEO Peter Weijmarshausen on stage at Mashable Connect Friday. Shapeways was one of the first companies to put a consumer spin on 3D printing. The startup&#8217;s website allows designers to upload their wares for printing and sell the results in an Etsy-like store. Those without design experience can tweak existing models to their liking before printing them in one of 25 different materials, including stainless steel, ceramics and sterling silver. Weijmarshausen says the company printed 750,000 products in 2011. He expects &#8220;many times more this year &#8212; millions.&#8221; The other company most often credited for the rise of the consumer 3D printing trend is MakerBot, which sells 3D printers for about $1,700. So how does the trend toward 3D printing products, rather than just prototypes, change the world? &#8220;Products will get better, quicker because you don&#8217;t have stock that you have to sell,&#8221; Weijmarshausen says. &#8220;You can do new versions tomorrow. You can do version seven in a week. And that way, we will get products that are much more relevant to us.&#8221; 3D printing allows designers to iterate quickly and without risk, which means they can incorporate feedback immediately. Instead of getting a loan, paying a manufacturer, putting it through retail channels and hoping it sells, designers can make just as many units as they sell. If they have new ideas or feedback, they can incorporate them immediately instead of waiting until their latest version sells out. The technology has already lowered the barrier to creating new products, but we&#8217;re not quite ready to abandon mass production. For one thing, 3D printing is still a lot more expensive than buying a mass-produced item. A custom ring costs $40, a bracelet can be $100 and a small vase costs about $50. While those prices aren&#8217;t at the most expensive end of their respective categories, they make printing large items impractical. &#8220;It&#8217;s lot of money for this vase,&#8221; said Weijmarshausen, referring to the $50 model sitting on the podium. &#8220;But at the same time, it&#8217;s the only vase in the world that looks like this&#8230;As this technology becomes more and more popular, I think the cost will come down.&#8221; MashableConnect-Friday-616px006 Click here to view this gallery. Mashable Connect Sponsors Buddy Media is the social enterprise software of choice for eight of the world&#8217;s top ten global advertisers, empowering them to build and maintain relationships with their consumers in a connections-based world. The Buddy Media social marketing suite helps brands build powerful connections globally with its scalable, secure architecture and data-driven customer insights from initial point of contact through point of purchase. For more information, visit http://www.buddymedia.com. AT&amp;T is bringing it all together for our customers, from revolutionary smartphones to next-generation TV services and sophisticated solutions for multi-national businesses. For more than a century, we have consistently provided innovative, reliable, high-quality products and services and excellent customer care. For more, visit http://www.att.com. Barnes &amp; Noble College Marketing (BNCM) helps brands thrive on campus. It is a division of Barnes &amp; Noble College Booksellers, LLC., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Barnes &amp; Noble, Inc. that operates more than 640 college bookstores across the country, serving more than 4.7 million students and faculty members. BNCM has the on-campus access and student understanding to deliver superior marketing programs for its brand partners. BNCM&#8217;s capabilities include: experiential and event marketing; product sampling, sweepstakes and promotions; digital marketing (social, email, web); on-campus advertising and postering; and programs targeting freshmen, graduates, alumni and athletic event fans. Visit www.bncollegemarketing.com. Hiscox specializes in tailored insurance coverage for a range of professional services firms in industries like IT, marketing, consulting and more. Hiscox Insurance Company Inc. has been protecting clients for over 100 years and is rated &#8216;A&#8217; (Excellent) for financial strength by A.M. Best. We offer professional liability insurance, general liability insurance and other policies direct, either online or over the phone, with customized coverage starting from just $22.50/month. Visit hiscoxusa.com/smallbiz for a fast, free quote now. Webtrends powers digital marketing success. Webtrends is at the forefront of real-time digital marketing relevance and customer experience management through unified customer intelligence. Our industry-leading analytics across mobile, social and web enables marketers to optimize campaigns, maximize customer lifetime value and deliver highly relevant digital brand experiences in real-time. Webtrends dramatically improve digital marketing results for more than 3,500 global brands including, in EMEA and internationally, Lloyds Banking Group, Barclays, HSBC, ASOS, Orange, T-Mobile, Microsoft, BMW, Toyota, Play.com, AllSaints, The Telegraph, and many more. www.webtrends.com Definition 6 is a Unified Marketing Agency that creates brand experiences that unite brands and people in motion. Through imagination, innovation and insight, we execute ideas that deliver continued value across all brand interactions. For more information, please visit http://www.definition6.com. The Adobe Digital Marketing Suite is an integrated set of applications which allow businesses to gather customer insight and optimize advertising, conversion and retention efforts as well as the creation and distribution of content. For example, using the Suite, marketers can identify the most effective marketing strategies and ad placements as well as create relevant, personalized and consistent customer experiences across digital marketing channels, such as onsite, display, e-mail, social, video and mobile. The Suite enables marketers to automatically adjust to customer interactions and better maximize marketing ROI, which leads to a positive impact the bottom line. http://www.adobe.com/solutions/digital-marketing.html The leading resource for human resource and business leaders to explore and discuss the latest workforce and workplace trends including social innovation&#8212;providing the in-depth research and insights needed to adapt and take advantage of what&#8217;s next. www.shrm.org More About: 3d printing, mashable connect, shapewaysFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/3d-printing-creative-commerce/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/3d-printing-creative-commerce/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week</title>
      <description>1. Pac-tivity The Tupac hologram keeps turning up in our top 10. It is already famous on social media, but what about a movie career? This week&#8217;s number one is this Tupac #hologram parody, posted to Twitter by @RatchetPictures (950+ followers). Click here to view this gallery. The upper echelon of popular Twitter pics this week dealt with cuteness, beauty and even some truth. And in between, there were reminders that all was not as it appeared. As the new month began, protest pictures found their way to Twitter, and as the week progressed, comedy took over. We certainly had no shortage of pictures from which to choose, sifting through 42 million to select this week&#8217;s top 10. Check out the full analysis for this week&#8217;s pics from our partners at Skylines, who created a custom algorithm to allow us to find these needles in a haystack the size of this planet. Gracing us with her insight is Skylines&#8217; writer and analyst Julie Donders (@IkbenJulie), who makes sense of these sometimes chaotic selections with her spot-on captions. SEE MORE: Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week Don&#8217;t miss this eclectic mix of comedy, chaos, creativity and courage as we bring to you this week&#8217;s Top 10 Twitter Pics. In case you missed them, here are last week&#8217;s Top 10 Twitter Pics. More About: Top 10 Twitter Pics, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/top-10-twitter-pics-16/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/top-10-twitter-pics-16/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Could Face $10 Million Fine For Tracking Safari Users</title>
      <description>Google may see the costliest repercussion from its alleged Apple Safari privacy breach coming from the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC). The FTC may fine Google more than $10 million for violating Internet privacy according to Bloomberg, citing &#8220;a person familiar with the matter&#8221; in its report. &#8220;We will of course cooperate with any officials who have questions,&#8221; Google spokesman Chris Gaither told Bloomberg. The Mountain View-based company was caught tracking user activity on mobile Apple devices. The search giant is accused of violating federal laws and user privacy by installing cookies and trackers onto default Apple Safari browsers. SEE ALSO: Google Caught Tracking Safari Users: What You Need to Know Google allegedly bypassed Safari settings with a software trick, maneuvering around the Safari limitations on third-party tracking using &#8220;special computer code.&#8221; The Wall Street Journal first reported the Google Apple Safari tracking in February. The code was first spotted by Jonathan Meyer, a researcher at Stanford University&#8217;s The Center for Internet and Society. Meyer described the &#8220;Safari Trackers&#8221; in a blog post. Google removed the Safari code after the WSJ report was published. In Google&#8217;s rebuttal, the company said it was only trying to get the Google &#8220;+1&#8243; button on many different websites. They said the code was not collecting any personal information from users at all. How will a hefty fine affect Internet privacy for users? Tell us in the comments if you think the fine will persuade more companies to abide by privacy laws. More About: apple, Google, ipad, iphone, privacy, safariFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/google-tracking-safari-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/google-tracking-safari-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Future of Social Is in the Palm of Your Hand</title>
      <description>When I leave the house in the morning, the first thing I check is that I have my phone with me. It&#8217;s not my keys nor my wallet, but my phone that I&#8217;m most worried about forgetting. My mobile device has become my lifeline in a lot of ways &#8212; and I know I&#8217;m not alone. When I walk outside, it seems hard to find someone who&#8217;s not on their phone. Whether they&#8217;re looking up directions on a maps app, checking in to their current location on Foursquare or taking a photo with Instagram, many of us rely on mobile devices to get things done efficiently and conveniently &#8212; and to stay connected. Long before Facebook bought Instagram last month, the mobile social networking boom was upon us. The $1 billion acquisition was just the icing on the cake. This was the jumping off point for a discussion on stage at Mashable Connect with myself, Brett Martin, co-founder and CEO of Sonar, Steve Jang, co-founder, chief product designer and CEO of SoundTracking, and Bart Stein, co-founder of Stamped on Saturday. Here&#8217;s a little bit more about what we talked about and why we&#8217;re certain mobile social networks are the communities of the future. Self-Expression in Real Time Social networks were built on the notion of sharing. Whether we&#8217;re revealing interests, photos or life moments, these platforms have become the ultimate vehicles of self-expression. The features built into mobile devices, such as cameras and GPS, enable even the most casual tech user to easily create his or her own media. Mobile editing and social apps help the content individuals produce to be more sophisticated, while remaining personal. &#8220;I think people are excited to take a bit of their everyday life with their phone and augment it toward something beautiful and emotional to share,&#8221; says Steve Jang, co-founder and CEO of Soundtracking. &#8220;As long as there is a captive audience that is responsive to this stream of personal media captured and shared on the fly, then I think we&#8217;ll continue to see people flock to these mobile communities.&#8221; Thirty-eight million Americans use mobile devices for social networking almost every day, comScore reports. It&#8217;s even surpassed gaming as the most-engaged mobile activity, according to Flurry. Like Jang said, these numbers will continue to rise alongside our desire to produce and engage with personal media. As more people access social networks from smartphones and tablets, they&#8217;ll realize these devices do more than make sharing easier and content creation better. They also allow for instantaneous connections. &#8220;It&#8217;s no longer good enough for some of us to come home from vacation or a night out to post our photos and thoughts,&#8221; says Brett Martin, co-founder and CEO of Sonar. &#8220;We&#8217;ve become so used to real-time sharing that it feels irrelevant to post pictures of and reactions to things that happened mere hours ago.&#8221; This real-time self-expression was essentially non-existent before the rise of mobile devices &#8212; and now it&#8217;s the norm. We&#8217;ve become accustomed to knowing what&#8217;s going on with our friends and family or favorite celebrities and organizations at the moment it&#8217;s happening. This allows us to feel as though we&#8217;re experiencing these activities with them, radically changing how we feel and, ultimately, connect. Stronger Relationships This increased connectedness can help us feel closer to our contacts, both fortifying existing relationships and forging new ones. Apps such as Face Time allow us to stay in touch with friends and family overseas while others, like Martin&#8217;s Sonar, help us discover new contacts through shared connections. These are the users &#8220;that know the value of relationships,&#8221; Martin says. But those get togethers with friends where you look up and everyone is tweeting, checking in or uploading a photo instead of talking face-to-face, makes you wonder: Is mobile social networking really helping us make the right connections? Jang says the stigma of people ignoring their IRL friends to engage on these networks &#8220;is outweighed by the benefit of being to stay in touch with a much larger group of friends and family and see, read, and listen to a vivid (albeit fleeting) snapshot of their lives.&#8221; For Martin, it&#8217;s certainly a concern. &#8220;But the best apps won&#8217;t need to hold you hostage to the screen,&#8221; he says. Rather, they should add dimension to relationships and enable you to engage with others in unprecedented ways, making it &#8220;easier than ever to make and maintain real life relationships,&#8221; says Stein. Enriched Lives At the core of any community is connecting people with a passion for a common interest. When it comes to mobile, the plethora of social apps make it easy for users to connect around any hobby or activity, no matter how niche or mainstream. Whether you&#8217;re looking for a restaurant or a relationship, apps allow you to do what you want to do better &#8212; right along with your community. &#8220;The best communities being built by mobile app creators today are the ones that already existed offline, but hadn&#8217;t been provided with technology and tools to enrich their experiences and relationships,&#8221; says Stein. &#8220;There must be a distinction made between the apps that add utility and improve people&#8217;s lives rather than those designed to waste time &#8212; the former actually improves relationships and the quality of interactions rather than diminishing them.&#8221; When asked if, as mobile app creators, they consider themselves community builders, Jang and Stein say the goal of each of their apps is to help an existing community build on what it&#8217;s already doing. For Soundtracking, it&#8217;s helping the music community share and engage with the songs they already love. For Stamped, it&#8217;s about providing people who enjoy sharing their favorites with technology that makes this easier. What&#8217;s Next? Mobile social networks are the communities of the future. So, what&#8217;s on the horizon for this up-and-coming space? Here&#8217;s what the panelists had to say: &#8220;It&#8217;s all about context, frictionless sharing and push-notification-driven user interfaces. The best apps won&#8217;t tell you about every random person or restaurant that you walk by; just the ones that will truly matter.&#8221; &#8212; Brett Martin, Co-founder and CEO, Sonar. &#8220;The combination of structured data with your social graph is the next big trend in mobile. There&#8217;s powerful structured data around places, objects and things that when combined with a social layer can generate and sustain a whole new class of apps. It&#8217;s easier than ever for developers to tap into APIs and publicly available data sources to build new sets of killer applications.&#8221; &#8212; Bart Stein, Co-founder, Stamped. &#8220;Moving forward, the mobile user experience of social networking will become more distributed across multiple apps&#8230; When Facebook launched its Messenger app, I loved that. It was a straightforward app that did one thing well and let me re-engage with the FB message feature again. Inside the all-in-one FB app, that feature was more difficult to use quickly and easily&#8230; It makes a lot of sense to think about a community&#8217;s social graph and data as an underlying network upon which you can develop simple, powerful and functionally-specific mobile apps.&#8221; &#8212; Steve Jang, Co-founder and CEO, Soundtracking. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, TommL MashableConnect-Friday-616px006 Click here to view this gallery. Mashable Connect Sponsors Buddy Media is the social enterprise software of choice for eight of the world&#8217;s top ten global advertisers, empowering them to build and maintain relationships with their consumers in a connections-based world. The Buddy Media social marketing suite helps brands build powerful connections globally with its scalable, secure architecture and data-driven customer insights from initial point of contact through point of purchase. For more information, visit http://www.buddymedia.com. AT&amp;T is bringing it all together for our customers, from revolutionary smartphones to next-generation TV services and sophisticated solutions for multi-national businesses. For more than a century, we have consistently provided innovative, reliable, high-quality products and services and excellent customer care. For more, visit http://www.att.com. Barnes &amp; Noble College Marketing (BNCM) helps brands thrive on campus. It is a division of Barnes &amp; Noble College Booksellers, LLC., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Barnes &amp; Noble, Inc. that operates more than 640 college bookstores across the country, serving more than 4.7 million students and faculty members. BNCM has the on-campus access and student understanding to deliver superior marketing programs for its brand partners. BNCM&#8217;s capabilities include: experiential and event marketing; product sampling, sweepstakes and promotions; digital marketing (social, email, web); on-campus advertising and postering; and programs targeting freshmen, graduates, alumni and athletic event fans. Visit www.bncollegemarketing.com. Hiscox specializes in tailored insurance coverage for a range of professional services firms in industries like IT, marketing, consulting and more. Hiscox Insurance Company Inc. has been protecting clients for over 100 years and is rated &#8216;A&#8217; (Excellent) for financial strength by A.M. Best. We offer professional liability insurance, general liability insurance and other policies direct, either online or over the phone, with customized coverage starting from just $22.50/month. Visit hiscoxusa.com/smallbiz for a fast, free quote now. Webtrends powers digital marketing success. Webtrends is at the forefront of real-time digital marketing relevance and customer experience management through unified customer intelligence. Our industry-leading analytics across mobile, social and web enables marketers to optimize campaigns, maximize customer lifetime value and deliver highly relevant digital brand experiences in real-time. Webtrends dramatically improve digital marketing results for more than 3,500 global brands including, in EMEA and internationally, Lloyds Banking Group, Barclays, HSBC, ASOS, Orange, T-Mobile, Microsoft, BMW, Toyota, Play.com, AllSaints, The Telegraph, and many more. www.webtrends.com Definition 6 is a Unified Marketing Agency that creates brand experiences that unite brands and people in motion. Through imagination, innovation and insight, we execute ideas that deliver continued value across all brand interactions. For more information, please visit http://www.definition6.com. The Adobe Digital Marketing Suite is an integrated set of applications which allow businesses to gather customer insight and optimize advertising, conversion and retention efforts as well as the creation and distribution of content. For example, using the Suite, marketers can identify the most effective marketing strategies and ad placements as well as create relevant, personalized and consistent customer experiences across digital marketing channels, such as onsite, display, e-mail, social, video and mobile. The Suite enables marketers to automatically adjust to customer interactions and better maximize marketing ROI, which leads to a positive impact the bottom line. http://www.adobe.com/solutions/digital-marketing.html The leading resource for human resource and business leaders to explore and discuss the latest workforce and workplace trends including social innovation&#8212;providing the in-depth research and insights needed to adapt and take advantage of what&#8217;s next. www.shrm.org More About: community, mashable connect, mobile social networkingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/future-social-mobile/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/future-social-mobile/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advice: How to Market to Millennials -- and How to Use Social Media to Get a First Job</title>
      <description>Last month I wrote a post called Tough love for marketing and PR job seekers. In it I challenged you to prove you are a great marketer by showing, not telling. I said that you need to create content that will brand you as someone to hire. Now. Starting today.I've delivered this advice to hundreds of people. Sadly for them, I know from experience that nearly all ignore this advice.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/davidmeermanscott/499782/lindsey-shows-how-market-millennials-and-how-get-first-job</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/davidmeermanscott/499782/lindsey-shows-how-market-millennials-and-how-get-first-job</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is This Censorship? Facebook Stops You From Posting &#226;&#8364;&#732;Irrelevant Or Inappropriate&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Comments</title>
      <description>Colleen Taylor / TechCrunch:Is This Censorship? Facebook Stops You From Posting &#8216;Irrelevant Or Inappropriate&#8217; Comments &#8212; Today was just another Saturday morning in blog land when Robert Scoble, the well-known tech startup enthusiast, went to post a comment on a Facebook post written by Carnegie Mellon student &#8230;</description>
      <link>http://www.techmeme.com/120505/p10</link>
      <guid>http://www.techmeme.com/120505/p10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Marketing Is Broken and How to Fix It</title>
      <description>The marketing world needs to stop being so afraid and start solving problems, according to Cindy Gallop, an entrepreneur and consultant whose prescription for growth calls for emphasizing creativity over data collection. Gallop, who spoke at Mashable Connect Saturday morning, critiqued the current state of marketing, which she believes is driven by fear. &#8220;Fear is the single worst dynamic in business,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Decisions made out of fear are always very bad decisions.&#8221; Such trepidation, predicated by the economy, has caused marketers to become much more cautious, hence the emphasis on data collection in lieu of risk-taking. In Gallop&#8217;s view, though, this array of data has caused paralysis. Lacking any single standard for tracking data, marketers are merely analyzing. To get over that, Gallop recommends a DIY approach: &#8220;You should decide what you are and what you want to measure,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Design your own metric system.&#8221; A self-styled system should also be more transparent about its data collection. In an age of transparency, Gallop says marketers should approach their relationship with clients on social media the same way they&#8217;d do it in real life. &#8220;When you meet someone you like, you want to know about them, so you ask them and you tell them things about yourself,&#8221; she says. &#8220;You reach a point where essentially on both sides you&#8217;re saying, &#8216;I want you to know me.&#8217; That&#8217;s the relationship you want to reach with consumers.&#8221; Yet Gallop thinks transparency alone isn&#8217;t enough, noting that advertisers are now judged by actions, not claims. As an example of this new type of &#8220;action branding,&#8221; she cited Levi&#8217;s decision to raise $2 million for the down-on-its-luck town of Braddock, Pa., in 2010 and feature it and its young mayor in an ad campaign. It&#8217;s unclear how effective such solutions are in the real world. Though there were doubtlessly other factors at play, the ad campaign seems to have helped Levi&#8217;s sales &#8212; the company&#8217;s 2011 revenues rose 8%. However, a similar program from Pepsi appears to have had a disastrous effect on sales and that brand recently abandoned the approach. MashableConnect-Friday-616px006 Click here to view this gallery. Mashable Connect Sponsors Buddy Media is the social enterprise software of choice for eight of the world&#8217;s top ten global advertisers, empowering them to build and maintain relationships with their consumers in a connections-based world. The Buddy Media social marketing suite helps brands build powerful connections globally with its scalable, secure architecture and data-driven customer insights from initial point of contact through point of purchase. For more information, visit http://www.buddymedia.com. AT&amp;T is bringing it all together for our customers, from revolutionary smartphones to next-generation TV services and sophisticated solutions for multi-national businesses. For more than a century, we have consistently provided innovative, reliable, high-quality products and services and excellent customer care. For more, visit http://www.att.com. Barnes &amp; Noble College Marketing (BNCM) helps brands thrive on campus. It is a division of Barnes &amp; Noble College Booksellers, LLC., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Barnes &amp; Noble, Inc. that operates more than 640 college bookstores across the country, serving more than 4.7 million students and faculty members. BNCM has the on-campus access and student understanding to deliver superior marketing programs for its brand partners. BNCM&#8217;s capabilities include: experiential and event marketing; product sampling, sweepstakes and promotions; digital marketing (social, email, web); on-campus advertising and postering; and programs targeting freshmen, graduates, alumni and athletic event fans. Visit www.bncollegemarketing.com. Hiscox specializes in tailored insurance coverage for a range of professional services firms in industries like IT, marketing, consulting and more. Hiscox Insurance Company Inc. has been protecting clients for over 100 years and is rated &#8216;A&#8217; (Excellent) for financial strength by A.M. Best. We offer professional liability insurance, general liability insurance and other policies direct, either online or over the phone, with customized coverage starting from just $22.50/month. Visit hiscoxusa.com/smallbiz for a fast, free quote now. Webtrends powers digital marketing success. Webtrends is at the forefront of real-time digital marketing relevance and customer experience management through unified customer intelligence. Our industry-leading analytics across mobile, social and web enables marketers to optimize campaigns, maximize customer lifetime value and deliver highly relevant digital brand experiences in real-time. Webtrends dramatically improve digital marketing results for more than 3,500 global brands including, in EMEA and internationally, Lloyds Banking Group, Barclays, HSBC, ASOS, Orange, T-Mobile, Microsoft, BMW, Toyota, Play.com, AllSaints, The Telegraph, and many more. www.webtrends.com Definition 6 is a Unified Marketing Agency that creates brand experiences that unite brands and people in motion. Through imagination, innovation and insight, we execute ideas that deliver continued value across all brand interactions. For more information, please visit http://www.definition6.com. The Adobe Digital Marketing Suite is an integrated set of applications which allow businesses to gather customer insight and optimize advertising, conversion and retention efforts as well as the creation and distribution of content. For example, using the Suite, marketers can identify the most effective marketing strategies and ad placements as well as create relevant, personalized and consistent customer experiences across digital marketing channels, such as onsite, display, e-mail, social, video and mobile. The Suite enables marketers to automatically adjust to customer interactions and better maximize marketing ROI, which leads to a positive impact the bottom line. http://www.adobe.com/solutions/digital-marketing.html The leading resource for human resource and business leaders to explore and discuss the latest workforce and workplace trends including social innovation&#8212;providing the in-depth research and insights needed to adapt and take advantage of what&#8217;s next. www.shrm.org More About: Cincy Gallop, mashable connectFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/cindy-gallop-marketing-connect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/cindy-gallop-marketing-connect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Marketing Is Broken and How to Fix It</title>
      <description>The marketing world needs to stop being so afraid and start solving problems, according to Cindy Gallop, an entrepreneur and consultant whose prescription for growth calls for emphasizing creativity over data collection. Gallop, who spoke at Mashable Connect Saturday morning, critiqued the current state of marketing, which she believes is driven by fear. &#8220;Fear is the single worst dynamic in business,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Decisions made out of fear are always very bad decisions.&#8221; Such trepidation, predicated by the economy, has caused marketers to become much more cautious, hence the emphasis on data collection in lieu of risk-taking. In Gallop&#8217;s view, though, this array of data has caused paralysis. Lacking any single standard for tracking data, marketers are merely analyzing. To get over that, Gallop recommends a DIY approach: &#8220;You should decide what you are and what you want to measure,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Design your own metric system.&#8221; A self-styled system should also be more transparent about its data collection. In an age of transparency, Gallop says marketers should approach their relationship with clients on social media the same way they&#8217;d do it in real life. &#8220;When you meet someone you like, you want to know about them, so you ask them and you tell them things about yourself,&#8221; she says. &#8220;You reach a point where essentially on both sides you&#8217;re saying, &#8216;I want you to know me.&#8217; That&#8217;s the relationship you want to reach with consumers.&#8221; Yet Gallop thinks transparency alone isn&#8217;t enough, noting that advertisers are now judged by actions, not claims. As an example of this new type of &#8220;action branding,&#8221; she cited Levi&#8217;s decision to raise $2 million for the down-on-its-luck town of Braddock, Pa., in 2010 and feature it and its young mayor in an ad campaign. It&#8217;s unclear how effective such solutions are in the real world. Though there were doubtlessly other factors at play, the ad campaign seems to have helped Levi&#8217;s sales &#8212; the company&#8217;s 2011 revenues rose 8%. However, a similar program from Pepsi appears to have had a disastrous effect on sales and that brand recently abandoned the approach. MashableConnect-Friday-616px006 Click here to view this gallery. Mashable Connect Sponsors Buddy Media is the social enterprise software of choice for eight of the world&#8217;s top ten global advertisers, empowering them to build and maintain relationships with their consumers in a connections-based world. The Buddy Media social marketing suite helps brands build powerful connections globally with its scalable, secure architecture and data-driven customer insights from initial point of contact through point of purchase. For more information, visit http://www.buddymedia.com. AT&amp;T is bringing it all together for our customers, from revolutionary smartphones to next-generation TV services and sophisticated solutions for multi-national businesses. For more than a century, we have consistently provided innovative, reliable, high-quality products and services and excellent customer care. For more, visit http://www.att.com. Barnes &amp; Noble College Marketing (BNCM) helps brands thrive on campus. It is a division of Barnes &amp; Noble College Booksellers, LLC., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Barnes &amp; Noble, Inc. that operates more than 640 college bookstores across the country, serving more than 4.7 million students and faculty members. BNCM has the on-campus access and student understanding to deliver superior marketing programs for its brand partners. BNCM&#8217;s capabilities include: experiential and event marketing; product sampling, sweepstakes and promotions; digital marketing (social, email, web); on-campus advertising and postering; and programs targeting freshmen, graduates, alumni and athletic event fans. Visit www.bncollegemarketing.com. Hiscox specializes in tailored insurance coverage for a range of professional services firms in industries like IT, marketing, consulting and more. Hiscox Insurance Company Inc. has been protecting clients for over 100 years and is rated &#8216;A&#8217; (Excellent) for financial strength by A.M. Best. We offer professional liability insurance, general liability insurance and other policies direct, either online or over the phone, with customized coverage starting from just $22.50/month. Visit hiscoxusa.com/smallbiz for a fast, free quote now. Webtrends powers digital marketing success. Webtrends is at the forefront of real-time digital marketing relevance and customer experience management through unified customer intelligence. Our industry-leading analytics across mobile, social and web enables marketers to optimize campaigns, maximize customer lifetime value and deliver highly relevant digital brand experiences in real-time. Webtrends dramatically improve digital marketing results for more than 3,500 global brands including, in EMEA and internationally, Lloyds Banking Group, Barclays, HSBC, ASOS, Orange, T-Mobile, Microsoft, BMW, Toyota, Play.com, AllSaints, The Telegraph, and many more. www.webtrends.com Definition 6 is a Unified Marketing Agency that creates brand experiences that unite brands and people in motion. Through imagination, innovation and insight, we execute ideas that deliver continued value across all brand interactions. For more information, please visit http://www.definition6.com. The Adobe Digital Marketing Suite is an integrated set of applications which allow businesses to gather customer insight and optimize advertising, conversion and retention efforts as well as the creation and distribution of content. For example, using the Suite, marketers can identify the most effective marketing strategies and ad placements as well as create relevant, personalized and consistent customer experiences across digital marketing channels, such as onsite, display, e-mail, social, video and mobile. The Suite enables marketers to automatically adjust to customer interactions and better maximize marketing ROI, which leads to a positive impact the bottom line. http://www.adobe.com/solutions/digital-marketing.html The leading resource for human resource and business leaders to explore and discuss the latest workforce and workplace trends including social innovation&#8212;providing the in-depth research and insights needed to adapt and take advantage of what&#8217;s next. www.shrm.org More About: Cincy Gallop, mashable connectFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/cindy-gallop-marketing-connect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/cindy-gallop-marketing-connect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP MCA - YouTube</title>
      <description>scottm: 2nded: RT @Broughton500: i'm not a fan of Coldplay (quite the opposite) but this is a beautiful tribute to Adam Yauch http://t.co/ckkFNRBG</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/scottm/statuses/198728348560654336</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/scottm/statuses/198728348560654336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychographics. What Type Are You?</title>
      <description>We can take clues from whether you ask to be shown the features, or the patterns, or the logical relationships, or how things can be sorted. These are visual clues. Or we can listen hearing clues, you may want to be told how things match your experiences, or what&#8217;s harmonious about it, or how things can be contrasted against something else, or how it relates to the people and things you prefer.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/adfilmtv/501859/psychographics</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/adfilmtv/501859/psychographics</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
