<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avenger controller company pisses off gaming community with bad customer support</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3395411"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://penny-arcade.com/2011/12/26/just-wow1</link>
      <guid>http://penny-arcade.com/2011/12/26/just-wow1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man sued over Twitter followers</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; A man is being sued by his former employer after he left the company and took a 17,000-strong Twitter following with him.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-16338040</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-16338040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eight Ways To Go Viral</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/swine-flu-virus.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="swine flu virus" title="swine flu virus" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor&amp;#8217;s note&lt;/strong&gt;: This guest post is written by Uzi Shmilovici, CEO and founder of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.futuresimple.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Future Simple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, the company behind &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.futuresimple.com/base"&gt;Base&lt;/a&gt;&#8212;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;a simple CRM for small businesses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What do Facebook, LinkedIn, Youtube, Dropbox and Skype have in common? Except for being ridiculously successful, they all enjoyed a strong viral effect that helped accelerate their growth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;How did they do that? Here&amp;#8217;s the thing; most people assume that these companies grew by pure word of mouth. Well, that&amp;#8217;s only half of the story. The other half is that they deliberately built viral features into their products that helped spread the word.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Eight Types of Virality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many entrepreneurs struggle with the question: &amp;#8220;How can I make my product more viral?&amp;#8221; After looking at many successful web startups, I boiled down virality to eight different tactics, or types, that are the most common. Grab a pen:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inherent virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The type of virality you&amp;#8217;ll die for. Simply put, a person gets no value from the&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;product unless other people use it as well. As a result, she shares the product with other people. Sharing is done via sharing mechanisms (e.g: invite your Gmail contacts) or through pure word of mouth.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Seeding, which means getting the first people on board is very hard because of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metcalfe's_law"&gt;Metcalf&amp;#8217;s Law&lt;/a&gt; (there&amp;#8217;s very low value for the first users of the product). However, the growth after the seeding period, usually through word of mouth, can be explosive. This is how Skype came to be what it is.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this type of virality, a person will benefit from using the product individually. However, she can get additional value from collaborating with other people, so she invites them to use the product. A classic example is folder sharing on Dropbox. This works very well if the value from collaborating is high.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this case the product is used to communicate with other people, some of which might be potential users. By &amp;#8220;riding&amp;#8221; this communication channel (usually email), the product is being spread. If you ever got an email sent with Constant Contact, you probably remember seeing their logo at the bottom. A more pervasive example is the &amp;#8220;Sent from my iPhone/iPad&amp;#8221; signature at the bottom of every email you send from your iPhone or iPad. Yes, even Apple is using viral tactics (actually, I believe BlackBerry started that with &#8220;Sent using BlackBerry&#8221;).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incentivized virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Offering an incentive to spread the word is a well-known tactic dating back to offline marketing. The incentive will usually be cash or a benefit in return of inviting other people to use the product. For instance, Gilt Group will give you a $25 credit for each person you refer. Dropbox will give extra space to both you and your invitee&#8217;s Dropbox accounts, which &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/How-effective-is-Dropboxs-referral-program-at-bringing-in-*paying*-users-i-e-how-many-subscribers-do-they-have#http://www.quora.com/How-effective-is-Dropboxs-referral-program-at-bringing-in-*paying*-users-i-e-how-many-s"&gt;turned out to work very well&lt;/a&gt;. Personally, I&amp;#8217;m not a big fan of the cash incentive approach as it is not very scalable but if you can make it work economically, it might be very effective.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embeddable virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This method works superbly well for content websites. The ability to take a piece of content and embed it anywhere on the web, with a link back to the original website. This will put your product in front of countless users. There&amp;#8217;s an interesting multiplier that occurs when new people who are exposed to the content embed it on their own website, promoting it even further. This approach has worked tremendously well for Youtube and Slideshare.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signature virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Users that are using your product, either embed one of the features in their own website or refer people to a hosted page to use a specific feature. In both cases, when this feature is displayed to other people, it also includes a &amp;#8220;powered by&amp;#8221; signature at the bottom, which then becomes a lead generation machine. Survey products are well known for the &amp;#8220;hosted survey&amp;#8221; approach (SurveyMonkey probably started it). This has also worked well for helpdesk companies such as Uservoice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this case, companies leverage existing social networks to spread the word about their product. Typically, you sign up for the product with a social network id (say your Facebook id) and then through using the product, you broadcast to your social graph the fact that you are using it. Zynga exploded on Facebook because every time you fed your goat, all your friends knew about it. Spotify&#8217;s killer integration with Facebook is another great example of that. There&amp;#8217;s much more depth to explore on the specific mechanics of using this tactic, but if you get it right, you&#8217;ll experience tremendous growth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can also add Twitter and Facebook accounts on top of an existing signup and broadcast to both whenever the user performs an action. Instagram does exactly that to get more exposure for the app and it seems to work well for them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also, I have no idea what are the results of the &lt;a href="http://cutcopy.heroku.com"&gt;CutCopy album page&lt;/a&gt; but I found their use of this tactic to be super interesting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pure word of mouth virality &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pure word of mouth happens when people are spreading the word about the product just because they enjoyed it, it&#8217;s free, or they think it&#8217;s cool. While this is very hard to quantify, there are two things you can do to support that kind of virality. First, build an awesome product that people really love (Evernote). Second, make it special and give people something to talk about. That&amp;#8217;s where branding comes into play. I don&amp;#8217;t have their numbers but I can guess that a significant part of Mailchimp&amp;#8217;s growth is from people talking about their &lt;a href="http://mailchimp.com/404/"&gt;funny quirkiness&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measuring Virality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you are like me, then you cannot imagine doing anything without measuring it, or as &lt;a href="http://youtu.be/G-c8gGZJ-28?t=53m10s"&gt;Mark Pincus says&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;#8220;You might as well not change it at all if you&amp;#8217;re not going to measure the impact of that change.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Measuring virality is very interesting. Many people are focused on the &amp;#8220;Virality Coefficient&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; how many new users on average does one user of your product &amp;#8220;infect.&amp;#8221; The holy grail is to reach a virality coefficient greater than 1. This usually results in exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The virality coefficient is super important, but there&amp;#8217;s one other critical number that you should pay attention to&#8212;the cycle time. The cycle time is the average time it takes from the moment that one of your users performs a viral action to the moment that a new user signs up because of this very action. It makes a huge difference if your cycle time is one day or 60 days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/viral-formula.png" rel="lightbox[474342]"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;David Skok of Matrix Ventures &lt;a href="http://www.forentrepreneurs.com/the-science-behind-viral-marketing/"&gt;gave a presentation&lt;/a&gt; about that recently, and actually devised a formula to calculate the amount of users you will get after a period of time based on the Virality Coefficient (K) and the Cycle Time (ct).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Having virality expressed in this way is beneficial as it boils down virality to the optimization of two variables: maximize K and minimize ct.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s really quite simple. Pass it on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Top image credit: &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ringai/3975402556/"&gt;hitthatswitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/474342/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/26/eight-ways-go-viral/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/26/eight-ways-go-viral/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Twitter Changes and How to Make the Most of Them</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/tools/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="social media tools" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/tools-pose.png" alt="social media tools" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Are you wondering how Twitter&amp;#8217;s changes will impact your use of its network?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Recently, Twitter got a &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/social-media-platforms-get-facelifts-this-week-in-social-media/" target="_blank"&gt;complete revamp&lt;/a&gt; that changed things drastically. Interestingly, it didn&amp;#8217;t pump the social network with more and more features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ryan Sarver, Twitter&amp;#8217;s head of API, explained it crisply: &amp;#8220;In a world where Facebook and Google are competing on features, &lt;strong&gt;Twitter wants to focus on being simple&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This article will &lt;strong&gt;review all the changes, from user interface changes to Twitter brand pages, what the new changes mean and how you can best use them&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#1: Easier and More Streamlined Navigation&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first thing you&amp;#8217;ll notice with the new Twitter is that navigating has become a lot easier and more streamlined. With just one click on any update, you can now &lt;strong&gt;get all the information you need from a tweet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It will show you the number of retweets, replies and favorites, without going anywhere else.&lt;span id="more-13143"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This means you can jump into the conversation right from there. It also gives you a great overview of how well that particular tweet has performed. While some &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/top-5-twitter-tools-for-social-media-community-managers/" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter tools&lt;/a&gt; offer this already, it is very helpful to have it right inside Twitter.com.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 492px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-1.png" alt="twitter changes" width="482" height="266" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;You can see all the information you need right here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another feature that might just have become very useful is the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Who to follow&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; box on the left. This is a fantastic new way to&lt;strong&gt; discover people &lt;em&gt;close to your network&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; whom you might not know about. You can click the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; on any person who is not suitable, and browse endlessly through this tool to find people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The little note below each of the suggested people tells you who from your network is already connected to that person. This makes expanding your Twitter tribe much more focused. I like this, as you aren&amp;#8217;t stabbing in the dark when connecting with new people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 307px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-2.png" alt="twitter changes" width="297" height="219" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;See who&amp;#39;s following these people before deciding to follow them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;immensely impressed &lt;/em&gt;with the new &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Discover&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; area in the new Twitter. It surfaces content much more intelligently now and becomes a very powerful place to find new articles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With one glance, you can&lt;strong&gt; browse through the hottest stories on the web and get updated on everything&lt;/strong&gt;, without having to search endlessly through past tweets. This area also has a complete &amp;#8220;Who to Follow&amp;#8221; stream ready for you that you can explore:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 493px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-3.png" alt="twitter changes" width="483" height="432" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;It&amp;#39;s now easy to discover the hottest stories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;How to Make the Most of the New Twitter.com in 10 Minutes a Day&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;These new design improvements mean that if you are super-busy handling all of your business activities, the new Twitter allows you to &lt;strong&gt;expand your network in a very short and focused stretch of time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips on what you can do:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Browse your new and improved stream for great tweets and conversations. Click &amp;#8220;open&amp;#8221; on any tweet to get the full context more easily.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Spend 5 minutes browsing the &amp;#8220;Who to Follow&amp;#8221; stream and expand your network easily and in a focused way.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Hop over to the new &amp;#8220;Discover&amp;#8221; area to find all of the latest stories from your network in one glance.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: The new &lt;a href="http://bufferapp.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt; browser extension has been updated to work inside the new Twitter. Click &amp;#8220;Buffer&amp;#8221; on any tweet next to &amp;#8220;Retweet&amp;#8221; and easily schedule your retweets to be posted at an optimum time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#2 and #3: Twitter Brand Pages and Embeddable Tweets&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Evidently, one of the biggest changes coming for businesses is &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/08/new-twitter-brand-pages/" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter brand pages&lt;/a&gt; alongside the new &lt;a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/29822/7-Epic-Uses-of-Twitter-s-New-Embeddable-Tweets-Feature.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;embeddable tweets&lt;/a&gt; function. While &lt;em&gt;only 21 brands were given access&lt;/em&gt; to creating their page, it is said to soon roll out to everyone else.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What is most notable about brand pages is that they allow you to &lt;strong&gt;pin the top tweet&lt;/strong&gt;, so it is not cluttered with replies. This means you can find one of your top-value tweets and have it ready whenever a new visitor arrives.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Secondly, you are also able to &lt;strong&gt;customize a banner slot right beneath your account information&lt;/strong&gt;. You can fill it with a promotion or special deal for your followers. Here is an example from Best Buy&amp;#8217;s brand page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 495px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BestBuy"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-4.png" alt="twitter changes" width="485" height="267" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Check out Best Buy&amp;#39;s Twitter Brand Page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the new embeddable tweets function, Twitter has also given a major &lt;em&gt;incentive to bloggers and publishers to come back&lt;/em&gt; to Twitter.com. To get to the embed function, just&lt;strong&gt; click &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Details&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; after you have expanded the tweet once. Then simply click the &amp;#8220;embed&amp;#8221; link&lt;/strong&gt; to get all of the options to include the tweet in your next blog post:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 491px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-5.png" alt="twitter changes" width="481" height="249" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Notice the &amp;quot;Embed this Tweet&amp;quot; link at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;The great thing is that you can&lt;strong&gt; customize the styling of the embedded tweet&lt;/strong&gt; right from there. This means you can control the position and text wrapping on the page. Once you are happy with your changes, just &lt;strong&gt;copy and paste the code into the HTML of your next blog post&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-6.png" alt="twitter changes" width="480" height="376" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;You can customize the Embeddable Tweets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how this looks (&lt;em&gt;note: what you see below is active, NOT a screen shot&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet tw-align-center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top 10 Facebook Apps for Fan Engagement and Building Community &lt;a title="http://bit.ly/sy33DR" href="http://t.co/5BagzFBY"&gt;bit.ly/sy33DR&lt;/a&gt; via @&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/smexaminer"&gt;smexaminer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8212; Cindy King (@CindyKing) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CindyKing/status/146825217233264641" data-datetime="2011- 12-14T05:33:54+00:00"&gt;December 14, 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Four Quick Tips to Make the Most of Embeddable Tweets&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Personally, I believe this feature can be an extremely powerful &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/4-blogger-tools-for-breaking-your-writing-block/" target="_blank"&gt;blogging tool&lt;/a&gt; for anyone using Twitter. The fact that it &lt;strong&gt;places a Follow button on the embedded tweet&lt;/strong&gt; alone is very attractive for giving any Twitter account a lot more exposure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re writing about an event, try finding relevant tweets to embed so you can &lt;strong&gt;give your article a more lively appearance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add credibility to your articles by embedding tweets from experts talking about the topic&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply search Twitter for some keywords to find relevant tweets.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;If you are reviewing a product or service, place a few tweets from across the Twitterverse at the bottom of your post to &lt;strong&gt;show more varied opinions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus tip: &lt;/strong&gt;Whichever tweet you embed,&lt;strong&gt; let the person who tweeted it know&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are providing them with additional exposure. They might just help you spread your content even more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#4: The New, Much Faster TweetDeck&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another equally significant announcement from Twitter is that &lt;em&gt;the new TweetDeck has been unveiled&lt;/em&gt;. As a heavy TweetDeck user myself, there is one most important improvement I see right away: &lt;em&gt;TweetDeck is no longer an Adobe Air app&lt;/em&gt;, which means it is less sluggish to use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since TweetDeck&amp;#8217;s acquisition by Twitter, it is evident that a lot of effort has been put into making the dashboard simpler and imitating the Twitter.com experience more closely. You&amp;#8217;ll realize this quickly as there is no bar at the top to add your tweets, but only a box similar to Twitter.com.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 493px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-7.png" alt="twitter changes" width="483" height="226" /&gt;The improved TweetDeck is easy to use.&lt;/dt&gt; &lt;/dl&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, my feeling is that these changes have &lt;em&gt;taken away some of TweetDeck&amp;#8217;s previous flexibility &lt;/em&gt;and functionality. Clearly, the new TweetDeck is geared toward more mainstream usage and less focused on providing the go-to dashboard for power users.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="mceTemp"&gt; &lt;dl id="" class="wp-caption " style="width: 493px;"&gt; &lt;dt class="wp-caption-dt"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-8.png" alt="twitter changes" width="483" height="348" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The new TweetDeck dashboard is geared for mainstream users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#5: The New iPhone and Android Apps for Twitter&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter&amp;#8217;s new mobile clients for Android and iPhone I would like to call huge successes. The experience, much like the new Twitter.com, has been greatly improved and streamlined for you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;access your #discover area&lt;/strong&gt; with top stories in the exact way as on Twitter.com. Also the&lt;em&gt; @mentions and news stream have received a major design update&lt;/em&gt;. They are much easier to browse and interact with. Especially whenever there are unread updates in one of your streams, it displays a little line beneath the icon like you see below:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 493px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-9.PNG" alt="twitter changes" width="483" height="720" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The improved mobile Twitter news stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 493px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-10.PNG" alt="twitter changes" width="483" height="720" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the improved mobile Twitter @mentions stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I also greatly enjoy is that on the home tab, you now have a notification counter of how many direct messages are in your inbox. At the same time, it&amp;#8217;s very easy to &lt;strong&gt;access your Twitter lists right from there with just one tap&lt;/strong&gt;. It makes focused reading of news a lot easier for you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 493px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1201lw-twitter-changes-11.PNG" alt="twitter changes" width="483" height="730" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to see the number of unread Direct Messages waiting for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Tips to Make the Most of the New Twitter Mobile Clients&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are quite&lt;strong&gt; a few hidden tricks and features on your new Twitter mobile clients that might just make your life a lot easier&lt;/strong&gt;. Here is a list of the top three things I found:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Whenever you&amp;#8217;re writing a tweet and you don&amp;#8217;t want to send it just now,&lt;strong&gt; hit &amp;#8220;Cancel&amp;#8221; and then &amp;#8220;Save as Draft.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; This is a great way to space out your tweets and avoid flooding your followers.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;You can easily &lt;strong&gt;connect multiple Twitter accounts from the home tab and switch between them conveniently&lt;/strong&gt;. Just click on &amp;#8220;change accounts&amp;#8221; and swap over to your business or other Twitter account.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;For better monitoring, &lt;strong&gt;save some Twitter searches&lt;/strong&gt;, as you can now easily &lt;strong&gt;access them right from the home tab too&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a great way to stay up to date with your most important keywords about your business.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h3&gt;How do you like the new Twitter?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Overall, I believe Twitter has done a fabulous job with their updates on the new Twitter. The one point I feel might need some improvement is the new TweetDeck. But I understand that this particular revamp happened more likely because of Twitter&amp;#8217;s overall &amp;#8220;focus on simple&amp;#8221; strategy than anything else.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What is worth noting is that &lt;strong&gt;Twitter is making a huge bet on bringing users from various clients back to Twitter.com&lt;/strong&gt;. Looking at the changes above, I have to say that for me this has definitely been true. I find myself browsing Twitter.com far more often. The brand pages especially can be a big reason for business owners to engage more on Twitter.com itself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Over to you now. &lt;strong&gt;What do you think?&lt;/strong&gt; So much has happened to Twitter recently. How do you like it? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Leave your questions and comments in the box below. &lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2F5-twitter-changes-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-them%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-twitter-changes-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-them/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="5 Twitter Changes and How to Make the Most of Them &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-twitter-changes-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-them/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-twitter-changes-and-how-to-make-the-most-of-them/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows Phone Marketplace Passes 50,000 Apps</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;script language="JavaScript" type="text/javascript" src="http://admin.brightcove.com/js/BrightcoveExperiences.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;object id="myExperience$BCpost" class="BrightcoveExperience"&gt;&lt;param name='wmode' value='opaque'&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /&gt;&lt;param name="width" value="608" /&gt;&lt;param name="height" value="342" /&gt;&lt;param name="playerID" value="1265504713001" /&gt;&lt;param name="publisherID" value="1130468786001"/&gt;&lt;param name="isVid" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="linkBaseURL" value="http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/" /&gt;&lt;param name="isUI" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="@videoPlayer" value="1349399989001" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It seems like only yesterday that the Windows Phone Marketplace hit 40,000 apps &amp;#8212; actually, it was &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/windows-phone-apps/"&gt;Nov. 17&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; and now Microsoft&amp;#8217;s mobile app store has just passed 50,000, according to &lt;a href="http://allaboutwindowsphone.com/news/item/13913_Windows_Phone_Marketplace_pass.php" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;All About Windows Phone&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Microsoft currently gives an official count of &amp;#8220;more than 35,000&amp;#8243; apps in the &lt;a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-US/marketplace?wa=wsignin1.0" target="_blank"&gt;Windows Phone Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;, a company spokesperson told &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt;. In the past, Microsoft has said that it doesn&amp;#8217;t count extremely simple apps such as wallpapers or multiple versions (i.e. a paid game that also provides a &amp;#8220;lite&amp;#8221; version) as individual apps, which may explain the large discrepancy between the official number and the estimate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In either case, it&amp;#8217;s a fraction of the number of apps in Apple&amp;#8217;s App Store or the Android Market (about &lt;a href="http://www.bgr.com/2011/10/21/android-market-surpasses-500000-published-apps/" target="_blank"&gt;600,000 and 500,000 apps&lt;/a&gt;, respectively). However, even though the number isn&amp;#8217;t large by app-store standards, the Windows Phone Marketplace is growing rapidly. The platform hit 50,000 apps sooner than all platforms except iOS, in just 14 months, the report notes. It took Android 19 months to reach that mark.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;#8217;s app store passed the milestone sooner than the site predicted, and it&amp;#8217;s seen a strong uptick in the number of apps submitted and approved in the past few weeks. The number of apps is growing at a rate of 265 items per day (see the graph below).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/&amp;title=Windows Phone Marketplace Passes 50,000 Apps&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/windows-phone-uptick.jpg" alt="windows phone uptick" title="windows phone uptick" width="620" height="400" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-857059" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;All About Windows Phone&lt;/i&gt; chalks up the platform&amp;#8217;s growth spurt to the increased availability of Windows Phones (the number of countries recently went up from 16 to 35) and the highly anticipated release of Nokia&amp;#8217;s Windows Phones, such as the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/lumia-710-t-mobile-us/"&gt;Lumina 710&lt;/a&gt; in the U.S. However, those events had been anticipated for a while, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t fully explain the sudden interest from developers, which isn&amp;#8217;t directly related to the spread of the platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s possible the release of the developer preview of Windows 8 may have been a factor. Since both Windows Phone and Windows 8 share the Metro user interface, more than a few Windows 8 developers who had never created apps in Metro may have been persuaded to give Windows Phone a try.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Even though the Windows Phone Marketplace is taking off, Microsoft faces many challenges before its mobile platform will seriously challenge Apple&amp;#8217;s or Google&amp;#8217;s. Charlie Kindel, the former general manager of Windows Phone&amp;#8217;s developer experience, &lt;a href="http://ceklog.kindel.com/2011/12/26/windows-phone-is-superior-why-hasnt-it-taken-off/" target="_blank"&gt;theorizes that Microsoft doesn&amp;#8217;t curry favor&lt;/a&gt; among carriers and manufacturers the same way Apple and Android have, and the whole platform suffers, even though, as Kindel says, it provides a superior experience in many ways.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At least developers seem to be finally warming up to the platform. Are you a Windows Phone developer or customer? Why do you favor it? And if you&amp;#8217;re not a fan, why not? Let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[via &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-marketplace-hits-50000-published-apps/" target="_blank"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;] &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/apps/"&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/developers/"&gt;developers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/metro/"&gt;Metro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/windows-phone/"&gt;windows phone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SbDIV1ptsAv1wsjVl8qE94jzxmA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SbDIV1ptsAv1wsjVl8qE94jzxmA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SbDIV1ptsAv1wsjVl8qE94jzxmA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SbDIV1ptsAv1wsjVl8qE94jzxmA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=Nc7sXbr53Ko:BGCKmo5Err4:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/tech/~4/Nc7sXbr53Ko" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/27/windows-phone-hits-50000-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Leaked Details of How Facebook Plans To Sell Your Timeline to Advertisers</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id="attachment_25022" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-25022 " style="margin: 5px 10px;" title="fbslide" src="http://www.betabeat.com/files/2011/12/fbslide.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="453" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Screengrab from an October 2011 presentation "Facebook Updates"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post from a former CTO who now does tech consulting for other start-up ventures and was briefed on Facebook's advertising strategy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you logged onto Facebook yesterday, perhaps you caught a link at the top of the News Feed that read: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/about/ads/?megaphone=1#click"&gt;"About Ads: Ever wonder how Facebook makes money? Get the details."&lt;/a&gt; The answers provided some context on the news that &lt;a href="http://blogs.cio.com/facebook/16712/facebook-ads-hit-news-feeds-2012"&gt;starting in January&lt;/a&gt;, Facebook will start integrating a type of ad, called "sponsored stories," that display your friends faces next to content they have "liked" in larger-sized ads your News Feed mix. "Facebook makes its money from showing you ads," the company told consumers yesterday and with the &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203893404577100433735615126.html"&gt;ramp up to its spring 2012 IPO&lt;/a&gt;, the social network is getting serious about that endeavor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In what seemed like an unrelated move, in September, Facebook announced a brand new type of profile called Timeline, where your whole personal history is laid out by month-by-month, all the way back to your birth. At the time, Facebook &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/about/timeline"&gt;described it&lt;/a&gt; to consumers as a chance to: "Share and highlight your most memorable posts, photos and life events on your timeline. This is where you can tell your story from beginning, to middle, to now." By the end of this year all 800 million plus Facebook profiles will have been converted to this new interface.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What most users don't know is that the new features being introduced are all centered around increasing the value of Facebook to advertisers, to the point where Facebook representatives have been selling the idea that Timeline is actually about re-conceptualizing users around their consumer preferences, or as they put it, "brands are now an essential part of people's identities."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The name itself is cleverly designed to conceal the fact that your profile no longer arranges information chronologically. Yes, things are laid out by year and by month.&lt;strong&gt; But, when it comes to what's displayed to your social circle at any given time, other metrics, including &lt;em&gt;direct&lt;/em&gt; payments to Facebook itself, will now influence the ranking and placement of stories.&lt;/strong&gt; This payola will be a crucial part of the &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/563/"&gt;graph rank&lt;/a&gt;, the new metric for placement that the social network uses to determine what appears on your profile.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Graph Rank" is a complex and non-published algorithm, but we know direct payments to Facebook and app/user popularity are important parts of the ranking. The newest thing is no longer on top. &lt;strong&gt;There is a rough month-by-month sort, but within the month it's graph rank, not chronological order, that determines placement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For advertisers and social app developers, capturing user tastes (which used to be good enough) is now secondary to knowing what users are doing right now. Your reading habits, music tastes, guilty TV pleasures, holiday gift purchases and so forth are part of stream of information from which Facebook wrings profits and a new advertising channel in and of themselves.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Disguising ads as your friends' updates is being offered up as an antidote to the dismal click-through rates for traditional web advertising. Sponsored stories in your feed and sidebar ads based on your friends' likes will become ubiquitous. &lt;strong&gt;Indeed in marketing materials, Facebook says these new premium ads are 90 percent accurate, compared to the industry average of 35 percent. "When people hear about you [the brand] from friends, they listen."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Facebook derives its revenue from advertising--an average of $100 million a month since last January. At this point, many understand that the business model revolves around selling the mountains of personal information people post to Facebook. In the ramp up to its IPO, the company is anxious to show better revenue growth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the post from Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/about/ads/?megaphone=1#click"&gt;yesterday morning&lt;/a&gt; explained, sponsored stories are different from ads in that a user's name or profile might appear alongside the ad, "If you've liked that business's page, the story about you liking the page (including your name or profile photo) may be paired with the ad your friends see." While sponsored stories don't include additional messaging from the sponsor, businesses pay Facebook to feature posts and activity that mention their brands. In both cases, these are only visible "to friends you've already shared this information with."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;How long users will tolerate this is unclear. There's already a &lt;a href="http://www.thedomains.com/2011/12/19/facebook-can-be-sued-for-like-ads-allows-a-class-action-suit-to-move-forward/"&gt;class-action suit &lt;/a&gt;pending in California against Facebook for integrating user's pictures without their permission in advertising based on "Likes." Many Spotify listeners and &lt;em&gt;Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; readers are no doubt regretting listening to that one good song from that otherwise unpardonable band, or clicking on that salaciously titled article, which then appeared on the screens of everyone they know along with their smiling profile picture.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-25080" title="Screen shot 2011-12-23 at 10.26.37 AM" src="http://www.betabeat.com/files/2011/12/Screen-shot-2011-12-23-at-10.26.37-AM-e1324654728184.png" alt="" width="600" height="439" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.betabeat.com/2011/12/23/exclusive-leaked-details-of-how-facebook-plans-to-sell-your-timeline-to-advertisers/</link>
      <guid>http://www.betabeat.com/2011/12/23/exclusive-leaked-details-of-how-facebook-plans-to-sell-your-timeline-to-advertisers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like Louis CK, the comedian. I also like Louis CK, the chap trying to do something different, making his own stuff and &lt;a href="https://buy.louisck.net/"&gt;distributing it straight to the audience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, I especially like his message to people who might want to download his material illegally instead of paying the five dollars:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;To those who might wish to &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; this video: look, I don&amp;#8217;t really get the whole &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; thing. I don&amp;#8217;t know enough about it to judge either way. But I&amp;#8217;d just like you to consider this: I made this video extremely easy to use against well-informed advice. I was told that it would be easier to torrent the way I made it, but I chose to do it this way anyway, because I want it to be easy for people to watch and enjoy this video in any way they want without &amp;#8220;corporate&amp;#8221; restrictions. Please bear in mind that I am not a company or a corporation. I&amp;#8217;m just some guy. I paid for the production and posting of this video with my own money. I would like to be able to post more material to the fans in this way, which makes it cheaper for the buyer and more pleasant for me. So, please help me keep this being a good idea. I can&amp;#8217;t stop you from torrenting; all I can do is politely ask you to pay your five little dollars, enjoy the video, and let other people find it in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you like something, even if you can get it for free, do try and do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://writeforyourlife.net/louis-ck-live-at-the-beacon-theater" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent link to 'Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater'" class="glyph"&gt;Read this post on Write for Your Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WriteForYourLife/~4/xTjySALLr7Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://buy.louisck.net/</link>
      <guid>https://buy.louisck.net/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like Louis CK, the comedian. I also like Louis CK, the chap trying to do something different, making his own stuff and &lt;a href="https://buy.louisck.net/"&gt;distributing it straight to the audience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, I especially like his message to people who might want to download his material illegally instead of paying the five dollars:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;To those who might wish to &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; this video: look, I don&amp;#8217;t really get the whole &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; thing. I don&amp;#8217;t know enough about it to judge either way. But I&amp;#8217;d just like you to consider this: I made this video extremely easy to use against well-informed advice. I was told that it would be easier to torrent the way I made it, but I chose to do it this way anyway, because I want it to be easy for people to watch and enjoy this video in any way they want without &amp;#8220;corporate&amp;#8221; restrictions. Please bear in mind that I am not a company or a corporation. I&amp;#8217;m just some guy. I paid for the production and posting of this video with my own money. I would like to be able to post more material to the fans in this way, which makes it cheaper for the buyer and more pleasant for me. So, please help me keep this being a good idea. I can&amp;#8217;t stop you from torrenting; all I can do is politely ask you to pay your five little dollars, enjoy the video, and let other people find it in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you like something, even if you can get it for free, do try and do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://writeforyourlife.net/louis-ck-live-at-the-beacon-theater" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent link to 'Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater'" class="glyph"&gt;Read this post on Write for Your Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WriteForYourLife/~4/xTjySALLr7Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://buy.louisck.net/</link>
      <guid>https://buy.louisck.net/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Simple (But Hidden!) Tricks All The New iPhone/iPad Owners Should Know http://t.co/RrbdkYmt by @grg</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a1.twimg.com/profile_images/1440079154/-5_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/TechCrunch"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;: 5 Simple (But Hidden!) Tricks All The New iPhone/iPad Owners Should Know &lt;a href="http://t.co/RrbdkYmt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/RrbdkYmt&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/grg" target="_blank"&gt;@grg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/TechCrunch/status/151458850325790720"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/26/ios-tips-and-tricks-iphone-ipad/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/26/ios-tips-and-tricks-iphone-ipad/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Chat Just Got Infinitely Better: Try This New Gimmick Now</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Be honest: has Facebook chat ever been your favorite form of instant messaging? For many of us, Gchat, Skype or even AIM are our preferred defaults. Now, a new gimmick is making us like Facebook&amp;#8217;s built-in chat function a whole lot more. As demonstrated in the photo above, you can make the profile pictures of Facebook users and pages show up inside your chat windows. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/&amp;title=Facebook Chat Just Got Infinitely Better: Try This New Gimmick Now&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/facebook-chat-gimick.jpg" alt="" title="facebook chat gimick" width="474" height="518" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-855515" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;1. Start chatting with someone (pretty simple).&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;ul&gt;2. When you&amp;#8217;d like to refer to a mutual friend or, say, Coca Cola, you dump their profile id (either their name or a string of numbers for those users who haven&amp;#8217;t claimed their choice URL) into double brackets. So, that would be [[cocacola]] for a picture of Coke, [[zuck]] for Mark Zuckerberg and [[mashable]] for the logo of where your learned about this new feature, and so on.&lt;/ul&gt; &lt;ul&gt;3. Amaze everyone on Facebook chat with this cool new gimmick. &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/07/hidden-ios-5-feature-emoji/"&gt;Hidden iOS 5 Feature Offers Tons of Beautiful Emoticons [PICS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What do you think, is this the end of the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/20/emoticon-history/"&gt;emoticon era&lt;/a&gt;, or will the Internet forever be dominated by the :-) face? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[via &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.geekosystem.com/how-to-make-rage-faces-facebook-chat/" target="_blank"&gt;Geekosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-chat/"&gt;facebook chat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rJDe5Eegi_Xw6plSUuQ2sCpmwK8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rJDe5Eegi_Xw6plSUuQ2sCpmwK8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rJDe5Eegi_Xw6plSUuQ2sCpmwK8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rJDe5Eegi_Xw6plSUuQ2sCpmwK8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=XQS2RbrtmnA:egpInNTk0Hg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/XQS2RbrtmnA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/26/facebook-chat-gimmick/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
