<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Where does trust come from?</title>
      <description>Hint: it never comes from the good times and from the easy projects. We trust people because they showed up when it wasn't convenient, because they told the truth when it was easier to lie and because they kept a promise when they could have gotten away with breaking it. Every tough time and every pressured project is another opportunity to earn the trust of someone you care about.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/where-does-trust-come-from.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/where-does-trust-come-from.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>62% of Library Users Don&#8217;t Know They Can Check Out E-Books [STUDY]</title>
      <description>As reading habits shift from printed to digital ink, public libraries are struggling to raise awareness of their digital offerings. The introduction of tablets and dedicated e-book readers has changed the way we read. Now, you&#8217;re just as likely to find fellow commuters or waiting-room dwellers reading an e-book as a physical one. While our libraries are busy trying to keep up with the rise of e-books, it turns out their patrons don&#8217;t know there are e-books available for lending. Some 62% of respondents to the Pew Research Center&#8217;s Internet and American Life Project's latest library survey said they didn&#8217;t know if their library offered e-book lending. In reality, three-&#8230; Continue reading... More About: e-books, e-readers, features, libraries, Pew Internet, Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/libraries-are-lending-e-books/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/libraries-are-lending-e-books/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Advanced Twitter Tips for Your Small Business</title>
      <description>So you're running a small business and you've got the basics of social networking mastered: You tweet often, you've created a venue on Foursquare and your Facebook Page is beautiful. How do you move to the next level of social marketing mastery? Devin Desjarlais, social media manager at Max Borges Agency, has five can't-miss tips for upping your Twitter game. 1. Don't Schedule and Split Scheduling tweets with a platform such as HootSuite or Tweetdeck can be a great way to spread out your business' social sharing throughout the day. However, Desjarlais says that it's important to pay attention to any responses your scheduled tweets may elicit -- the follow-up conversation is jus&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Marketing, open forum, Small Business, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/twitter-tips-small-business/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/twitter-tips-small-business/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Close-Up Photos of Texture You Can Almost Feel</title>
      <description>Kyle Dove Click here to view this gallery. Texture represents an object's feel or consistency. You can feel the glossy texture of your computer keys or the slick condensation of a glass of water. But take a look at these 20 photos. You can see texture, too. From the stickiness of an old piece of gum to the fuzziness of a spider's skin, sometimes you can see the texture of an object almost as well as you can feel it. For this week's Mashable Photo Challenge, we wanted to explore the visual side of texture. So we asked our readers to take a close look at the world around them. SEE ALSO: 33 Stunning Weather Photos From Readers Around the World Readers sent in all kinds of close-ups that show texture. We selected 20 of th&#8230; Continue reading... More About: community, Mashable Photo Challenge, photography, Photos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/texture-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/texture-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Close-Up Photos of Texture You Can Almost Feel</title>
      <description>Kyle Dove Click here to view this gallery. Texture represents an object's feel or consistency. You can feel the glossy texture of your computer keys or the slick condensation of a glass of water. But take a look at these 20 photos. You can see texture, too. From the stickiness of an old piece of gum to the fuzziness of a spider's skin, sometimes you can see the texture of an object almost as well as you can feel it. For this week's Mashable Photo Challenge, we wanted to explore the visual side of texture. So we asked our readers to take a close look at the world around them. SEE ALSO: 33 Stunning Weather Photos From Readers Around the World Readers sent in all kinds of close-ups that show texture. We selected 20 of th&#8230; Continue reading... More About: community, Mashable Photo Challenge, photography, Photos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/texture-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/texture-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Pages Allow Targeted Updates: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?LinkedIn Targeted Status Updates Available to All Company Pages: You can now select a target audience for updates shared on your LinkedIn Company Page. You can specify your target audience by company size, industry, job function, seniority, geography and whether they are employees of your company or not. Targeted Status Updates were launched to select LinkedIn customers and are now available to all Company Pages.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iuDgan3s4d4Facebook Introduces Subscriptions Pricing Option for Apps: Facebook app developers can now integrate subscription pricing to offer recurring revenue opportunities. Facebook is also enabling local pricing features to allow businesses to apply different prices based on each market.The new Subscriptions feature "will be available to to all Facebook.com and mobile web apps in July."Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:Which social network do you want to learn more about?What to do you do when someone rips off your blog posts?Do you want more &#8220;Followers&#8221; on Twitter or more &#8220;Likes&#8221; on Facebook?SlideShare Presentations Now Optimized for Pinterest: &#8221;Pinterest optimization for SlideShare presentations provides a fun new way to share and discover the visual web.&#8221; When readers go to pin a SlideShare presentation, the &#8220;slides are captured as larger images with attribution for authors. And when people browse Pinterest and discover SlideShare content, they can immediately engage in embedded content.&#8221; Pinterest Announces More Attribution and Inline Play: Pinterest is partnering with other social networks to provide more attribution.In addition to the SlideShare optimization mentioned above, Pinterest users will find attribution and improved optimization with these sites: Etsy, Kickstarter and SoundCloud.View Verified Twitter Profiles With or Without Replies: You can now visit the profiles of verified Twitter accounts and decide whether you want to see all of their feeds with replies or without any replies. &#8220;Remember that replies on Twitter begin with an @username and are only seen by people who follow both the Tweet author and the @username at the beginning of the Tweet.&#8221;This new Twitter feature allows you to visit a Twitter user's profile and choose whether you want to filter out the replies and only see the content this user shares with everyone.YouTube Automatic Captions Are Now Available in Spanish: YouTube just expanded its language accessibility by adding a Spanish automatic captions feature. And if you want to see YouTube videos in even more languages, you can combine auto-captions with YouTube&#8217;s auto-translate feature to generate subtitles in more than 50 languages."When a video has recognizable speech, you'll see a 'CC' button appear in the bottom of the player, which will instantly add captions of the video in Spanish. Just look for this icon and click 'Transcribe Audio'."HootSuite Extends LinkedIn Company Page Integration to All Users: &#8220;HootSuite extends its LinkedIn integration capabilities, allowing 4 million HootSuite users the ability to maintain and manage LinkedIn Company Pages.&#8221;HootSuite users can monitor, schedule and post to LinkedIn Company Pages.Google+ Opens its API to Flipboard: Google+ recently announced a partnership with Flipboard, the news app. &#8221;The API will soon allow Flipboard users to Google+ comment on and +1 Flipboard items, in addition to sending individualized pieces of content to Google+ Circles.&#8221; Google+ users can expect to see more Google+ integration in the future.Here&#8217;s a couple of useful social media tools worth noting:Fanzy: A free Facebook app that rewards fans for spreading the word about your brand.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3U8SlWomfksInfra Cloud Receptionist: A simple click-to-call application for Facebook pages.The Infra Cloud Receptionist Facebook app helps small businesses bridge the gap between visitors on their Facebook pages and the phone calls they need to build their business.And don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/linkedin-pages-allow-targeted-updates-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/linkedin-pages-allow-targeted-updates-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Apps You Don&#8217;t Want to Miss</title>
      <description>It can be tough to keep up with all the new apps released each week. But you&#8217;re in luck: We take care of a lot of that for you, creating a roundup each weekend of some of our own new and updated app highlights from the week. This week we found an app that will help you get directions to where you're going and get the best gas prices along the way, as well as an app that will help you find a hotel once you reach that destination -- even if you're arriving in the wee hours of the morning. An update to a popular existing app will give you a fun game to play while you're riding in the car, and another significant update will let you document your travels and share them with the world&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, App, apps, iphone, mobile app, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/app-roundup-6-23/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/app-roundup-6-23/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megaupload Founder Kim Dotcom Returns to Twitter, Promotes 'Megabox'</title>
      <description>Kim Dotcom, the quixotic millionaire founder of file-sharing service Megaupload who&#8217;s wanted for extradition to the U.S., returned to Twitter this week to prove to the world he&#8217;s still creating new platforms despite his entanglements with law enforcement. Dotcom also used the new account to announce that &#8220;Megabox,&#8221; a new music discovery and sharing service, is still on its way despite his still being under arrest. He&#8217;s previously said that Megabox, which would compete with similar platforms such as Spotify, would let artists keep almost 90% of the profits made from their music. Dotcom, arrested in New Zealand after file-sharing service Megaupload was brought down on charges of computer piracy in January, has also been using the reactivated Twitter account (@kimdotcom) mostly to post photos and thank supporters during his ongoing extradition hearing. In true Dotcom style, he&#8217;s also been poking fun at his situation, tweeting jokes about the FBI and police. He&#8217;s also met with Apple founder Steve Wozniak, who visited him in New Zealand. Dotcom&#8217;s assets have been frozen and he remains under house arrest in New Zealand while a court weighs the American extradition request. U.S. law enforcement officials have accused Dotcom and his staff of being a part of the &#8220;Mega Conspiracy, a worldwide criminal organization whose members engaged in criminal copyright infringement and money laundering on a massive scale.&#8221; The fate of the data still stored on Megaupload&#8217;s servers is still unknown. The Electronic Frontier Foundation is suing the Federal Bureau of Investigation over the files, which the EFF argues that the site&#8217;s users have a right to access. What should happen to the Megaupload data? Share your opinion in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megaupload Founder Kim Dotcom Returns to Twitter, Promotes 'Megabox'</title>
      <description>Kim Dotcom, the quixotic millionaire founder of file-sharing service Megaupload who&#8217;s wanted for extradition to the U.S., returned to Twitter this week to prove to the world he&#8217;s still creating new platforms despite his entanglements with law enforcement. Dotcom also used the new account to announce that &#8220;Megabox,&#8221; a new music discovery and sharing service, is still on its way despite his still being under arrest. He&#8217;s previously said that Megabox, which would compete with similar platforms such as Spotify, would let artists keep almost 90% of the profits made from their music. Dotcom, arrested in New Zealand after file-sharing service Megaupload was brought down on charges of computer piracy in January, has also been using the reactivated Twitter account (@kimdotcom) mostly to post photos and thank supporters during his ongoing extradition hearing. In true Dotcom style, he&#8217;s also been poking fun at his situation, tweeting jokes about the FBI and police. He&#8217;s also met with Apple founder Steve Wozniak, who visited him in New Zealand. Dotcom&#8217;s assets have been frozen and he remains under house arrest in New Zealand while a court weighs the American extradition request. U.S. law enforcement officials have accused Dotcom and his staff of being a part of the &#8220;Mega Conspiracy, a worldwide criminal organization whose members engaged in criminal copyright infringement and money laundering on a massive scale.&#8221; The fate of the data still stored on Megaupload&#8217;s servers is still unknown. The Electronic Frontier Foundation is suing the Federal Bureau of Investigation over the files, which the EFF argues that the site&#8217;s users have a right to access. What should happen to the Megaupload data? Share your opinion in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pac-Man Comes Alive in Stunning 3D Street Art [PICS]</title>
      <description>A street in Venlo, The Netherlands, recently got a taste of the Pac-Man universe when artist Leon Keer painted pavement with the game's iconic yellow character, maze, ghostly enemies, power pellets and Pac-dots. "The 3D Pac-Man piece I made is to bring alive memories from the past," Keer told Mashable. "A recognizable theme always attracts the eye of the beholder." Keer spent three days creating the Pac-Man artwork. People have spotted his paintings across the world in countries such as the U.S., Germany, France, The United Arabic Emirates and Australia. "Street painting belongs to the street -- after we finish a piece, we say goodbye and it will be public domain," he says. "T&#8230; Continue reading... More About: art, Gaming, nostalgia, pac-man, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/pac-man-3d-street-art/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/pac-man-3d-street-art/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Announces Sharp Price Cuts for Google Maps [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Lots of sites and apps use Google Maps &#8212; paying dearly for those privileges &#8212; but there have been some high-profile defections lately, including Apple and Foursquare. In a reaction to that, Saturday Google announced lower prices for websites and apps that use more than 25,000 downloads of its maps per day over a 90-day period. How low? The new rates are $.50 per 1,000 maps downloaded, according to The New York Times. That&#8217;s a far cry from the previous tariff, which was eight times higher at $4. That means a site with 1 million pageviews per day would no longer have to pay $3,900 per day for the use of Google Maps &#8212; now that price will be reduced to a mere $487.50. There&#8217;s been some tough timing for Google and its ubiquitous Maps lately. The company announced updates to its Google Maps earlier this month (June, 2012), including offline mapping for Android phones, Street View for nature trails and 3D Google Earth maps, all rolling out in the next few weeks. We saw a tour of that 3D feature, and found its flyover effect to be downright mesmerizing. Meanwhile, Apple has abandoned Google Maps for its own in-house mapping it plans to use in its upcoming iOS 6 this fall, and Foursquare jumped ship in favor of collaboratively developed OpenStreeetMaps. Perhaps these new bargain prices will keep Google Maps out of the red ink.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/google-maps-price/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/google-maps-price/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>60 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>More About: Business , COMMUNICATIONS , Features Week In Review , Social Media , Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/digital-media-resources-44/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/digital-media-resources-44/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
