<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Forge Lets You Play Games In Google+ Hangouts [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Tabletop Forge is a Google+ application that allows you to play online board games inside a Google+ Hangout. It allows users to play a variety of dice games and strategy games with players around the world, while using the video chat feature. Users can also create and play on user-generated boards, or load maps and monsters to play within the app. A campaign on Kickstarter to fund the project asks for $5,000. With nearly $40,000 raised so far and 41 hours left on the campaign, we can say it was very well received. With the Kickstarter funds, the team behind Tabletop Forge wants to hire developers to make the code more robust and employ artists to&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Gaming, Google, kickstarter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/tabletop-forge-lets-you-play-games-in-google-hangouts-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/tabletop-forge-lets-you-play-games-in-google-hangouts-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Apps You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss</title>
      <description>It can be tough to keep up with all the new apps released each week. But you&#8217;re in luck: We take care of a lot of that for you, creating a roundup each weekend of some of our own new and updated app highlights from the week. This week we found a few water-based games that require you to come up with a little strategy in order to win, and we found an old favorite game that has finally made its way over to Android. iPhone owners saw an update this week to a popular music app, and got a new photography app that will let you take some pretty unique shots. Another app will help you keep up-to-date on everything going on at the Tour de France, and another will keep you in-the-know w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, App, iphone</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/7-apps-7-7/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/7-apps-7-7/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bay Parties It Up For Social Media Day 2012</title>
      <description>There was a full house at The Box SF for Mashable's third-annual Social Media Day celebration in San Francisco on Saturday, June 30, 2012. The sold-out event featured networking, dancing, gadgets and, most importantly, commemorating the importance of social media in the world today. Mashable staff and fans danced the night away to San Francisco-based DJ Duo A Plus D - a.k.a. Adrian and Mysterious D. A Plus D, creators of Bootie, the biggest mashup bootleg party in the world - kept the party going all night with their amazing mashups including an unforgettable mix of Beethoven with House of Pain. See Mashable's complete coverage of Social Media Day Global sponsor Motorola Mob&#8230; Continue reading... More About: San Francisco-San Jose, social media day</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/the-bay-parties-it-up-for-social-media-day-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/the-bay-parties-it-up-for-social-media-day-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moonwalking Man Thrills Crowd With Moves</title>
      <description>Commenters say this is "the super moonwalk" and "moon running." The fast moving, backwards moonwalker in this clip is Eric Nash, according to his Twitter account. He goes by the handle @Onelovecandyman on Twitter and YouTube. He posted the video on July 5 after doing this move somewhere outside after what appears to be a rain shower. So far the video has more than 630,000 views. Nash's Twitter account says he's based in Santa Monica, Calif. and is a performer in the Los Angeles-based group Street Performers United. The Internet seems to love Michael Jackson's legendary dance move. In 2010, this video of the "Walmart moonwalker" went viral. Shortly after Jackson's death in 200&#8230; Continue reading... More About: YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/moonwalking-man-thrills-crowd-with-moves/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/moonwalking-man-thrills-crowd-with-moves/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Pinterest Pins This Week</title>
      <description>Our top 10 Pinterest pins will brighten up your day with beautiful photos and refreshing ideas. Each week Pinterest brings us an array of wonderful images and tips, and we choose 10 to share with you. One of the things Pinterest is known for is its helpful tips and craft ideas. From a pin that will change the way you set up your home electronics, to a pin that shares a handy eye-brightening Photoshop tip, we hope these pins add to your Pinterest experience. In addition to tips and recipes, there is no shortage of gorgeous imagery in this week&#8217;s top 10 pins. There is a gorgeous shot of Nordic fog from Pinterest power-user Jennifer Chong and a photo of a gamer/movie-lover&#8217;s comfy paradise. All of our top 10 pins are repinned in this Pinterest board for you to easily repin and follow the users we found them from. We collect our weekly top 10 to share with you the pins we enjoyed from the visual network this past week. Everyone&#8217;s Pinterest experience is different and revoles around their own personal interests, but we hope our pins provide a diving-in point to the vast sea of Pinterest. What were your favorite pins this past week?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/top-10-pinterest-pins-4/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/top-10-pinterest-pins-4/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Pinterest Pins This Week</title>
      <description>Our top 10 Pinterest pins will brighten up your day with beautiful photos and refreshing ideas. Each week Pinterest brings us an array of wonderful images and tips, and we choose 10 to share with you. One of the things Pinterest is known for is its helpful tips and craft ideas. From a pin that will change the way you set up your home electronics, to a pin that shares a handy eye-brightening Photoshop tip, we hope these pins add to your Pinterest experience. In addition to tips and recipes, there is no shortage of gorgeous imagery in this week&#8217;s top 10 pins. There is a gorgeous shot of Nordic fog from Pinterest power-user Jennifer Chong and a photo of a gamer/movie-lover&#8217;s comfy paradise. All of our top 10 pins are repinned in this Pinterest board for you to easily repin and follow the users we found them from. We collect our weekly top 10 to share with you the pins we enjoyed from the visual network this past week. Everyone&#8217;s Pinterest experience is different and revoles around their own personal interests, but we hope our pins provide a diving-in point to the vast sea of Pinterest. What were your favorite pins this past week?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/top-10-pinterest-pins-4/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/top-10-pinterest-pins-4/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics Mobile App: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Google Analytics Launches a New Mobile App: Google Analytics has &#8220;a new set of reports in beta called Mobile App Analytics that help marketers and developers better measure their mobile apps.&#8221;These new Mobile App Analytics reports are "tailored for mobile app developers and marketers."YouTube&#8217;s Google+ Integration Makes it Easy to Change Outdated YouTube Usernames: Did you choose a cute username for your YouTube account and now you want to change it? YouTube users can now use their Google+ profile name for their YouTube channels without any impact on their YouTube channel."If you are currently YouTube user joeysam87, you can now appear as Joey Samson, the full name from your Google+ profile (with an actual space in the middle!), along with any photo you uploaded."Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:What&#8217;s your &#8220;Home&#8221; page?How do you set up WordPress blog categories, tags and SEO?Should companies monitor employee social media use?Google+ Platform Extending to Mobile: Google+ announces &#8220;an offering for mobile developers&#8212;the Google+ platform for mobile, in early developer preview.&#8221;Google+ integration gets easier for app developers.Twitter and LinkedIn Break Up: &#8220;LinkedIn and Twitter announced an end to their partnership that allowed users to sync updates from the two sites.&#8221;Here are a useful social media tool and an infographic worth noting:Seesmic Ping: Seesmic&#8217;s new mobile posting tool.Check out this new mobile version of Seesmic to share your updates and stay connected.IBM CEO Study 2012: Here&#8217;s an excerpt of the infographic created with the results of this study.Click to see the rest of this infographic: How will CEOs change their use of social media?And don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-analytics-mobile-app-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-analytics-mobile-app-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Text from Dog,' Other Accounts Imagine What Pets Might Say</title>
      <description>The web is home to many animals who have been personified on various social media accounts. An imaginative Tumblr account called &#8220;Text from Dog&#8221; posts SMS conversations between a dog and his owner. Apparently, if your dog could text, he might ask about bacon or if he can chase the postman. The account&#8217;s funny text conversations have garnered lots of attention from tens of thousands readers who have liked and rebloged the posts. The dog featured in the Tumblr account just goes by dog and desires to be a superhero named &#8220;Batdog.&#8221; Another account called &#8220;Louis vs. Rick&#8221; is about a man who taught his cat to use instant messaging. There are a bevy of online services and apps that help owners monitor their pets, like RemindMyPet, that lets you stay up-to-date with your pet&#8217;s flea medication. We wished our pets could talk when we were kids; perhaps this is the adult version of that hope. Technologists and tinkerers have been using technology to figure out more about our pets and even offer them the joys we have, like social networking. What do you think of these accounts with communicating animals? Tell us in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/text-from-dog-other-accounts-imagine-what-pets-might-say/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/text-from-dog-other-accounts-imagine-what-pets-might-say/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CERN scientists inexplicably present Higgs boson findings in Comic Sans | The Verge</title>
      <description>For many of us, the most shocking revelation to come out of CERN's Higgs boson announcement today was quite unrelated to the science itself. Rather, we were blown away by the fact that a team made up...</description>
      <link>http://mobile.theverge.com/2012/7/4/3136652/cern-scientists-comic-sans-higgs-boson</link>
      <guid>http://mobile.theverge.com/2012/7/4/3136652/cern-scientists-comic-sans-higgs-boson</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://www.zefrank.com/zesblog/archives/2012/07/a_conversation.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.zefrank.com/zesblog/archives/2012/07/a_conversation.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
      <description>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition I don't say this often, butplease share this one. http://tellmetodrawsomething.tumblr.com/ https://twitter.com/#!/JeremiahMc From: weepingprophet Views: 309 14890 ratingsTime: 03:47 More in Film &amp; Animation</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XFGAQrEUaeU&amp;feature=youtube_gdata</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XFGAQrEUaeU&amp;feature=youtube_gdata</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Questions to Ask During Your Next Interview</title>
      <description>Jayne Mattson is Senior Vice President at Keystone Associates, a leading career management and transition services consulting firm in Boston. Mattson specializes in helping mid-to-senior level individuals in new career exploration, networking strategies and career decisions based on corporate culture fit. As you look for a new job, will you take any job offer or are you looking for the right one? What does the right job mean? Too often job seekers do not take enough time to reflect on where they have been in their careers before they actively begin their new job search. And when they receive an offer, they do not have any criteria that help them determine the right fit. To help you identify what the right role would look like, think back on times during your career when you were the most satisfied. What role did you love doing, what type of manager were you working for and what was the culture like during this time? Finding a perfect fit comes down to three main questions that your potential employer must answer: Now you know your criteria for the right role, you need to ask courageous questions in your interview &#8212; not safe ones &#8212; to stand out from your competition. Safe questions include: A response from an interviewer will give you some answers, but will you find out what you really need to know to take the job with confidence? Here are more courageous questions to ask. 1. How receptive are you to feedback from your employees when do you do something they disagree with? If one of your values is being able to speak up (diplomatically, of course) when you disagree with a certain decision or behavior of your manager or peers, then this is for you. This question will help you understand how receptive your manager and others would be to constructive feedback without fear of retribution. 2. As a manager, what frustrates you about the people that work for you? As often as you can during the interview, ask questions where the manager would be able to tell you about a specific situation and provide concrete anecdotes. In this case, you want to know what frustrates him or her, so if you get the job, you will know what behaviors to watch out for in yourself. 3. Is there a project your department is working on now? If so, how are you interacting with your staff on it? You certainly want direction from your new manager, but not one that micro-manages your work. If you ask the safe question, &#8220;Do see yourself as a micro-manager?&#8221; they might answer, &#8220;No, I am not at all.&#8221; However, if you ask the riskier question, you may hear he is involved in the project every step of the way &#8212; a potential red flag for you about his style. 4. Can you give me an example of how you work collaboratively with other departments? Your idea of how people collaborate can be completely different than others, so this question helps you assess if the environment is compatible with the way you work best. 5. Does the company welcome celebrating special occasions in employees&#8217; lives? What was the last occasion your department celebrated? This question is a must if your idea of a fun workplace culture includes celebrating special occasions. Now, if the person mentions, &#8220;We don&#8217;t tend to celebrate,&#8221; you could follow up and get a sense whether they would be receptive to it the future. 6. What would be the three things that your peers would say you do extremely well? This question is often asked about you &#8212; the interviewer is listening carefully to what you will say. In some cases, they might follow up with people you are referring to in your answer to verify what you said. You could ask this question to the manager, potential peer or even HR to get a better idea of how the company operates. Since working in teams is much more prevalent in today&#8217;s businesses, you&#8217;ll want to know more about your colleagues. 7. I understand the company has a formal recognition program; however, what type of recognition have you recently given to one of your staff? If recognition or praise is one of your values, then this is a good question. It not only tells you about the company culture, but also if the manager is generous with recognizing the great work of his team. Nearly everyone wants recognition for the work they do, but in very different ways. Find out whether the methods of the company you&#8217;re considering work for you. 8. Has anyone on your staff been promoted over the last couple of years? If so, what was the reason why this person was promoted? If you are looking for development opportunities, you will want to know what those would look like. You&#8217;ll also want to know if the person was promoted because they pushed the subject or if the manager led the process. 9. What type of work do you delegate to your staff? You want to work for a manager who delegates, so you can develop beyond your role. If a manager is not a good delegator, then he might be insecure about his role and not want you to know what they are doing. This could potentially hold you back from promotions or development. 10. What are the three main factors you will be using to determine the right person for this job? This question is best asked toward the end of the interview, so the interviewer might use some of what you have to offer as some of the factors. You should find out how you fit in with the manager and job criteria, so if you could address the concerns in the post-interview correspondence and next round of interviews. 11. What have been the main characteristics of your favorite employees? When someone is talking about a favorite employee, watch for their body language, tone of voice and their word usage. These factors will help you determine if you have some of their same qualities and if not, it will give you more to think about after the interview. 12. What was the company&#8217;s most strategic decision made in the last year? Could you describe how they came to this decision? You want to work for a company that is planning for the future. By asking this question, it will demonstrate to the interviewer that you are thinking ahead. It will also help you understand what you might need to do to keep yourself current in your field and continue to add value to the company. 13. Can you give me an example of how and why one of your staff made a major mistake, and what was your response to it? You want to be able to take risks, but you also want to know your manager will support you in resolving it &#8212; not reprimand you. Asking this question will give you a sense of the level of risk-taking that would be acceptable. Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/questions-job-interview/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/questions-job-interview/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
