<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RT @neiltyson: The best engineering flow chart ever: http://t.co/Rs7GNh4U</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Carl Beeth &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; RT @neiltyson: The best engineering flow chart ever: http://twitter.com/neiltys... &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; 3 minutes ago &lt;p&gt; from Twitter &lt;p&gt; - Comment - Like &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/neiltyson/status/149569759485235200</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/neiltyson/status/149569759485235200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>68-Year-Old Skateboarding Professor Becomes Viral Meme [PICS]</title>
      <description>Tom Winter, 68-year-old University of Nebraska classics professor, rose to Internet stardom after a picture of him riding his skateboard, with a briefcase in hand, became a Reddit top post on Thursday. Numerous blogs and news publications wrote stories about the web-famous skateboarding professor. Winter had never heard of Reddit until his students notified him about his popular picture on the website. He checked the network out for himself and found some of the memes hilarious. He thought others were full of confusing &#8220;contemporary slang.&#8221; He received even more Internet love on Friday when BuzzFeed published a The 30 Best Teachers Of All Time, with Winter landing on top. &#8220;You can roll, but you can&#8217;t hide,&#8221; Winter told Mashable when asked what he makes of all this. When Mashable asked him about meme culture, he thought &#8220;memes&#8221; referred to the novel &#8220;The Selfish Meme&#8221; by British evolutionary biologist Richard Dawkins. The sight of a professor on a skateboard may be surprising for some, but Winter thinks it&#8217;s normal. He drives to work and then skateboards on his Arbor Pocket Rocket board around campus. He even tries skateboarding tricks. He has battle wounds to show it &#8212; he once broke a rib while attempting a wheelie. &#8220;Walking sucks, so I get there on my wheels,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I am 19 except [my] joints are all of 68. Walking is of discomfort. Once I get the board going, I can keep my balance and the joints are happy.&#8221; For more Winter-inspired hilarity, check out the gallery below. Winter reviews nine memes that fans have created using his picture. Image courtesy of Reddit"Got his B.A. in being B.A" "Ah, well whoever made this like using B.A." Winter said. "My daughter had to assure me that badass is good thing." Image via Quick Meme.Click here to view this gallery. More About: internet memes, memes, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/skateboarding-professor-memes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/skateboarding-professor-memes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Look Inside the New Facebook HQ: You&#8217;ll Like This [PICS]</title>
      <description>Facebook HQ. You Like This The company is now completely moved out of its Palo Alto pad, and into the much more spacious Menlo Park facility it broke ground on last year. Click here to view this gallery. It&#8217;s been a little more than a year since Facebook bought a 57-acre campus on the outskirts of Menlo Park in Silicon Valley, and started the slow process of turning it into its headquarters of the future. Well, the future is now. As of last week, every last Facebook staffer has been moved into the Menlo Park facility, which is almost unrecognizable compared to the way it looked a year ago. Mashable checked in on the new Facebook HQ in December, but there&#8217;s been a lot going on since then. The entire campus has a fresh coat of paint &#8212; not to mention fresh graffiti-style spray painted and stenciled artwork everywhere. (Employees are encouraged to &#8220;hack their space.&#8221;) We got an unprecedented behind-the-scenes look at what makes Facebook tick &#8212; the high-tech booking systems, amusingly-named conference rooms, and premium caffeination facilities. (What really makes Facebook so eager to constantly upgrade itself? Two words: Philz Coffee.) We saw plenty of things that make working at the social network so much fun &#8212; including a wall where Jeremy Lin had marked his height, towering above the rest of the staff. Take a look at the pics, and tell us in the comments whether you&#8217;d want to work here. More About: Facebook, Facebook HQ, mark zuckerberg, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/facebook-hq/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/facebook-hq/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audi Reveals &#8216;E-Sound&#8217; Engine Noise, Could Save Lives [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Just when we were thinking of how delightful it was that electric cars were so nice and quiet, Audi adds sound effects to its R8 e-tron electro-beast concept car, saving absent-minded pedestrians from an unfortunate encounter with this battery-powered road rocket. Audi&#8217;s not the first manufacturer to cover its legal posterior with sound effects in its electric vehicles, and it certainly won&#8217;t be the last. Well, at least Audi&#8217;s interpretation sounds like a futuristic gas guzzler, rather than a tree full of chirping birds. Take a look at (and a listen to) Audi&#8217;s interpretation of what an electric car should sound like, and let us know in the comments if you think this is entirely necessary. More About: electric cars, TechFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/audi-e-sound/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/audi-e-sound/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week</title>
      <description>1. April Fools</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/top-10-twitter-pics-week-164231044.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/top-10-twitter-pics-week-164231044.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest is Now the No. 3 Social Network in the U.S. [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Pinterest is now the number three most-popular social network in the U.S., behind Facebook and Twitter, according to Experian Hitwise. A new report from the researcher shows Pinterest got 21.5 million visits during the week ending Jan. 28, a nearly 30-fold increase over a comparable week in July. Not surprisingly, the site skews female with a 60/40 ration of women to men visitors. Experian rep Matt Tatham says Pinterest beat its next-closest competitor, LinkedIn, in total visits in February. Tatham says the rankings by total visits for March is as follows: 1. Facebook: 7 billion 2. Twitter: 182 million 3. Pinterest: 104 million 4. LinkedIn: 86 million 5. Tagged: 72 million 6. Google+: 61 million The report, which tracks visits rather than unique visitors, is based on web traffic and doesn&#8217;t factor in visits from mobile sites. According to Experian&#8217;s reckoning, Foursquare only got 2.9 million visits in March and Instagram got 10.2 million. ComScore, which doesn&#8217;t measure mobile traffic either, but ranks sites by uniques rather than total visits, did not include Pinterest in its list of the top 50 web properties in February. However, LinkedIn made number 27 with 36 million visitors. ComScore listed Pinterest as its number three &#8220;top-gaining&#8221; properties, however, with 17.8 million total visitors that month. ComScore&#8217;s March figures were not available at press time. More About: Experian Hitwise, Facebook, Google, pinterest, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>43 New Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>If you missed any of Mashable&#8216;s resources this week, hopefully it wasn&#8217;t because you were dealing with that nasty &#8220;Flashback&#8221; virus (make sure you check if your Mac has been infected by using this nifty script). Once you know you&#8217;re not one of the 600,000 unlucky ones hit with the malware virus, get caught up with our weekly features roundup! This week, we&#8217;ve covered the ways to add LinkedIn to your company&#8217;s website, tech time warp videos that will take you back to the &#8217;80s and &#8217;90s and memes brought to life via Twitter. We also have a Q&amp;A with author Jonah Lehrer, an office tour of StumbleUpon&#8217;s San Francisco headquarters and infographics on topics ranging from slacktivism to employee privacy. We even have the best Draw Something sketches from Mashable readers, like you. Go ahead and enjoy this week&#8217;s digital media resources. Editor&#8217;s Picks How to Be Creative: The Science of Genius In his book Imagine: How Creativity Works, author Jonah Lehrer posits that geniuses are not superheroes, but rather products of unstifled imagination and free-flowing ideas. How One Website Connects Those in Need With Government Assistance Finding a government program specifically tailored to one&#8217;s needs and location can be difficult and intimidating. That&#8217;s where innovative website Aunt Bertha comes in. Conan O&#8217;Brien Takes Over Mashable for April Fools&#8217; Day Just in case you weren&#8217;t obsessively checking Mashable last weekend, we wanted to give you the full picture of one of Mashable&#8217;s best-ever April Fools&#8217; Day pranks. Enjoy! Why &#8216;Slacktivists&#8217; Are More Active Than You Think [INFOGRAPHIC] Sortable created this infographic, which looks at the rise of slacktivism. 11 Early Pics From Android Instagram Users Instagram launched for Android, and users are already flocking to the app to show off their best skills. Social Media Get Your Nerd On With Nerdist Industries&#8217; New YouTube Channel Nerdist Industries has launched a new platform for its nerdy content in partnership with YouTube. 7 Useful Pinterest Tools to Supercharge Your Pinfluence Several third-party sites and services have piggybacked on Pinterest&#8217;s success, and can help you get more out of the social networking site. 10 Hilarious Memes Brought to Life on Twitter Can&#8217;t get enough of those &#8220;Advice Animals?&#8221; Follow you these memetastic characters on Twitter for non-stop Internet hilarity. 20 TV Shows With the Most Social Media Buzz This Week [CHART] Which TV shows generate the most buzz on social networks? Find out each week from our social TV chart. Pinerly: Hands on With the Newest Pinterest Analytics Tool New startup Pinerly wants to help you get a grip on your &#8220;Pinalytics.&#8221; We go hands-on with the beta service. How Google+ Can Succeed at Business Without Really Trying G+ is Google&#8217;s Trojan horse thanks to these features, which make it a great tool for enterprise social collaboration. What&#8217;s at Stake When Employers Ask for Social Media Passwords? [INFOGRAPHIC] Who is requesting access to social media information? Does access to employees&#8217; social media passwords leave an employer legally vulnerable? MLB Fan Cave: The Core Of Major League Baseball&#8217;s Social Strategy The MLB Fan Cave and the people in it are at the very core of Major League Baseball&#8217;s social media strategy. 8 Tips To Maximize Your Brand&#8217;s YouTube Presence Brands need a YouTube game plan. Here are eight tips for creating such a plan and turning your brand&#8217;s YouTube channel into a video hotspot. 25 Most-Buzzed Universities on the Internet MIT is the most-buzzed about university on the Internet. 9 Ways to Engage Your Employees on Pinterest Businesses can use Pinterest to encourage employees to get to know each other, and to communicate their personalities to the wider public. How Social Media Can Help You Land That New Job [INFOGRAPHIC] Social media can play a major role in finding that first job or hopping to a better one. For more social media news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s social media channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Business &amp; Marketing 4 Facebook Features Marketers Can&#8217;t Afford to Ignore Marketers need to know which networks are the most vital to their industry, and what features are key. In Facebook&#8217;s case, there are four. YouTube&#8217;s 20 Most-Shared Ads in March [VIDEOS] March&#8217;s list of most-shared YouTube ads is quite diverse. We&#8217;ve got tear-jerkers, special effects, animation, comedy and more! The Impact of Online Giving [INFOGRAPHIC] Millions of charitable dollars are given online every year. Where does it all go? What&#8217;s it worth? And how have digital donations changed the game? Impact Investing: How One Foundation Empowers Social EntrepreneursMashable spoke with John Walker, finance director of Echoing Green, a foundation that awards grants based on the individual&#8217;s potential and not the business plan. 9 Ways to Add LinkedIn to Your Company Website Adding LinkedIn&#8217;s social features to a company website is a great way to tap into the large-scale recruitment platform. Here are the nine key plugins. 3 Twitter Rumors and What They Could Mean for Brands Twitter is trying to become more attractive to advertisers. Read on for three possible changes Twitter could be making for brands. Stumble Into StumbleUpon&#8217;s San Francisco Office [PICS] Take a look inside the discovery platform&#8217;s innovative California headquarters. How One Company Helps Sales Teams Leverage Their Social Influence [VIDEO] Jon Ferrara, founder and CEO of Nimble, talks about how social media can be combined with CRM for better sales. 5 Best Practices for Creating Viral Branded Videos Want to know how to get your brand&#8217;s campaign to go viral? Here are a few great insights to consider. Crowd-Powered: Why Doritos Lets Fans Make Its Super Bowl Ads The cheesy chip company gives the reigns to its consumers to develop Super Bowl commercials. Here&#8217;s how it all works. How One Non-Profit Aims to Create Open-Source Government This politically tuned non-profit&#8217;s objective is to make the government&#8217;s public data more accessible to everyone in real-time. Learning Experiment Sparks Student Imagination With Cute Robots Reboot Stories uses experimental education projects to keep kids in low-income areas engaged with learning. Crowdfunding: What it Means for Investors The crowdfunding feature in the recently passed JOBS Act will not only impact startups, it will affect investors, too. Here&#8217;s how. 4 Ways to Rethink the Press Release Check out the four examples of companies reinventing how they use and present the press release. For more business news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s business channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Tech &amp; Mobile 10 Upcycled Gadgets for Your Home and Office Check out these 10 upcycled tech gadgets repurposed as modern home and office accessories. 20 Cool Easter Eggs Hidden in Google&#8217;s 8-Bit Maps Google Maps transformed into a gamer&#8217;s paradise, adding an 8-bit layer filled with landmarks and gaming characters to its virtual globe. 7 High-Tech Cars that will Save You Gas Money [PHOTOS] With the price of gas topping $4 a gallon in many parts of the U.S., people are once again buying more fuel-efficient electrics and hybrids. 25 Best &#8216;Draw Something&#8217; Sketches From Mashable Readers [PICS] We asked Mashable&#8216;s readers to show us the best Draw Something sketches they have created. How &#8216;Draw Something&#8217; Is Taking Over the World [INFOGRAPHIC] It&#8217;s official: The world is obsessed with Draw Something. Learn the numbers behing the break-out game&#8217;s astounding growth. Hang Ten! How the History of Surfing Went Digital How the author of the successful Encyclopedia of Surfing is gathering online support to take the print project completely digital. This Is What Your Future Home Might Look Like Believe it or not, the future of the urban architecture could be in plain sight. We explored two viable options. 9 Bold Predictions for the Digital World of 2020 Click through the slideshow to see what our experts foresee: artificial intelligence, cloud computing, virtual healthcare and digital jewelry. Happy 404 Day! Here Are the Web&#8217;s Funniest Error Messages [PICS] In honor of 4/04/12, we recapped some of the Internet&#8217;s funniest 404 error messages. 7 Tech Time Warps That Will Blow Your Mullet Off [VIDEOS] These YouTube videos look at today&#8217;s most used apps and technology as if they had been created in the &#8217;80s and &#8217;90s. 7 Crazy Tech Toys You Could Buy With Your Tax Refund The average U.S. federal tax refund is $2,946. Think of all the awesome gadgets you could get with it! 8 Handy Tablet Styluses to Boost Your Creativity Whether you&#8217;re sick of getting fingerprints all over your iPad or you want to get seriously creative, try a stylus for your tablet. For more tech news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s tech channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci. More About: Business, COMMUNICATIONS, Features Week In Review, Social Media, TechFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/digital-media-resources-4-7/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/digital-media-resources-4-7/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage Events Like A Pro With WordPress</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;ve ever tried working with, coding for or just thinking about anything to do with events, you know they are a total nightmare in every possible way. Repeating events, schedules, multiple days, multiple tracks, multiple prices, multiple speakers, multiple organizations, multiple payment options &#8212; the list goes on on for quite some time. Today we&#8217;ll show you how to make event management an easy &#8212; nay, enjoyable &#8212; task by making WordPress do the grunt work for you. We&#8217;ll be looking at out-of-the-box WordPress features, plugins and themes and a DIY approach to managing events. Please do let us know if you have more or better ideas. In A Nutshell I know some people don&#8217;t like to read lengthy reviews, so here are my recommendations in the shortest possible form. We&#8217;ll look at all of these recommendations in depth, so read on if you want to know more about them. If money is not an issue or you just want the best possible combination of products, I recommend using Event Espresso to manage the events and Eventure from ThemeForest to display them. This will set you back at least $125 (more if you need add-ons for Event Espresso), but it will give you one of the most powerful event-management setups you can get without touching any code. If you don&#8217;t need a payment gateway, multiple-day event-specific options or other advanced features or you&#8217;re on a budget, you could use Events Manager Free Version, Event Espresso Lite or Events Made Easy. These are all free and easy to use, providing roughly the same functionality. You might also want to purchase a theme to display your events nicely, which will set you back at least $35, but this is in no way required. Event Management Features Before we get to specific tools, let&#8217;s look at some of the features we get from an event-management system. You might not need all of these, but looking at them is useful when planning your system. Events Obviously, our event-management plugin should at least support events. The ability to create events that are separate from your regular posts is a powerful feature, allowing you to add events to your website&#8217;s existing content. Event Taxonomies Regular posts can be ordered into taxonomies &#8212; categories and tags. Having separate taxonomies for events (i.e. event categories and event tags) is useful for separating them from your regular content. If you organize Web development conferences, you might want to differentiate between design- and coding-related ones, or you might want to single out JavaScript- and Ruby-related ones. Your regular content might have nothing to do with Web development, so having separate taxonomies would come in handy. Registrations Allowing people to register for events right there on your website can greatly boost attendance. The path a user has to take from discovering your event to participating becomes that much shorter, which translates into a better user experience and more registrants. You will also need to be able to manage registrations through the back end. Registrants should be listed somewhere, with easy access to their details. Payment Gateways The ability to accept payments online breaks down another barrier between your events and potential attendees. A feature that allows you to accept the widest variety of payment methods would be ideal. Speaker Management As a software programmer, I don&#8217;t like when I enter data somewhere and it&#8217;s not stored in an easily reusable way. The ability to manage speakers across your events is a big plus because it opens up access to powerful features later on. This feature should include the ability to add biographies and photos of speakers to the website. Venue Management As with speaker management, having all your locations stored properly will make them ease to reuse in future. If you need to schedule another event at the same venue, there&#8217;s no need to reenter the details; just select it from a menu, and off you go. Participating Organizations Another nice feature is being able to attach companies to events. Companies will often host events, and giving them some recognition for it is a nice thing to do in return. Sponsors Almost all major events have sponsors that contribute in some way (usually with money). They often require you to add their logo in various places. Being able to add the names, descriptions and logos of sponsors for an event would be handy. Notification Management There are two kinds of notifications we might want to control. On-site notifications are shown to users once they perform specific actions. When a user successfully pays for a ticket or encounters an error while registering, an on-site notification should pop up to let them know what&#8217;s going on. Being able to tailor the language of these to your style would be a nice feature. The second type of notification are email messages to participants. Confirmations, reminders and so on would all be customized to your style. Form Management Controlling the information to gather from registrants is key to finding sponsors and making the lives of users easier. Being able to control this on an event-by-event basis would be best. Some events require less information from users, others more. Coupon Management Many events offer coupons for promotional purposes. If you want to engage users beyond your website, then giving coupons for third parties to distribute is a great tactic. Creating multiple coupons for various events would enable you to manage a full-blown coupon campaign. Price Management Another way to persuade visitors to register is to offer different price options, such as early-bird pricing, student discounts, last-minute offers and so on. Multiple Day Events Many events have so much going on that splitting them into multiple days is the only way to go. Being able to control this from the administration section would be a great plus, especially when coupled with price-management options (such as registration for one day only). Repeating Events If you are organizing a repeating event, you wouldn&#8217;t want to have to create it from scratch a hundred times a year. Scheduling and repeating tools would help minimize your effort. Powerful Global and Miscellaneous Settings A great event-management system has to have great global and miscellaneous settings. Settings for creating an events listing page, changing currencies, setting time zones and so on are all part of a complete system. Complete Solutions All of the WordPress plugins in this section are paid plugins, but if you&#8217;re running a serious operation, then the first two listed here are well worth the money. The three best plugins around are Events Planner, Events Manager and Event Espresso. Event Espresso is by far the best of the lot, but all three are versatile and under constant development. Event Espresso Event Espresso is the cream of the crop. It has built-in support for almost all of the features mentioned above (except perhaps sponsor management) &#8212; and much more! It enables you to set up multiple forms of payment, multiple event dates and times, multiple prices, discounts, promotions (coupons), locations (even virtual ones) and emails. It also creates posts for events automatically and does so much more! Event Espresso also has a free &#8220;Lite&#8221; version, which gives you a taste of the solution. The lite version is actually pretty robust and can be used for simple situations. It includes event and attendee management, automated emails, customizable registration and PayPal Standard Payment. You can easily tailor the design of event listings to your current theme. If you are willing to dish out the money for this plugin, I recommend getting a premium website theme as well and modifying that as needed. Event Espresso is not cheap, but its feature set is top notch, so the price is justified. The basic version costs $89.95, which contains all of the features that 95% of people will need. From there, you can download free and paid add-ons to the basic system. Some free add-ons are for payment gateways, social media and calendars. MailChimp integration, recurring events management, developer customization options, WordPress integration, Groupon integration, multiple event registration and shopping cart integration (coming soon) is available at between $25 and $35 a pop. Most of these are well worth their money, although getting the WordPress members integration for free would have been nice, because that&#8217;s not a huge programming leap. A gallery will be added here with 3-4 images of how an event is displayed by default, a screenshot from the admin, etc. The images can be found in the images/gallery/ folder of this draft Events Planner Events Planner is another well-rounded system. It doesn&#8217;t have all of the features of Event Espresso, but it does give you a lot to work with. Event categories, tags, instructors, locations, companies, notifications, payments, registrations and more can be managed with ease. The main difference between Events Planner and Event Espresso is that the former&#8217;s UI is less polished, and some features found in both are not as well implemented in it. Despite this, Events Planner remains extremely flexible and robust. If you don&#8217;t want to part with almost a hundred bucks, you&#8217;ll be able to grab Events Planner for $39, plus another $24 if you need plugins that supports advanced date- and time-specific functions. Events Planner does not have a lite version, but you can create a custom installation yourself and test drive the pro version. This is a little unusual for plugins, but it does mean you can fully test it before purchasing. A gallery will be added here with 3-4 images of how an event is displayed by default, a screenshot from the admin, etc. The images can be found in the images/gallery/ folder of this draft Events Manager Events Manager is very similar to Events Planner in many ways. Some features have a better UI in Events Planner, while others are better in Events Manager. Were the price not so different, it would be a matter of preference, but because Events Manager costs a lot more than Events Planner, I would not recommend this solution. Events Manager will set you back $75, and the price buys you only one year&#8217;s worth of upgrades. There are no plugins or add-ons here (which could be a good thing), but the higher price and losing access to updates after a year seems a bit cheeky at this price point. Events Manager has a free version that gives you a lot of functionality. It supports event and booking management, recurring events, locations and more. A gallery will be added here with 3-4 images of how an event is displayed by default, a screenshot from the admin, etc. The images can be found in the images/gallery/ folder of this draft Final Verdict Of the three, Event Espresso is the clear winner. It supports every feature the other two do and a lot more. It also has handy (albeit slightly expensive) plugins, with more to come. Even at $89, if you run a successful business (or plan to), it isn&#8217;t a high price to pay for the features you get. If you can&#8217;t spend that much on a plugin, then Events Planner is a very capable alternative that will not leave you wanting. When all is said and done, it does cost less than half of Event Espresso and still has 80% of its features. I would still heartily recommend it. If you don&#8217;t need payment options, however, and you need a free solution, the free version of this plugin might be your best option. Have a look at the partial solutions below. Partial Solutions Quite a few solutions do not offer advanced features such as payment gateways and coupon management but do allow some flexibility and customizations for events. The best options for a simpler approach are All-in-One Event Calendar, Event Organiser and Events Made Easy, as well as the free versions of Event Espresso and Events Manager. In a showdown, it would be a close call between Event Espresso and Events Manager. All-in-One Event Calendar creates a new post type for your events, allowing you to keep blog posts and events side by side. It supports event categories, tags and a few other options. Because it allows you to create a calendar page, it&#8217;s a great solution if you need something simple and workable in minutes. Event Organiser has all of the same functions plus a lot more! It has permission settings, permalink settings, importing and exporting options and even venue support. In addition, it has an admin calendar view that gives you a useful overview of your events. Events Made Easy has all of the features of All-In-One Event Calendar (except event tags), and it supports registrations and locations. If you absolutely need to support on-site registration, this would be the easiest to use. The UI is the least polished, though, so it won&#8217;t look as pretty in the administration section, but the features are solid. Final Verdict Despite the great features offered by these plugins, I would stick with Event Espresso Lite or the free version of Events Manager. Apart from offering more functionality, they will also ease your transition if you need the full-blown system later on. Using WordPress Out Of The Box If you don&#8217;t need to manage data for each event, WordPress&#8217;s core functionality will do just fine. Here are a few ideas to get you started: Use posts to store events. If you want to be able to have regular posts as well, distinguish them using categories. Create top-level categories for distinguishing organizations, sponsors and venues. Use your website&#8217;s registration functionality to manage past attendees, or use it as a master attendee list if separate registration is not required for your events. Create pages for important information such as payment options. Use PayPal buttons in event posts to let people register and pay directly through PayPal. Many of these features are far from optimal for event-intensive websites, but if you just need something simple that you can set up in 10 minutes, give it a go. If you do choose this option, pay close attention to consistency. If your goal is expansion, you are guaranteed to want a better system later on, and consistency will ensure that you can make the switch without a hiccup. Comparing All Of The Options There is a lot to learn and a lot of options if you want to get started with event management. To make your life easier, here is a table with all of the features discussed, along with the solutions that support them. Click on the image to go to the large version (it&#8217;s a bit small to look at here). Event-Friendly Themes While the plugins do a nice job of helping you manage events, they are not designed to make your website pretty, which is equally important. No matter which route you take, you will need to do some work to make things fit perfectly, but some premium themes out there will shorten this process. Eventure $35 | Large screenshot | Live preview Diarise $70 | Large screenshot | Live preview Events (from Elegant Themes)Large screenshot | Live preview EventureLarge screenshot | Live preview Conclusion Whichever solution you choose, you will have to put in a few hours of work to make your website work well and look good. I usually advise using free software whenever possible, but this happens to be one of those areas where I would go with a complete solution. Getting it right from the get-go will save you a lot of headaches in the long run. If you can afford to spend over $100 on managing events, go for Event Espresso, coupled with one of the premium themes mentioned above. If you want to spend as little as possible, then try Events Manager Free Version, Event Espresso Lite or Events Made Easy. If you don&#8217;t plan on expanding a lot or you need multiple price points, go with Events Made Easy because it is completely free, with no paid version, so supporting the developer by using his product would be a nice gesture. If you do plan on expanding, go with Event Espresso Lite because the pro version will have everything you need when you&#8217;re ready to buy it and you won&#8217;t have any migration or data problems. (al) &#169; Smashing Editorial for Smashing Magazine, 2012.</description>
      <link>http://wp.smashingmagazine.com/2012/04/05/manage-events-like-pro-with-wordpress/</link>
      <guid>http://wp.smashingmagazine.com/2012/04/05/manage-events-like-pro-with-wordpress/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Gamification Can&#8217;t Be Stopped</title>
      <description>From recycling, to personal health, to corporate culture, gamification is seeping into all aspects of everyday life. The practice of applying game mechanics to non-game contexts &#8212; for example fandom, separating trash from glass or meeting company goals &#8212; has exploded in the past few years. Since the beginning, the California-based company Bunchball has been at the emerging industry&#8217;s forefront and today works with companies including including Comcast, the Los Angeles Kings, Hasbro and Warner Bros. Bunchball founder Rajat Paharia (see photo) was one of the term&#8217;s earliest adopters and the company owns the domain gamification.com. Bunchball recently introduced a new product, called Nitro Flamethrower, that&#8217;s touted as the first personalized gamification product and something Paharia says will power the industry to stronger traction. &#8220;It&#8217;s spread not only incredibly deep, but it also reaches almost everywhere now,&#8221; Paharia says. &#8220;And I think it&#8217;s only going to penetrate deeper as long as people continue to see value.&#8221; The power of game mechanics to invest people in websites, shows, teams, companies and other properties is what Paharia says has fueled the rise of his company and others like it. But he says Bunchball&#8217;s road to success was rocky at first. The company started out building social games in 2005, but found that to be a dead end. Facebook hadn&#8217;t yet launched its gaming platform and few thought the genre could catch on, so Bunchball changed course. Applying game mechanics to non-game settings was also a tough sell at first, until an ironic twist helped Bunchball get established: Facebook launched its gaming platform and the industry Paharia entered too early to capitalize on exploded. But as products like Foursquare and FarmVille became popular, Bunchball&#8217;s new tack gained more believers. One of the company&#8217;s early hits came in 2007, when it created a gamified website for NBC&#8217;s The Office. Based off a storyline in the show, users signed up on a social network as employees of the Dunder Mifflin paper company. Users earned &#8220;Schrute Bucks&#8221; for making comments, posting photos and performing tasks that built engagement and buzz for the show. Before long, the site was populated with loads of user-generated content. &#8220;NBC loved it because they were paying all these users fake money to do real work,&#8221; Paharia says. In the five years since, Bunchball has gone on to leverage gamification concepts for more than 100 clients. In the next five years, Paharia sees gamification becoming more widespread in the health, media and employee-training spaces, among others. What are the keys to that continued rise? Paharia points to more customization for companies to tailor campaigns to their own needs, expanding beyond primarily individual challenges to promote more team-based engagement, and further incorporating real rewards beyond virtual points and badges. &#8220;Gamification is all about providing sustained user engagement,&#8221; Paharia says. &#8220;The word itself implies a transformation of something that exists, and people are starting to see more and more how they can apply it to their own situations.&#8221; Photo courtesy of Bunchball.com More About: Business, gamificationFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/gamification-bunchball/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/gamification-bunchball/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About.me iPhone App Launches With &#8216;Who&#8217;s Nearby&#8217; Feature</title>
      <description>The simple one-page profile platform About.me is now available on iPhones. Since its 2010 launch and acquisition by AOL, around 1.5 million people have built a splash page, a collection of their social media handles. An About.me page consists of a background photo, as little as two or three lines of text and buttons linking to a person&#8217;s social networks. It&#8217;s a summary of who you are online that you can attach to email signatures, attach to Twitter and now view on your phone. The personal pages are short and sweet. The sleek interface packs a punch with its analytics system. Stats include views per month, clicks, links to you, average time spent on people and more. Now, About.me iPhone app users can make pages on-the-go as well as connect with people on the street with the mobile app. The &#8216;Who&#8217;s Nearby&#8217; feature &#8212; unique to the app &#8212; is something that will appeal to people watchers, co-founder Ryan Freitas told Mashable. &#8220;There is this ability to create an opportunity for discovery, to see the way people are literally around you in a geographical location and how they represented themselves creatively,&#8221; Freitas said. &#8220;They have done something interesting to show off who they are as a person.&#8221; The app brings many pieces of the successful web platform to the iPhone. About.me creators say much of the website&#8217;s appeal lies in the ability for people to browse the directory, not limited to friends. SEE ALSO: 38 Million Americans Visit Social Networks on Mobile Devices &#8216;Near Daily&#8217; [STUDY] &#8220;People enjoy the people-watching we provide,&#8221; Freitas said. &#8220;Not voyeurism, but about getting additional information about the people around you.&#8221; Privacy consistently being a controversial topic with location-based apps, About.me requires users to opt-in to become visible on the network. The app does more than finding businesses on the go, says Freitas. It&#8217;s about finding interesting people to follow on Twitter or cool websites to visit. &#8220;With the app, it doesn&#8217;t always need to be about utility,&#8221; Freitas said. &#8220;It can be about something as simple as finding out interesting people around you who you haven&#8217;t met yet.&#8221; About.me is now working on apps for iPad and Android market. More About: about me, aol, Business, iphone, Social Media, social networkingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/about-me-iphone-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/about-me-iphone-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
