<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Media Is Taking Over the News Industry [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>More than ever, people are using Twitter, Facebook and other social media sources to learn about what&#8217;s happening in the world as traditional news outlets become increasingly less relevant to the digital generation. American forces&#8217; raid on Osama Bin Laden, Whitney Houston&#8216;s death, the Hudson River plane landing &#8212; these are just a few of many major news stories ordinary citizens broke on Twitter first. Professional journalists, meanwhile, use Twitter all the time to break news quickly before writing up full articles. And the business side is going digital too. Online news now generates more revenue than print newspapers. But the trend toward Internet and social media-based news &#8212; and the accompanying rush to be first to report a story &#8212; also comes with pitfalls. Some 50% of news consumers have received &#8220;breaking news&#8221; via social media, only to find out later it was erroneously reported. All this and more comes from the online education portal Schools.com, which pulled research from sources including the Washington Post, Pew Research Center and Reuters to put together the infographic below. Check it out to see the fuller picture of how social media is coming to dominate the news industry. How much do you rely on social media for news compared to more traditional sources? Has that balance changed for you recently? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy iStockphoto, DNY59 More About: Facebook, infographics, News, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/social-media-and-the-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/social-media-and-the-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smartphone Graphics to Soon Surpass Xbox 360? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Want your phone&#8217;s graphics to match those of top gaming systems such as the Xbox 360? Just wait until about 2014 when graphics hardware giant NVIDIA estimates that smartphone graphics might whip those of the popular gaming console. According to a chart showing yearly graphic performance of console, PC, and mobile devices, it looks like your smartphone could soon host the same type of graphics processing unit (GPU) as the Xbox 360. Apple&#8217;s new iPad, with its stunning Retina display, makes games such as Infinity Blade Dungeons look even crisper. But could your smartphone replace your Xbox gaming system? Maybe not yet &#8212; at the moment this is just speculation. Plus it&#8217;s been six years since Microsoft, Sony, and Nintendo have updated their consoles. It&#8217;s possible sharper graphics are on everyone&#8217;s &#8220;to-do&#8221; list. Would you prefer to play games on your smartphone, console or both, if the graphics were both top-notch? Tell us in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, svariophoto More About: Gaming, infographics, smartphones, xbox</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/smartphone-graphics/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/smartphone-graphics/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Digital Ways to Make a Difference This Earth Day</title>
      <description>Are you busy preparing for Earth Day this Sunday? Are you worried that you&#8217;ll end up being a slacktivist when it comes to saving the planet? Don&#8217;t fret &#8212; there&#8217;s plenty you can do to make a real difference, even if it&#8217;s only from your computer or mobile device. Check out the following ways you can use digital channels to get involved this year. 1. Plant Trees Through Catalog Spree Catalog Spree, an eco-friendly app for catalog shopping on the iPad, has partnered with the Arbor Day Foundation, a non-profit conservation and education organization dedicated to planting trees. The Arbor Day Foundation will plant one tree for every download of Catalog Spree during the month of April as part of an &#8220;Earth Month&#8221; initiative. Download the app here. 2. Fundraise via Edward Norton&#8217;s Green Earth Day Challenge Actor Edward Norton is the United Nations goodwill ambassador for biodiversity, and he&#8217;s teaming up with Groupon this Earth Day for an &#8220;Earth Day Challenge.&#8221; If you&#8217;re passionate about a green cause, put together a team and start a fundraising campaign through Norton&#8217;s online crowdfunding platform, CrowdRise. The team that raises the most money will win a $25,000 check from Groupon for their organization, and the second and third winning teams will receive $15,000 and $10,000, respectively, for their organizations. But when you think about it, everyone wins from this challenge &#8212; each team is generating green ideas and money. At the time of the press release, the participating organizations include Conservation International, Ian Somerhalder Foundation, Global Green, Conservation Lands Foundation, Friends of the Virgin Islands Nation Park, Wiser Earth and National Wildlife Humane Society. Contest instructions and rules are here, but get going! The contest ends May 15. 3. Recycle E-waste Through HP and Staples On April 12, Hewlett-Packard (HP) and Staples announced a free recycling program that allows consumers across the United States to recycle their electronics easily and free. Customers can drop off their technology for recycling at the service desk of their local Staples store. Staples will collect the devices and consolidate them at its distribution centers, where a certified e-Stewards and R2 recycler will arrange to have the materials transported to one of its processing centers. 4. Play a Social Game for Social Good Disney Animal Kingdom Explorers is a new ecologically-minded Facebook game inspired by Walt Disney&#8217;s Animal Kingdom theme park. Players are part of the Global Wildlife Research team, an international organization of conservationists, environmentalists and naturalists. The game has partnered with the Jane Goodall Institute, a global nonprofit that empowers people to make a difference for all living things. In honor of Earth Day, the Disney Worldwide Conservation Fund has pledged to donate 20 cents to the Jane Goodall Institute for the DisneyNature Tchimpounga Natural Reserve project for every install and tutorial completion by players referred from the URL www.PlayAnimalKingdom.com. The Disney Worldwide Conservation Fund has pledged to donate up to $250,000 until April 26. Every player makes a difference. 5. Support the Earth, One Inch at a Time TerraYebo, a for-profit social enterprise with a focus on &#8220;doing well by doing good,&#8221; has launched MyInchofTheEarth.com, a website with patent-pending technology allowing anyone to claim any square inch of the planet for $1 to support worldwide causes and non-profit organizations. In recognition of Earth Day and National Park Week (April 21-29), TerraYebo has partnered with the National Park Foundation, the official charity of America&#8217;s national parks, which proceeds from MyInchofTheEarth.com will help support. 6. Let Cuteness Educate You About Endangerment It&#8217;s believed that fewer than 1,600 giant pandas currently exist in the world. That&#8217;s why Explore.org will be releasing a new live feed of five giant panda cubs on Earth Day. &#8220;There is something magical and inspiring about watching panda cubs interact with each other in real-time,&#8221; said Explore.org&#8217;s founder, Charlie Annenberg, in a press release. &#8220;The hope is that by viewing these cams, people will develop deeper emotional connections not just to the bears, but also to the planet. Once someone has fallen in love with the world again, he or she is more likely to be a better steward of it,&#8221; he added. There are links on Explore.org to help you donate to different causes, and you can share the videos with your networks to spread awareness. Watch the live feed here. 7. Go Green With Google Maps You&#8217;ve probably used Google Maps before, but have you used it to go green? The Biking Directions feature is available in over 200 U.S. cities and in nine Canadian regions, illustrating bike lanes, hills and route suggestions, making it easier to leave your gas guzzler behind. Google Transit can map the quickest public transit routes in more than 470 cities around the world. And if you want to carpool and avoid traffic, the Traffic layer displays real-time traffic conditions on your route. As an extra perk for those of you who drive electric vehicles, you can easily find electric vehicle charging stations by typing &#8220;ev charging station in [your city]&#8221; directly into Google Maps. 8. Teach Kids About Conservation With Discovery Education The Nature Conservancy, the leading conservation organization working in more than 30 countries to protect the environment for future generations, has partnered with Discovery Education to launch Nature Works Everywhere, an online destination that teaches younger generations the importance of environmental conservation. Nature Works Everywhere provides teachers, students and families with free resources to explore and understand nature. 9. Sell a Book, Save a Tree With Lulu Publishers Lulu.com is an open publishing platform, helping authors and artists create work in multiple formats and markets and helping buyers find the content they need. They&#8217;ve always been keen on staying green, using the latest in print-on-demand and e-book technology and utilizing a global network of printers to help cut down the carbon imprint from shipping books. For Earth Day, Lulu is hosting a sales contest for authors to sell the most books between April 18 and April 25 &#8212; winners receive some sweet prizes, but best of all, Lulu will plant a tree for every contest entry received. What are you doing for Earth Day this year? Let us know in the comments. Images courtesy of iStockphoto, lightkeeper, teekid, SondraP, johnwoodcock. More About: crowdfunding, earth day, environmentalism, Social Good, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/digital-earth-day-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/digital-earth-day-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>William Shatner Takes His Millionth Twitter Follower Out To Dinner [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Following William Shatner on Twitter has its perks, at least if you&#8217;re the Star Trek star&#8217;s millionth follower. Troy Pound from South Carolina was the millionth person to follow Captain Kirk, and in return he and his wife were recently treated to a dinner with man himself. Shatner had promised to take lucky one million out to dinner before he reached the number, a promise he made good on recently while traveling close to Pound in Charlotte, NC for his one-man show &#8220;Shatner&#8217;s World.&#8221; Shatner posted a grainy cell phone video of the dinner, which occurred on Tuesday, on his YouTube channel. The star&#8217;s follower count has grown considerably since Pound hit the follow button, with close to 20,000 more people now following the Priceline negotiator. While Pound boldly went where no Shatner fan has gone before, Shatner does regularly interact with his fans directly on Twitter and both reads and responds to tweets sent his way. The same night that he met with Pound and his wife he commented on his twitter stream &#8220;I just love that I can read people&#8217;s tweets in the audience just before the show.&#8221; Shatner regularly retweets messages from his followers and will often send personalized messages thanking them for kind words or attending one of his performances. The dinner outing was part of the performer&#8217;s 81st birthday celebration. What do you think about Shatner heading to dinner with his millionth follower? Do you think other celebrities should follow suit and make an effort to meet some of their followers as well? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Twitter, William ShatnerFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/william-shatner-dinner/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/william-shatner-dinner/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millennial Consumers: Engaged, Optimistic, Charitable [STUDY]</title>
      <description>A study comparing Millennials with non-Millennials sheds light on some of the key behaviors and attitudes of the generation. Currently numbered at 79 million &#8212; and growing in influence &#8212; Millennials are expected to outnumber the Baby Boomer population 78 million to 56 million by 2030. The Boston Consulting Group recently surveyed 4,000 Millennials aged 16 to 34, as well as 1,000 non-Millennials aged 35 to 40. The report&#8217;s complete findings are available online. Here&#8217;s a summary of the key takeaways of the survey, and what marketers and companies need to keep in mind as the generation continues to become more dominant. Millennials are actively engaged in consuming and influencing In contrast to the stereotypical view that they are lazy and entitled, Millennials are extremely optimistic about the ability of business and government to influence global change. They are more likely than non-Millennials to purchase products that support a cause, and when they make direct donations &#8212; which 34% of them do &#8212; nearly half donate through mobile devices. Millennials are also more likely than their non-Millennial counterparts to broadcast their thoughts and experiences online, and to contribute their views to user-generated content. For example, 60% of Millennials spend time rating products and services and uploading videos, images and blog entires online. Millennials favor recommendations from peers or friends For the Millennial, an expert doesn&#8217;t necessarily have to be someone with credentials &#8212; rather, it can mean anyone with firsthand experience. Crowd-sourcing is popular among the generation, and more than half of the Millennials surveyed (53%) reported exploring brands through social networks. They are also much more likely than non-Millennials to use their phones to read reviews or research products while shopping. Half of them reported doing this, whereas for non-Millennials, only 21% engaged in this behavior. Millennials are &#8220;digital natives&#8221; Using new technology is old news to Millennials, and they tend to own multiple devices &#8212; 72% reported using MP3 players, 67% use gaming platforms and 59% own smartphones. In comparison, 80% of non-Millennials reported using desktop computers at home, and 60% owned basic cell phones. The upshot? Millennials are much more likely to multitask while online, and are comfortable doing so across a variety of platforms such as mobile, tablet and gaming. The Millennial generation is also heavily engaged with social media, with nearly half (47%) of those surveyed indicating their lives feel richer when they are connected to people online. 33% also favor brands that have Facebook pages and mobile websites, compared with 17% of non-Millennials. What are the implications of these findings? According to Jeff Fromm, executive vice president at Barkley advertising agency and the founder of the Share.Like.Buy Millennial marketing conference, the way the Millennial generation has engaged with brands, channels and other models online has been instrumental in creating the current &#8220;participation economy.&#8221; And companies need to keep up with them, Fromm adds. &#8220;Since these consumers are always in a hurry, it&#8217;s critical to determine how you can get them to spend time developing a relationship with your brand,&#8221; Fromm says. The survey also found non-Millennials tend to have negative views toward Millennials, which may have inadvertently affected how executives have been appealing to them as consumers. But considering the critical role the generation is currently playing in influencing communication channels, the need to develop marketing, brands and business models to appeal to Millennials is without question. &#8220;Some may argue that the peak spending years of the Millennials are far enough in the future that companies can take their time in developing well-targeted, appealing products and services,&#8221; says Chris Egan, COO of the customer experience analytics agency SMG. But we believe that staying on top of Millennial trends is critical because they will ultimately influence today&#8217;s big spenders, the 35-to-74-year-old non-Millennials.&#8221; To help companies better tailor their messaging to Millennials, the Boston survey identified six subsets of the U.S. Millennial population. Here they are, along with representative quotes: Hip-ennials (29%) &#8212; &#8220;I can make the world a better place.&#8221; Millennial Moms (22%) &#8212; &#8220;I love to work out, travel and pamper my baby.&#8221; Anti-Millennials (16%) &#8212; &#8220;I&#8217;m too busy taking care of my business and my family to worry about much else.&#8221; Gadget Gurus (13%) &#8212; &#8220;It&#8217;s a great day to be me.&#8221; Clean and Green Millennials (10%) &#8212; &#8220;I take care of myself and the world around me.&#8221; Old School Millennials (10%) &#8212; &#8220;Connecting on Facebook is too impersonal, let&#8217;s meet up for coffee instead!&#8221; What do you think of these findings? Do they agree with your own experiences with Millennials? Sound off in the comments. Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, TommL&#8236; More About: Marketing, millennialsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/millennial-consumers-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/millennial-consumers-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jawbone Jambox Makes Big Sound With Small Speaker</title>
      <description>The Summer Gadget Series is presented by the Galaxy Nexus from Sprint. Android 4.0, Google Wallet and Google Play make it pure Google. Truly Unlimited data from Sprint makes it unstoppable. Check it out. Product: Jawbone Jambox Price: $199.99 / &#163;159.99 / &#8364;199.99 What It&#8217;s Good For: Wireless, portable audio and speakerphone calls Who It&#8217;s Good For: Anyone with a Bluetooth-enabled laptop or phone Limitations: High price. Bottom Line: You don&#8217;t have to compromise on style, sound or size with the Jambox &#8212; but it will cost you. A Look at the Jambox Aliph boldly describes its Jawbone Jambox as &#8220;the smallest, best sounding wireless speaker and speakerphone on the planet.&#8221; It can pair with your Bluetooth-enabled phone or laptop to stream music, other audio and take calls, but is it really as good as Aliph&#8217;s confident claim? The first thing you need to know about this device is that it really is small. As in, 151mm by 57mm by 40mm small. The second is that it&#8217;s loud. Capable of pumping out 85 decibels, you&#8217;re looking at a tiny speaker that can actually deliver on the &#8220;room-filling sound&#8221; promise. Hooking up the Jambox is a cinch. There are no complicated controls, and the speaker itself has minimal buttons. There simply are volume controls, the &#8220;Talk&#8221; button on top, an on/off switch and ports on the side. To make things even easier, it lets you know it&#8217;s paired via its built-in voice control (it also alerts you of low battery levels the same way). If you don&#8217;t like the default voice, you can change it via the bundled software. Be warned though, some of the options are a little cheesily seductive for some tastes. However, if you like the idea of your gadgetry purring, &#8220;I&#8217;m paired, ready for action,&#8221; in an over-sexed female voice, this option is going to fall into the &#8220;pros&#8221; column for you. Jambox in Action The sound quality belies the size of the Jambox. Thanks to its proprietary tech (two acoustic drivers and a passive radiator woofer) and sound-enhancing &#8220;LiveAudio&#8221; functionality, this tiny box can really pump out the tunes &#8212; delivering surprisingly balanced sound from such a small unit. Its voice capabilities are also very good, with crisp call quality. And the best thing is the Jambox looks good doing it. With four designs &#8212; a classic &#8220;Black Diamond,&#8221; funky &#8220;Blue Wave,&#8221; cool &#8220;Grey Hex&#8221; and fun &#8220;Red Dot&#8221; &#8212; the JAMBOX will not let you down in the aesthetics department, whatever your personal style. It feels sturdy too, thanks to its stainless steel construction and solid rubber casing. The Jambox also delivers as far as battery life goes, meaning its portable ambitions are not let down by poor power consumption. Once fully charged via the bundled micro-USB cable, you can expect a full day&#8217;s use out of the speaker (the official boast is 10 hours). Finally, as with all good connected gadgetry these days, the Jambox is updatable. You can download apps and software upgrades, as well as personalize settings, via the bundled &#8220;MyTalk&#8221; software. If you&#8217;ve got the cash to burn, then we are confident in stating that the Jambox will not disappoint. In fact, it&#8217;s such a great little product that it might even end up delighting you. 1. The Jawbone Jambox The Jambox gives you a wireless way to listen to audio from your laptop or phone. It also boasts speakerphone functionality, thanks to a built-in mic.Click here to view this gallery. Series presented by the Sprint Galaxy Nexus The Summer Gadget Series is presented by the Galaxy Nexus from Sprint. Android 4.0, Google Wallet and Google Play make it pure Google. Truly Unlimited data from Sprint makes it unstoppable. Check it out. More About: Aliph, features, Gadgets, Jawbone Jambox, mashable, review, speakers, Summer Gadget Series, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/jawbone-jambox-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/jawbone-jambox-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Timeline Image Changes: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Timeline for Business Image Changes: On April 26, Facebook will be updating the display size of the profile picture/avatar on all Facebook pages. If you have a tightly integrated design, you should be aware of this change. Be ready to update your profile picture on April 26. The new profile picture will be 160 x 160 pixels and will sit at 23 pixels from the left and 210 pixels from the top of the page.Facebook Syncs Email Addresses: &#8220;With your @facebook.com email address, people can email you using any traditional email system (e.g., Hotmail, Yahoo! or Gmail), and the emails will be delivered to your Facebook Messages.&#8221; Facebook now syncs your email address with your Facebook name."Now, the address people use to get to your timeline and send you email on Facebook will be the same."Discussion from our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:Rewards for social media activity?Fangate alternatives in TimelineCorporate Blogging &#8211; What is best practice for vetting guest bloggers?Facebook Announces the New Preferred Marketing Developer Program: The goal of this program is &#8220;to bring developers to the right clients and make it possible for any brand or company to find consultants who can work with them to build comprehensive Facebook campaigns and presences.&#8221;The Preferred Marketing Developer Program makes it easier for businesses to find the service providers they need.Klout Testing Brand Pages: Klout is testing brand pages (known a &#8216;squads&#8217;) with their exclusive brand partner Red Bull. Brand Squads, &#8220;currently in beta, are Klout&#8217;s way of giving influencers a place to be recognized and have a direct impact on the brands they care about most.&#8221;"As part of this beta launch, Red Bull has offered Perks that will roll out to their top influencers over the next few weeks."Dashboard Ads Coming to Tumblr: &#8220;Advertisers will be able to buy ad units on the &#8216;Featured&#8217; section of Tumblr&#8217;s dashboard, which gets approximately 120,000 impressions a day.&#8221;Pinterest Third Most Popular Social Media Site, Study Show: The 2012 Digital Marketer: Benchmark and Trend Report from Experian confirms the rise in popularity of Pinterest.Here are a few social media tools worth noting:DivvyHQ: A spreadsheet-free editorial calendar application.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h8vhu2ILveMSpringpad: A tool to create notebooks of things that matter to you, together with friends, family and co-workers. It&#8217;s a bit like Pinterest with more features.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=biAl_nnwf6USociabell: A browser add-on for Facebook users to use the Facebook search box to search Google, YouTube and more, with only one click.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AjW34Bx8e-sDealsJoy: A new deal-based commerce site which gives the power directly to business owners."Create, launch and manage your special offers and deals directly to your fan base through the easy to use DealsJoy platform."And don&#8217;t miss this:Social Media Examiner presents Social Media Success Summit 2012! (online conference)Join 27 social media experts at Social Media Examiner&#8217;s big online conference! Go here to learn more.What social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-timeline-changes/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-timeline-changes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our children and Facebook. AVG releases its latest &#8216;Digital Diaries&#8217; research</title>
      <description>Earlier this week, AVG, providers of security software, released the latest part of its series about the activity of children online called Digital Diaries. The study was conducted by Research Now for AVG and the series covers child digital development through different age groups. The latest installment is about 14 to 17 year olds and the project began in 2010 with children who are not even born yet. According to earlier reports in the series, 23% of children in the UK have a digital footprint before they are born as parents post sonograms and other details about their lives. So it&#8217;s worth considering how the next generations will grow and what their digital activity will look like in the future. The information was released at an event where Tony Ancombe, AVG&#8217;s ambassador for free products, Simon Milner, Facebook&#8217;s director of policy for the UK and Ireland and Steve Kuncewicz, a lawyer, specialised in online and social media issues discussed the upbringing of children in a digital age. Ancombe says that the many stages of the Digital Diaries research is important to AVG, &#8220;It&#8217;s interesting to us as a tech company to know what our children are doing as we can see both where to develop product and where kids need to be safe. It&#8217;s also interesting to find out how online security works in a family home.&#8221; According to AVG&#8217;s reports, 41% of UK parents have accessed their child&#8217;s social networking account without that child knowing. Milner has a teenager and a twelve year old of his own and remarked that as with most parents of children that age, he does not get a lot of communication from them. He said he saw little harm in the examples of parental snooping but that Facebook does try to help parents know that their children can control their own online experience. &#8220;I don&#8217;t expect Facebook to help with parenting but I do expect Facebook to provide the tools to help them keep safe. Most of the spying is probably innocent. Beyond this, there may be a point where checking up on your kids may be invading their privacy and likely to be resented, which is counter-productive. Parents need to be approachable and have a trusting relationship. Though this isn&#8217;t easy, it should include their children&#8217;s internet lives. We aim to provide the tools for kids to manage their profiles and find help when they feel vulnerable. We think it&#8217;s important that parents understand that as well as keeping an eye on their kids, they need to have a conversation about digital footprints and how to manage that.&#8221; A teenager&#8217;s right to privacy The discussion at the Digital Diaries launch also looked at the possibility that a child&#8217;s online profile could be compared to their diary. If that is the case, should it have the same level of privacy? Kuncewicz says that a reasonable approach is needed when it comes to tackling the privacy of children. &#8220;You have to consider whether the things that kids do have a reasonable expectation of privacy. Balance their human right to their private family life against whether their parents can intrude. Parents should be looking at this sort of thing because it is easy to advocate responsibility to Facebook but in my experience, people don&#8217;t tend to use the tools available or read the terms of use to understand the controls you have. It&#8217;s easier to block someone on a social network than it is to make sure your kids aren&#8217;t &#8216;sexting&#8217; from a mobile phone. Simon Milner says that Facebook&#8217;s controls are becoming better adapted to suit user requirements, &#8220;As a platform like Facebook matures, people get to know the tools available. There&#8217;s a lot more inline control now for users. You can use your timeline as a diary and you can set it so so that only you will see that. We see people using those tools more and more.&#8221; Last year&#8217;s EU Kids Online [PDF] study provided a comprehensive set of data where kids and parents were asked about their online activity. The differences between risk and opportunity were outlined. Most kids in the research played games, learned or communicated online and some were aware of risks. The definitions of risky behaviour for children online may not be entirely clear to all parents but the report goes some way to clarifying this. It says that 40% of 9-16 year old internet users in Europe had looked for new friends, 34% added people to their networks that they had never met face-to-face. 15% had sent personal information to someone they had never met face-to-face and 14% had sent a photo or video of themselves to someone they had never met. Though some parents may be wary of breaking the bond of trust with their children, talking through the issues and providing support should help children be prepared for when children feel hassled or uncomfortable online. Social and networking maturity There have been recent cases highlighted where job interviewees or established employees have allegedly been asked for their passwords for social networking sites. But even without bizarrely asking permission for the keys to someone&#8217;s profile, there is concern that young people are not always aware of the consequences of their actions online and how that may impact on their later life decisions. Simon Milner says that it is to be expected that parents would be concerned about this. &#8220;It&#8217;s the same with everything to do with teenage children,&#8221; he says. &#8220;You worry about everything but it is dependent on the child and how they act too. When it comes to digital technologies, parents have always worried about the latest innovation, television, mobile phones and now digital footprint and social networks. Services like Facebook are set up to control a digital footprint and parents are best equipped to advise on life decisions. You cannot stop kids from making mistakes and in some cases sometimes children need to make mistakes so that they can learn.&#8221; Kuncewicz says that employers are still finding their way when it comes to the acceptable boundaries of vetting prospective employees. He also points out that there are areas where social profiles can cross over into the information that a prospective employer is not entitled to ask for. &#8220;Employers are struggling to work out what they can use amid the information that is out there. You have to be very careful as an employer possibly using personal data, even when it is posted publicly because there is often information there about religious beliefs, sexual proclivity and a lot of employers will routinely look people up without thinking about the fact that there may be a data protection problem or other issue under the equality act.&#8221; As the latest instalment of Digital Diaries covers young people up until the age of 17, it is on target for the age where kids are thinking about applications to universities. Ancombe says that he believes that higher education establishments are likely to be searching the profiles of prospective students. Facebook does go some way to protecting minors on its site so at least if they are prone to posting indiscretions, it is not as easy to spot. &#8220;We have default settings that make the profiles of under 18s more private,&#8221; says Milner. &#8220;They are not searchable. So even the things they think they are showing to everyone, they&#8217;re not. It&#8217;s important to ensure that your kids have the right age on their profile, to ensure they don&#8217;t get inappropriate adverts but also to ensure that by default they are more private than adult users.&#8221; But there is research that says there are many users of Facebook who are too young and not only do parents know that their underaged kids are on social networks but that they actively helped them to get there. Milner says that underaged children are not welcome on Facebook. &#8220;We don&#8217;t want kids under thirteen on the platform and we will deactivate and delete these accounts. It&#8217;s an issue we are aware of but we don&#8217;t have a solution to it, other platforms have the same problem and no one has a solution to it.&#8221; Digital schooling So who is responsible for the digital education of youth? In many other aspects of growing up, teachers as well as parents take a role in child development. Should social networks also play their part? Milner feels that there should at least be acknowledgement. &#8220;I think that the role of bringing up kids is between parents, teachers and wider society,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Facebook knows that it has a role to play in how children mature digitally. Teachers have a tough job and I don&#8217;t think we should suggest that managing their pupils social media profiles should be their prime role. &#8220;Not only can we think of social networking in education in terms of e-safety but there is a sense that schools can and are using Facebook for education where people can learn in a more social way. Facebook in schools, rather than be a worry for teachers, could be a useful tool.&#8221; Naturally this tallies with the roll out of FB pages for schools currently beginning in the States. Milner says that already groups are available now and people can set up and control very carefully who has access to it. The difference with the Facebook Communities product is that it has tools so that only people with an email account for that specific institution can access it. Milner did not know when the Facebook communities pages for schools would be coming to the UK and clarified that one of the issues that has come up along this process is how best to transfer an existing group to a community page. He says that the issue is still being worked through. The implementation of official school pages for schools may also broach the awkward area of teacher-pupil relations online. Kuncewicz says that teachers have been warned off online communication with pupils in the past so the provision of services like this may offer some clarity about the boundaries between teachers and their students online. With mobile Web, peer pressure for kids to have technology earlier and teenagers accessing the web in their rooms, it&#8217;s no wonder that parents worry about what their offspring may be getting into digitally. This research on habits and interaction at least goes some way to knowing what to expect as more and younger children arrive online.</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/04/21/our-children-and-facebook-avg-releases-its-latest-digital-diaries-research/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/04/21/our-children-and-facebook-avg-releases-its-latest-digital-diaries-research/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Nike Makes a Soccer Uniform From 13 Recycled Bottles [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>At the European soccer championships this June, top national teams including the Netherlands, Portugal and France will be decked out in stylish new Nike uniforms. But there&#8217;s a catch &#8212; the &#8220;kits,&#8221; as they&#8217;re called, are made from recycled bottles. It takes an average of 13 plastic bottles to manufacture a set of uniforms and shorts. The video above gives some insight &#8212; albeit choppily edited, music-heavy insight &#8212; into how the uniforms are made. The two-minute spot &#8212; which gained more than 60,000 views in its first three days on YouTube &#8212; was a collaboration between Nike and the marketing outfits Conscious Minds and Optimist LA. Check it out above and let us know what you think in the comments. More About: Advertising, Nike, sports</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/nike-soccer-uniform/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/nike-soccer-uniform/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cadillac Teases &#8216;Super Cruise&#8217; Semi-Autonomous Car [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Cadillac took a step closer to the self-driving car, showing off Super Cruise, encompassing way-cool features that edge ever-so-closer to automatic pilot on the highways. It&#8217;s not nearly as advanced as Google&#8217;s self-driving vehicle. Cadillac warns that this new semi-autonomous driving tech only works under certain optimal conditions, assisting you with automatic steering, braking and lane-centering on highways. It uses a combination of radar, ultrasonic sensors, cameras and GPS map data to keep that Caddy on the straight-and-narrow. We&#8217;re a bit concerned about this almost driverless tech &#8212; might some drivers depend on it too much, only to be unpleasantly surprised by its limitations? Don&#8217;t expect to pick up a cruisemobile with these features on board just yet &#8212; Cadillac&#8217;s not making any promises about when Super Cruise will make its big debut, but teases us with the possibility of it appearing in Cadillacs by the middle of this decade. More About: Cadillac, cars, self-driving car, TechFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/cadillac-super-cruise-car/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/21/cadillac-super-cruise-car/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Social Media Into Your Integrated Marketing Communications (IMC) Plan</title>
      <description>Integrated Marketing Communications (IMC) is a process of planning, executing, and monitoring the brand messages that create customer relationships. Like social networking, IMC is about managing day to day interactions with customers and prospects.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/crthts/492724/integrating-social-media-your-integrated-marketing-communications-imc-plan</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/crthts/492724/integrating-social-media-your-integrated-marketing-communications-imc-plan</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
