<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Does Social Media Marketing Really Work? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>From Twitter to Facebook, to Google+, to YouTube, to Foursquare and more, social media use is the hottest thing in marketing. But does it really work? Brands and businesses are certainly making a stronger push than ever on social media, which makes sense &#8212; that&#8217;s where the people are. Figuring out just how much social media marketing returns on investments of time and money, however, is harder to do. Facebook marketing company Pagemodo recently pulled research from sources around the web to produce the infographic below, looking at just how much faith marketers have in social media. The aggregated data shows a sense of conservative optimism. 64% of business owners say social media marketing is a promising tactic and they believe it provides returns &#8212; but they aren&#8217;t willing to go all in with it just yet and favor a more cautious approach. 20% are more bullish on its potential, according to the same study, while just 6% are hardcore skeptics. How do marketers and entrepreneurs measure whether social media marketing pays off? Most do so by measuring the accumulation of friends, likes, followers and other online connections. 39% look at shares of brand content, while 35% measure actual leads from social media. Just 18% measure success by overall brand awareness and favorability as gauged by consumer surveys. Check out the infographic below for more on how much faith businesses put in social media as a marketing tool, and for tips on additional ways to maximize results and measure influence. Then let us know in the comments &#8212; do you think social media marketing provides real results? Thumbnail image via iStockphoto, courtneyk More About: infographics, Marketing, social media marketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/social-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/social-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>App Helps Steer You to Lowest Gas Prices [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>More than 30 million people will drive at least 50 miles over Memorial Day Weekend, according to results a survey from the AAA. No matter where they fill up their tanks along the way, they&#8217;ll likely spend less money on gas than last year. National gas prices on Friday averaged $3.67 per gallon, down from $3.81 a year ago. Those who still want to beat the average, however, can get some help from an app called GasBuddy. The app, which is available for both Android and iPhone devices, crowdsources gas prices and directs users to the stations where they&#8217;re lowest. Watch a demo of the app in the video above and tell us in the comments where you&#8217;ll be headed this weekend. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, aydinmutlu More About: gas, gas buddyFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/gasbuddy-demo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/gasbuddy-demo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Facebook Integration Shows What Your Friends Are Learning</title>
      <description>The Pinterest-like website for learning that the founders of Grockit launched Thursday now has a Facebook integration that shows your friends what you&#8217;re learning. Learnist, the newly launched product, allows anyone to compile content pieces onto a board (they call it a &#8220;learning&#8221;) that may look familiar. Unlike Pinterest, however, creators suggest a path in which to consume each content component. Users can check off each component as they go or &#8220;re-add&#8221; it to one of their own learnings. The idea is to avoid the misinformation, hacked-together how-to articles and other useless content one must weed through in a typical Google search and instead provide a clear learning path that will eventually include some form of assessment. Topics range from the frivolous &#8212; like how to find the best pizza in Brooklyn &#8212; to common core standards taught in classrooms. Regardless of which of them you look at, you can now assure your Facebook friends you&#8217;re getting smarter. More About: education, Grockit, learnist</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/learnist-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/learnist-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behold: The First Video Taken with Google Glasses</title>
      <description>Google has debuted the first video taken with its new set of eyewear from its Project Glass project. And for those of you who haven&#8217;t been keeping up, Project Glass&#8217; sci-fi-looking glasses allow a person to do many of the same things you do with your smartphone, except without the need of a separate device. The eyewear will display user interfaces for different programs, allow you to snap pictures, and as we said, even record live video that is likely to cause nausea in some people upon viewing. Over the past week, Google co-founder Sergey Brin and others from the company have been field testing the eyewear, and taking pictures to show off what it can do in a real life setting. We&#8217;ve embedded the video below of a Google employee performing flips on a trampoline. Let us know what you think in the comments. Photo via Google Filed under: offBeat, VentureBeat</description>
      <link>http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/25/google-glasses-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</link>
      <guid>http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/25/google-glasses-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Pushes &#8216;Close Friends&#8217; List, Becomes More Like Google+</title>
      <description>Facebook is testing a new feature called Close Friends, which lets you know every action the people you add to the list take on the social network. Facebook told Mashable it began the push to some users Thursday. When you sign into Facebook, you&#8217;ll be prompted to &#8220;Star Your Close Friends&#8221; to guarantee you don&#8217;t miss their important moments. In other words, you can now stay close to people you indicate as high-priority friends without ever interacting, visiting their profile or catching an update in your news feed. Facebook&#8217;s explanation of the new features emphasizes organizing your friends into Smart Lists, based on where you work, live, went to school or family, to ensure you share with just the right people. You can also view a news feed of your Close Friends update &#8212; much like a feed of a certain Google+ circle &#8212; by selecting the list from below the Friends tab on the left-hand side. I decided to try out the new feature Friday morning, by adding about 20 friends to my Close Friends list. I added stars &#8212; Facebook conveniently suggests a pretty good idea of who you consider your close friends based on your interactions &#8212; and was ensured my friends wouldn&#8217;t know they&#8217;d been added to my list. Within an hour, I&#8217;d received a handful of notifications &#8212; only none of them had anything to do with me. My friends had joined events, shared stories and posted to their Timelines and I didn&#8217;t miss a beat. I was eager to test out the feature because it seemed like an easier way to create lists &#8212; something I&#8217;ve been meaning to do on Facebook since Google+ rolled out its Circles feature. But the Close Friends feature became annoying as soon as my phone was flooded with status updates that looked like this one (taken from the phone of someone who put me on their Close Friends list): If you receive mobile notifications from Facebook, it will send you an update every time someone you add to the list takes an action. If you&#8217;ve never restricted your push notifications on mobile before, this feature might be the one to drive you to cut some of them. Do you organize your Facebook friends into lists? If so, do you only share certain posts with certain people? BONUS: 10 Facebook Tips for Power Users 1. View Photos Full-Screen You can browse Facebook photos in full-screen mode, making for a better gallery viewing experience. In an album, click on the first image, then hover over the photo. A floating menu will appear along the bottom of the image. Click on "Options" and you'll see the ability to "Enter Fullscreen." Now you can browse with a clean, black background. To return to normal mode, simply hit the Escape key or the "X" on the top-right of your display.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, GoogleFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/facebook-close-friends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/facebook-close-friends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Pushes &#8216;Close Friends&#8217; List, Becomes More Like Google+</title>
      <description>Facebook is testing a new feature called Close Friends, which lets you know every action the people you add to the list take on the social network. Facebook told Mashable it began the push to some users Thursday. When you sign into Facebook, you&#8217;ll be prompted to &#8220;Star Your Close Friends&#8221; to guarantee you don&#8217;t miss their important moments. In other words, you can now stay close to people you indicate as high-priority friends without ever interacting, visiting their profile or catching an update in your news feed. Facebook&#8217;s explanation of the new features emphasizes organizing your friends into Smart Lists, based on where you work, live, went to school or family, to ensure you share with just the right people. You can also view a news feed of your Close Friends update &#8212; much like a feed of a certain Google+ circle &#8212; by selecting the list from below the Friends tab on the left-hand side. I decided to try out the new feature Friday morning, by adding about 20 friends to my Close Friends list. I added stars &#8212; Facebook conveniently suggests a pretty good idea of who you consider your close friends based on your interactions &#8212; and was ensured my friends wouldn&#8217;t know they&#8217;d been added to my list. Within an hour, I&#8217;d received a handful of notifications &#8212; only none of them had anything to do with me. My friends had joined events, shared stories and posted to their Timelines and I didn&#8217;t miss a beat. I was eager to test out the feature because it seemed like an easier way to create lists &#8212; something I&#8217;ve been meaning to do on Facebook since Google+ rolled out its Circles feature. But the Close Friends feature became annoying as soon as my phone was flooded with status updates that looked like this one (taken from the phone of someone who put me on their Close Friends list): If you receive mobile notifications from Facebook, it will send you an update every time someone you add to the list takes an action. If you&#8217;ve never restricted your push notifications on mobile before, this feature might be the one to drive you to cut some of them. Do you organize your Facebook friends into lists? If so, do you only share certain posts with certain people? BONUS: 10 Facebook Tips for Power Users 1. View Photos Full-Screen You can browse Facebook photos in full-screen mode, making for a better gallery viewing experience. In an album, click on the first image, then hover over the photo. A floating menu will appear along the bottom of the image. Click on "Options" and you'll see the ability to "Enter Fullscreen." Now you can browse with a clean, black background. To return to normal mode, simply hit the Escape key or the "X" on the top-right of your display.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, GoogleFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/facebook-close-friends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/facebook-close-friends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;The Avengers&#8217;: The First All-Star Movie By Design</title>
      <description>Jeff Gomez is CEO of Starlight Runner Entertainment, a New York based production company that consults with Hollywood studios on some of their most popular entertainment franchises. Follow him @Jeff_Gomez. With some industry observers projecting global box office revenues as high as $2 billion for The Avengers, it&#8217;s clear that the film is an unprecedented success. Many have pegged Marvel Studios franchise producer Kevin Feige&#8217;s creative and strategic approach in building a shared &#8220;story world&#8221; out of a series of movies (Iron Man, Incredible Hulk, Iron Man II, Captain America and Thor) that coalesced into a kind of all-star movie in Joss Whedon&#8217;s Avengers. But contrary to popular belief, this is not the first time a mess of heroes (or anti-heroes) have been assembled in the service of a greater purpose&#8218; or multiple revenue streams. Our love of team-ups, in fact, dates back to the Stone Age. Early man imbued all things around him with animus, and the coolest things &#8212; the sun, the moon, the ocean &#8212; were either the incarnations of, or controlled by superior beings, gods. It was just a matter of time before pantheons formed, relationships got complicated, and villains arose to challenge the benevolent. In the Beginning In the myth of Jason and the Argonauts, stalwart and charismatic Jason assembled a crew of some of the hottest celebs of his day in order to retrieve the Golden Fleece. These included Hercules, Medea and Orpheus, all stars of their own myths and legends. In The Iliad, the epic poet Homer (the Joss Whedon of his time) brings together dozens of Greek gods and heroes and crashes them into the Trojan War. The story was such a hit, Homer followed up some years later with a sequel in The Odyssey. In the late 15th century, Thomas Malory took a mass of tales and legends around the character of King Arthur and wove them into a single story called Le Morte d&#8217;Arthur. There we see all of the heroic Knights of the Round Table (Lancelot, Galahad, Perceval, Gawain, etc.) united for the first time. A century later, the Italians were having fun mixing and matching prominent characters&#8218; often portrayed in masks and capes&#8218; from literature, theater and opera in their Commedia dell&#8217;Arte. Heroic pantheons became a motif in so-called low art in the 19th and 20th centuries. Pulp anti-heroes or notorious gunslingers met one another in dime store novels, but the comic books of the 1940s kicked things up a notch, uniting some of the most powerful and popular costumed heroes of the time to save the world from certain doom. All-Star Comics #3, for instance, introduced us to The Justice Society of America, teaming Hawkman, the Flash, the Spectre, Green Lantern and others in adventures that must have certainly blown young minds. From &#8220;Frankenstein&#8221; to Manga But the precedent that most clearly laid the foundation for Avengers can be tracked back to the great horror movies from Universal Pictures in the &#8217;40s. After experiencing huge hits with such films as Dracula and Frankenstein, the studio took a cue from the comic books of the time and started cross-pollinating their franchise. So Frankenstein Meets the Wolf Man was followed by House of Frankenstein, where posters screamed, &#8220;All Together! Frankenstein&#8217;s Monster, Wolf Man, Dracula! Hunchback! Mad Doctor!&#8221; The monsters would reunite two more times, until popular comedy duo Abbott and Costello killed them off once and for all by making the whole situation laughable. You might say the Japanese have had the most fun with pop culture pantheons. With the rise of the post-World War II ethos of keiretsu, concepts and characters tended to flow more easily between formal rival media companies. Heroes and villains could more readily show up in one another&#8217;s storylines, and the rest of the world got to enjoy the results with such franchises as Toho&#8217;s giant monster movies. Godzilla Versus Mothra featured the first rubber-suited cross-over, but no child of the &#8217;60s could ever forget Destroy All Monsters, uniting Godzilla, Rodan, Anguiras and a megaton of other goggle-eyed kaiju in defense of the Earth against the triple-headed, lightning-spitting King Ghidorah. Always game to top themselves, the Japanese have more recently been mixing and mashing their own superhero franchises on television and in theaters. Five, 10 and 30 Kamen Riders, each from their own TV series, have banded together to save the world from escalating menaces. Check out this awesome team-up of every Power Ranger who ever existed in an epic battle against an alien armada from the climactic episode of Kaizoku Sentai Gokaiger: Crafting For Greatness So what makes Marvel&#8217;s Avengers different from all of these previous mash-ups? A few things, actually. By all accounts, Kevin Feige and his team laid out a vision for how every Marvel movie would dovetail into the others, each introducing characters and elements that come into play in the others, all building toward Avengers. No writer, director or studio exec had incorporated this level of planning into how his or her franchise would unfold and interlock, not even George Lucas for his Star Wars movies. In addition to somehow skirting all the reasons why such an endeavor could not be possible under contemporary Hollywood business and creative constraints, Marvel Studios also played the technology and digital distribution cards like no other in history. Armed with the knowledge that their superheroes are the closest things we have to a godlike pantheon, Marvel worked triple-time over the several years to dust off these characters and reintroduce them to the world. Animated series, chapter books, action figures, video games, Blu-rays loaded with crash courses in Avengers lore, even a million-dollar Facebook game that mixed X-Men and Spider-Man into the four-color stew. We were set up like ten-pins and Avengers, as recounted by the cleverly chosen Joss &#8220;Homer&#8221; Whedon, could only bowl us over. Here&#8217;s both the takeaway and the challenge studios face in the wake of Avengers: a well-known and coherent story world is a rare and precious thing, and there is great power in a grand unifying narrative. Replicating Success The threads that tie 20th Century Fox&#8217;s X-Men franchise together are loose at best, with various filmmakers fraying even those with different, often contradictory takes on the material. Warner Bros. approach to the DC heroes has been almost entirely auteur-driven, with Batman, Superman and Green Lantern existing in entirely different universes. It will be some years before any of those characters can meet on the big screen, even if the studio wanted them to. We experience a certain kind of exhilaration when our gods unite toward a common purpose. That&#8217;s why we have All-Star baseball games, and why we&#8217;ll forever remember how Bruce Springsteen, Stevie Wonder, Willie Nelson, Michael Jackson, Tina Turner and a host of others joined forces to sing &#8220;We Are the World&#8221; for starving people in Africa. They are our champions, and their adventures together forge national, and now global narratives. To repeat the success of The Avengers, however, studios will need visionaries up to the cause, new kinds of storytellers as savvy with how narrative unfolds across multiple media platforms, and use licensing campaigns to build equity in lesser known characters, as with how to turn a good scene. Super nerds, thy time has come! More About: contributor, features, Marvel, the avengers, transmediaFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/avengers-planned-pantheon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/avengers-planned-pantheon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The History of Facebook&#8217;s Developer Platform [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>The Facebook Platform&#8217;s stated mission is to &#8220;build the social web.&#8221; With help from social app developers, it certainly met its goal. May 24 marks the fifth anniversary of Facebook Platform. The project first launched at the 2007 f8 conference to 70 app developers, like Washington Post and Digg. Fourteen months later, at f8 2008, more than 30,000 apps existed on Facebook Platform. An extension of Facebook Platform, Facebook introduced Connect at the same 2008 conference. Facebook Connect enabled third-party websites to build social integration into their user experiences. As a result of these developments, Facebook hosted an unparalleled social experience both on its site and off. Companies like Zynga introduced hit games like FarmVille on the platform, and the &#8220;like&#8221; button social plugin launched on external websites. (In the first 24 hours, external site &#8220;like&#8221; buttons received 1 billion impressions.) Not to mention, Facebook Platform opened up the opportunity for additional business transactions &#8212; Disney acquired games company Playdom in 2010, and EA acquired Bejeweled Blitz maker PopCap in 2011. By Sept. 2011, Platform was responsible for creating 182,000 American jobs and a $12.19 billion value to the economy. SEE ALSO: Facebook Tests New Timeline Design [PICS] With the launch of Timeline, Facebook has only expanded the possibilities of app development. And somehow we get the feeling it has only just begun. How have Facbeook&#8217;s social apps on-site and off changed your social experience? Where would Facebook be today, had it not launched Facebook Platform? Here&#8217;s your chance to sound off in the comments below. More About: dev, Facebook, facebook platform, infographics, social apps, Social MediaFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/facebook-developer-platform-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/facebook-developer-platform-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Spotify Apps for Finding New Music</title>
      <description>Nick Cicero is a social media strategist at On Ideas, an integrated creative agency. Follow him @nickcicero. In the never-ending quest to keep our ear buds satisfied, Spotify has emerged as a leader in bringing the social graph to the music listening experience. And with the introduction of Spotify Apps in November, developers were given the option to create new and exciting ways to make that experience even better. The result? A host of great apps that will enhance how you discover music. Here are six we like. 1. We are Hunted The science of social music, We are Hunted pulls in sentiment data from social media, blogs, P2P networks, and message boards to create a playlist of the 99 most talked about songs from emerging and mainstream artists. Click here to view this gallery. More About: contributor, features, online music, spotify, Spotify apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/spotify-apps-music/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/spotify-apps-music/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obama and Romney Go Head-to-Head on Twitter [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>One of the battles in the war for the White House is being fought on Twitter. It&#8217;s common knowledge that Obama&#8217;s beating Romney hand-over-fist in followers: the president has more than 15 million followers, compared to Romney&#8217;s half-million. However, the number of social followers alone doesn&#8217;t mean much &#8212; instead, the key to waging a successful political campaign on Twitter is engagement. Along those lines, how does President Obama&#8217;s Twitter presence stack up with that of Republican rival Mitt Romney? PeekAnalytics, a social audience measurement service, did some digging to find out. President Obama has more than 5,000 times the &#8220;pull,&#8221; or influence, than the average Twitter account, compared to Mitt Romney at 466 times the average. That means Obama has 12 times the influence of Romney. That seems like a clear win in the Obama column &#8212; until you consider that Obama has 30 times the followers that Romney does, meaning Romney is doing a better job of influencing his smaller audience. SEE ALSO: Obama vs. Romney: The Social Showdown Breaking down both presidential contenders&#8217; followers into demographic categories, PeekAnalytics says Obama&#8217;s followers are more international (48% of Obama&#8217;s followers live abroad compared to 10% for Romney), they&#8217;re younger (58% are between the ages of 18-25, whereas 43% of Romney&#8217;s followers are in that bracket), and female (47% for Obama, 29% for Romney) than Romney&#8217;s social audience. Meanwhile, Romney&#8217;s followers tend to have higher incomes (30% of Romney&#8217;s followers make more than $100,000 a year, that category makes up 22% for Obama). Can the candidates&#8217; Twitter following tell us anything about their chances come Election Day? According to PeekAnalytics, a higher percentage of Romney&#8217;s followers come from crucial battleground states, save Ohio. For more, check out PeekAnalytics&#8217; infographic below. Do you think presidential campaigns are using Twitter effectively? Sound off in the comments below. Disclaimer: Mashable and PeekAnalytics have a commercial relationship, but Mashable did not pay for this report. More About: 2012 presidential campaign, barack obama, Mitt Romney, Politics, Social Media, Twitter, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/obama-romney-twitter-head-to-head/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/obama-romney-twitter-head-to-head/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HS Student&#8217;s Social-Media-Fueled Campaign Propels Him Into Local Office</title>
      <description>Josh Lafazan, an 18-year-old high school senior from Syosset, New York, shattered all kinds of records when he was elected to his school district&#8217;s board last week. He became the youngest-ever elected official in New York state, and voter turnout was well above normal. How did Lafazan make such an achievement possible? In part, thanks to smart use of the web and social media. While many commentators are marveling at the Internet&#8217;s ability to bring together large swaths of people from across nations, Lafazan&#8217;s campaign did just the opposite: he used his website and social media, such as Facebook and live video service Spreecast, to bring together his nearby friends and neighbors under his campaign&#8217;s banner. &#8220;Josh was the only candidate for school board to have a personal website,&#8221; said Jake Asman, Lafazan&#8217;s campaign manager and fellow Syosset High School student. &#8220;He really went out there and expressed his campaign views. He used his Facebook page and Spreecast the same way.&#8221; On Spreecast, Lafazan engaged in face-to-face town halls with his soon-to-be constituency. Asman credits the video site with a great deal of the campaign&#8217;s success. &#8220;Spreecast was a big one for us,&#8221; said Asman. &#8220;We had more than 2,000 views on our first Spreecast. Josh was able to interact directly, face-to-face with members of the community. It&#8217;s one thing to have a story on [the local news], it&#8217;s another for people to ask questions directly. He answered every question he got, it took almost two hours.&#8221; Lafazan also built up a sizable community of followers on Facebook. A note he posted thanking his supporters gathered more than 400 likes &#8212; an impressive feat for a candidate in a campaign with only a few thousand voters. Social media proved useful when the campaign took a turn for the bizarre. The Syosset school district accused Lafazan&#8217;s father, Jeffery, of stealing information about the district&#8217;s residents. An automated message that went out to voters before the election said that &#8220;Jeffrey Lafazan unlawfully removed district records that contained the names and addresses of residents. He removed the records without permission and ran away,&#8221; according to NBC. Lafazan&#8217;s father later returned the documents, saying he didn&#8217;t know he wasn&#8217;t allowed to take them. Lafazan, meanwhile, labeled the accusations as a &#8220;smear campaign.&#8221; He took to Facebook to explain his side of what happened, and Asman said that move helped Lafazan beat the rumors. &#8220;When the school district tried to pull their smear campaign, Josh hopped on Facebook and sent out a status with what had really happened,&#8221; said Asman. &#8220;It got 250 likes and 200 shares. People very quickly realized what was happening.&#8221; Of course, Lafazan campaigned hard in the offline world, too. &#8220;He was in the community and the high school every day, interacting with neighbors and other seniors that were 18 and could vote,&#8221; said Asman. Lafazan went on to win the election by more than 2,000 votes, or 82% of the total votes &#8212; and it looks like he&#8217;ll be using social media to govern, not just to campaign. &#8220;If anyone has any suggestions to help improve this district,&#8221; wrote Lafazan in a post-victory Facebook post, &#8220;do not hesitate to contact me and share those ideas with me.&#8221; How is social media changing local elections in your neighborhood? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, sjlocke More About: Facebook, Politics, Social Media, spreecast, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/josh-lafazan-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/josh-lafazan-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ketchup Slides Out of Bottles With LiquiGlide [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Smacking the ketchup bottle to get that last dollop out is a (small) but wide spread problem most people would rather avoid. Scientists at MIT did just that and created a secret substance they dubbed LiquiGlide. Bottles are coated in the FDA-approved substance, and the ketchup just slides right out when you tilt the bottle. The team would like to put the &#8220;super slippery&#8221; substance on numerous other bottles. The bottles for sauces alone is a $17 billion market, one of the scientists said to Fast Company. Another substance with a similar sounding name &#8212; Liquipel &#8212; debuted at CES earlier this year. It is used for waterproofing cellphones, but like LiquiGlide, it has numerous other intended uses. Would you like to see bottle companies adopt the LiquiGlide technology? What else do you think this could be used for? Tell us in the comments. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, fotobazilio &#8236; More About: Inventions, mitFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/ketchup-slides-out-of-bottles-with-liquiglide-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/ketchup-slides-out-of-bottles-with-liquiglide-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
