<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Battery Life Do Your Apps Zap? This Tool Will Check</title>
      <description>A group of UC Berkeley scientists has turned their research about battery life into a handy app that can extend yours. Carat, which is available for iOS and Android, measures your phone's energy use and suggests actions that will make it more efficient. It tells you which of your apps are using the most battery and which may have energy-hogging bugs that can be fixed by re-downloading them. Carat also tells you how your average battery life compares to that of other users. What is hogging battery life on your phone? Let us know in the comments. More About: App, Carat, UC Berkeley</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/carat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/carat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook CTO to Leave This Summer</title>
      <description>Facebook CTO Bret Taylor is planning to leave the company for more entrepreneurial pursuits, Taylor announced Friday afternoon. In a note posted to his Facebook page, Taylor said he was eager to begin work on another startup with his friend Kevin Gibbs, a senior staff software engineer at Google, on a yet-unnamed project. "I had always been upfront with Mark that I eventually wanted to do another startup,&#8221; he said in an interview with AllThingsD's Kara Swisher, which was published at the same time as Taylor's Facebook note. &#8220;And we felt it was the best time after the IPO and the launch of some recent things for me to do that.&#8221; Taylor has overseen Facebook's platform and mobil&#8230; Continue reading... More About: bret taylor, Facebook</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/facebook-cto-bret-taylor-leaving/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/facebook-cto-bret-taylor-leaving/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook CTO to Leave This Summer</title>
      <description>Facebook CTO Bret Taylor is planning to leave the company for more entrepreneurial pursuits, Taylor announced Friday afternoon. In a note posted to his Facebook page, Taylor said he was eager to begin work on another startup with his friend Kevin Gibbs, a senior staff software engineer at Google, on a yet-unnamed project. "I had always been upfront with Mark that I eventually wanted to do another startup,&#8221; he said in an interview with AllThingsD's Kara Swisher, which was published at the same time as Taylor's Facebook note. &#8220;And we felt it was the best time after the IPO and the launch of some recent things for me to do that.&#8221; Taylor has overseen Facebook's platform and mobil&#8230; Continue reading... More About: bret taylor, Facebook</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/facebook-cto-bret-taylor-leaving/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/facebook-cto-bret-taylor-leaving/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook App Center: What Does It Actually Do?</title>
      <description>Facebook announced its App Center Thursday night -- but it wasn't immediately clear how users would benefit, or whether it simply added another layer between you and apps you download to your smartphone. More than 600 apps are featured in the App Center. These apps are not new, and are already able to sync with your Facebook account, should you let them. What has changed: now you can go to Facebook.com/appcenter, and choose apps you want to download on your Android or iOS device. Those apps then show up as notifications in your Facebook mobile app. Click the notification and it will take you to the regular app store on your phone so you can download the app in question. But you still&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apps, Facebook, facebook apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/facebook-app-center-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/facebook-app-center-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Dads Are Plugging In, Getting Social [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do you consider yourself to be a &#8220;digital dad?&#8221; If you use social media to connect with your kids or other parents, count yourself as part of this savvy group. With Father&#8217;s Day around the corner, Euro RSCG Worldwide asked 1,000 dads across the U.S. how the Internet and social media has affected their parenting style, dividing the respondents into groups of &#8220;digital dads&#8221; and &#8220;Average Joes.&#8221; The survey shows dads are plugging in just as much as their teens. In fact, 62% of digital dads say they&#8217;re more tech-savvy than the average 15-year-old. Similarly, more than three-quarters of digital dads and 57% of Average Joes use Facebook, YouTube, Twitter and other sites to monitor their kids&#8217; interactions on the web. While you may think those watchful eyes create friction between parents and teens, the study finds just the opposite. &#8220;Social media is now providing new ways to engage with your family, and also is bringing families closer together,&#8221; says Tom Morton, chief strategy officer, New York and co-chief strategy officer, North America. In the same sentiment, digital dads are forming their own online communities &#8212; 64% have used social media to connect with other parents. Those dads are also sharing more as 52% have written about a parenting experience on the web, and 66% have posted a photo of their child on a social networking site or blog. SEE ALSO: 10 Father&#8217;s Day Gifts For Geeky Dads The survey also finds that the majority of fathers think their kids are smarter as the result of new technology and greater access to information, but they are increasingly becoming less proficient in the English language. Around 76% of digital dads and 68% of Average Joes agree that kids who grow up without access to the Internet are at a serious disadvantage. But those same dads say increasing technology can distract kids, impairing their ability to communicate face to face. And while &#8220;ttyl&#8221; and &#8220;ur&#8221; may be faster to text, dads think this is hurting their kids&#8217; ability to read and write English at expected levels. Check out the infographic below, and tell us how you&#8217;re a &#8220;digital dad&#8221; in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/digital-dads-are-plugging-in-getting-social-infographic/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/digital-dads-are-plugging-in-getting-social-infographic/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School dinner blogger 'banned'</title>
      <description>A nine-year-old girl who became an internet hit after blogging about her school dinners claims she has been banned from taking photographs of her meals</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-18454800</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-18454800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer 7 'tax' a first</title>
      <description>The Australian online retailer Kogan.com has introduced the world's first "tax" on use of Microsoft's Internet Explorer 7 (IE7) browser.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-18440979</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-18440979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Social Media Destroying Real-World Relationships? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>There's no doubt social media enables us to organize our real-world relationships, and even meet new people outside the digital realm -- both of which can be great, life-enhancing things. But could social networking have an adverse effect on our quality of life? Consider this: 24% of respondents to one survey said they've missed out on enjoying special moments in person because -- ironically enough -- they were too busy trying to document their experiences for online sharing. Many of us have had to remind ourselves to "live in the now" -- instead of worry about composing the perfect tweet or angling for just the right Instagram shot. Worldwide, Facebook users spend 10.5 billion m&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, infographics, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/social-media-real-world-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/social-media-real-world-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half of Small Businesses Not Concerned About Security Breaches [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>One billion data records have been compromised in the last eight years -- costing companies about $48 billion -- but not all small businesses are concerned about how a security breach could actually impact them, according to a new infographic. On the heels of the news that nearly 1.5 million passwords were compromised from LinkedIn and eHarmony, information security firm Shred-It released an infographic that looks at how companies view both paper and electronic data breaches. Shred-It conducted a survey among 1,136 U.S. small business owners with companies of fewer than 100 employees, and 100 corporate-level executives who work for companies with a minimum of 500 employees. It's import&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, security</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/security-breach-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/security-breach-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half of Small Businesses Not Concerned About Security Breaches [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>One billion data records have been compromised in the last eight years -- costing companies about $48 billion -- but not all small businesses are concerned about how a security breach could actually impact them, according to a new infographic. On the heels of the news that nearly 1.5 million passwords were compromised from LinkedIn and eHarmony, information security firm Shred-It released an infographic that looks at how companies view both paper and electronic data breaches. Shred-It conducted a survey among 1,136 U.S. small business owners with companies of fewer than 100 employees, and 100 corporate-level executives who work for companies with a minimum of 500 employees. It's import&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, security</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/security-breach-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/security-breach-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Hot Trends Driving Men&#8217;s Ecommerce</title>
      <description>Andres Izquieta is co-founder/CEO of Five Four Club, a new subscription ecommerce service that provides men with monthly packages of apparel, based on a brief sixty-second style profile they fill out when signing up for the service. When it comes to ecommerce categories like grooming and fashion, the women&#8217;s market has long been the focus of marketers. And who can blame them. Women historically make upwards of 80% of the purchase decisions in the home, they&#8217;re statistically more active online, and tend to maintain longer session times on websites. Plus, they&#8217;re natural &#8216;window shoppers&#8217; &#8212; in the physical and virtual world. That said, in the past year, the men&#8217;s ecommerce market has seen more than a half dozen ecommerce launches, including Mr. Porter, Birchbox Man, and Dollar Shave Club. Here are the six major trends driving this growth. Five years ago, the number of male-focused online retail sites in categories such as fashion and style were limited, in part because it was widely believed that men don&#8217;t shop online. However, according to a recent iProspect survey , 70% of men research and buy online, with 67% making more than one purchase each month. The result: according to IBM Global Business Services , the sales of men&#8217;s apparel was on track to grow 8.26% in the first half of 2012. This is the largest increase seen in the category in decades. Ten years ago a man&#8217;s grooming products, like a lot of his clothing, were based on what was available at local, mass-market stores. A review of media and marketing at the time showed just a few male-focused magazines on the market to give men the access and exposure that helps drive purchases. With online content, social networks, and other tools, men are now being exposed to more options than in the past. This has created a new and growing appetite to expand tastes, styles, and products. In addition, online retailers can tap into what men seek and need in a way that offline retailers, because of issues like overhead, can not. For example, a recent industry trend study said that up to 37% of male shoppers check social networks for comparison shopping and other related information. For many women shoppers, abundance and variety are often key. For most men, it is usually the opposite. One look inside a man&#8217;s medicine chest or under his sink will often yield to a small handful of key products. A single item, such as a jacket, can carry him through most wardrobe needs. For men, it&#8217;s not about the volume of merchandise, but the right items to fit his various lifestyle needs. Concepts like &#8216;curated&#8217; shopping, styling services, and pared down collections, such as Gilt Man, can do well when targeting the online male shopping consumer. When it comes to purchases, male shoppers just want to get what they need and get it fast. That doesn&#8217;t mean that thought and time doesn&#8217;t go into what men buy, or that men don&#8217;t do their fare share of browsing within their shopping experiences. But ease and access are important components. That&#8217;s why subscription commerce concepts are booming in the men&#8217;s online shopping category. These services often require little more than a minute or so of time and conveniently provide whatever a man needs. It&#8217;s not a surprise to then see the explosion of companies like Dollar Shave Club or Birchbox Man. These services enable men to receive what they need in a streamlined way. A new breed of companies, brands, and retailers are tapping into specific niche spaces. This can be as specific as body type, shoes, or other specialty needs. Companies like Karmaloop hit the urban street style, while Mr. Porter tends to the professional male. The average consumer will return to a product he or she believes works for them over and over again. This is consistent regardless of gender, income, or other factors that drive offline or online purchases. By consistently giving men not only what they want, but in the way that they want, dozens of legacy brands like Dockers and Banana Republic have secured and maintained loyal male followings. Upstart companies, be it in subscription commerce, specialty retail, curated shopping, or discount merchandise, can achieve the same by adhering to where and what motivates male consumers at the core level. This can help drive men to a brand and keep them there.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/trends-men-online-shopping/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/trends-men-online-shopping/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Hot Trends Driving Men&#8217;s Ecommerce</title>
      <description>Andres Izquieta is co-founder/CEO of Five Four Club, a new subscription ecommerce service that provides men with monthly packages of apparel, based on a brief sixty-second style profile they fill out when signing up for the service. When it comes to ecommerce categories like grooming and fashion, the women&#8217;s market has long been the focus of marketers. And who can blame them. Women historically make upwards of 80% of the purchase decisions in the home, they&#8217;re statistically more active online, and tend to maintain longer session times on websites. Plus, they&#8217;re natural &#8216;window shoppers&#8217; &#8212; in the physical and virtual world. That said, in the past year, the men&#8217;s ecommerce market has seen more than a half dozen ecommerce launches, including Mr. Porter, Birchbox Man, and Dollar Shave Club. Here are the six major trends driving this growth. Five years ago, the number of male-focused online retail sites in categories such as fashion and style were limited, in part because it was widely believed that men don&#8217;t shop online. However, according to a recent iProspect survey , 70% of men research and buy online, with 67% making more than one purchase each month. The result: according to IBM Global Business Services , the sales of men&#8217;s apparel was on track to grow 8.26% in the first half of 2012. This is the largest increase seen in the category in decades. Ten years ago a man&#8217;s grooming products, like a lot of his clothing, were based on what was available at local, mass-market stores. A review of media and marketing at the time showed just a few male-focused magazines on the market to give men the access and exposure that helps drive purchases. With online content, social networks, and other tools, men are now being exposed to more options than in the past. This has created a new and growing appetite to expand tastes, styles, and products. In addition, online retailers can tap into what men seek and need in a way that offline retailers, because of issues like overhead, can not. For example, a recent industry trend study said that up to 37% of male shoppers check social networks for comparison shopping and other related information. For many women shoppers, abundance and variety are often key. For most men, it is usually the opposite. One look inside a man&#8217;s medicine chest or under his sink will often yield to a small handful of key products. A single item, such as a jacket, can carry him through most wardrobe needs. For men, it&#8217;s not about the volume of merchandise, but the right items to fit his various lifestyle needs. Concepts like &#8216;curated&#8217; shopping, styling services, and pared down collections, such as Gilt Man, can do well when targeting the online male shopping consumer. When it comes to purchases, male shoppers just want to get what they need and get it fast. That doesn&#8217;t mean that thought and time doesn&#8217;t go into what men buy, or that men don&#8217;t do their fare share of browsing within their shopping experiences. But ease and access are important components. That&#8217;s why subscription commerce concepts are booming in the men&#8217;s online shopping category. These services often require little more than a minute or so of time and conveniently provide whatever a man needs. It&#8217;s not a surprise to then see the explosion of companies like Dollar Shave Club or Birchbox Man. These services enable men to receive what they need in a streamlined way. A new breed of companies, brands, and retailers are tapping into specific niche spaces. This can be as specific as body type, shoes, or other specialty needs. Companies like Karmaloop hit the urban street style, while Mr. Porter tends to the professional male. The average consumer will return to a product he or she believes works for them over and over again. This is consistent regardless of gender, income, or other factors that drive offline or online purchases. By consistently giving men not only what they want, but in the way that they want, dozens of legacy brands like Dockers and Banana Republic have secured and maintained loyal male followings. Upstart companies, be it in subscription commerce, specialty retail, curated shopping, or discount merchandise, can achieve the same by adhering to where and what motivates male consumers at the core level. This can help drive men to a brand and keep them there.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/trends-men-online-shopping/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/trends-men-online-shopping/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
