<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips for Dealing With Upset Facebook Fans</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/how-to/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="social media how to" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/how-to-pose.png" alt="social media how to" width="190" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What do you do when &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;#8217;ve just received a less-than-complimentary Facebook wall post&lt;/strong&gt; from someone who likes your business (or used to, so it seems)?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The customer could have a simple complaint, or be so upset he&amp;#8217;s gone on the offensive, making sure you and the rest of your community knows he&amp;#8217;s angry.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your next steps are key&lt;/strong&gt; to retaining not only the business of the angry customer, but the business of other fans who like your page as well.&lt;span id="more-11382"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#1: Respond no matter what&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s vitally important that the complaints and issues your fans pose on your wall are addressed. &lt;strong&gt;Inactivity on your part will appear as though you&amp;#8217;re trying to ignore the issue&lt;/strong&gt; and sweep it under the rug. Being unresponsive does nothing more than incite more anger and increase the chance the user will come back with even more angry wall posts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Moreover, your community can see that angry post. If you don&amp;#8217;t reply, it appears as though you are unconcerned with customer support, which can be detrimental to your reputation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A response that illustrates respect and understanding for customers&amp;#8217; concerns will&lt;strong&gt; indicate your intention to rectify any problems.&lt;/strong&gt; By addressing this upset fan, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/Newegg?sk=wall" target="_blank"&gt;Newegg&lt;/a&gt; is demonstrating that they value their fans&amp;#8217; opinions&#8212;even the negative ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 465px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0811jb-new-egg.png" alt="Newegg" width="455" height="208" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An upset fan who promises to shop Newegg less frequently still receives prompt, respectful customer service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#2: Be patient and understanding&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In dealing with upset fans, you must &lt;strong&gt;remember that you are closer to your industry, products and services than they are&lt;/strong&gt;. What may seem like basic, common knowledge to you is often foreign to the end user.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take a step back and &lt;strong&gt;put yourself in your customer&amp;#8217;s shoes&lt;/strong&gt;. This can go a long way in understanding why he or she is frustrated. It may not be your company&amp;#8217;s fault that the customer is upset.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Whether or not the fault lies on your end, &lt;em&gt;a simple apology will go a long way in keeping the customer&amp;#8217;s business.&lt;/em&gt; Instead of trying to figure out where the blame lies, &lt;strong&gt;turn upset fans into loyal customers by making their experience better&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#3: Contact the Customer Privately&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sending a private message or email to the customer opens up more options for you to address his or her complaints. The goal here is to &lt;strong&gt;extend some sort of token letting the customer know you&amp;#8217;re sorry&lt;/strong&gt; he or she is dissatisfied with your company, and you&amp;#8217;re willing to make it right. Whether that&amp;#8217;s offering the number of the manager&amp;#8217;s direct phone line or a discount off the next purchase, moving the conversation from public to private allows you to&lt;strong&gt; give the customer a personal touch that signals you care.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, offering things like direct lines and special discounts publicly can lead to other people creating problems just to get that special treatment, so it&amp;#8217;s best to keep these practices off the wall.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/hayneedle?sk=wall" target="_blank"&gt;Hayneedle&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; customer shown below isn&amp;#8217;t visibly upset about the damaged order, Hayneedle handles the situation perfectly, and contacts the customer privately to resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 465px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0811jb-hayneedle.png" alt="hayneedle" width="455" height="156" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Hayneedle moves conversation with a customer from the Facebook wall to private messages to better help the customer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#4: Consider asking the fan to remove the post&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Say you&amp;#8217;ve discussed the issue privately, any problems have been straightened out, and the faultfinder is, once again, your happy customer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While your wall is an integral part of your web presence, the customer may be unaware of how important it really is to your reputation. If he or she is satisfied with the resolution you&amp;#8217;ve reached and grateful for the time you&amp;#8217;ve spent making things right, &lt;strong&gt;there&amp;#8217;s nothing wrong with privately asking the person to remove the post. &lt;/strong&gt;Most of the time, he or she will remove the angry wall post.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#5: Respond back to the original post&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a general rule, you, the Facebook page admin, should not remove negative posts. &lt;/em&gt;Not everyone is going to have a glowing review of your product or company. Social media users know this, and if they see nothing but positive comments, they&amp;#8217;ll assume your company is deleting the bad comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t feel comfortable asking your customer to remove the post, you do have the option of publicly responding back to that post. &lt;strong&gt;Express happiness in the resolution you&amp;#8217;ve reached and thankfulness for her business&lt;/strong&gt;. Even a negative post can be a good thing, as long as the last comment is positive. Your reputation among your community will soar when &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/top-5-social-media-myths-debunked/" target="_blank"&gt;they see how well you take care of your customers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/zappos?sk=wall" target="_blank"&gt;Zappos&lt;/a&gt; is shown below addressing a negative comment. The helpful attitude effectively nullifies any poor reflection on Zappos or their services.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 465px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0811jb-zappos.png" alt="zappos" width="455" height="119" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Zappos responds quickly with understanding and a desire to create a better experience for their upset fan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#6: Let your community respond&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Letting your community respond for you is really the end result of all the earlier steps. It requires copious time, energy and patience with your fans, and a fantastic product. After you&amp;#8217;ve engaged with your fans for a period of time by answering questions and offering support, you&amp;#8217;ll notice that your fans will be more active on your page, even to the point of assisting each other.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s great about getting this community support is that there&amp;#8217;s a genuine credibility when fans endorse your business for you. They become your eager virtual support agents, answering questions and solving problems before you have a chance to. But this is a level you can only achieve if you&amp;#8217;ve nurtured and supported your community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ThePamperedChef?sk=wall" target="_blank"&gt;The Pampered Chef&lt;/a&gt; has built a fantastic online community of users who love the product so much, and who have been given such great support themselves, peers will answer each other&amp;#8217;s questions before The Pampered Chef has to respond.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 465px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0811jb-pampered-chef.png" alt="pampered chef" width="455" height="383" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An outpouring of community support is the direct result of The Pampered Chef&amp;#39;s top-notch customer service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#7: The Last Resort&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;If the offended party is unreceptive to your customer service attempts, blatantly hostile and only active in your community to start arguments, banning the individual is a last-resort option. And anyone leveling expletives or racial slurs against your staff or fans should be banned. Your staff and your fans don&amp;#8217;t deserve to be subjected to the abuse, and in the end, they will respect you more because you took the initiative.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#8217;s been your experience? How has your business handled complaints from upset fans on your Facebook wall in the past?&lt;/strong&gt; What has worked? What hasn&amp;#8217;t? Leave your comments in the box below. &lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2F7-tips-for-dealing-with-upset-facebook-fans%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/7-tips-for-dealing-with-upset-facebook-fans/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="7 Tips for Dealing With Upset Facebook Fans &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/7-tips-for-dealing-with-upset-facebook-fans/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/7-tips-for-dealing-with-upset-facebook-fans/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why CNN Acquired Zite [INTERVIEW]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/20777645?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In tablets generally and the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/07/08/ipad-usage-report/"&gt;iPad particularly&lt;/a&gt;, consumers have found a device conducive to reading news.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s no surprise then that a growing number of newsreading apps have appeared, from individual, branded apps such as the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/03/22/wsj-ipad-single-issues/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; for iPad &lt;/a&gt; to independent apps such as &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/flipboard"&gt;Flipboard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/editions"&gt;Editions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/zite"&gt;Zite&lt;/a&gt;, which are designed for consuming content from a variety of sources.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The last of these was &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/cnn-acquires-zite/"&gt;acquired by CNN Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;. In an emailed statement, CNN&amp;#8217;s general manager of digital, KC Estenson, suggested that Zite will continue to work with a wide array of media partners and that its technology will also be leveraged &amp;#8220;to help CNN&amp;#8217;s websites and apps serve more personalized content, making our current digital services even better.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Zite would continue to operate as an independent company on a day-to-day basis under existing CEO Mark Johnson, the statement said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Still, we were left with many questions. Why Zite? Will it truly remain independent? Will the new subsidiary be free to strike partnerships with other media outlets? Will the algorithms be tweaked to feature CNN content more prominently?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;These are some of the questions we posed to both Estenson and Johnson in a phone interview Tuesday afternoon, parts of which are transcribed below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;#038;A With KC Estenson, CNN &amp;#038; Mark Johnson, Zite&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Zite?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Estenson: We saw in Zite a best-in-class product. It&amp;#8217;s deeply loved by the people who have it, and we thought it would be a nice addition to our digital portfolio. Secondly, there&amp;#8217;s great technology behind it. We&amp;#8217;re seeing a lot of inteest in this space now, but these guys have been working on this for six years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Johnson: The iPad is really well suited to reading. I think what&amp;#8217;s interesting about Zite is that it brings you really interesting information you might not have otherwise read. It&amp;#8217;s not just repackaging information.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;#8217;re seeing &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/flipboard-tv-film/"&gt;Flipboard move into TV and film&lt;/a&gt;, while &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/pulse-bookmarklet-chrome-add-on/"&gt;Pulse is getting into bookmarklets and extensions&lt;/a&gt;. Where is Zite going next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Johnson: We still see a huge market in giving you the information most relevant to you. We&amp;#8217;re focusing on content right now, news-type content. We really want to focus on giving people a great personalized iPad magazine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your competitors are &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/12/10/sports-illustrated-flipboard/"&gt;striking partnerships with content publishers&lt;/a&gt; left and right. Are you doing the same?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Johnson: We&amp;#8217;re certainly having a lot of conversations right now. We&amp;#8217;re looking at ways to work with publishers to help them monetize and distribute their content. But we have nothing to announce right now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flipboard has &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/25/flipboard-ads-conde-nast/"&gt;recently begun displaying ads&lt;/a&gt; in its app. Are you planning on doing the same?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Johnson: We&amp;#8217;re not going to rush the business model here. Part of the [attraction of] the deal was not to have unnatural pressure on Zite to deliver financially. The goal is to get a great product and the business model will follow. We can imagine a variety of ways this company can monetize itself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And how do you plan on integrating Zite with CNN&amp;#8217;s existing digital properties?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Estenson: Zite is going to stand alone as an independent operation. Mark will be running it in San Francisco. The development office is in Vancouver. The technology that powers Zite over time we will begin to leverage with CNN&amp;#8217;s digital services, but it won&amp;#8217;t be an overnight thing. But over the course of the next 18 months or so I can imagine a world where CNN starts to serve up more personally relevant content. That can help with CNN&amp;#8217;s traffic recirculation and those sorts of things on the site. The important thing is that Zite stays.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can we expect CNN&amp;#8217;s content to feature more prominently on Zite in the future?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Johnson: Absolutely not. Our personalization algorithms look for most interesting content on the web, whether that comes from CNN or elsewhere. Our algorithms are completely agnostic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will Zite still be free to pursue partnerships with media companies beyond CNN?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Estenson: Yes. You&amp;#8217;ll see them do a wide variety of deals. We have a lot of experience at CNN with content partnerships. The web is a really interconnected space, a lot of linking and crosslinking of articles. That same philosophy will be remixed and repurposed. You&amp;#8217;ll see us help Zite with that in a variety of ways.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/cnn/"&gt;cnn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/interview/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/zite/"&gt;zite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/media/"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.media" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/entertainment" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/cglQuf-vVuv8ltFKQjcyJaQMIVk/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/cglQuf-vVuv8ltFKQjcyJaQMIVk/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/cglQuf-vVuv8ltFKQjcyJaQMIVk/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/cglQuf-vVuv8ltFKQjcyJaQMIVk/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=OypTKw7lxZw:nzALi-4-OJ8:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/OypTKw7lxZw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/cnn-zite-acquisition-interview/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/cnn-zite-acquisition-interview/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flickr Boosts Location Privacy With Geofences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/&amp;title=Flickr Boosts Location Privacy With Geofences&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/flickr-geofence.jpg" alt="" title="flickr geofence" width="275" height="" class="alignright" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/flickr"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; has introduced a new privacy feature called geofences that allows users to create geographic privacy settings for photos&amp;#8217; location data. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the new &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/account/geo/privacy/" target="_blank"&gt;feature&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; users can draw a circle on a map to designate a geofence and then choose a geographic privacy setting for that area. Users can create up to 10 geofences, and previously uploaded photos are also updated with the new geo-privacy settings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;You might want to create a geofence around the your &amp;#8216;home&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;school&amp;#8217; that only allows &amp;#8216;Friends and Family&amp;#8217; to see the location of the photos you geotag in that area by default,&amp;#8221; Flickr explains in a blog post on the new feature. &amp;#8220;So the next time you upload a photo with a geotag in the radius of a geofence, it will follow the geo privacy setting you&amp;#8217;ve designated for that hotspot.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Flickr, a Yahoo property, has been characterized as slow to innovate, especially amid the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/mobile-photo-sharing/"&gt;mobile photo-sharing&lt;/a&gt; boom. The geofences feature, however, addresses one of the primary concerns associated with geotagged images &amp;#8212; Flickr claims to have more than 300 million geotagged photos and videos on its site &amp;#8212; and should receive a welcome reception from the service&amp;#8217;s users.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/flickr/"&gt;flickr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/geofence/"&gt;geofence&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/geotagging/"&gt;geotagging&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/photo-sharing/"&gt;photo sharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PNQH7Squ12Nm979E5_urz0cpVzo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PNQH7Squ12Nm979E5_urz0cpVzo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PNQH7Squ12Nm979E5_urz0cpVzo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PNQH7Squ12Nm979E5_urz0cpVzo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=JzJR7i37fTc:YyByshr91Pg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/JzJR7i37fTc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/flickr-geofences/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hootsuite launches advanced facebook functionality - pages, events, groups and walls http://j.mp/nmHIUp</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a0.twimg.com/profile_images/1166013646/thedrum_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/peterjblack"&gt;Peter Black&lt;/a&gt;: hootsuite launches advanced facebook functionality - pages, events, groups and walls &lt;a href="http://j.mp/nmHIUp" target="_blank"&gt;http://j.mp/nmHIUp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/peterjblack/status/108398304555053056"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://hootsuite.com/manage-facebook?utm_source=facebook&amp;utm_campaign=hootbook</link>
      <guid>http://hootsuite.com/manage-facebook?utm_source=facebook&amp;utm_campaign=hootbook</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Best Practices for Restaurants on Facebook</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/webinar-form_the-definitive-guide-to-facebook-publishing-and-moderation.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;#038;u tm_content=PublishingModeration_Webinar&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Newsletter|Mashable|SITESERVED|Partner_Post_-_(4_moved_from_2010__24_ordered)_2August|PARTNERPOST" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/&amp;title=13 Best Practices for Restaurants on Facebook&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/buddy-media-logo-1001.jpg" alt="" title="buddy media logo 100" width="100" height="60" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-591699" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-marketing-series"&gt;Facebook Marketing Series&lt;/a&gt; is supported by &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/webinar-form_the-definitive-guide-to-facebook-publishing-and-moderation.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;#038;u&lt;br /&gt; tm_content=PublishingModeration_Webinar&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Newsletter|Mashable|SITESERVED|Partner_Post_-_(4_moved_from_2010__24_ordered)_2August|PARTNERPOST" target="_blank"&gt;Buddy Media&lt;/a&gt;. Now that Facebook will no longer allow your brand to hide comments from your followers, knowing the right strategies for moderating is paramount. Download &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/webinar-form_the-definitive-guide-to-facebook-publishing-and-moderation.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;#038;u tm_content=PublishingModeration_Webinar&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Newsletter|Mashable|SITESERVED|Partner_Post_-_(4_moved_from_2010__24_ordered)_2August|PARTNERPOST" target="_blank"&gt;our guide to Facebook publishing and moderation&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/facebook-food-360.jpg" class="alignright" title="Facebook Food" width="275" height=""&gt;Everyone has to eat, and 700 million of those people are also on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Naturally, there are a lot of restaurants on the world&amp;#8217;s largest social network, though there could be a lot more, and many of the ones that do have Facebook Pages could be better. To that end, &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; spoke with social media stars from the hospitality industry about some best practices when it comes to Facebooking food.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Be Transparent&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/jimmy-johns-be-responsive.png" alt="" title="jimmy johns be responsive" width="501" height="225" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714335" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We never want to delete any negative reviews,&amp;#8221; says Ashley Tyson, social media manager at &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/4food" target=_blank"&gt;4Food&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, 4Food streams all @-mentions on a 240-square-foot media wall inside the restaurant. &amp;#8220;Nobody expects a restaurant to always be perfect, but an honest response and quick offer to resolve the situation is what differentiates a good restaurant from a bad one.&amp;#8221; Above, you&amp;#8217;ll see that when Judy complained about a wrong order at her local Jimmy John&amp;#8217;s, the company showed initiative and replied with an email address and a willingness to work hard to regain trust.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And just like you shouldn&amp;#8217;t only pay attention to good reviews, you shouldn&amp;#8217;t play favorites to those with a large social network. The average Facebook user has 130 friends. But just because someone has more or less doesn&amp;#8217;t mean they&amp;#8217;re a more or less valuable customer. Be sure to respond to everyone and address everyone&amp;#8217;s concerns &amp;#8212; in a timely manner. &lt;a href="http://facebook.com/chipotle" target="_blank"&gt;Chipotle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s Joe Stupp says it&amp;#8217;s company policy to answer every (or almost every) Facebook post, whether it&amp;#8217;s positive or negative, typically within an hour or two. And people do appreciate the round-the-clock responses, no matter how &amp;#8220;popular&amp;#8221; they are on Facebook. &amp;#8220;Just because somebody has a high friend count or a high &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/klout"&gt;Klout&lt;/a&gt; score on social media doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean they are important in their community,&amp;#8221; says Stupp. &amp;#8220;Vice-versa is also true.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. You Must Respond&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Picture-22.png" alt="" title="brother jimmys" width="479" height="213" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-720255" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You want to engage your fans on your Facebook Page, but you also want them to know that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are engaged, too. Be sure to answer questions, address concerns, and acknowledge when people take the time to post on your Page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Even if it&amp;#8217;s just a thank you for a nice remark, be sure to respond to your fans. &amp;#8220;Never underestimate how far the words &amp;#8216;thank you&amp;#8217; can go,&amp;#8221; says Amanda Spurlock, Zagat&amp;#8217;s social media editor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Educate Your Fans&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/mermaid-how-to.png" alt="" title="mermaid how to" width="481" height="196" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714301" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Restaurants have a unique opportunity &amp;#8212; they can showcase the food, provide recipes, explain the origin of a dish and shoot videos of the chefs in action. That kind of content never gets old, and it doesn&amp;#8217;t even have to be original &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;s so much stuff on YouTube, and all you need to do is unearth it. &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/themermaidnyc" target="_blank"&gt;The Mermaid Inn&lt;/a&gt; posted this how-to video on its Facebook Page to show fans how to cook and eat lobster &amp;#8212; an item they sell, so it&amp;#8217;s related to the restaurant but also adds value.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tyson says that because 4food receives new shipments of fresh produce and product every day, she likes to &amp;#8220;use social media to educate our followers on fresh shipments, how we prepare our food (from scratch, with no artificial ingredients or fillers), where it comes from, etc.&amp;#8221; She adds that as the locavore and sustainability movements gain steam, consumers are more interested in this angle than ever before. &amp;#8220;People want to know they&amp;#8217;re eating the freshest, tastiest and most healthful product possible,&amp;#8221; Tyson says.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. Show Off Your Goods&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/hill-country-pics.png" alt="" title="hill country pics" width="482" height="343" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714305" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Food not only tastes and smells delicious &amp;#8212; it looks beautiful, too. Post pictures of your dishes like &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/hillcountrychicken" target="_blank"&gt;Hill Country&lt;/a&gt; does, because those &amp;#8220;food porn&amp;#8221; pics are sure to make people salivate and get them in the door. There&amp;#8217;s a reason things like &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/foodspotting"&gt;Foodspotting&lt;/a&gt; exist &amp;#8212; people like looking at artful food. However, Spurlock has a word of caution before you start uploading pics: &amp;#8220;Make sure that the photos are appetizing because not all cellphone photos of food turn out appetizing, even if it does look nice on the plate.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t even always need a picture &amp;#8212; sometimes a sensory description will do the trick. Case in point: &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/BeautyandEssex" target="_blank"&gt;Beauty &amp;#038; Essex&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s bacon Bloody Mary:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/beauty-essex-bloody-mary.png" alt="" title="beauty essex bloody mary" width="471" height="149" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714319" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Don&amp;#8217;t Just Sell &amp;#8212; Be Interesting&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/be-relevant.png" alt="" title="be relevant" width="487" height="220" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714001" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yes, your restaurant is a business, and your goal is to make profit. But you don&amp;#8217;t have to do the hard sell on Facebook &amp;#8212; oftentimes restaurants are overly promotional. &amp;#8220;While consumers love to hear about new menu items and special offers, they don&amp;#8217;t want to interact with anyone that appears too self serving,&amp;#8221; says Tyson. Think about your brand and then try to find the right mix of promotions and special offers, education, customer service, engagement, etc. Use a diverse set of content to establish and build your brand. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On National Oyster Day (who knew that existed?), &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Island-Creek-Oyster-Bar/157874490904010" target="_blank"&gt;Island Creek Oyster Bar&lt;/a&gt; posted a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; video &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s a soft sell that doesn&amp;#8217;t desperately scream &amp;#8220;Come eat here!&amp;#8221; yet still plants the seed that could get consumers to crave oysters. Sharing fun facts pertaining to your cuisine or the team is also a fun way to get people excited about your food, and it humanizes the brand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another way to promote your brand is to let others do it for you. After all, word of mouth marketing is the most effective (and authentic). Stupp recommends that you motivate your customers to become ambassadors by treating them well, listening to them, talking to them, informing them and being interesting and engaging. Once you do that, your loyal fans will spread the word &lt;em&gt;for you&lt;/em&gt; (for free!) online and in real life.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;6. Share Your Press&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/graham-elliot.png" alt="" title="graham elliot" width="491" height="234" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714323" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve worked hard to get good reviews and spur people to write blog posts about your food. Go ahead and share it with the world. This goes in tandem with avoiding the hard sell &amp;#8212; by being awesome, you&amp;#8217;ll motivate people to spread the word. More publicity means more customers, and it will snowball as long as your product is delicious and your customer service remains excellent. Chicago eatery &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/graham-elliot"&gt;Graham Elliot&lt;/a&gt; is great at posting press, which shows that the restaurant &lt;em&gt;gets&lt;/em&gt; a lot of press, and also serves to brag about the cool things they do, like hosting a pop-up restaurant at this year&amp;#8217;s Lollapalooza music festival.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;7. Flaunt Your Social and Digital Savvy&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/jimmy-johns.png" alt="" title="jimmy john&amp;#039;s" width="640" height="" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714329" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A small percentage of restaurants are on social platforms and seeing success. &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/jimmyjohns" target="_blank"&gt;Jimmy John&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt;, the Midwest sandwich chain, is one of them. Not only do they have an iPhone app for ordering, but it&amp;#8217;s also their Facebook profile picture, which is a great way to increase awareness of said app. At the very least, be active on Twitter and Facebook, and it&amp;#8217;s also great to have a blog or an app. And all of these things should be promoted on your Facebook Page, like the Jimmy John&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.freakyfast.com/" target="_blank"&gt;company blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;8. Be Consistent Online and Offline&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Picture-18.png" alt="" title="waffle truck fb" width="488" height="351" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-719967" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Be sure that your community managers are &amp;#8220;as well-versed in your restaurant food and service and intangibles as your best employees in the field,&amp;#8221; says Stupp. You don&amp;#8217;t want people to get answers on Facebook and hear a different story when they show up for dinner. It can be hard to maintain seamless communication &amp;#8212; especially if there are different locations that may have different offerings or hours, but it&amp;#8217;s important to stay in the loop and make sure that the information put out by your restaurant is accurate and consistent across all platforms, whether they be social platforms or in-person. Being inconsistent will lead to confusion and frustration for your customers, who may feel like they were promised one thing, only to be told something else upon arrival.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;9. Don&amp;#8217;t Give Away Too Much&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Picture-2.png" alt="" title="mermaid smm" width="458" height="70" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714111" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Whereas a bike store or car dealership are typically single-purchase businesses (how many bikes and cars does one person need?), restaurants are in a unique position in that someone could be a customer &lt;em&gt;every single day&lt;/em&gt;. And while group deals and offering discounts might be good for a one-time promotion to increase Likes, you don&amp;#8217;t want to give &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; much away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/02/24/free-chipotle-facebook/"&gt;NBC Facebook and Chipotle promotion&lt;/a&gt; for a buy one, get one free burrito was a huge success that got a lot of people buzzing and in the shops, but the business didn&amp;#8217;t have to lose too much money on it, because for every free burrito, there was a paid burrito. Just giving away product or offering steep discounts a la Groupon can have detrimental effect on the perceived value of your product, thereby making customers less likely to want to pay full price once the deal is over.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A once-in-a-while promotion that isn&amp;#8217;t too generous &amp;#8212; like the Mermaid Inn&amp;#8217;s Social Media Monday word of the day for 20% off &amp;#8212; keeps people coming back week after week without giving too much away. Plus, you&amp;#8217;ll get a sense of your social media influence if you offer a code or buzzword on Facebook for in-store redemption.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Experiment with different times and codes to discover when people are more inclined to be driven to your store by social media, says Tyson. You want to use Facebook to enhance traffic and sales, but to do so most effectively, you have to know when people are paying the most attention to you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re looking to build loyalty and Likes and keep people coming back, don&amp;#8217;t just give away product. The best thing to do is respond to people, talk to them like they&amp;#8217;re your friends and show your appreciation for them. To customers, that&amp;#8217;s worth more than a free sandwich.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;10. Be Charming&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/which-wich-be-charming.png" alt="" title="which wich be charming" width="619" height="591" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714293" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/beauty-essex.png" alt="" title="beauty &amp;amp; essex" width="483" height="154" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-714315" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Work can be stressful, so when someone sneaks away from the office for lunch or dinner, they want to be delighted. Whether you&amp;#8217;re a quick sandwich lunch stop or a white-tablecloth establishment, you can be charming and human. &lt;a href="http://www.whichwich.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Which Wich&lt;/a&gt;, a sandwich chain, literally flirts with its customers on Facebook, presenting a Like-gate that&amp;#8217;s modeled after a middle school-esque &amp;#8220;Do you like me? Check one. Yes/No&amp;#8221; note.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We know there&amp;#8217;s a human behind your Facebook Page, so you don&amp;#8217;t need to stifle him &amp;#8212; let a genuine voice come through.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;11. Respect and Appreciate Your Team&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/chipotle.png" alt="" title="chipotle" width="478" height="189" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-713921" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A company is nothing without the people who comprise it, and the same can be said for restaurants &amp;#8212; it takes many people to run the machine. When a customer posts about a positive experience on Facebook, be sure to pass it on to the team and also thank the customer and tell him you&amp;#8217;re doing so &amp;#8212; both parties will feel special and appreciated.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, sometimes people write about not-so-positive experiences, and that can be a trickier situation to manage. &amp;#8220;If someone complains about a particular individual or restaurant prior to an objective investigation, take the correspondence off the wall but make sure you let the customer know this and why you are doing it,&amp;#8221; says Stupp, adding that your team has a &amp;#8220;right to fair treatment&amp;#8221; and should not &amp;#8220;be guilty in the eyes of the public until proven innocent.&amp;#8221; Be sure you resolve any issues, apologize for the perceived wrongdoing and let the customer know what steps have been taken to remedy the situation &amp;#8212; follow-through is key if you&amp;#8217;re trying to get that customer back in the door.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also realize that your staff is on social media sites and are essentially ambassadors for your store. Show some appreciation, and they&amp;#8217;ll appreciate their job even more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;12. Facebook Is Not Twitter&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/northern-spy.jpg" alt="" title="northern spy" width="640" height="70" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-720253" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sure, it&amp;#8217;s easy to automatically syndicate your Twitter posts to Facebook and vice versa, but is it a good idea? No. &amp;#8220;You have to think of Facebook as it&amp;#8217;s own platform,&amp;#8221; says Spurlock. Just consider the 140-character limit on Twitter. That means Twitter-to-Facebook posts will be extremely short (and photos and links won&amp;#8217;t show up like they do when you post directly to Facebook), and Facebook-to-Twitter posts will likely get cut off and people may be annoyed that they have to go to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If someone is following you on Twitter, they don&amp;#8217;t want to be told to go to Facebook every time for more information on each of your posts,&amp;#8221; says Spurlock. &amp;#8220;Also it gets rid of any incentive for someone to follow you on both platforms if everything you&amp;#8217;re doing on them is the same.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Variety is the spice of life, and food establishments should know that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;13. Target Consumers With Facebook Ads&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Facebook-Zip-Code-Targeting-.png" alt="" title="Facebook-Zip-Code-Targeting-" width="453" height="321" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-705911" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A new Facebook feature allows advertisers to &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/11/facebook-ads-zip-code/"&gt;target consumers based on zip codes&lt;/a&gt;, which means that you can blast an ad to those who live within walking distance of your restaurant. There are some tricks of the trade when exploring the world of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-ads-tips/"&gt;Facebook advertising&lt;/a&gt;, and it can be an effective way to build your fan base on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Series Supported by Buddy Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/webinar-form_the-definitive-guide-to-facebook-publishing-and-moderation.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;#038;u tm_content=PublishingModeration_Webinar&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Newsletter|Mashable|SITESERVED|Partner_Post_-_(4_moved_from_2010__24_ordered)_2August|PARTNERPOST" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/buddy-media-logo-1001.jpg" alt="" title="buddy media logo 100" width="100" height="60" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-591699" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-marketing-series"&gt;Facebook Marketing Series&lt;/a&gt; is supported by &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/webinar-form_the-definitive-guide-to-facebook-publishing-and-moderation.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;#038;u&lt;br /&gt; tm_content=PublishingModeration_Webinar&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Newsletter|Mashable|SITESERVED|Partner_Post_-_(4_moved_from_2010__24_ordered)_2August|PARTNERPOST" target="_blank"&gt;Buddy Media&lt;/a&gt;. Now that Facebook will no longer allow your brand to hide comments from your followers, knowing the right strategies for moderating is paramount. Download &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/webinar-form_the-definitive-guide-to-facebook-publishing-and-moderation.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;#038;u tm_content=PublishingModeration_Webinar&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Newsletter|Mashable|SITESERVED|Partner_Post_-_(4_moved_from_2010__24_ordered)_2August|PARTNERPOST" target="_blank"&gt;our guide to Facebook publishing and moderation&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="http://insidefacebook.com" target="_blank"&gt;Inside Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-marketing-series/"&gt;Facebook Marketing Series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/restaurants/"&gt;restaurants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business &amp;amp; Marketing&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business &amp;amp; Marketing on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business &amp;amp; Marketing channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/-VHW5KyrAqr6X2SL8Haq-CZvEkg/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/-VHW5KyrAqr6X2SL8Haq-CZvEkg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/-VHW5KyrAqr6X2SL8Haq-CZvEkg/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/-VHW5KyrAqr6X2SL8Haq-CZvEkg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=HjjxY4ik8qg:IEqCRJtUeck:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/HjjxY4ik8qg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/facebook-marketing-restaurants/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Embed Twitter Testimonials on Your Website</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="tweetmeme_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Fhow-to-embed-twitter-testimonials-on-your-website%2F"&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Fhow-to-embed-twitter-testimonials-on-your-website%2F&amp;amp;source=smexaminer&amp;amp;style=normal&amp;amp;service=bit.ly&amp;amp;service_api=R_d59caa5bf89cd7663e205e72cb1d6cc1&amp;amp;b=2" height="61" width="50" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/how-to/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="social media how to" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/how-to-pose.png" alt="social media how to" width="190" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What matters to most potential customers is not what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; say about your business, but what &lt;em&gt;your existing customers&lt;/em&gt; have to say.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a simple strategy to help you &lt;strong&gt;convince prospects to become customers. &lt;/strong&gt;And it&amp;#8217;s done by embedding Twitter testimonials on your website.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Why Testimonials Matter&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When potential customers check out your business online, they want to see proof that you deliver what you promise. It&amp;#8217;s important that you &lt;strong&gt;provide evidence that you have happy customers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Testimonials are powerful because they come straight from your customers in their own words. It&amp;#8217;s important you &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/3-rewards-and-3-risks-of-making-customers-brand-ambassadors/" target="_blank"&gt;add testimonials to your site&lt;/a&gt;. You can easily &lt;strong&gt;tap into tweets from people who say great things about your business&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;span id="more-10491"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Why Tweets Make Good Testimonials&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tweets make great testimonials for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;They&amp;#8217;re &lt;strong&gt;short&lt;/strong&gt;, so they get to the point quickly.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;People write them in a moment of enthusiasm, so they&amp;#8217;re &lt;strong&gt;filled with praise and excitement&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;They&amp;#8217;re &lt;strong&gt;written for public review&lt;/strong&gt;, so you don&amp;#8217;t need to ask permission to use a tweet as a testimonial&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;What kinds of tweets make great customer testimonials? Those whose entire content is about your business, your product or your service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-1-good-testimonial.jpg" alt="good testimonial" width="480" height="214" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An example of a customer testimonial written as a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Use Twitter Favorites to Display Testimonials&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter makes it easy for your business to&lt;strong&gt; capture and display tweets when you mark them as Favorites&lt;/strong&gt;. To make this strategy work, you must &lt;strong&gt;use Favorites exclusively for testimonials&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To Favorite a tweet, hover your mouse over the tweet. Twitter displays a list of commands that are not visible until you hover on the tweet. &lt;strong&gt;Locate the Favorite (star) option and click it&lt;/strong&gt;. Twitter adds this tweet to your list of Favorite tweets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-tweet-from-someone-else.jpg" alt="tweet from someone else" width="480" height="99" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An example of a tweet showing the Favorite option while hovering the mouse over it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter allows you to &lt;strong&gt;display your most recent Favorite tweets on your website or blog using a widget&lt;/strong&gt;. Every time you mark a new Favorite tweet, Twitter adds it to your customer testimonials automatically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 250px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-finished-twitter-widget.png" alt="finished twitter widget" width="240" height="294" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An example of a Twitter widget displaying customer testimonials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;How to Create Your Testimonials Twitter Widget&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before you start creating your Twitter Favorites widget, you need this information:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The size of the spot for your Twitter widget on your site in pixels (height and width).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Optional: The hex code (for example: #d34e01) for colors used on your site to customize the widget.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;You may also need technical assistance to insert the HTML code into your blog or website.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To &lt;strong&gt;create and customize your widget&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#1: The Twitter Widgets page&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Choose widgets for your website on the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/about/resources/widgets" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter Widgets page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click My Website&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 250px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-5-widget-website.jpg" alt="widget website" width="240" height="166" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Click &amp;quot;My Website&amp;quot; to display the widgets available for your website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click Faves Widget&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-6-widget-faves.jpg" alt="widget faves" width="480" height="133" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Faves Widget contains a list of tweets you mark as favorites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Make sure you have Favorited some tweets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#2: Customize your widget heading&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;To &lt;strong&gt;customize your widget&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Change the Title to What People Are Saying About (or something similar)&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Change the Caption to your business name (if necessary).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-7-faves-widget-settings.jpg" alt="faves widget settings" width="480" height="307" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget Settings page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click Test Settings&lt;/strong&gt; to see your changes take effect (if necessary). On the right, Twitter displays your widget with your favorites and your settings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#3: Customize your widget preferences&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click Preferences&lt;/strong&gt;. Twitter displays the Customize Your Faves Widget Preferences page. This page allows you to customize how your widget works. Choose the options that you want for your widget.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Poll for New Results keeps checking for new tweets marked as a Favorite.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Include Scrollbar lets you add more tweets than fit into the widget display area.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;To make your list scroll through your tweets, choose Timed Interval and Loop Results.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;To remove the date, uncheck Show Timestamps. (Leave this checked if you want to display the customer testimonial dates.)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-8-widget-preferences.jpg" alt="widget preferences" width="480" height="490" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget Preferences page showing common preference options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;To see the effect of your options, &lt;strong&gt;click Test Settings&lt;/strong&gt;. Experiment until the widget works the way you want it to work on your site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#4: Customize your widget to your site and brand colors&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click Appearance&lt;/strong&gt;. Twitter displays the Customize Your Faves Widget Appearance page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This page allows you to change the colors used in your widget. Use the hex codes for your site colors to exactly match your Twitter widget to your site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To &lt;strong&gt;change a widget color&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Click the color box next to the color you want to change. Twitter displays a color picker window.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-9-widget-appearance-before.jpg" alt="widget appearance before" width="480" height="281" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget Appearance page showing the five color options you can customize to match your website or blog branding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Type the hex code for the desired color.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-10-widget-appeance-colorpicker.jpg" alt="widget appeance colorpicker" width="480" height="312" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget Appearance page showing a color picker window for one color option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Click Done. Twitter updates the color box and the widget example.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-11-widget-appearance-done.jpg" alt="widget appearance done" width="480" height="324" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An example of the Customize Your Faves Widget Appearance page showing a color picker after typing the hex code for a new color choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Click Test Settings to see your colors (if necessary).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#5: Customize your widget to fit the space on your site&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click Dimensions&lt;/strong&gt;. Twitter displays the Customize Your Faves Widget Dimensions page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Type the height and width of your finished widget in pixels.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-12-widget-dimensions.jpg" alt="widget dimensions" width="480" height="252" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget Dimensions page showing the Widget Dimensions boxes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#6: Finish your Twitter Faves Widget&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you have finished customizing your Twitter Faves Widget, click Finish &amp;amp; Grab Code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-13-widget-complete.jpg" alt="widget complete" width="480" height="521" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget Dimensions page showing the Finish &amp;amp; Grab Code button.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter displays the code in a text box in the middle of the page. Copy and paste this code into a text file for storage, or directly into your website.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-14-widget-code-box.jpg" alt="widget code box" width="480" height="436" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The Customize Your Faves Widget page showing the HTML code box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tip&lt;/strong&gt;: When you leave this page, your customization settings are lost. &lt;strong&gt;Save this code permanently&lt;/strong&gt; by storing it in a text file, Microsoft Word document or other location.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Your website uses this code to display your Twitter widget. You insert the code into your website at the location where you want the Twitter widget to appear. Common places for Twitter widgets include:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The front page of your website. Put your customer testimonials where new visitors can easily find them.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In your blog sidebar. If your website gets traffic landing directly on blog posts, consider adding your Twitter widget in the blog sidebar.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In your website footer. You can adjust the height of the Twitter widget to fit your footer height.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you install the code, the Twitter widget appears immediately and displays your current favorite tweets. As you mark new tweets as favorites, they appear in the widget, also.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 250px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711ck-finished-twitter-widget.png" alt="finished twitter widget" width="240" height="294" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;An example Twitter widget using favorites as testimonials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;It&amp;#8217;s Your Turn&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think? Have you used tweets as testimonials on your site? &lt;/strong&gt;Have you tried the Twitter Favorites Widget? What testimonial strategy works well for your business? Leave your comments in the box below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-embed-twitter-testimonials-on-your-website/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-embed-twitter-testimonials-on-your-website/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zynga To Delay IPO Because of Market Conditions [REPORT]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/&amp;title=Zynga To Delay IPO Because of Market Conditions [REPORT]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/ZYNGA.jpg" alt="" title="ZYNGA" width="225" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-666713" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/zynga/"&gt;Zynga&lt;/a&gt; is delaying its IPO &amp;#8212; originally set for next month &amp;#8212; until November, according to a report.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The social gaming company is spooked by the &amp;#8220;rocky stock markets,&amp;#8221; according to the report in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/news/business/zynga_loses_zing_IddRen9FeEBmOlKS3oVThL" target="_blank"&gt;The New York Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, which cites two sources with knowledge of Zynga&amp;#8217;s plans. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; could not reach reps from Zynga for comment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In late June, Zynga &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/zynga-ipo-2/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; plans to go public. The company, which is behind &lt;i&gt;FarmVille&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;CityVille&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Mafia Wars&lt;/i&gt;, among other titles, hopes to raise $1.5 billion to $2 billion in its IPO. But since the debt ceiling debate this summer, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/04/tech-stock-winners-loser/"&gt;tech stocks have been hit hard&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Zynga&amp;#8217;s is one of several social media IPOs planned over the next few months. Another high-profile social media IPO, Groupon&amp;#8217;s, has also &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/27/groupon-sec-ip/"&gt;reportedly been delayed&lt;/a&gt;, but because of SEC accounting concerns, rather than stock market conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/groupon/"&gt;groupon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/ipos/"&gt;IPOs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/zynga/"&gt;Zynga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business &amp;amp; Marketing&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business &amp;amp; Marketing on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business &amp;amp; Marketing channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/lynmsIanN5J42k8jzoS0DgD0O44/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/lynmsIanN5J42k8jzoS0DgD0O44/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/lynmsIanN5J42k8jzoS0DgD0O44/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/lynmsIanN5J42k8jzoS0DgD0O44/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zYRud6YQCOo:MvBznQEmfO8:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/zYRud6YQCOo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/zynga-ipo-delay/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greg Kot Tweets from SXSW | Follow Kot on his blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/#!/gregkot</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/#!/gregkot</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movie Trailers Released Exclusively Via QR Code for The First Time [PICS]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/&amp;title=Movie Trailers Released Exclusively Via QR Code for The First Time [PICS]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/mmm-qr-code-640.jpg" alt="" title="mmm-qr-code-640" width="640" height="625" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-718347" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Fox Searchlight is shunning traditional promotional opportunities for its upcoming film &lt;em&gt;Martha Marcy May Marlene&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, the studio is rolling out an elaborate &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/qr-code/"&gt;QR code&lt;/a&gt; campaign for the movie, which hits theaters on October 21.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rather than go the traditional route of releasing teasers and trailers, Fox Searchlight opted to go digital.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The studio put QR codes on ad materials such as posters, theater standees and coasters in New York City and Los Angeles. There are two separate trailers for the film embedded within the QR codes. According to Fox Searchlight, this is the first time a studio has exclusively released trailers via QR code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t see the QR codes for the marketing materials in person, you can access &lt;a href="http://www.marthamarcymaymarlenemonolith.com/" target="_blank"&gt;them online&lt;/a&gt; via a website that is designed to emulate the theater standees. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.foxsearchlight.com/marthamarcymaymarlene/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martha Marcy May Marlene&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; stars Elizabeth Olsen (the younger sister of Mary-Kate and Ashley) and Academy Award nominee John Hawkes. The film is about a young woman who struggles to reconnect with her family after fleeing a cult. The film debuted at the Sundance Film Festival in January, where director Sean Durkin winning the U.S. Directing Award in the Dramatic category.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/movies/2011/01/elizabeth-olsen-martha-marcy-sundance-fox-searchlight.html" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Zeitchik&lt;/a&gt; wrote about the film for the &lt;em&gt;L.A. Times&lt;/em&gt; back in January, noting that &amp;#8220;nearly every choice Durkin makes seems driven by artistry instead of commerciality &amp;#8230; this makes for a cinephile&amp;#8217;s dream &amp;#8212; and a marketer&amp;#8217;s, well, something else.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The marketing team at Searchlight seems to understand the challenge of promoting this type of film, which is why we think that the decision to use QR codes is spot-on. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In addition to the QR campaign, Fox Searchlight also has an experimental website, &lt;a href="http://www.iamateacherandaleader.com/" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.iamateacherandaleader.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re excited to see more marketers &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/23/creative-qr-codes/"&gt;embracing QR codes&lt;/a&gt;, especially in the film business. Let us know your thoughts on this project and campaign in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;One Sheet Poster&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/#24323One-Sheet-Poster"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="One Sheet Poster" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-code-posters/mmmm-one-sheet.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;John Hawkes Teaser&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/#24325John-Hawkes-Teaser"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="John Hawkes Teaser" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-code-posters/mmmm-hawkes-teaser.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Elizabeth Olsen Teaser&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/#24327Elizabeth-Olsen-Teaser"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Elizabeth Olsen Teaser" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-code-posters/mmm-olsen-teaser1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/elizabeth-olsen/"&gt;elizabeth olsen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/fox-searchlight/"&gt;fox searchlight&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/martha-marcy-may-marlene/"&gt;martha marcy may marlene&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/movies/"&gt;Movies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/qr-codes/"&gt;QR Codes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/media/"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.media" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/entertainment" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1J9YIq9eFftrsJCRFDk-KamCesc/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1J9YIq9eFftrsJCRFDk-KamCesc/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1J9YIq9eFftrsJCRFDk-KamCesc/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1J9YIq9eFftrsJCRFDk-KamCesc/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2SSOO_UFcug:GbeKhJlsYEU:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/2SSOO_UFcug" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/25/martha-marcy-may-marlene-qr-codes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREAKING: Google Buys Motorola for $12.5 Billion</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/&amp;title=BREAKING: Google Buys Motorola for $12.5 Billion&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/android-everywhere-360.jpg" alt="" title="" width="225" height="" class="alignright" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Google has purchased Motorola Mobility, a company that makes many of the phones its Android operating system runs on, for $ 12.5 billion &amp;#8212; a 63% premium on its current share price.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The acquisition, Google said in a &lt;a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Google-to-Acquire-Motorola-bw-4079820793.html?x=0&amp;#038;.v=1" target="_blank"&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;#8220;will enable Google to supercharge the Android ecosystem.&amp;#8221; The company will continue to be run as a separate business.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Buying a hardware company is an unusual move for Google. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More to come&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/android/"&gt;android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/bJKohTBS26jaZMUf31NmU1uJjmo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/bJKohTBS26jaZMUf31NmU1uJjmo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/bJKohTBS26jaZMUf31NmU1uJjmo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/bJKohTBS26jaZMUf31NmU1uJjmo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=-x0KFt_3J6g:Yv7Oz7q_9pE:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/-x0KFt_3J6g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/15/google-motorola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social TV by the Numbers: VMAs Edition [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/26/vmas-all-access-live-ipad/"&gt;2011 MTV Video Music Awards (VMAs)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/beyonce-baby/#comments"&gt;broke records&lt;/a&gt; on both MTV and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. At 10:35pm ET, Beyonce&amp;#8217;s live performance and baby bump reveal generated 8,868 tweets per second.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The guys at &lt;a href="http://trendrr.tv/" target="_blank"&gt;Trendrr&lt;/a&gt; put together this infographic that breaks down the social TV aspect of the award show. The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/vma-mtv-2011-videos/"&gt;2011 VMAs&lt;/a&gt; generated more than 5.5 million social media mentions on Sunday, August 28, 2011. The majority of those mentions were from Twitter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The overwhelming amount of mobile device usage indicates that MTV&amp;#8217;s second-screen approach with the VMAs really worked. Trendrr also tells us that the fact that &amp;#8220;Beyonce&amp;#8221; didn&amp;#8217;t even register as one of the most popular hashtags shows that the #VMA branding was working successfully. According to Trendrr, this &amp;#8220;shows the real maturity of hashtags as vehicle to drive connected TV conversations.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s interesting to see the breakdown across networks &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/topics/follow/getglue"&gt;GetGlue&lt;/a&gt; and to see what times activity was at its peak.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/&amp;title=Social TV by the Numbers: VMAs Edition [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/trendrrtv_mtv_vma_2011-972.jpg" alt="" title="trendrrtv_mtv_vma_2011-972" width="972" height="2130" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-721121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/infographic/"&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mtv/"&gt;mtv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-tv/"&gt;social tv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/trendrr/"&gt;Trendrr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/vmas/"&gt;vmas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/media/"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.media" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/entertainment" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/O_zDQf0G5js" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social TV by the Numbers: VMAs Edition [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/26/vmas-all-access-live-ipad/"&gt;2011 MTV Video Music Awards (VMAs)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/beyonce-baby/#comments"&gt;broke records&lt;/a&gt; on both MTV and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. At 10:35pm ET, Beyonce&amp;#8217;s live performance and baby bump reveal generated 8,868 tweets per second.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The guys at &lt;a href="http://trendrr.tv/" target="_blank"&gt;Trendrr&lt;/a&gt; put together this infographic that breaks down the social TV aspect of the award show. The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/29/vma-mtv-2011-videos/"&gt;2011 VMAs&lt;/a&gt; generated more than 5.5 million social media mentions on Sunday, August 28, 2011. The majority of those mentions were from Twitter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The overwhelming amount of mobile device usage indicates that MTV&amp;#8217;s second-screen approach with the VMAs really worked. Trendrr also tells us that the fact that &amp;#8220;Beyonce&amp;#8221; didn&amp;#8217;t even register as one of the most popular hashtags shows that the #VMA branding was working successfully. According to Trendrr, this &amp;#8220;shows the real maturity of hashtags as vehicle to drive connected TV conversations.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s interesting to see the breakdown across networks &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/topics/follow/getglue"&gt;GetGlue&lt;/a&gt; and to see what times activity was at its peak.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/&amp;title=Social TV by the Numbers: VMAs Edition [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/trendrrtv_mtv_vma_2011-972.jpg" alt="" title="trendrrtv_mtv_vma_2011-972" width="972" height="2130" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-721121" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/infographic/"&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mtv/"&gt;mtv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-tv/"&gt;social tv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/trendrr/"&gt;Trendrr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/vmas/"&gt;vmas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/media/"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.media" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/entertainment" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5NtgDJtY9s88rJ9YwWPFimtUHXw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=O_zDQf0G5js:CmxYM7u3AGQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/O_zDQf0G5js" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/30/vmas-social-tv-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
