<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think Hockey '09: The Secret to Winning Puck Battles</title>
      <description>&lt;a href=http://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.cbc.ca/video/%23/Sports/CBC%27s%2520Hockey%2520Night%2520in%2520Canada/Think%2520Hockey/ID%3D1237582316&amp;source=video&amp;vgc=rss&amp;usg=AFQjCNHnwCoqV449QSCCGkSKpyCuLuxTmQ&gt;&lt;img src=http://2.gvt0.com/ThumbnailServer2?app=vss&amp;contentid=a6ba3e909dbd5216&amp;offsetms=1&amp;itag=w160&amp;hl=en&amp;sigh=__tnEi2mplI4diJ9yEOu5GxzmBqjk= width=160 height=120&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;John Stevens demonstrates the secret to winning puck battles. &lt;p/&gt;&lt;div style="color:green;font-size:smaller;"&gt;cbc.ca&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.cbc.ca/video/#/Sports/CBC's%20Hockey%20Night%20in%20Canada/Think%20Hockey/ID=1237582316</link>
      <guid>http://www.cbc.ca/video/#/Sports/CBC's%20Hockey%20Night%20in%20Canada/Think%20Hockey/ID=1237582316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Klout Unveils Brand Pages</title>
      <description>Klout unleashed Brand Squads, its version of brand pages, into beta on Tuesday with Red Bull as its sole launch partner. The startup &#8212; which measures influence on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and Foursquare to assign Klout users scores from 0 to 100 &#8212; will gradually roll out more Brand Squads in the coming weeks and months. Each Squad will feature the brand&#8217;s logo, the list of the top 10 and top 100 influencers about the brand, an activity stream and any brand-specific deals offered through Klout&#8217;s Perks platform. &#8220;The bottom line is that we are creating a place where influencers can be recognized and have an impact on brands,&#8221; Klout spokeswoman Lynn Fox told Mashable. Companies have had success engaging with consumers and promoting products or services via brand pages on Facebook, Google+ and Twitter. Now, Klout wants to jump in the game to empower everyday brand advocates. For example, instead of Red Bull talking to fans or touting things as it does across social networks, it&#8217;s the other way around on Klout. &#8220;With Brand Squads, you will see a dynamic list of top influencers for each brand, watch conversations flow across social media, monitor information about a brand&#8217;s recent developments and earn access to special Perks,&#8221; Klout product manager David Temple said in an announcement. &#8220;If you&#8217;re one of Red Bull&#8217;s top advocates, they&#8217;ll keep you informed with a subscription to The Red Bulletin and make sure that you&#8217;ve had a chance to try their new Red Bull Total Zero by sending you a 4-Pack,&#8221; Temple says. &#8220;The very top influencers will get some sweet merchandise or even a VIP Red Bull experience, like a behind-the-scenes look at the X-Games.&#8221; How important do you think Klout&#8217;s Squads will be for brands? Sound off in the comments. BONUS: What Else Does Klout Have in Store for 2012? Looking ahead, Klout is still building scoring models for seven more services (YouTube, Instagram, Tumblr, Blogger, WordPress.com, Last.fm and Flickr) that have already been integrated onto Klout users&#8217; dashboards. Klout also plans to add Quora, Yelp, Posterous, Livefyre, Disqus, bit.ly and BranchOut. SEE ALSO: Klout Mobile App Is One Step Closer With Acquisition of BlockBoard Klout likely will continue improving its Topics feature (see screenshots below) and Klout Perks platform. The Topics feature, which rolled out in September and lets you gain insights on top influencers and +K recipients for specific content areas, got a visual update in December with a &#8220;sashes&#8221; and an &#8220;Add a Topic&#8221; button. Clickable Topics on Your Dashboard On your Klout dashboard, you can click on a topic to open its Topic Page. In December 2011, Klout rolled out sashes and an "Add a Topic" button. A blue sash goes to users with the most +Ks for any topic, while a gold sash is given to influencers based on Klout's algorithm. People who fall into both categories receive a blue-and-gold sash. Click here to view this gallery. More About: Brand pages, brands, Business, klout, red bull, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/klout-brand-squads-pages-red-bull/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/klout-brand-squads-pages-red-bull/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Tumblr&#8217; to Overtake &#8216;Blog&#8217; in Google Searches</title>
      <description>Just as Kleenex became a stand-in for &#8220;tissue&#8221; years ago, is &#8220;Tumblr&#8221; on its way to replacing &#8220;blog&#8221;? Google search results show that may be the case. By the end of 2012, there will be more people searching &#8220;Tumblr&#8221; than &#8220;blog,&#8221; according to Google&#8217;s data. Randall Munroe, creator of the popular web comic XKCD, first made the observation with his own chart. Munroe&#8217;s not the only one to note Tumblr&#8217;s ascendance. ComScore data show Tumblr got 21.8 million unique visitors in the U.S. in March, compared to 8.4 million in March 2011. Despite that surge in traffic, Tumblr CEO David Karp told Advertising Age last week that he has no desire to monetize the platform via an AdSense-like program: &#8220;Our attitude toward all this attention on Tumblr, which we could very easily throw a Google AdSense on and be profitable tomorrow &#8212; that&#8217;s so far down the list, I mean, we&#8217;re selling our desks to avoid that, it&#8217;s a complete last resort.&#8221; BONUS: How Tumblr Rekindled the Art of Animated GIFs 1. Osamu Tezuka "From a classic Osamu Tezuka short, parodying old cartoons -- an example of a GIF clip that stands alone effectively."Click here to view this gallery. Thumbnail courtesy of ozneo. More About: blog, tumblrFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/tumblr-blog-google-searches/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/tumblr-blog-google-searches/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Details Strategic Partnership with Coca-Cola</title>
      <description>Spotify CEO Daniel Ek announced on Wednesday during an Ad Age Digital press conference in New York City that it is partnering with companies such Coca-Cola and will build branded apps for them within the music platform. The music-streaming service held its own press event hours later to further discuss the partnership with Coca-Cola. &#8220;We are taking the music agenda to the next level with Coca-Cola,&#8221; Ek told attendees. &#8220;This is a huge milestone for us. This will bring awareness to more people around the world about Spotify and enable them to share music with family and friends.&#8221; Emmanuel Seuge, head of global sports and entertainment marketing at Coca-Cola, noted that the move is a strategic partnership more than an advertising deal. &#8220;This is not an advertising deal and we don&#8217;t disclose the amount of investment anyway,&#8221; Seuge said. &#8220;This is more of a strategic partnership. Our logo is important, but we want to be a part of the conversation with music fans. We are going to push our content more than our logo.&#8221; He also discussed how music has always been a part of the Coca-Cola brand. &#8220;Partnership has always been a part of the way we run our business and it&#8217;s based on shared value,&#8221; Seuge said. &#8220;Music has always been a part of the way we engage consumers. In 1955, we commissioned Ray Charles to write our radio spot and we have always communicated with music.&#8221; The partnership will focus on global expansion, technology, social and music. Through live events such as the upcoming Olympics to TV and digital media, Coca-Cola said it will be working with Spotify to develop the music experience. &#8220;Spotify is becoming our global music partner, from the Olympics to other campaigns,&#8221; Seuge said. &#8220;What&#8217;s important now is not just building awareness but being a part of the conversation.&#8221; Although some expected a Spotify iPad app launch at the press event, Ek said it wouldn&#8217;t debut today. &#8220;It&#8217;s in the works,&#8221; Ek said. &#8220;Today&#8217;s focus is on our partnership with Coca-Cola.&#8221; Spotify has pulled out the stops recently to grow its presence online. Last week, it made it easy for music fans and web editors to embed playlists, songs or albums to a website or blog for free. The Spotify Play Button was designed to give users a way to legally share music online. SEE ALSO: Facebook Adds &#8216;Listen&#8217; Button to Band, Artist Pages Spotify also recently announced plans to keep the service free in the U.S. indefinitely. The company initially granted U.S. consumers access to the platform with no restrictions for six months. For those who didn&#8217;t sign up for a premium package &#8212; ranging from $4.99 to $9.99 a month &#8212; the site would be limited to 10 free hours of streaming music each month. It&#8217;s unknown how long the streaming service will remain free in the U.S. In 2011, Spotify expand introduced an application programming interface (API), so third-party developers can make Spotify&#8217;s music library available to their own users for a fee. More About: Music, spotifyFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/spotify-coca-cola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/spotify-coca-cola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLASH: Dick Clark dead at 82...</title>
      <description>FLASH: Dick Clark dead at 82(First column, 1st story, link)</description>
      <link>http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/dick-clark-entertainment-icon-nicknamed-americas-oldest-teenager/story?id=16076252</link>
      <guid>http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/dick-clark-entertainment-icon-nicknamed-americas-oldest-teenager/story?id=16076252</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Retro iPhone Covers That Celebrate Vintage Tech</title>
      <description>1. Vintage Typewriter You can almost hear the keys clack on this vintage typewriter decal. Cost: $18.99Click here to view this gallery.IPhone cases and covers are an affordable and fun way to give your handset a makeover. Rather than just decorative decals, we&#8217;re looking at skins, covers and cases inspired by other products &#8212; in this instance, vintage technology. Whether you&#8217;re a fan of retro gaming, love the classic chrome looks of old school gadgetry, or hark back to an era of analogue audio, we&#8217;ve got a skin to suit. SEE ALSO: 10 Tidy iPhone Cases to Replace Your Wallet Take a look through our awesome image gallery above. Let us know in the comments below which covers you&#8217;d consider taking a trip back in time with. More About: apple, cases, Etsy, features, geek, iphone, iphone accessories, iphone casesFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/retro-iphone-covers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/retro-iphone-covers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rest In Peace: TV Legend Dick Clark Dies Of Massive Heart Attack At Age 82</title>
      <description>Dick Clark -- famed TV producer, and "New Year's Rockin' Eve" host -- died from a massive heart attack this morning TMZ has learned.Clark's rep tells TMZ, the TV icon had been in St. John's hospital in L.A. after undergoing an outpatient&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://www.tmz.com/2012/04/18/dick-clark-dead-heart-attack/</link>
      <guid>http://www.tmz.com/2012/04/18/dick-clark-dead-heart-attack/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Lecture Teaches You Everything You Need to Know About Iran</title>
      <description>Can you really learn everything you need to know about topics ranging from healthcare to global affairs in five-minute online videos? That&#8217;s the promise of a new series from 92Y&#8217;s Campaign for the American Conversation and the Harvard Kennedy School. The plan: Produce a series of online lectures from some of the sharpest minds in politics and economics. The goal: Make those lectures incredibly accessible to those with absolutely no prior knowledge of the subject. In the first of the series, posted above, former U.S. Undersecretary of State Nicholas Burns gives the low-down on American-Iranian engagement. Relations between the two countries are cold, he says, because it&#8217;s been decades since they have held a continuing dialogue at the national level. That partially explains why the State Department&#8217;s efforts to reach out to Iranian citizens over the Internet are so vital to President Obama&#8217;s foreign policy. In the Obama administration&#8217;s dual-track policy on Iran, the U.S. is keeping pressure on the Iranian government while extending a diplomatic olive branch of peace to Iranian citizens. SEE ALSO: Iran&#8217;s Electronic Curtain: How the U.S. Is Tearing It Down Other top U.S. universities, such as Princeton and Stanford, are going so far as to put entire courses online at no cost to the student. Do you think digital lectures and courses will help tear town the ivory towers of academia? Sound off in the comments below. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, CGinspiration More About: 92y, education, iran, US, Video, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/online-lecture-iran/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/online-lecture-iran/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Tests &#8216;Trending Articles&#8217; Insert in the Newsfeed [SCREENSHOTS]</title>
      <description>Facebook is testing a &#8220;Trending Articles&#8221; placement in the Newsfeed, screenshots sent in by multiple sources suggest. &#8220;Trending Articles&#8221; displays a group of stories &#8212; between three and six, from the screenshots we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; all pulled from the social reader apps of news organizations like The Guardian, The Washington Post and The Huffington Post. Users see a thumbnail, headline, source and first 100-odd characters of each story, as well as the name of the friend(s) who have already read it. The insert is prominent, to the point where it actually seems to &#8220;take over&#8221; the Newsfeed. David Holley, who sent over the screenshot below, called it &#8220;obnoxious as hell.&#8221; He said he was surprised to see it in his Newsfeed in the first place because he doesn&#8217;t use any of the social reader apps. What&#8217;s more, those articles weren&#8217;t really &#8220;trending&#8221; &#8212; only one of his friends had read each of the articles highlighted in the section. Screenshot courtesy of David Holley. It may be only a test, but at this point, the feature &#8212; which already exists in different forms on Twitter and Google+ &#8212; seems more annoying than helpful. I&#8217;d rather see a &#8220;Trending Articles&#8221; tab on the side of the page that allows me to tap into the stories of the moment. I&#8217;m not interested in having what are essentially advertisements for social reader apps taking up valuable real estate in my Newsfeed. Facebook could not be reached for comment. Top screenshot taken by Mashable&#8217;s Stephanie Haberman. Front page thumbnail courtesy of iStockphoto, -Oxford- More About: Facebook, Media, NewsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/facebook-trending-articles/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/facebook-trending-articles/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Media Is Taking Over the News Industry [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>More than ever, people are using Twitter, Facebook and other social media sources to learn about what&#8217;s happening in the world as traditional news outlets become increasingly less relevant to the digital generation. American forces&#8217; raid on Osama Bin Laden, Whitney Houston&#8216;s death, the Hudson River plane landing &#8212; these are just a few of many major news stories ordinary citizens broke on Twitter first. Professional journalists, meanwhile, use Twitter all the time to break news quickly before writing up full articles. And the business side is going digital too. Online news now generates more revenue than print newspapers. But the trend toward Internet and social media-based news &#8212; and the accompanying rush to be first to report a story &#8212; also comes with pitfalls. Some 50% of news consumers have received &#8220;breaking news&#8221; via social media, only to find out later it was erroneously reported. All this and more comes from the online education portal Schools.com, which pulled research from sources including the Washington Post, Pew Research Center and Reuters to put together the infographic below. Check it out to see the fuller picture of how social media is coming to dominate the news industry. How much do you rely on social media for news compared to more traditional sources? Has that balance changed for you recently? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy iStockphoto, DNY59 More About: Facebook, infographics, News, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/social-media-and-the-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/social-media-and-the-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
