<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Investor&#8217;s TV Special Looks for Next Mark Zuckerberg</title>
      <description>Tech investor Peter Thiel is looking for 20 of the biggest innovators in Silicon Valley under the age of 20, offering $100,000 to contestants so they can further develop their projects. In a CNBC special called "20 Under 20: Transforming Tomorrow," the two-part series follows the journey of 20 young men and women who aim to become the next Steve Jobs and Mark Zuckerberg. The show, which airs on July 11 and July 12 at 10:00 p.m. ET on CNBC, will show contestants pitching concepts to a room for of Silicon Valley investors and entrepreneurs, including Sean Parker and Elon Musk SEE ALSO: One-way Ticket to Mars, Please: Startup Plans Space Colon&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, Entertainment, Facebook, investors, mark zuckerberg, mashable video, steve jobs, TV</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/20-under-20-transforming-tomorrow/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/20-under-20-transforming-tomorrow/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Leap Second Bug&#8217; Causes Glitches for LinkedIn, Reddit, More</title>
      <description>After an extra second was added to the clock on Saturday to better align it with the Earth's rotation schedule, a whole slew of websites from LinkedIn, Foursquare and Reddit to Mozlila, Yelp and Gawker sites experienced technical issues. Known as a "leap second," which is a basic one-second adjustment applied to the Coordinated Universal Time (UTC) to keep it up-to-date with solar time, the additional second added didn't sit well with various web servers. For example, Reddit said it was having Java and Cassandra issues and Gawker's entire site network was down for about 45 minutes. Other sites such as Yelp and Stumbleupon also reported technical trouble. We are having some Jav&#8230; Continue reading... More About: foursquare, linkedin, reddit, space, technology, trending, World, yelp</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/leap-second-bug-outages/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/leap-second-bug-outages/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build &#8212; and Keep &#8212; an Engaged Audience [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Every web publisher -- and especially content marketer -- yearns for an engaged and loyal audience. But with the sheer volume of noise, clutter and -- well, content -- online it can be hard to figure out how to reach people and keep them coming back for more. The content marketing agency BlueGlass knows a lot about how to do this well. They've run successful campaigns for clients including eBay, Conde Nast and Greatist. Now BlueGlass is ready to share some of its secrets with Mashable readers. The company produced this exclusive infographic to run down some of the ways you too can build an engaged audience online. Here are a few quick tips: Make sure you have a gripping headline, ke&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/how-to-build-an-engaged-audience-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/how-to-build-an-engaged-audience-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"All we need is 250 votes..."</title>
      <description>This is cruel marketing. If you're like me, you've gotten dozens of emails over the last week about a promotion that Chase and Living Social are running in which they're promising local businesses that work within their community a chance to win a grant for $250,000. The emails almost always have the line, All we need is a vote from 250 kind friends and supporters like you. Here's why it's doubly dangerous. First, clearly the organization doesn't actually get a grant in exchange for only getting 250 online votes. Hey, 250 online votes won't even get you a pack of chewing gum these days. No, all the votes do is make you eligible to apply for the grant. And yet the organization, perhaps a worthy one, is now spamming thousands of people offering this sliver of hope, all in rush to get 250 votes, even though the chances that anything will happen are perilously close to zero. There are only 12 grants available in total. That's pitiful. Hopes raised, hopes dashed. And then, for the small businesses, the ones who get through this hurdle and then get through the hurdle of the application, once again, hopes raised, hopes dashed. There's nothing wrong with competitions and difficult to achieve goals. Nothing wrong with making it hard to get into Brown or get a Gates Foundation grant. The dangerous mistake is making the organizations (and then their core supporters) think it's likely, or easy. You end up not only burning the brand of Living Social and Chase (who probably had good intentions) but by extension, hurting the brand and permission relationships of the very organizations you're trying to help. Peter and the wolf... the villagers aren't going to come next time. Pepsi did the same thing with charities last year, and my concern is the same: when you activate your supporters, you need a clear path to victory, not a wild goose chase. One significant way around this: have the outbound messages of the tribe be about more than the grant. Figure out how putting in the effort to help your local organization actually strengthens ties, instead of weakening them. The pursuit could be even better than the prize if you establish the right groundwork. To be really clear: it's harder to cut through the clutter than ever before, but just because a gimmick is going to cut through the clutter doesn't mean you should use it. It doesn't pay to make a lot of noise if that noise ends up hurting you in the long run.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/07/all-we-need-is-250-votes.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/07/all-we-need-is-250-votes.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Barack Obama &#8220;Sings&#8221; Call Me Maybe</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s the endlessly viral song that won&#8217;t seem to die. President Obama is the latest to join in on the &#8220;Call Me Maybe&#8221; trend. The President (presumably unknowingly) performs the song via a clever mashup from YouTube channel baracksdubs. Carly Rae Jepsen&#8217;s &#8220;Call Me Maybe&#8221; has taken on a life of its own and inspired multiple re-imaginings and spin-offs. The trend of college sports teams performing the crazy catchy song started with the Harvard baseball team. Soon, sports teams all over were joining in. SEE ALSO: Watch 11 Sports Teams Rock Out to &#8216;Call Me Maybe&#8217; [VIDEOS] Other memorable renditions included the quirky video from the Miss USA contestants and Donald Trump. There seems to be no end in sight for &#8220;Call Me Maybe.&#8221; How do you want to see the catchy pop song re-incarnated next? More About: barack obama, Call Me Maybe, Entertainment, Music, obamaFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/president-barack-obama-sings-call-me-maybe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/president-barack-obama-sings-call-me-maybe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudi Arabia allows women in Olympics</title>
      <description>Saudi Arabia will let its female athletes compete in the Olympics for the first time, its embassy in London said.</description>
      <link>http://edition.cnn.com/2012/06/25/sport/saudia-arabia-olympic-women/index.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+rss%2Fcnn_latest+%28RSS%3A+Most+Recent%29</link>
      <guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2012/06/25/sport/saudia-arabia-olympic-women/index.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+rss%2Fcnn_latest+%28RSS%3A+Most+Recent%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Questions to Ask During Your Next Interview</title>
      <description>Jayne Mattson is Senior Vice President at Keystone Associates, a leading career management and transition services consulting firm in Boston. Mattson specializes in helping mid-to-senior level individuals in new career exploration, networking strategies and career decisions based on corporate culture fit. As you look for a new job, will you take any job offer or are you looking for the right one? What does the right job mean? Too often job seekers do not take enough time to reflect on where they have been in their careers before they actively begin their new job search. And when they receive an offer, they do not have any criteria that help them determine the right fit. To help you identify what the right role would look like, think back on times during your career when you were the most satisfied. What role did you love doing, what type of manager were you working for and what was the culture like during this time? Finding a perfect fit comes down to three main questions that your potential employer must answer: Now you know your criteria for the right role, you need to ask courageous questions in your interview &#8212; not safe ones &#8212; to stand out from your competition. Safe questions include: A response from an interviewer will give you some answers, but will you find out what you really need to know to take the job with confidence? Here are more courageous questions to ask. 1. How receptive are you to feedback from your employees when do you do something they disagree with? If one of your values is being able to speak up (diplomatically, of course) when you disagree with a certain decision or behavior of your manager or peers, then this is for you. This question will help you understand how receptive your manager and others would be to constructive feedback without fear of retribution. 2. As a manager, what frustrates you about the people that work for you? As often as you can during the interview, ask questions where the manager would be able to tell you about a specific situation and provide concrete anecdotes. In this case, you want to know what frustrates him or her, so if you get the job, you will know what behaviors to watch out for in yourself. 3. Is there a project your department is working on now? If so, how are you interacting with your staff on it? You certainly want direction from your new manager, but not one that micro-manages your work. If you ask the safe question, &#8220;Do see yourself as a micro-manager?&#8221; they might answer, &#8220;No, I am not at all.&#8221; However, if you ask the riskier question, you may hear he is involved in the project every step of the way &#8212; a potential red flag for you about his style. 4. Can you give me an example of how you work collaboratively with other departments? Your idea of how people collaborate can be completely different than others, so this question helps you assess if the environment is compatible with the way you work best. 5. Does the company welcome celebrating special occasions in employees&#8217; lives? What was the last occasion your department celebrated? This question is a must if your idea of a fun workplace culture includes celebrating special occasions. Now, if the person mentions, &#8220;We don&#8217;t tend to celebrate,&#8221; you could follow up and get a sense whether they would be receptive to it the future. 6. What would be the three things that your peers would say you do extremely well? This question is often asked about you &#8212; the interviewer is listening carefully to what you will say. In some cases, they might follow up with people you are referring to in your answer to verify what you said. You could ask this question to the manager, potential peer or even HR to get a better idea of how the company operates. Since working in teams is much more prevalent in today&#8217;s businesses, you&#8217;ll want to know more about your colleagues. 7. I understand the company has a formal recognition program; however, what type of recognition have you recently given to one of your staff? If recognition or praise is one of your values, then this is a good question. It not only tells you about the company culture, but also if the manager is generous with recognizing the great work of his team. Nearly everyone wants recognition for the work they do, but in very different ways. Find out whether the methods of the company you&#8217;re considering work for you. 8. Has anyone on your staff been promoted over the last couple of years? If so, what was the reason why this person was promoted? If you are looking for development opportunities, you will want to know what those would look like. You&#8217;ll also want to know if the person was promoted because they pushed the subject or if the manager led the process. 9. What type of work do you delegate to your staff? You want to work for a manager who delegates, so you can develop beyond your role. If a manager is not a good delegator, then he might be insecure about his role and not want you to know what they are doing. This could potentially hold you back from promotions or development. 10. What are the three main factors you will be using to determine the right person for this job? This question is best asked toward the end of the interview, so the interviewer might use some of what you have to offer as some of the factors. You should find out how you fit in with the manager and job criteria, so if you could address the concerns in the post-interview correspondence and next round of interviews. 11. What have been the main characteristics of your favorite employees? When someone is talking about a favorite employee, watch for their body language, tone of voice and their word usage. These factors will help you determine if you have some of their same qualities and if not, it will give you more to think about after the interview. 12. What was the company&#8217;s most strategic decision made in the last year? Could you describe how they came to this decision? You want to work for a company that is planning for the future. By asking this question, it will demonstrate to the interviewer that you are thinking ahead. It will also help you understand what you might need to do to keep yourself current in your field and continue to add value to the company. 13. Can you give me an example of how and why one of your staff made a major mistake, and what was your response to it? You want to be able to take risks, but you also want to know your manager will support you in resolving it &#8212; not reprimand you. Asking this question will give you a sense of the level of risk-taking that would be acceptable. Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/questions-job-interview/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/questions-job-interview/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Content Creators Benefit From The New SEO</title>
      <description>Due to big changes in the SEO landscape, designers, photographers, videographers and writers have new opportunities to build their reputation, expand brand awareness and generate more leads. This post describes five important developments that content creators should be aware of, and then we&#8217;ll outline several ways to capitalize on them. Five SEO Developments That Favor Content Producers Thanks to self-publishing and social networks, the world is drowning in content. Google&#8217;s response: make it easy for searchers to drill down to exactly what they are looking for. Today, we can perform a search and look at the results all together in one big chunk, or we can carve off just a piece. We can look at search results from complete strangers, from people we know or from both. In the past, search results simply connected keywords to websites. Today, in pursuit of an easier way to drill down, Google also connects keywords to social networks, user behavior and authors. Here are five ways this is playing out, and why it&#8217;s all great news for content creators. 1. Personalized Search While search engine users are accustomed to getting objective results on search engine results pages (SERPs), Google now serves up &#8220;subjective&#8221; results as well. When logged into Google and with personalized search turned on, you will see SERPs that include results based on your Web browsing history, as well as content authored or endorsed by your social connections. Personalization can radically change what you see in regular searches and image searches. Here is a Google image search that demonstrates the difference. My search for &#8220;how to use twitter&#8221; with personalization turned off yields the following: Image search without personalization. With personalization turned on, the results look like this: Image search with personalization. Notice that the first two rows of images are completely different. At the top of my personalized search, I see 10 images associated with my Google+ connections. With personalized search turned on, I also have the option to view only my personal results. This is intriguing. Google is doing everything it can to encourage personalized search. It has a selfish interest in doing so: it wants as many people as possible to be logged into Google for as long as possible, using Google products, providing Google with data and being exposed to personalized Google ads. As personalized search gains traction with users, content creators will be able to gain a lot of search visibility in three ways: Creators become visible to their direct connections. Content associated with a particular creator will get top position in personalized searches conducted by people who have circled them. Imagine what would happen if a creator tripled the number of circles they were in, or if Google began to incorporate Twitter and Pinterest follows into its personalized search results. Creators become visible to their indirect connections. If a creator&#8217;s content is endorsed by someone in the Google+ network, the content could appear in the personalized results of searches conducted by that person&#8217;s connections. The ripple effect can extend a considerable distance. Creators become visible to people who visit their website. If someone frequents a creator&#8217;s website, Google will serve that creator&#8217;s content in their personalized searches. The trend: As time goes on, expect Google to get smarter about how it ranks personalized content, and for Google to cast a wider net across social networks to retrieve it. Quick tip for creatives: Strengthen and broaden your social connections to give your work more exposure on search engines. Keep looking for better ways to bring new visitors to your website, and to keep them coming back. 2. The Importance of Social Shares One factor that Google considers in evaluating a page of content is its social shares. Google sees likes, +1s, tweets and other types of shares as indicators of content quality and trustworthiness. This is reasonable enough: a blog post with 1500 retweets has more clearly established value than a comparable post with five. Social sharing is more important than ever. At the moment, how much value Google accords to social shares is still unclear, which is fair enough because many questions remain unanswered. Is a tweet more or less valuable than a like? How do you evaluate the authority of the person doing the sharing? How are people gaming the system to inflate the number of shares? Nevertheless, we should expect social sharing to grow in importance for SEO. First, there is demand: people would love to consider social endorsements for certain types of searches, provided they have confidence in the data. Secondly, there is self-interest: Google is committed to its social network, Google+, and isn&#8217;t about to ignore it on its own search engine. The trend: Social sharing now has its biggest impact on standard search results. Expect Google to ratchet up the presence of share-influenced links in personalized results as well. For instance, we could start to see a variety of segmented search options that display content shared by a defined subset of your connections. Quick tip for creatives: Make social-sharing buttons prominent to make it easy for people to share content on your website; actively engage in social media; and publish your content on websites where content is widely shared. 3. The Rise Of Search Segmentation In the old days, there weren&#8217;t too many ways to slice and dice search results. Today, there are scores. Tomorrow, there will be hundreds. Multiple search options create opportunities. More segmentation means more opportunity for freelance authors to improve their search visibility based on the nature of their content. When results are lumped together in one big mass, it&#8217;s challenging for a small enterprise to stand out. However, if creatives focus their content efforts on, for example, standing out in a particular segment, then they could capture a larger share of segmented searches. (An example of how to go about this appears in the &#8220;Reading Level&#8221; segment in the next section.) Note, too, that segmented search offers a &#8220;personalized&#8221; option, where, again, users can zero in on content based on their browsing history and social connections. The trend: Google will continue to categorize content to help users drill down to search results that are precisely relevant to their intent, rather than broadly relevant to their keywords. In particular, segmented search options for images and video will become much more sophisticated, in response to our insatiable appetite for visual content. Quick tip for creatives: Stay current on how Google segments content, and shape yours to stand out in segments that are natural homes for your work. 4. More Emphasis on Quality and More Transparency For years, creatives have complained that &#8220;black hat&#8221; SEO tactics pollute rankings, pushing high-quality content down the page. However, as Google&#8217;s algorithm grows more sophisticated, it gets better at combatting black-hat practices &#8212; more great news for content producers. Google is sending clearer SEO signals. Google fights content spam by emphasizing quality in its algorithm and by being transparent in how quality is calculated. Quality has always been a focus; the current level of transparency is something new. Google&#8217;s Panda update, released in 2011, was a declaration of war against content manipulators. A primary goal of this algorithm change &#8212; and of many that followed &#8212; was to decisively penalize worthless content and to reward highly relevant, meaningful and trustworthy content. In addition to the algorithmic measures, Google is taking the smoke and mirrors out of search by more openly communicating algorithm changes to SEOs and the general public. Why? In some cases, black-hat tactics were inadvertent, caused by website administrators using outdated techniques or misinterpreting Google&#8217;s algorithmic intent. Furthermore, a good deal of high-quality content gets lost in the search shuffle because creators simply ignore SEO. More than ever, Google wants every website to be optimized and optimized properly. The more high-caliber content Google can serve up to users in SERPs, the more business it will do. The trend: Google will push hard in this direction, devising more accurate methods of evaluating the relevance, substance and trustworthiness of content. It will get better at interpreting both the inherent quality of the work itself and the social-sharing data associated with it. Quick tip for creatives: Stay up to date on how to communicate the quality of your text, images and video to Google. (Links to step-by-step tutorials on how to do this are provided at the end of this post.) 5. Google+ and the rel=author Link Google enthusiasts see the Google+ social network as the greatest thing since sliced bread. Most everybody else thinks Google+ is less useful for marketing than sliced bread. But whether or not you like Google+, the network cannot be ignored for SEO. Content creators ought to take note of two particular aspects of the network. The rel=author link builds a creator&#8217;s brand and search visibility. First, Google+ content gets indexed and ranked. In fact, when you publish original content on Google+, not only is it indexed and ranked, but it is given prime positioning in personalized SERPs. Images and video that are stored on Google or associated with personal pages on Google+ also receive greater exposure in search, as demonstrated earlier in the screen captures for image search. Secondly, the rel=author link associates a page of Web content with its author&#8217;s personal Google+ profile. This is a technical mouthful, but it&#8217;s a big deal for creatives. Google has begun to link content to its creators as well as its publishers. &#8220;Authorship markup,&#8221; or &#8220;author rank,&#8221; is being developed at a furious rate because people sometimes want the option of searching for content by a particular creator or want results ranked according to the authority or expertise of the creators. The trend: High-authority creators will see their content become more visible in search results, and for that reason, publishers will need to seek out high-authority creators to boost traffic to their websites. Quick tip for creatives: Set up a personal Google+ profile and incorporate the rel=author link into your published content. (Instructions on how to do this are provided in the next section.) How To Capitalize On The New SEO Given these recent developments, let&#8217;s look at how authors can manage their content to increase its visibility and obtain all of the benefits that go along with that. Some of the following suggestions are technical in nature, while others are creative techniques that are not always thought of as aspects of SEO. However, with Google getting better at evaluating the quality of content, people are now less able to inflate the ranking of inferior content through technical manipulation and must instead treat the quality of their content itself as the linchpin of their SEO program. Create Highly Sharable Content SEO is no longer a game of mechanical keyword placement. In fact, SEO has moved even beyond a game of relevance and substance. For content to succeed in search today, it must be relevant, substantive and sharable. Content creators can use a variety of stylistic and marketing techniques to enhance social interest in their content, including the following: Convert dry text into visually engaging content to generate immediate interest; Provide consistently informative, well-researched and enlightening content that generates long-term interest; Develop a unique voice and style; Take a provocative stance or add humor when appropriate and compatible with the corporate style; Provide detailed content on a topic that has not been widely covered (scarcity of information increases demand); Attribute information to factual sources (trustworthy content is more confidently shared); Link generously (encourage sharing by setting a good example); Title content creatively to spark curiosity; Use Web design and typographic best practices to optimize readability and scannability; Embed video in blog posts and Web pages; Display attractive and intuitive social-sharing buttons; Give users an incentive to share. Set-Up Methods and Benefits: Use The rel=author Link Here&#8217;s a basic outline of how to set up rel=author links for your content. Google has a more thorough rundown. Create a personal Google+ profile page with a high-quality headshot; Validate your email address; In the byline of any content that you create, set the anchor text to be your name as it appears in your Google+ profile, and link to your profile with a URL that looks like this: https://plus.google.com/102318046680468697385?rel=author. When your content is published, link back to its URL from the &#8220;Contributor to&#8221; section of your Google+ profile. Once your content is indexed, your Google+ profile picture and name, along with the publication date, title and description, will (sometimes) appear in SERPs, in both standard and personalized results. This gives you more exposure, and it instills trust in users that the content has a human author, and that the author is reputable. This adds up to higher ranking and more people clicking through to your content. Please note: Author attribution is still in the early stages of development. Google frequently changes both the procedures for setting up links and the presentation of author information in SERPs. The instructional link above should be up to date whenever you are ready to dive in. How to set up different types of content: Guest blog posts Set up a rel=author link somewhere in your content. The most sensible place to do this is either in the byline or in the bio area. If the blog doesn&#8217;t accommodate such placement, then a rel=author link in the body of the post would work, too. Infographics If you create an infographic, add a blurb below the image saying, &#8220;Infographic by [your name],&#8221; with a rel=author link. Video Follow the same procedure as described above for infographics. Dual authorship What if an article is coauthored or the author wants to credit a photographer? The best practice is to use only one rel=author link per page. If more than one link appears on a page, the first that appears in the markup will be the one whose name and image are featured in SERPs. Bring Back Blog Marketing Blogs are back. In terms of social sharing, blog posts are far more likely to be shared than standard Web pages. In terms of segmentation, blog posts figure prominently in search segments such as news, time ranges and, of course, blogs. Here are some blogging techniques that fit especially well in today&#8217;s SEO environment: Incorporate the rel=author link into the byline of every post in your archive. This establishes you as the author and gives all of your existing content an SEO boost. Several WordPress plugins are available to automatically set up the links for single- and multi-author blogs. If you are using another CMS, check with the developer to see whether and how it supports rel=author linking. Ramp up guest blogging efforts. Getting published on highly authoritative, highly shared blogs has always been useful, and adding the rel=author link to your guest posts delivers even more value. Blog directly on Google+. Earlier, we mentioned that Google indexes and ranks original Google+ posts. To take advantage of this, some &#8220;plussers&#8221; are actually writing lengthy original posts on the network. This strategy could be well worth testing, especially if you already have an active presence on the network. And it could work particularly well for photographers, designers and videographers, who can surround their visual content with keyword-optimized text. Consider the Reading Level When Composing Let&#8217;s consider an example of creating targeted content to capitalize on Google&#8217;s segmented search. Depending on the topic, writing at a particular reading level could be quite advantageous for SEO. For instance, here is how Google categorizes content that matches a search for &#8220;social media marketing&#8221;: If you wrote a post about social media marketing at an advanced reading level, Google would probably rank it very low in its fully aggregated SERPs. Because the vast majority of content (82%) is written at an intermediate level, Google assumes that is what searchers are looking for. However, for segmented searches, it&#8217;s a different story. Writing an advanced article would probably make you highly visible to people drilling down to that reading level. And even though it&#8217;s a small group (2%), it could include people with a lot of interest and ready to take action. Another possibility is to write a basic article about social media marketing. Here again, there is less search competition (16%), and there is a good chance that people who are new to social media will want to drill down to basic articles. Google does not clearly explain how it defines these three reading levels. But its model, according to Google&#8217;s Daniel M. Russell, is based primarily on input from teachers who have classified various pages of text. You can read more about Google&#8217;s reading level model on Russell&#8217;s personal blog. The New SEO Formula: Relevance + Substance + Shares = Visibility At one time, SEO was a fairly straightforward exercise in shaping content on a particular domain to rank highly on basically one flavor of SERPs for a given set of queries. But as we&#8217;ve seen, Google now considers who created the content in addition to where the content lives, and query options have expanded thanks to the segmentation of search options. On top of all this, personalized search options enable users to view results based on the online behavior of themselves and their social media connections. While technical expertise still matters tremendously in SEO, authorship is gaining ground, and quickly. Google is attempting to cut out the SEO middleman and make search a matter of directly connecting great content creators (as defined by the inherent quality of their work and their popularity) with searchers who will find great value in their content. This explains why Google is being more forthcoming about its algorithm: the maneuver levels the technical playing field and forces SEO practitioners to differentiate themselves through the content itself. What more could content creators ask for? Resources Below are resources containing detailed information on content-related SEO techniques that should be of interest to creatives who market themselves and their work. &#8220;Author Information in Search Results,&#8221; Google Webmaster Tools Instructions on setting up rel=author links. &#8220;Google Evaluates Reading Level?!?,&#8221; Pure Visibility How Google evaluates reading levels and why it matters to writers. &#8220;Webmaster Guidelines: Quality Guidelines,&#8221; Google Webmaster Tools Best practices for content quality. &#8220;Image Publishing Guidelines,&#8221; Google Webmaster Tools &#8220;Video Best Practices,&#8221; Google Webmaster Tools &#8220;Search by Image,&#8221; Google How image search works. &#8220;Facebook + Twitter&#8217;s Influence on Google&#8217;s Search Rankings,&#8221; Rand Fishkin, The Daily SEO Blog Note: All images used for this post have exclusively been created by Straight North. (al) (il) &#169; Brad Shorr for Smashing Magazine, 2012.</description>
      <link>http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2012/06/28/content-creators-benefit-from-new-seo/</link>
      <guid>http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2012/06/28/content-creators-benefit-from-new-seo/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook&#8217;s Mobile Future Rests On Today&#8217;s Feature Phone Users</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s Note: The following guest post by Thomas Clayton, the Chief Executive Officer of voice blogging startup Bubble Motion. Prior to Bubble Motion, Clayton was GM of the Worldwide Telecom Business at BEA Systems, an infrastructure software company acquired by Oracle for $8.5B USD. Clayton holds a BA from Harvard Business School and a BS degree from UC Berkeley. It goes without saying that Facebook is the darling of this era&#8217;s technology boom. However, as many have repeated over the last month since its IPO, the company is now turning to face some major obstacles. Namely, adoption of the service is slowing, and the company is making little revenue off its increasingly large base of mobile users. I&#8217;m going to explain how Facebook can both supercharge user adoption &#8211; potentially hitting three billion users by 2014 &#8211; and who they can work with to boost their mobile revenues drastically. In fact, the strategy may seem counter-intuitive in its simplicity: Facebook must prepare to go old school and partner with wireless carriers in its fastest growing emerging markets. Find Tomorrow&#8217;s Smartphone Users Today, there are five billion mobile connections across the globe. According to Cisco, by 2016, this number will double to 10 billion connections across eight billion mobile devices. Facebook has the opportunity to be installed on every single one, but the company must start now in order to get in front of this coming wave of smartphone adoption. Who are the smartphone users of tomorrow? The feature phone users of today. Facebook&#8217;s long-term vision and successfully monetizing mobile depends on penetrating this market. The company knows this: they&#8217;ve improved the biggest draws of Facebook on mobile, the News Feed, released the standalone Facebook Camera app, and are rolling out a mobile-only ad platform. On the feature phone side, they acquired Snaptu in March 2011 &#8211; an app platform that allowed users to access services like Facebook and Twitter from web-enabled feature phones. They rolled the technology out as Facebook for Every Phone in June 2011, and partnered with hundreds of operators around the world to entice users by making the associated data free for 90 days. In the year since, the app page has registered a whopping 90 million likes. With today&#8217;s social juggernauts building their mobile services exclusively on smartphone platforms like iOS, Android, and Windows Phone, they are leaving out an enormous potential user base: 90 percent of mobile users in the developing world do not have smartphones. For example, mammoth developing economies in Asia such as China, India, and Indonesia all have a smartphone penetration rate of less than 10 percent, compared to 50+ percent in the U.S. and most developed countries. Moreover, 90 percent of those feature phones do not even have data connectivity. Thus, even companies that build apps enabled for feature phones, are still missing out on the masses in extremely large developing markets. Catering to feature phone users in the developing world in the short-term allows companies to ensure a vast upside in five years, as users accelerate their migration towards lower-cost smartphones. Services and social networks like Facebook are currently only addressing the tip of the iceberg of this unrealized upside. They should look to entrench their services even deeper into the developing world in order to fuel mass growth and user adoption. After all, while average ARPU of these feature phone users in developing markets is significantly lower than smartphone users in developed markets and the mobile ad revenue markets are still in their infancy, the consumers willing to pay for subscription service and access to social media services is phenomenally higher than in developed markets since paying for these types of services via a prepaid card is the norm and far more frictionless. Friending Emerging Market Operators Many of Facebook&#8217;s services can be adapted to feature phones via very basic telephony services &#8211; SMS and voice networks for retrieval of updates and USSD for authentication and login. Thus, a user wouldn&#8217;t even need a data connection, much less a smartphone or app. Of course, this is not an easy endeavor and requires deploying servers in an operator&#8217;s network, but looking at the new users it would bring to the service, it is an extremely small price to pay. This would allow the billions of users on feature phones with no data connectivity in feature phones to access the service &#8211; and their willingness to pay a monthly subscription for this is extremely high. Moreover, it acts as bridge to higher tech mobile devices as consumers upgrade over the next five years. Working with mobile operators can be challenging, but ultimately phenomenally rewarding. For example, my company Bubble Motion was able to attract 17 million users in less than two years and monetize them quite significantly, with no marketing spend whatsoever, by working directly with wireless carriers in a handful of target countries across Asia. Our potential user footprint is a whopping 2+ billion feature phones, which is far beyond what we could&#8217;ve hoped for on a smartphone app. We recently launched a smartphone app version of our service, Bubbly, but for the foreseeable future, our feature phone users will be the overwhelming majority of our revenue stream. Like I said, while ARPU of smartphone users may be higher, the willingness of social media-starved feature phone users to pay for services is significantly higher. By cracking a few deals with mobile operators in target high-growth countries, Facebook could see their user numbers shoot upwards once again. Facebook has some experience in this already &#8211; they&#8217;ve already partnered with AT&amp;T, Verizon and T-Mobile in the U.S. and with Bango in the U.K, mostly to streamline payment through Facebook credits charged directly to user mobile bills. They&#8217;ve also partnered with emerging market carriers to peddle their feature phone app &#8211; but only on superficial levels like subsidizing data costs for users for 90 days. Compared to the App Store model, leveraging operator networks makes it much easier to reach the masses. On the other hand, working with operators is not easy, which is why so many Valley companies have shunned the idea. However, those with the scale and reach of Facebook or Twitter, need to embrace operators to take their user growth and service to the next level. Facebook Can Start Making Money in Mobile It won&#8217;t be a lot at first, but by working with mobile carriers, Facebook can extract a healthy revenue share from operators. For example, our current average revenue per user (ARPU) is around $4 in Japan &#8211; this is the same amount Facebook makes off of its web-based U.S. users, where it has established a strong ad revenue model. By contrast, we&#8217;re making it solely off usage and access via mobile, which users are completely okay with when accessing services via their mobile device. Feature phone users can spend money much more easily than their smartphone counterparts (especially those on Android), due to the fact that they are tied into a network&#8217;s billing service. In Asia and most developing markets, a very small percentage of smartphone users have entered their credit card information into Google Play for app purchases &#8211; in fact, most do not even have credit cards! Direct billing makes up for the greater engagement and web-access that comes with using a smartphone app. In fact, as I write this article, Facebook is announcing frictionlesspayments in collaboration with mobile operators. However, this still does not address the feature phone users without a data plan, which is the overwhelming majority of mobile users globally. This is where integrating tightly with operators, especially in emerging markets, will pay huge dividends. As feature phone users become increasingly engaged with the service and then upgrade to smartphones, this trickle will turn into a torrent. They&#8217;ll be much more likely to open their wallets after having done so in the past &#8211; you have to attach the hose before turning on the water. Although partnering with mobile operators is something Facebook has been working on over the past year, expect to see them double down on these efforts in the years to come. To date, it has been primarily focused on getting them to make data charges free for accessing Facebook via their mobile device. Once again, this is great, but does not address those that do not even have data plans &#8211; which are the true masses. All of these lessons come from experience. Our service started out as an operator- embedded service via voice calls and SMS, similar to Twitter in the early days, and has only recently launched a smartphone app version. This has enabled us to both attract a massive audience &#8211; one which is now following the evolutionary path as they migrate towards smartphones and a higher-touch experience, all while sticking with our service. In that way, we find ourselves well positioned for the coming Asian smartphone boom. Although Facebook has made some good strides in this direction, it should double down and embrace the emerging market trend in order to find the serious money in mobile.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/01/facebooks-mobile-future-rests-on-todays-feature-phone-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/01/facebooks-mobile-future-rests-on-todays-feature-phone-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Hashtag History Gets a Musical Tribute [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Here's a funky little piece of weekend edutainment: the history of the Twitter hashtag as performed by horn player and YouTube music video maker Paul the Trombonist. Raps interspersed with jazzy trombone interludes tell how the now-ubiquitous number sign followed by letters went from a random nothing on the social network to something tweeters today rely on to spread important news, tell jokes and tell they world they're #winning. We haven't vigorously vetted Paul's history lesson, but it checks out against a quick web search. If Paul the Trombonist looks familiar to you, it's because he's also the man behind "Playing With Your Phone While Sitting on the Toilet," a viral hit from&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Twitter, Video, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/twitter-hashtag-history/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/twitter-hashtag-history/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon cloud outage takes down Netflix, Instagram, Pinterest, &amp; more</title>
      <description>An outage of Amazon&#8217;s Elastic Compute Cloud in North Virginia has taken down Netflix, Pinterest, Instagram, and other services. According to numerous Twitter updates and our own checks, all three services are unavailable as of Friday evening at 9:10 p.m. PT. Amazon&#8217;s service health dashboard indicates that there are power issues in its North Virginia data center, most likely caused by severe storms in the region. Independent checks by VentureBeat of Netflix, Instagram, Pinterest, and Heroku show each site not operating. Netflix acknowledged the issue on its customer support Twitter account: We will update this post when we have more. Developing post. Refresh for updates. Storm clouds photo: divingrocks/Flickr Filed under: cloud</description>
      <link>http://venturebeat.com/2012/06/29/amazon-outage-netflix-instagram-pinterest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</link>
      <guid>http://venturebeat.com/2012/06/29/amazon-outage-netflix-instagram-pinterest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amazon cloud outage takes down Netflix, Instagram, Pinterest, &amp; more</title>
      <description>An outage of Amazon&#8217;s Elastic Compute Cloud in North Virginia has taken down Netflix, Pinterest, Instagram, and other services. According to numerous Twitter updates and our own checks, all three services are unavailable as of Friday evening at 9:10 p.m. PT. Amazon&#8217;s service health dashboard indicates that there are power issues in its North Virginia data center, most likely caused by severe storms in the region. Independent checks by VentureBeat of Netflix, Instagram, Pinterest, and Heroku show each site not operating. Netflix acknowledged the issue on its customer support Twitter account: We will update this post when we have more. Developing post. Refresh for updates. Storm clouds photo: divingrocks/Flickr Filed under: cloud</description>
      <link>http://venturebeat.com/2012/06/29/amazon-outage-netflix-instagram-pinterest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</link>
      <guid>http://venturebeat.com/2012/06/29/amazon-outage-netflix-instagram-pinterest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
