<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest is Now the No. 3 Social Network in the U.S. [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Pinterest is now the number three most-popular social network in the U.S., behind Facebook and Twitter, according to Experian Hitwise. A new report from the researcher shows Pinterest got 21.5 million visits during the week ending Jan. 28, a nearly 30-fold increase over a comparable week in July. Not surprisingly, the site skews female with a 60/40 ration of women to men visitors. Experian rep Matt Tatham says Pinterest beat its next-closest competitor, LinkedIn, in total visits in February. Tatham says the rankings by total visits for March is as follows: 1. Facebook: 7 billion 2. Twitter: 182 million 3. Pinterest: 104 million 4. LinkedIn: 86 million 5. Tagged: 72 million 6. Google+: 61 million The report, which tracks visits rather than unique visitors, is based on web traffic and doesn&#8217;t factor in visits from mobile sites. According to Experian&#8217;s reckoning, Foursquare only got 2.9 million visits in March and Instagram got 10.2 million. ComScore, which doesn&#8217;t measure mobile traffic either, but ranks sites by uniques rather than total visits, did not include Pinterest in its list of the top 50 web properties in February. However, LinkedIn made number 27 with 36 million visitors. ComScore listed Pinterest as its number three &#8220;top-gaining&#8221; properties, however, with 17.8 million total visitors that month. ComScore&#8217;s March figures were not available at press time. More About: Experian Hitwise, Facebook, Google, pinterest, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Begins Testing Its Augmented Reality Glasses</title>
      <description>On Wednesday, Google gave people 20/20 vision about a secret augmented-reality project called Project Glass. The glasses are the company's first foray into wearable computing.</description>
      <link>http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/04/04/google-begins-testing-its-augmented-reality-glasses/</link>
      <guid>http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/04/04/google-begins-testing-its-augmented-reality-glasses/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These "Texts from Hillary Clinton" are hilarious http://t.co/evUtO0In (via @bostonmamas)</title>
      <description>phdinparenting: These "Texts from Hillary Clinton" are hilarious http://t.co/evUtO0In (via @bostonmamas) &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://textsfromhillaryclinton.tumblr.com/</link>
      <guid>http://textsfromhillaryclinton.tumblr.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do You Leave Work at 5:30? [POLL]</title>
      <description>Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg recently revealed that she leaves work every day at 5:30 p.m. and is home for dinner at 6 with her kids. Sandberg said that she&#8217;s only been &#8220;brave enough&#8221; to talk about her work habits in the last two years. If you also leave work early, Sandberg&#8217;s stance may assuage some of your guilt. If you regularly work later, but feel you&#8217;re doing it out of duty rather than actual need, maybe you&#8217;ll think twice &#8212; after all, Sandberg is doing OK. Then again, maybe you think that cutting out for dinner may be fine for someone of Sandberg&#8217;s stature, but you&#8217;re on your way up and need to prove yourself. Whatever the case, we&#8217;d like to hear from you. Please take the poll below and feel free to chime in in the comments section as well. Thumbnail image courtesy of World Economic Forum, Flickr Do you leave work at 5:30? More About: Facebook, polls, Sheryl SanbergFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/do-you-leave-work-at-530-poll/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/do-you-leave-work-at-530-poll/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Sues Five Major Spammers</title>
      <description>Twitter&#8217;s had it with spammers and wants to send a message with the help of law enforcement. On Thursday, the company filed a suit against five separate web tools and providers that allegedly make it easier to spam people on Twitter. &#8220;Twitter now has more than 140 million active users, and we continue to grow at a record pace,&#8221; Twitter said in a statement. &#8220;As our reach expands, we become a more attractive target for spammers. Even though spam is a small fraction of the content you can find on Twitter, we know just how distracting it can be.&#8221; The defendants in the suit are TweetAttacks (tweetattacks.com), TweetAdder (tweetadder.com), TweetBuddy (tweetbuddy.com), James Lucero (of justinlover.info) and Garland Harris (of troption.com), and are allegedly in violation of The Twitter Rules. &#8220;Taking legal action sends a clear message to all would-be spammers that there are serious and costly consequences to violating our Rules with their annoying and potentially malicious activity,&#8221; notes the statement. Twitter is not the first social network to get the law on its side to combat spammers. Earlier this year, Facebook and the Attorney General of Washington state teamed up to file two lawsuits against &#8220;clickjackers&#8221; who worked to spread spam on Facebook. In 2009, Google fought &#8220;Google money&#8221; schemes and the following year targeted illegal online prescription pharmacies. What do you think about Twitter&#8217;s lawsuit against these websites? What do you think the outcome will be? Tell us in the comments. Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, courtneyK More About: Google, spam, spammers, TwitterFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/05/twitter-sues-spammers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/05/twitter-sues-spammers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Americans Reading More Ebooks on Computers Than Ereaders, Phones [STUDY]</title>
      <description>One in five Americans read an ebook in the past year, according to a 3,000-person survey released Wednesday by the Pew Research Center. Of those one in five, 42% said they read an ebook on a computer, making it the most popular device for reading electronic copies of books. It&#8217;s a surprising finding, in part because desktops aren&#8217;t the most enjoyable nor convenient device for reading ebooks, and partly because most ebook publishers and retailers have prioritized mobile, ereader and tablet reading experiences over the desktop. Amazon, for instance, launched two generations of Kindle ereaders, as well as applications for smartphones and tablets, before it released apps for Macs (March 2010), the web (September 2010) and PCs (November 2010). After personal computers, the survey found that ereaders are the most popular devices among ebook readers (41%), followed by cellphones (29%) and tablets (23%). What else do we know about people who read ebooks? For one, they&#8217;re more voracious in their reading habits. The average ebook-reading person read 24 books in the past 12 months, compared to 15 for non-ebook readers. And ebook-reading respondents are not abandoning print: 88% said they read print as well as ebooks last year. Test subjects indicated they preferred ebooks for quick access and portability, but chose printed books for reading with children or sharing with others. Collectively, ebook reading is on the rise. According to Pew, four times as many people are reading on ebooks on a given day now than two years ago. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, mikkelwilliam More About: amazon, ebooks, ereaders, Kindle, nook, Pew</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/americans-ebooks-computers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/americans-ebooks-computers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups, This Is How Design Works &#226;&#8364;&#8220; by Wells Riley</title>
      <description>A guide to understanding digital %26 physical product design for startups</description>
      <link>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</link>
      <guid>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Tips To Maximize Your Brand&#8217;s YouTube Presence</title>
      <description>Michael &#8220;MJ&#8221; Jaindl is chief client officer at Buddy Media, maker of the social-enterprise software of choice for eight of the top ten advertisers in the world. Visit Buddy Media&#8217;s blog for more on social marketing. Creating an account on YouTube is simple, and building a channel for your brand is quick and easy. But at a time when most brand managers know the potential of this video-hosting medium, it&#8217;s not enough to simply have a presence. A brand must stand out to viewers by turning its channel into a destination. Otherwise, it runs the risk of getting lost among the more than 3 billion videos already viewed on YouTube each day. SEE ALSO: 6 Best Practices For Small Business YouTube Marketing This is why brands need a YouTube game plan that covers all aspects of the brand channel, including aesthetic, video content, and comment moderation. Below are eight tips for creating such a plan and turning your brand&#8217;s YouTube channel into a video hotspot. 1. Create a Schedule While every brand may not have the resources to churn out new videos every week, laying out a schedule and adhering to it will force you to create fresh content. That will draw people back to the channel, which is what you want. One way to make sure you&#8217;re creating regular video content is to develop a recurring series with a theme. This will make it easier to come up with ideas when you are stuck. DirecTV, for instance, has a playlist on their official channel devoted to how-to videos that provide users valuable information on their dish product. Using an activity calendar like the one shown above, you can remind your social networks about the type of content you&#8217;re publishing. You can create one yourself by syncing your YouTube content schedule with your other social networks to map out a strategy for cross-promotion. 2. Keep it Short YouTube generally caps videos at 15 minutes, but the closer you get to that limit, the less likely you are to keep viewers engaged. Consider that those watching may not have that kind of time. Telling a story in one or two minutes will help ensure that anyone watching sees your entire message. Many brands upload their television ads, which are usually under five minutes, to YouTube. A good example is Acura&#8217;s Super Bowl commercial featuring Jerry Seinfeld, which has received more than 18 million views. 3. Promote One of the great things about YouTube is its sharing functionality. On the other hand, with 48 hours of video being uploaded to YouTube every minute, there is a lot of competition for eyeballs on the site. This is why you must use existing digital assets to promote your channel and its content. Start by posting your videos across social networks to increase viewership, but remember that this will not necessarily drive traffic. You must also make sure you are posting links to the channel itself and actively encouraging users to subscribe. Earning subscribers will increase the chance that people will see new videos as soon as they log in to the YouTube homepage. It is also critical to optimize videos by entering a title with targeted keywords, a detailed description (the more the better!), and relevant keywords in the tags field. Filling in the important textual details will make it easier for users to find your videos because Google displays YouTube videos on the first page of search results. 4. Have a Channel Aesthetic YouTube gives you plenty of options to create a customized appearance for your channel. Make sure you create an aesthetic reflective of your brand&#8217;s overall digital presence. To ensure that visitors know they are watching a video coming straight from your organization, use logos and colors they already associate with your brand. In this example, Ford uses a simple design with a header that provides a familiar feeling to those accustomed to seeing Ford&#8217;s online presence. 5. Don&#8217;t Ignore the Comments Section There are two separate areas where you need to monitor comments. Users can comment on your channel homepage as well as below individual videos. YouTube administrators have the option to allow all comments, moderate comments before they are approved, or disable all comments. This is the case for both the channel and for individual videos. Additionally, comments can be moderated after the fact, by reporting them as spam or simply removing them from the comments section. It is important to monitor the chatter on videos and your channel page to make sure you are responding to conversations that warrant a response, as well as moderating inappropriate content that may pop up. Because comments are displayed so prominently, you can&#8217;t ignore them. Of course, you shouldn&#8217;t delete every negative comment, but you can set standards for deleting comments with foul language or other offensive content. 6. Choose Your Featured Video Wisely First impressions are everything. So when someone lands on your channel, don&#8217;t you want to put your best foot forward? Select a high-quality video that is entertaining, timely, and relevant. Switch the featured video regularly in order to keep your channel fresh and appealing. You also want to make sure your featured video has an eye-catching title that will make people want to watch it. The homepage for the Under Armour channel has a good example featuring Cam Newton. Notice the starter image that appears beneath the play button. You have the option to change the starter thumbnail within the video&#8217;s settings, too. 7. Make Playlists of Related Content Creating playlists are a great way to help viewers find more relevant content once they are finished watching a video. With the new YouTube layout, brands can place featured playlists front-and-center on the channel page. Within a playlist viewers can easily find related videos and can watch them, one after the next, without needing to manually press the play button. It&#8217;s important to make sure your playlists are accurately labeled so that users know exactly what they will find within each one. 8. Pay Attention to Analytics YouTube provides free analytics for your channel. This means you have access to performance data (views, subscribers); engagement data (likes, comments, shares, etc.); demographic data (location and gender of viewers); and per-video metrics. By reviewing this information you can better gauge how effectively you are utilizing the content on your channel and how you can fine-tune it to create an even better experience for your viewers and subscribers. Editor&#8217;s Note: Ford and Under Armour are clients of the author&#8217;s company. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, ozgurdonmaz More About: brands, contributor, features, social media marketing, YouTubeFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/05/brands-youtube-presence-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/05/brands-youtube-presence-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Is Investigating iPad Wi-Fi Issues [REPORT]</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://technews.garf.us/?p=145921&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+technewstk+%28Tech+News%29</link>
      <guid>http://technews.garf.us/?p=145921&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+technewstk+%28Tech+News%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Glass: One day... - YouTube</title>
      <description>We believe technology should work for you &#8212; to be there when you need it and get out of your way when you don't. A team within our Google[x] group started Pr...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media</title>
      <description>The Customer Experience Series is supported by Webtrends. Get insider tips and a step-by-step guide to acquiring, engaging and nurturing fans. Download the Playbook. We all know social media is an important tool for brand awareness and customer acquisition &#8212; but how exactly are you supposed to convert random Twitter and Facebook users into real-life customers? Well, that depends. Different brands have different challenges when it comes to customer acquisition: &#8220;If you&#8217;re our customer, you&#8217;ve signed up for a year-long service, unlike the Starbucks of the world, where you can be a customer by coming in for a cup of coffee one day,&#8221; says Lisa D&#8217;Aromando, social media community manager at Equinox. Whether you&#8217;re a clothing shop, a restaurant or a subscription service, you must tailor your strategy so that it makes sense for your brand. That said, there are a few universal ways to help your company attract new faces on the social web. &#8220;I&#8217;m a big believer in creating and sharing meaningful content,&#8221; says Danni Snyder, co-founder and creative director at jewelry brand Dannijo. &#8220;Over time, that is every brand&#8217;s best bet for creating and sustaining a following that will grow their business.&#8221; But what does it all entail? Mashable spoke with some super-social brands about how they find new customers and lock in their existing ones they have as repeat buyers. 1. Get Your Search On There are 340 million tweets sent per day &#8212; odds are that a few of them are referencing your brand, though you may not realize it. &#8220;Just because chatter on social media channels isn&#8217;t mentioning your brand by handle or hashtag doesn&#8217;t mean it isn&#8217;t happening,&#8221; says McKee Floyd, director of brand development at Sweetgreen. The key is to be proactive. For the company&#8217;s upcoming Sweetlife Festival, Floyd set up Twitter searches for &#8220;sweetlife&#8221; and &#8220;sweetlife festival&#8221; on TweetDeck, which pulls the tweets even if users didn&#8217;t include the hashtag. &#8220;As groups of friends have conversations back and forth on Twitter about whether or not they should buy tickets, we monitor and chime in with helpful info, answering logistical questions about the festival and hopefully swaying them towards choosing to attend.&#8221; Geoff Alexander, managing partner at Chicago&#8217;s Wow Bao, says his team also uses TweetDeck to search for certain keywords &#8212; such as &#8220;wow bao,&#8221; &#8220;baomouth&#8221; and &#8220;hot Asian buns&#8221; &#8212; and they reply to any and all posts they find. Wow Bao initially got into social media because there wasn&#8217;t a budget for advertising, so the brand opted to spread the word by giving away buns. &#8220;@BaoMouth searches the Internet for ways to reward people &#8212; giving away bao, full meals or mobile money [for the food truck],&#8221; says Alexander. But the search tactic works for more than just food concepts. Danni Snyder says she monitor mentions of Dannijo religiously and also searches Twitter for &#8220;jewelry.&#8221; Consuming social media buzz about jewelry &#8212; and not just Dannijo&#8217;s wares &#8212; helps the brand be &#8220;aware of what people are talking about, what they like and don&#8217;t like, etc.&#8221; says Snyder, which can help Dannijo cultivate a new audience with their next collection. One tip for finding new customers is to see who&#8217;s engaging with your competitors &#8212; if someone just started following or tweeted at or checked in at another bakery in the neighborhood, you could tweet at the person to come check out your cupcakes. They customer will appreciate the shout-out and the fact that you handpicked them to be your customer. Get clever with searches that are relevant to your business and offerings to help you target potential customers &#8212; then reel them in by being charming and human, not salesy. 2. Use Images to Engage Who would have thought Mr Dannijo would be back in such a good way?! #EVERYBODY #eyespy #MRDANNIJO @manrepeller @danielleasnyder @jodielynns #putaneyeonit A picture is worth a thousand words &#8212; photos drive twice as much engagement as text posts do on Facebook. So if you&#8217;re looking to attract some new fans, start snapping pics. Snyder says Instagram is her favorite medium for connecting with fans. &#8220;You can subliminally market without annoying your customers because each post is capable of accomplishing a number of things,&#8221; she says. &#8220;In one post, we can showcase a new design available at Dannijo.com, thus driving traffic to our ecommerce site; show how we&#8217;d style the jewelry; mention a tastemaker friend like Questlove or ManRepeller and promote them while they&#8217;re wearing Dannijo; inspire discussion and engagement, gaining valuable customer feedback; and provide followers some visual inspiration and insight into your creative process.&#8221; But the pics need not be product-focused. Dannijo posts photos of food and musicians that embody the Dannijo vibe. Similarly, Rent the Runway posts pictures of various style trends. &#8220;On Facebook, we try to use as much imagery as possible &#8212; not just promotional imagery of our dresses, but images that relate to pop-culture,&#8221; says Jenny Fleiss, president and co-founder of Rent the Runway. For example, in anticipation of the upcoming Great Gatsby movie, the RTR blog posted about Gatsby-inspired fashion trends. 3. Host a Competition Nothing gets customers going like some swag, so contests are a great way to boost your followers and engagement. But be strategic about what you&#8217;re offering, or else you could attract the wrong followers. ModCloth hosts monthly photo contests that garner hundreds of entries and thousands of votes. &#8220;Our most recent contest, Thrifted Treasures, asked our fans to share their favorite vintage finds, and our community could vote up their favorites,&#8221; explains Natasha Khan, ModCloth&#8217;s social media manager. &#8220;The social actions surrounding that event brought in thousands of new fans, which we otherwise would not have gained.&#8221; Khan says contests and offers have been the most high impact customer generation events for ModCloth. But if you&#8217;re planning on hosting a contest, Khan has a few suggestions. First, build in actions that allow the fan to share to their social networks, as this will increase virality. Second, stay true to your brand. Third, tweak the contest to fit the platform on which you&#8217;re running it &#8212; &#8220;On Facebook that means sharing photography, on Twitter it means wordplay hashtags, and for Polyvore it means styling outfits,&#8221; says Khan. &#8220;Quality is more important than quantity when it comes to Facebook fan growth. If your company product is clothing and your prize is free iPads, then you will gain followers that might not belong to your core demographic. Make sure the reward is something your customer will value, such as a gift card or grab bag of your products,&#8221; says Khan. 4. Spice Up The Platforms With so many platforms to manage, be sure to have a distinct M.O. on each channel &#8212; and cross-pollinate sparingly. If a customer sees the same information and pictures on Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Instagram and Pinterest, she need only follow you on one of these platforms. Also, be wary of overpromotion. Nothing is more of a turnoff than a constant sales messaging &#8212; people easily can unfollow, and they will. Interestingly, many of Wow Bao&#8217;s posts have nothing to do with bao &#8212; @BaoMouth tweets during award shows and keeps a lively conversation going on a number of topics, winning people over with its spunky personality. Of course, a big reason why you use various social media channels is to promote your product, so there are some things to keep in mind for the messaging when you are pushing your goods. &#8220;Prove the value of being a Facebook fan. If you can find the same content and offers on other channels, there is no incentive to also follow the brand on Facebook,&#8221; Khan says. &#8220;Exclusive Facebook-only offers and original content reinforces our investment in the channel.&#8221; The same goes for every other social platform. For Equinox, Facebook is for broadcasting of events and initiatives, like Cycle For Survival, Twitter is more conversation and geared toward responding to questions about membership, fitness routines and healthy eating, and Foursquare is the platform on which to find offers for Equinox&#8217;s spa and shop, which are open to the public. &#8220;Every Monday in March, we posted a different Foursquare check-in special for The Shop at all of our locations,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;Since you don&#8217;t have to necessarily be a member to go to The Shop or The Spa, these specials are accessible to everyone,&#8221; and can lure in potential customers into becoming Equinox members. The company&#8217;s Q blog is another digital project where you&#8217;ll find awe-inspiring videos and original lifestyle content &#8212; a great way to add value for potential customers. &#8220;Q was launched to extend our brand and increase this word-of-mouth among our target audience. It gives people &#8212; members and nonmembers &#8212; topics and material from our Equinox experts to share with others,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;In lieu of promos, we create a different sort of currency: highly produced, branded content on Q with exclusives for our social media communities.&#8221; 5. Make It Personal No one like a mass message &#8212; consumers like to feel as if they&#8217;re the only ones being spoken to. You should know your customers and speak to them in personal ways to establish touchpoints that build relationships and create loyalty. &#8220;I like to make it very personable &#8212; if someone tweets a question I make sure to answer immediately,&#8221; says Steven Rojas, social media director at GrandLife Hotels. &#8220;Often I go as far as Googling that person to make sure I know as much as I can about them before reaching out. I want to humanize the brand so people don&#8217;t feel like they are speaking to a computer but to an actual person who cares about what they are saying. My obsession for all things digital never sleeps, so I make sure everyone gets what they need, when they need it.&#8221; Live chats are another effective way to offer intimate interaction and engagement with fans. &#8220;It&#8217;s about having a conversation with your community, so we often do live chats with our stylists on Facebook to answer any styling questions customers may have,&#8221; says Fleiss. &#8220;These posts tend to elicit the most &#8216;Likes&#8217; and comments.&#8221; While you&#8217;re browsing sites for comments to respond to, don&#8217;t ignore negative feedback &#8212; addressing the complaint is an opportunity to convert an unhappy customer into an impressed brand ambassador. &#8220;We&#8217;re very appreciative when someone takes the time to let us know about a bad experience or an issue because then we can help fix it,&#8221; says Jenny Danzi, a Mountain Dew brand manager. &#8220;Reply to every complaint to turn those consumers into advocates &#8212; even if you can not offer an instant fix, people appreciate getting a human response,&#8221; she adds. And don&#8217;t forget that even the littlest gesture can make a big difference. &#8220;Sometimes for us it can be as simple as letting consumers know where they can find our products,&#8221; says Danzi. Wow Bao takes it to the next level, proactively finding ways to create touchpoints with consumers. &#8220;We comment on any and all posts mentioning people&#8217;s birthdays and pop culture,&#8221; says Alexander. &#8220;We even schedule posts for people&#8217;s birthdays, when people post something like, &#8216;My birthday is in 12 days&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; a very personalized tactic that can go a long way. 6. Let Your Customers Shine Nothing makes a customer feel better than being acknowledged &#8212; or better yet, honored &#8212; by their favorite brand. Is there a way to offer kudos to your loyal fans? If so, make it happen. Because women love to talk about what they&#8217;re wearing &#8212; and often wear RTR to social events such as weddings and cocktail parties &#8212; Rent the Runway strives to move these conversations online. &#8220;We have weekly style award contests on our blog and Facebook Page, and a section of our site called RTR Moments where women can share photos of themselves in RTR dresses,&#8221; says Fleiss. For Mountain Dew, whose fan base is extremely young and active on social media, the &#8220;Diet Mountain Dew Supernova Spotter&#8221; is a great way to celebrate the return of the fan-chosen flavor in addition to highlighting the passion of the fans. &#8220;Dew drinkers can upload their photo of Diet Supernova, and on Friday we&#8217;ll open the entries up to public voting. Fifteen winners will each get a Diet Dew hoodie, and everyone who enters can easily share their Diet Supernova passion with friends,&#8221; Danzi says. For Equinox, whose social media fan base is largely comprised of members, the goal isn&#8217;t as much to incentivize people to join (they already have), but to make them feel special for being members. &#8220;We have a Facebook app where members can refer friends directly, and if the friend joins, the member gets a referral bonus,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;We also just launched a program on Twitter where we&#8217;re rewarding our advocates by offering them private group fitness classes for them and their friends. This gives us a way to say &#8216;thanks&#8217; to those who always post about us, and it gives them something to talk about with their friends &#8212; online and off.&#8221; Brands, how does your company acquire new customers on social media? Consumers, what makes you want to become a customer? Let us know in the comments. Series supported by Webtrends The Customer Experience Series is supported by Webtrends. Create campaigns that lead to greater click-throughs, conversions and revenue. Want to get started? Download the Playbook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci More About: Customer Experience Series, features, instagram, mashable, rent the runway, Social Media, Sweetgreen, tweetdeck</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/customer-acquisition-social/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/customer-acquisition-social/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
