<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Unemployed bussed in to steward river pageant</title>
      <description>Coachloads of jobless people brought in to work unpaid on river pageant as part of Work ProgrammeA group of long-term unemployed jobseekers were bussed into London to work as unpaid stewards during the diamond jubilee celebrations and told to sleep under London Bridge before working on the river pageant.Up to 30 jobseekers and another 50 people on apprentice wages were taken to London by coach from Bristol, Bath and Plymouth as part of the government's Work Programme.Two jobseekers, who did not want to be identified in case they lost their benefits, said they had to camp under London Bridge the night before the pageant. They told the Guardian they had to change into security gear in public, had no access to toilets for 24 hours, and were taken to a swampy campsite outside London after working a 14-hour shift in the pouring rain on the banks of the Thames on Sunday.One young worker said she was on duty between London Bridge and Tower Bridge during the &#163;12m river spectacle of a 1,000-boat flotilla and members of the Royal family sail by . She said that the security firm Close Protection UK, which won a stewarding contract for the jubilee events, gave her a plastic see-through poncho and a high-visibility jacket for protection against the rain.Close Protection UK confirmed that it was using up to 30 unpaid staff and 50 apprentices, who were paid &#163;2.80 an hour, for the three-day event in London. A spokesman said the unpaid work was a trial for paid roles at the Olympics, which it had also won a contract to staff. Unpaid staff were expected to work two days out of the three-day holiday.The firm said it had spent considerable resources on training and equipment that stewards could keep and that the experience was voluntary and did not affect jobseekers keeping their benefits.The woman said that people were picked up at Bristol at 11pm on Saturday and arrived in London at 3am on Sunday. "We all got off the coach and we were stranded on the side of the road for 20 minutes until they came back and told us all to follow them," she said. "We followed them under London Bridge and that's where they told us to camp out for the night &#8230; It was raining and freezing."A 30-year-old steward told the Guardian that the conditions under the bridge were "cold and wet and we were told to get our head down [to sleep]". He said that it was impossible to pitch a tent because of the concrete floor.The woman said they were woken at 5.30am and supplied with boots, combat trousers and polo shirts. She said: "They had told the ladies we were getting ready in a minibus around the corner and I went to the minibus and they had failed to open it so it was locked. I waited around to find someone to unlock it, and all of the other girls were coming down trying to get ready and no one was bothering to come down to unlock [it], so some of us, including me, were getting undressed in public in the freezing cold and rain." The men are understood to have changed under the bridge.The female steward said that after the royal pageant, the group travelled by tube to a campsite in Theydon Bois, Essex, where some had to pitch their tents in the dark.She said: "London was supposed to be a nice experience, but they left us in the rain. They couldn't give a crap &#8230; No one is supposed to be treated like that, [working] for free. I don't want to be treated where I have to sleep under a bridge and wait for food." The male steward said: "It was the worst experience I've ever had. I've had many a job, and many a bad job, but this one was the worst."Both stewards said they were originally told they would be paid. But when they got to the coach on Saturday night, they said, they were told that the work would be unpaid and that if they did not accept it they would not be considered for well-paid work at the Olympics.Molly Prince, managing director of Close Protection UK, said in a statement: "We take the welfare of our staff and apprentices very seriously indeed."The staff travelling to the jubilee are completing their training and being assessed on the job for NVQ Level 2 in spectator safety after having completed all the knowledge requirements in the classroom and some previous work experience. It is essential that they are assessed in a live work environment in order to complete their chosen qualifications."The nature of festival and event work is such that we often travel sleeping on coaches through the night with an early morning pre-event start &#8211; it is the nature of the business &#8230; It's hard work and not for the faint-hearted."We had staff travel from several locations and some arrived earlier than others at the meeting point, which I believe was London Bridge [pictured left], which was why some had to hang around. This is an unfortunate set of circumstances but not lack of care on the part of CPUK."The company said it had spent up to &#163;220 on sponsoring security training licences for each participant and that boots and combat trousers cost more than &#163;100.The charity Tomorrow's People, which set up the placements at Close Protection under the work programme, said it would review the situation, but stressed that unpaid work was valuable and made people more employable. Tomorrow's People is one of eight youth charities that were supported in the Guardian and Observer's Christmas appeal last year.Abi Levitt, director of development services at the charity, said: "We have been unable to verify the accuracy of the situation with either the people on work experience or the business concerned."We will undertake a review of the situation as matter of urgency. Tomorrow's People believes strongly in the value of work experience in helping people to build the skills, confidence and CV they need to get and keep a job and we have an exemplary record going back nearly 30 years for our work with the long-term unemployed."Queen's diamond jubileeUnemploymentJob huntingWork &amp; careersShiv Malikguardian.co.uk &#169; 2012 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our Terms &amp; Conditions | More Feeds</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2012/jun/04/jubilee-pageant-unemployed</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2012/jun/04/jubilee-pageant-unemployed</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Visualizations Show Global Facebook Activity [GALLERY]</title>
      <description>Social Jetsetters This is a great visualization of Facebook users' travel habits. Instead of using airport check-ins, it uses check-ins at two far-off locations as a proxy, making it more informative. Check out the clear North American-European connection, as well as the highly noticeable long-haul travel routes.Click here to view this gallery.Facebook has 800 million active users around the world who constantly update their statuses, upload photos and check-in to locations. That&#8217;s an incredibly difficult amount of activity to process &#8212; so hopefully these beautiful visualizations will help. The above four maps were posted by Justin Moore, data scientist at Facebook, to the company&#8217;s data blog on Monday afternoon. Moore used a Java-based applet called Processing to create the beautiful info-packed images. &#8220;The images. . .attempt to visually analyze how people are using location with Facebook and present some unique slices of data,&#8221; wrote Moore. What surprises you the most about these visualizations? Share your thoughts in the comments below. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, Olena_T More About: data, Facebook, Photos, Social Media, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/facebook-visualizations/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/facebook-visualizations/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buddy Media CEO Makes Unforgettable &#8216;We Got Bought&#8217; Video</title>
      <description>Buddy Media is not a brand most consumers would recognize, but in the halls of social media and marketing, it&#8217;s a king. It connects major brands with their customers throughout all the major social media networks. Now, thanks to a $689 million acquisition, it&#8217;s set to become part of cloud computing and CRM giant Salesforce.com (the deal should close later this summer). Still, it&#8217;s this incredible video that could make Buddy Media and its cofounder and CEO Michael Lazerow a household name. As Lazerow explains in the text accompanying the YouTube video, the clip is raw and emotional. However, throughout it, Lazerow doesn&#8217;t speak a single word. Instead, he tells his own remarkable story and a bit about the acquisition, via a keynote slideshow on his iPad. Lazerow, who has had a life-long heart condition is smiling during most of it, but he&#8217;s also clearly wiping away a tear or two as he reacts to some of what he&#8217;s sharing. His main message, though, is not so much about the acquisition or his heart, but about fear and whether it&#8217;s holding you back. It&#8217;s clearly not hindering Lazerow. What do you think of the Buddy Media CEO&#8217;s sentiment? Is now the right time to share something so deeply personal or was this the perfect way to celebrate the deal and make his point? Share your thoughts in the comments. More About: Buddy Media, Salesforce, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/buddy-media-ceo-makes-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/buddy-media-ceo-makes-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Media Is Changing the Sports Ticketing Market [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Social media hasn&#8217;t only revolutionized sports fans&#8217; experiences at the game &#8212; it&#8217;s also changed how they get there in the first place. One in five fans use social networks to invite friends to games, according to a recent report by the Sports Business Journal. Nearly 15% of ticket buyers say their purchases have been influenced by Facebook posts. And engaging fans on social media doesn&#8217;t just help sports teams reach potential buyers &#8212; it literally pays off. According to the same research, fans who buy tickets through social media links pay more than one-and-a-half times as much on average compared to all buyers. Why? They typically make their purchases farther in advance. The flash deals site for sports tickets Crowd Seats recently pulled research from Ticketmaster, the Sports Business Journal and the marketing firm Burson-Marsteller to produce the infographic below. Crowd Seats is no stranger to social media&#8217;s impact on the ticketing business, either &#8212; a full third of its sales come through social media and CEO Justin Cener is speaking this week at the Sports Business Journal&#8216;s ticketing symposium. SEE ALSO: How Social Media Is Changing Sports [INFOGRAPHIC] Check out the full infographic below for more on how social media has impacted the sports ticket market, and how Major League Baseball teams are leveraging social media this season to put butts in their seats. Have you ever bought tickets to a sporting event through social media? Would you do it again? Share with us in the comments. More About: infographics, sportsFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/social-media-sports-tickets-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/social-media-sports-tickets-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Travel Tools for Planning Your Family Adventure</title>
      <description>1. Trippy As you can tell by the screenshot, Trippy looks very similar to Pinterest. At first, that's almost precisely how Trippy functioned, too. Recently, Trippy incorporated vacation planning into its otherwise simple "pinboard" functionality. Trippy's new map tool locates all the photos you've posted to your boards and pins them to a world map, so you can localize your travel wish list. Furthermore, Trippy has added Facebook Timeline integration, so consider connecting the social network to share your travel plans with friends. Click here to view this gallery.When it comes to planning an inexpensive, convenient vacation, you can never have enough travel tools in your arsenal. Whether you&#8217;re simply in the wish-list phase or well past the hotel-booking stage, digital and online resources can help. We&#8217;ve collected seven of our favorite travel tools that will inspire you, as well as help you organize and share your next holiday. Learn more about Thailand from user-curated sites like Wanderfly, or set up travel deal notifications on sites like TripTwit. SEE ALSO: 10 Free Must-Have Travel Apps for Android What tools do you find most helpful for planning vacations? Share advice for fellow travelers in the comments below. More About: apps, features, lifestyle, Social Media, travel</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/travel-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/travel-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Fascinating Things We Learned From Reddit This Week</title>
      <description>1. The White House Makes Beer NPR interviewed Michelle Obama this week about gardening, but Reddit users were more interested in the mention of the White House's home-brewed beer. White House Honey Ale is the first homemade beer to have been made in the White House. As one commenter mentioned, there are now two additional styles being brewed: White House Honey Blonde Ale and White House Honey Porter. Click here to view this gallery.Some of the most interesting things on Reddit are also the most unexpected. For instance, a post that&#8217;s just supposed to make people laugh might leave users learning something new. Or maybe an interesting interview with a celebrity includes a moment that&#8217;s fascinating, but has nothing to do with the original topic of discussion. Those are some of the most valuable moments on Reddit. For example, this week users got a biology lesson in the comments of a funny bird photo. They also learned that the White House makes beer, which came up when Michelle Obama told NPR about gardening. SEE ALSO: Reddit 101: Co-Founders Explain the Community [VIDEO] Ironically, the book that&#8217;s famous for making you look really hard for something small, &#8220;Where&#8217;s Waldo?&#8221; is also part of this week&#8217;s interesting facts. Seeking more odd facts? Check out last week&#8217;s roundup here. More About: fact, features, reddit</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/reddit-roundup-6-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/reddit-roundup-6-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Miiverse, Nintendo&#8217;s New In-Game Social Network</title>
      <description>Nintendo&#8217;s E3 press conference might not be until Tuesday morning, but that didn&#8217;t stop the company from releasing a few details about what it has in store for the gaming show a few days early including Miiverse. Designed for Miis around the world to meet, Nintendo showed off the network and a redesigned Wii plaza during a pre-E3 livestream Sunday afternoon along with more details about the highly-anticipated Wii U. SEE ALSO: Nintendo Shows Off Controller, Social Functions of Wii U A social network of sorts, Miiverse lets you communicate with other players in real-time using the Wii U Game Pad. Miis will congregate in the plaza around icons representing different titles, letting you see quickly what games are popular at the moment &#8212; including titles you don&#8217;t own &#8212; and find friends who might be interested in the same title you are. &#8220;It&#8217;s as native to Wii U as the Wii U Gamepad,&#8221; Nintendo President Satoru Iwata said during the presentation. Miis will be able to communicate with both players they know, and simply other players who are in the plaza at the time who speak the same language as they do. Players can send text messages as well as drawing and images. Players will also have the opportunity to share screenshots from a game on a wall within Miiverse. In addition to real-time communication, Miiverse will also allow for in-game posting, so you can leave messages and tips for friends who might play a game later. A spoiler checkbox in the messaging system can help prevent you from finding out more than you want to know about a game while you play. Both the Wii U and Nintendo 3DS will support Miiverse, although it will not be available when the Wii U launches later this year. The network will also be accessible through your PC or smartphone via a Miiverse web app. Nintendo has not revealed whether the Wii will support the network. What do you think of Miiverse? Does it make you more excited for the Wii U&#8217;s upcoming launch? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. Controller Improvements A shot of how the prototype controller has been modified for the Wii U.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Mii, Miiverse, Nintendo, Wii U</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/nintendo-miiverse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/nintendo-miiverse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Mean To Be Alarmist, But The TV Business May Be Starting To Collapse</title>
      <description>In the first decade of the commercial Internet--the 1990s and early 2000s--there were frequent murmurings that newspapers were screwed. The digital audience didn't read newspapers, people pointed out. They visited web sites. They read articles here and there. But they didn't put the stack of articles, photos, and ads known as a "newspaper" on their breakfast table and flip through the whole thing. What's more, the digital audience stopped using newspapers as a reference and source for commerce. They browsed on eBay and Craigslist instead of reading classifieds. They got their movie news from movie sites. They got real-estate listings from real-estate sites. They learned about "sales" and other events from email and coupon sites. And so on. In other words, the user behavior that had supported newspaper companies for a century began to change. But for almost a whole decade, the newspaper industry barely noticed. Subscriptions kept going up. Ads kept going up. Stocks kept going up. Those who said that newspapers were screwed were dismissed as clueless doom-mongers, at least by newspaper executives. Then this happened: And lots of newspaper companies went broke or almost went broke. And the stock of The New York Times Company, the country's premiere newspaper, fell from $50 to $6. (See: "The Incredible Shrinking New York Times") In other words, newspapers were screwed. It just took a while for changing user behavior to really hammer the business. The same is almost certainly true for television. In our household, as in many households, television consumption has changed massively over the past decade, especially over the past 5 years. We almost never watch television shows when they are broadcast anymore (with the very notable exception of live sports) We rarely watch shows with ads, even on a DVR We watch a lot of TV and movie content, but always on demand and almost never with ads (We're now so used to watching shows via Netflix or iTunes or HBO that ads now seem like bizarre intrusions) We get our news from the Internet, article by article, clip by clip. The only time we watch TV news live is when there's a crisis or huge event happening somewhere. (You still can't beat TV for that, but soon, news networks will also be streamed). We watch TV and movie content on 4 different screens, depending on which is convenient (TV, laptops, phones, iPad) If not for live sports, which are consumed by exactly one member of our household (me), there is no way we would be paying for cable TV or any other kind of traditional pay TV anymore. And even as a sports fan, I'm starting to find the fragmented multi-channel coverage of the few sports I watch--like tennis (Grand Slams), baseball (Yankees), and football (Jets/Giants)--so annoying that I may soon investigate just getting those via direct subscriptions. In other words, in our household, and in many other households like ours, the same thing has happened to the TV business that has happened to the newspaper business: The user behavior that supported the traditional all-in-one TV "packages"--networks and cable/satellite distributors--has changed. We still consume some TV content, but we consume it when and where we want it, and we consume it deliberately: In other words, we don't settle down in front of the TV and watch "what's on." And, again with the exception of live sports, we've gotten so used to watching shows and series without ads that ads now seem extraordinarily intrusive and annoying. Our kids see TV ads so rarely that they're actually curious about and confused by them: "What is that? A commercial?" For now, our type of household may still be in the minority, but we won't be for long. And our type of household is the type of household that many advertisers and TV networks want to reach. We're still in "the demo" (24-55), and we're still buying a lot of stuff. So, what are the key points of this shift in user behavior for the traditional TV business? "Networks" are completely meaningless. We don't know or care which network owns the rights to a show or where it was broadcast. The only question that's relevant is whether it's available on Netflix, Hulu, Amazon, or iTunes. This means that one of the key traditional "businesses" of TV--the network--is obsolete. The majority of what we pay our cable company is wasted. We get broadband Internet from our cable company, and we use that constantly. But we also get 500 channels that we almost never watch, along with a couple (HBO, Tennis Channel) that we pay extra for and do watch occasionally. We rarely watch TV ads, and when we do, we're usually doing something else at the same time--like typing. Also, the ads seem startlingly intrusive, because we're not used to them. More directly, what this means is this: The vast majority of money TV advertisers spend to reach our household (~$750 a year, ~$60/month) is wasted, because we rarely watch TV content with ads, and, when we do, we rarely watch the ads. The vast majority of money we pay our cable company for live TV (~$1,200 a year / ~$100/month) is wasted, because we almost never watch live TV and we can get most of what we want to watch from iTunes, Netflix, Hulu, and Amazon. This user behavior has been changing for a while, and, so far, it has had almost no impact on the TV business. On the contrary, the networks and cable companies are still fat and happy, and they're coining more and more money every year. But remember what happened in the newspaper business. When the Internet arrived, user behavior started to change. It took a decade for this change in behavior to hit the business. But when it hit the business, it hit it hard--and it destroyed it shockingly quickly. And the same thing seems likely to happen to the TV business. The only questions are: When will it happen? What will it do? Let's take the second first. What is the shift in user behavior likely to do to the TV business? The traditional "network" model is likely to break down and be replaced with far larger "libraries" of content and far more efficient content production, acquisition, and distribution. Some of the content produced by networks will still be consumed (and, therefore, produced), but the idea of getting "affiliate fees" and selling advertising for each of dozens of branded networks seems absurd. This change is already occurring, of course: Traditional networks are being replaced by Netflix, iTunes, and uber-networks like "NBC Universal" and "Time Warner." There is so much money in the network business right now that, initially, this shift won't mean much. Over time, however, it will. Unprofitable networks will be merged with profitable ones. Unprofitable shows and overpaid talent will be cut. Overpaid managers will get fired. Production costs, on aggregate, will drop. Sets, crews, newsgathering, etc. will be consolidated. The fat will get squeezed out of the system. The cost of traditional pay TV will have to drop--users will have to get more for less, or they'll stop paying for much at all. I might value the TV content we get through our cable company at $20 a month--about 1/5th of what we pay for it. Eventually, as soon as I can figure out ways to get the few sports I watch another way, we'll stop paying the $100. Ultimately, the distinction between "TV" and other forms of video content will disappear. We'll pay some distributors for bundles of that content, we'll buy some of it directly, and we'll get some of it for free. But a lot of the money that is currently being wasted by us and to reach us will be spent much more efficiently. Bottom line, as it has in newspapers, the TV business is going to have to get radically more efficient. It won't disappear--newspapers haven't disappeared--but the fat and happy days will have to end. As for the other question, "when," the answer may be "now." Cable TV ratings over the past year have dropped sharply, as this chart from Citi shows. A recent survey from Nielsen, meanwhile, included some startling statistics, including the following: The percent of people worldwide who watch TV at least once a month dropped from 90% to 83% over the past year. The percentage of people who watch video on a computer once a month--84%--is now higher than the percentage who watch TV. Needless to say, a decade ago, newspaper industry forecasters were not expecting newspaper advertising to do this: Similarly, TV forecasters are not expecting TV advertising or subscriptions to do that over the next 10 years. On the contrary, they're expecting TV advertising to just keep going up. But user behavior is changing fast. And at some point, that's going to hammer the business. SEE ALSO: UH OH: This New Nielsen Data Suggests People Aren't Watching TV Anymore Please follow SAI: Media on Twitter and Facebook.Join the conversation about this story &#187;</description>
      <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/tv-business-collapse-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.businessinsider.com/tv-business-collapse-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cats away! Artist turns his dead pet into flying helicopter after it is killed by a car - Daily Mail</title>
      <description>Many animal lovers find it hard to part with their pets when they die. So when cat Orville, named after the famous aviator Orville Wright, was run over by a car, his artist owner decided to turn him into a permanent piece of artwork as the ultimate tribute by transforming him into a flying helicopter. Dutch artist Bart Jansen first stuffed Orville before teaming up with radio control helicopter flyer Arjen Beltman to build a specially-designed flying mechanism to attach to the cat. The end result, named the Orvillecopter, is now on show at the Kunstrai art festival in Amsterdam where visitors can watch Orville flying for themselves. Jansen said the Orvillecopter is 'half cat, half machine', and part of a visual art project to pay tribute to his cat Orville. Jansen, part of the art cooperative Generaal Pardon, said: 'After a period of mourning he received his propellers posthumously.' He added that Orville will soon be 'flying with the birds' stating: 'Oh how he loved birds. He will receive more powerful engines and larger props for his birthday. So this hopping will soon change into steady flight.'</description>
      <link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2154283/Cats-away-Artist-turns-dead-pet-flying-helicopter-killed-car.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2154283/Cats-away-Artist-turns-dead-pet-flying-helicopter-killed-car.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xbox Music Will Bring 30 Million Tunes to Your TV, Smartphone, Tablet</title>
      <description>Microsoft announced Xbox Music &#8212; a new music service coming to the console, PCs, Windows 8 tablets and Windows Phone devices &#8212; at its E3 press conference Monday. Sporting a library of more than 30 million tracks, the service is presumably killing off Microsoft&#8217;s Zune service on those other mobile devices. While Microsoft didn&#8217;t offer a ton of details, it did give a brief demo. In addition to announcing Xbox Music, the company also announced a number of new games for its existing Xbox 360 console as well as a new feature called SmartGlass. SmartGlass will allow users to mirror the content on tablets or smartphones on their television using the Xbox. SmartGlass also lets users continue watching a film on TV that they started watching on a tablet. E3, the Electronic Entertainment Expo, is an annual video game-centered show in Los Angeles all week. EA, Ubisoft and Sony all have press conferences scheduled for later Monday. Nintendo will be holding its press conference Tuesday morning, but it already released some details about its Wii U console Sunday during a pre-E3 event. What do you think about Xbox Music? let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: e3, E3 2012, Tech, xbox, Xbox 360, Xbox Music</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/xbox-music/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/xbox-music/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Nonprofit Applies for New Domains: Meet .ngo and .ong [EXCLUSIVE]</title>
      <description>The Public Interest Registry (PIR), the non-profit that manages and operates the .org domain, has formally submitted its applications to the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) for the .ngo and .ong domain extensions. The application process is part of ICANN&#8217;s initiative to expand domain extensions across the Internet as early as 2013. The .org top-level domain (TLD) is the world&#8217;s third largest &#8212; behind .com and .net &#8212; with more than 9.9 million web addresses registered worldwide. Since its inception in 2002, PIR has managed the .org domain while serving the interests of non-profits and non-governmental organizations (NGOs). By applying for the .ngo and .ong extensions, PIR can continue to work with the global NGO community and expand its service. (The .ong extension is the .ngo equivalent for Spanish, Italian, French and other Romance languages.) When PIR brainstormed on what the extension should be, .ngo resonated with the team, according to CEO Brian Cute. &#8220;NGO itself, as an acronym, is a very well-known term,&#8221; Cute told Mashable. &#8220;It&#8217;s a very strong self-identification, those three letters, which is very important on the Internet when you want to be found.&#8221; Although the .org extension is often associated with non-profits and has been their go-to domain extension, it is an open domain, meaning that individuals and for-profit corporations from can register under it as well. But .ngo will be administered as a closed domain exclusively for NGOs, and there will be a verification component at the time of registration. If the .ngo extension is approved, non-profits and NGOs that currently have a .org extension won&#8217;t be required to make the transition. &#8220;It&#8217;s really their choice,&#8221; Cute said. &#8220;If they have a .org site and they&#8217;re interacting robustly with their donors and their community, they may not want to. That&#8217;s fine. If they aren&#8217;t online yet, or they recognize that the benefit of a verified registration and website and .ngo gives them better positioning with their stakeholders, then it&#8217;s the right move.&#8221; Cute also said that making the transition to .ngo is something PIR can facilitate fairly easily. There are more benefits to the .ngo extension as well. PIR will offer an online directory service of NGOs registered with the extension to increase visibility, searchability and the ability to share information in a closed group setting. Additionally, PIR is planning for an NGO community program, investing in the community as part of the .NGO effort. This means that PIR will reinvest the money it receives from .ngo and .ong registrations into the non-profit sphere. PIR will help grassroots NGOs in the developing world get online and set up a website through a cost-effective web service. &#8220;We [want to help] get them online, but also train them to use WordPress, and empower them to control their online presence and their website,&#8221; Cute said. &#8220;For us, that&#8217;s the impact part of it that we see as being really compelling. It&#8217;s not just the web address and getting the website. This really holds potential for lifting that community in important ways.&#8221; According to Cute, PIR probably will not know for certain if its applications are approved until January 2013, since the ICANN evaluation process can take some time. On June 13, ICANN will reveal the 2,100 domain extensions that were submitted by the May 30 deadline. It will be interesting to see the submissions, which may include extensions such as .sport and .music. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, ronstik. More About: Domain Names, ICANN, Social Good</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/pir-ngo-domain-extension/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/pir-ngo-domain-extension/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mashable Weekend Recap: 52 Stories You Might Have Missed</title>
      <description>As we kicked off the first weekend of the summer season here at Mashable, our posts stayed focused on the hottest social media, technology, viral videos and fascinating finds from the world over. And find we did, with a boatload of new apps arriving, summer sports pumping up the social media, hilarious YouTube clips and tech from the near and far future. No need to worry about missing anything &#8212; we&#8217;ve gathered every morsel in one handy place for you. So here it is, our revamped Weekend Recap, complete with a new section, &#8220;Editor&#8217;s Picks,&#8221; where I chose the posts that not only garnered the most traffic, but that I thought were the weekend&#8217;s best. So have at it, and go out there and make a great week! Editor&#8217;s Picks 7 Apps You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss &#8216;Game of Thrones&#8217; Parodied to the Tune of Maroon 5 [VIDEO] 10 Funniest Tweets of the Week The Subtle Usefulness of &#8216;NSFW&#8217; Top 10 Tech This Week [PICS] Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week Photo Sharing App Picplz to Shut Down on July 3 News &amp; Opinion Essentials Oprah Book Club Returns in New Digital Form Foursquare App Getting a Face-Lift This Week [PICS] Nintendo Shows Off Controller, Social Functions of Wii U [PICS] AnyTouch Turns Any Surface Into a Touchscreen [VIDEO] Partial Lunar Eclipse Monday Sets Stage for Venus Transit 5 Ways Social Media Is Revolutionizing Talent Acquisition Foursquare App Getting a Face-Lift This Week [PICS] Android Angst: Ice Cream Sandwich Adoption Moving Slowly [VIDEO] TomTom Launches Quirky YouTube Summer Contest [VIDEOS] Pinterest Rolls Out Curated Newsletter for Users Cellphone Plans Could Be Data-Only in 2 Years, Says AT&amp;T CEO Reddit 101: Co-Founders Explain the Community [VIDEO] In a Relationship: Mobile Apps and the Cloud [INFOGRAPHIC] YouTube&#8217;s 10 Most-Shared Ads in May Facebook to Receive GLAAD Award for LGBT Efforts What to Expect From E3 2012 Egyptian President Ousted During Arab Spring Is Sentenced to Life in Prison One-way Ticket to Mars, Please: Startup Plans Space Colony in 2023 Mets Pitch First No-Hitter in 50-Year History Are Obese Employees Killing Your Company? [INFOGRAPHIC] BlindSquare: App Uses Foursquare Data to Help the Blind Navigate Streets It&#8217;s Facebook Election Week: How You Can Vote on Your Privacy Google To One-Up Apple, Announce 3D Maps a Week Earlier [VIDEO] SEE ALSO: All the Weekend Recaps Ever Published Weekend Leisure 5 Fascinating Things We Learned From Reddit This Week Umbrella Makes 8-Bit Sounds When Rained On [VIDEO] 12 Top Tumblrs for Gamers Internet Users React to Potential &#8216;Zombie Apocalypse&#8217; Magnetic Phone Mount Could Make Your Life Easier [VIDEO] Katie Couric Creates Spotify Playlist for Diamond Jubilee [AUDIO] Wear Your Own Voice Recording Around Your Neck Radical Skateboarding Tricks Dazzle in Super Slow-Motion [VIDEO] Write, Read, Share on Widbook, the &#8216;YouTube of Books&#8217; Are Teens Beginning to Prefer Twitter to Facebook? &#8216;O Fortuna&#8217; Animation Filled with Memes, Misheard Lyrics [VIDEO] Portable Electricity Generator Uses a Single Tea Light For Power [VIDEO] Older Internet Users Pick Better Passwords Than Teens [STUDY] Helpful Resources The Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Tumblr 7 Travel Tools for Planning Your Family Adventure Top 5 Mashable Comments and Conversations This Week 50 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed How to Use Social Media for Employee Referrals 10 Tools for Planning Great Meals 5 Startups Infusing Social Good with Innovation 5 Ways Facebook Can Boost Corporate Volunteering 8 Tools for Hacking Your Productivity Here&#8217;s last week&#8217;s Weekend Recap. More About: Weekend recap</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/weekend-recap-57/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/weekend-recap-57/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
