<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Drops LinkedIn Partnership</title>
      <description>LinkedIn announced via a blog post on Friday that Twitter would no longer be partnering with the business-networking site to sync updates from one site to the other. This ends a partnership that began in 2009. LinkedIn users can still create updates on the site and click a button to share to Twitter as well, but the the reverse is no longer possible. The LinkedIn post by Ryan Roslansky, head of content products at LinkedIn, pointed to Twitter's own Friday blog post about "delivering a consistent experience on Twitter." Perhaps Twitter wants to separate itself from the business networking company after the recent password breach in which 6 million LinkedIn passwords were stolen. Li&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Drops LinkedIn Partnership</title>
      <description>LinkedIn announced via a blog post on Friday that Twitter would no longer be partnering with the business-networking site to sync updates from one site to the other. This ends a partnership that began in 2009. LinkedIn users can still create updates on the site and click a button to share to Twitter as well, but the the reverse is no longer possible. The LinkedIn post by Ryan Roslansky, head of content products at LinkedIn, pointed to Twitter's own Friday blog post about "delivering a consistent experience on Twitter." Perhaps Twitter wants to separate itself from the business networking company after the recent password breach in which 6 million LinkedIn passwords were stolen. Li&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Won&#8217;t Support Flash in Android 4.1</title>
      <description>And thus ends the tale of Flash on mobile browsers: Adobe has announced it will not support Flash Player browser plugin for Android 4.1 and onward. "There will be no certified implementations of Flash Player for Android 4.1," writes Adobe on its official blog, adding that it recommends "uninstalling Flash Player on devices which have been upgraded to Android 4.1." It all started with Steve Jobs, though, who famously called Flash a "relic" from another era in an open letter in April 2010. Apple then said it would not support Flash on the iPad, iPhone and iPod touch, and for a while Flash support was seen as a competitive advantage for Android. As it turned out, Jobs was right about&#8230; Continue reading... More About: adobe, android, Flash</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/flash-in-android-4-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/flash-in-android-4-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Livestrong CEO: 'Social Media Is Changing the World' [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Mashable&#8216;s third annual Social Media Day will bring together thousands of people worldwide to celebrate the digital revolution this Saturday. We talked with Doug Ulman, President and CEO of Livestrong, about how social media is mobilizing initiatives for a better world. He notes that people are not only using digital to coalesce around causes but also to connect with one another and share their stories. &#8220;Social media is worth celebrating because it gives us all a voice,&#8221; Ulman says. Watch the video above to hear more about Ulman&#8217;s thoughts about social media&#8217;s ability to inspire change throughout the world. We invite you to join fellow social media enthusiasts by hosting or attending a Social Media Day Meetup in your area. Already have big Social Media Day plans? Tell us more about how you&#8217;re celebrating the digital revolution in the comments below.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/livestrong-social-media-day/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/livestrong-social-media-day/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Sony Became a Pinterest Rock Star</title>
      <description>Callan Green, senior social media specialist at Sony Electronics, never thought she would want a pair of leather pants.&#8220;But I saw enough pins on Pinterest that I thought, &#8216;Oh my gosh, I have to own them,&#8217; and I went out and bought some.&#8221;It was the fall of 2011 and she was discovering firsthand the power of Pinterest to drive sales.The image-based, pinboard-sharing social media site launched in March 2010 is now the third-largest social network, behind Facebook and Twitter.In March 2012, it tallied 2.3 billion page impressions to over 4 million unique visitors a day.&#8220;We were all using [Pinterest] personally,&#8221; said Green of the social media team at Sony Electronics, &#8220;and realized the power of the platform to drive people&#8217;s interest in purchasing.&#8221;Organization: Sony ElectronicsSocial Media Handles &amp; Stats:Website: SonyFacebook &#8211; 3,190,131 fansTwitter &#8211; 85,836 followersYouTube &#8211; 10,307,450 viewsPinterest &#8211; 2,582 followersLinkedIn &#8211; 21,206 followersBlogHighlights:Over 2,500 followers in the first six months since launching the Sony brand page on Pinterest800% increase in traffic from Pinterest to Sony Store website since launching the pagePin It button has received more than 10 times the clicks from Sony Store vs. Tweet This buttonMore than 4 million brand impressions (via Curalate dashboard)Here are 6 things Sony did to make Pinterest work for them.#1: Research What People are Already PinningWhen they began research to find out what people were already pinning about Sony, they found a nascent community that was pinning not only Sony products, but also ads, logos, pictures taken with their Sony cameras and all manner of creative expression related to the brand. Launching a brand page seemed like a natural extension.Fans were already pinning a wide array of images related to the Sony brand.The Sony team identified three things they wanted to focus on with the platform:Drive sales to the websiteIncrease brand affinityGrow the Sony communityBut before starting to think about driving sales or building the community, they put in three months of preparation planning and populating about 10 boards with visually appealing content&#8212;at first mostly repins of what others were already sharing.When they felt they had a solid base of content, they launched the Pinterest Sony brand page both internally and externally at the same time, taking advantage of their biggest base of Sony fans&#8212;their employees&#8212;with an internal contest.#2: Involve Employees and Internal Team from the Start&#8220;We have so many Sony fans that are already at our fingertips, we wanted to get them involved from the very start. A lot of companies do this backwards, thinking of their employees last,&#8221; said Green.The contest encouraged employees to check out and follow the Sony boards and to create a board of their own about what Sony meant to them.Participation was better than expected, with several hundred employees requesting Pinterest invites and generating a slew of content that Sony was able to repin on the brand board.&#8220;That content was key in helping us to turn around and repin to create better, more authentically pleasing boards,&#8221; said Green. &#8220;There are people who have been at Sony for 30 years, and they had access to assets that I&#8217;d never seen or even heard of.&#8221;The team also reached out to the Corporate Communications team.&#8220;They&#8217;ve been really helpful in sending us content for pins and creating content for us,&#8221; said Green.The key to generating internal support is to give feedback about their contributions, letting them know what is working and what isn&#8217;t.&#8220;More often than not, their ideas have worked and they get very excited and want to contribute more,&#8221; she said.#3: Make Your Website Pinterest-FriendlyCompany buzz from the contest also helped generate support internally to get the Pin It button on the Sony Store website within a few weeks of launching the board. At the time, the site did not have any social plugins. A Tweet This button was subsequently added.Sony was an early adopter of the Pin It button.&#8220;The excitement about Pinterest got the web team to get really creative and figure out a way to make it work,&#8221; said Green.Adding the Pin It button increased the number of pins from the Sony site about tenfold over what it had been before.#4: Plan a Strategic Mix of BoardsTo craft the Sony Pinterest presence, the team created a mix of lifestyle and fun pages interspersed with commercial product pages.Boards featuring retro Sony products and ads were designed to appeal to fans of the brand, as was the Sony Art board highlighting art created with Sony products or featuring the brand logo.The team also built boards to stimulate conversation with the wider, non-techie community, such as Sony Artist Style, a fashion board of Sony recording artists, and Rooms We&#8217;d Love to Live In, where Sony products take over. The board features pictures of stunning places users would like to inhabit.On the commercial side, boards such as Brand New Sony Products and Sony on Sale provide direct links to the Sony store.#5: Create Original Content and Exclusive ProgramsSony created its first content specifically for Pinterest on the Sony Art board, bringing in a photographer and art director to create the image of Sony cameras arranged in a heart shape to give the Pinterest community something they couldn&#8217;t find anywhere else. Reaction was positive, generating repins, likes and comments.Collage of Sony cameras created exclusively for Pinterest.The Sony on Sale board also offers Pin Deals, where an exclusive Pinterest offer is unlocked once the deal gets repinned 20 times.The research and preparation is paying off for Sony.&#8220;Month over month, we continue to see an increase in traffic from Pinterest back to our site,&#8221; said Green.In mid-May 2012, there had been an 800% increase in traffic from Pinterest to the Sony Store since before launching the brand page.In addition, the store&#8217;s Pin It button has received more than 10 times the number of clicks than the Tweet This button.Although a hard ROI is difficult to measure at this point, Sony management sees investing time in the platform as a good use of resources and is willing to see where it goes.#6: Promote Through Other ChannelsThe main challenge, according to Green, is that there is currently not an easy way on Pinterest to find followers. &#8220;It&#8217;s very hard to get eyeballs on Pinterest,&#8221; she said.Currently the team is taking advantage of tools like Pinreach and Curalate to help monitor their brand, but the most effective tactic so far to drive users to the Pinterest page has been to get the message out on other media.Sony has posted on their other social platforms, used email blasts and media releases, written about it on their own blog and reached out to other bloggers in an effort to find followers.Sony officially launched the Pinterest page with a blog post in February 2012.The Bottom LineThe Sony team was careful to balance the promotional pages with fun content, but Green&#8217;s biggest surprise has been seeing where the most engagement has come from.&#8220;The Brand New Product board, where we&#8217;re driving the most sales from &#8230; is consistently our most popular engagement board. Which proves to me that people definitely want the fun and the fluff and the brand stuff, but at the end of the day, people on Pinterest do want products, they want to pin products and they want to buy products. There&#8217;s room for both kinds of strategy,&#8221; she explains.What do you think? Is your brand on Pinterest? What can you do to develop and engage a Pinterest following? Leave your questions and comments in the box below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/pinterest-case-study-sony/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/pinterest-case-study-sony/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone: The 5-Year-Old That Changed the World [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Love or hate Apple products, there's no denying the iPhone's indelible mark on technology, culture and business. Five years ago, the first iteration was unleashed on throngs of early adopters, who ogled its touchscreen interface and poked at little icons. Today, the smartphone concept is no longer the bastion of tech nerds and fan girls. It has become standard issue, thanks in large part to the iPhone's overwhelming success and iconic design. The device revolutionized Apple itself. iPhone sales were a tiny slice of Apple pie in 2007. In 2012, it accounts for 58% of the company's revenue (which, overall, has skyrocketed, thanks to a culture of iTunes and apps propagated by the iPhone). SEE ALSO: Apple by the Numbers [INFOGRAPHIC] Sales of the iPhone (and its related services and accessories) even trump the revenue of entire companies like Microsoft and Disney. It's no wonder that Apple is consistently a front-runner for the most valuable company in the world by market cap. Our friends at Statista have compiled relevant data about the iPhone's ascendance. Check out the graphic below and tell us about your first iPhone experience in the comments. For more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/iphone-5-anniversary-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/iphone-5-anniversary-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Facebook Testing a 'Want' Button?</title>
      <description>Facebook may be testing a &#8220;Want&#8221; button that would allow you to add products to a virtual wish list. According to Tom Waddington, a web developer for the site Cut Out + Keep, Facebook has a disabled &#8220;Want&#8221; button included in the Javascript coding its list of social plug-ins. This means that &#8212; in addition to existing plug-ins such as subscribe and the Like button that allow users to see friend activity across the site &#8212; a &#8220;Want&#8221; button would likely allow members to see what items others in their network want to purchase. &#8220;The code was released to the Facebook Javascript SDK on Wednesday,&#8221; Waddington told Mashable. &#8220;I keep track of the changes to the file.&#8221; Waddington said he discovered a few other new tags &#8212; such as &#8220;degrees,&#8221; &#8220;page events,&#8221; &#8220;social context&#8221; and &#8220;privacy selector&#8221; &#8212; but they don&#8217;t seem to be working as well: &#8220;I&#8217;m still exploring the code to see what else is new.&#8221; Although the button is currently not listed on Facebook&#8217;s developer site as a social plugin, Waddington said that the Want button would only work on Open Graph projects with under the tag &#8220;products.&#8221; Waddington tried to install the Want button onto his blog, but received an error message in the process. &#8220;The button displays on the site, but clicking it shows an error message,&#8221; Waddington said. &#8220;Facebook hasn&#8217;t enabled any apps to publish Wants yet.&#8221; Facebook hasn&#8217;t yet responded to a request for comment. Waddington&#8217;s discovery was first noted by Inside Facebook on Thursday. The Want app would allow the company to collect a lot of information about member interests, just as the Like button already does. The move would also allow merchants greater integration with Facebook without having to build their own apps or platforms. &#8220;E-commerce sites could increase social exposure by including a Want button,&#8221; Waddington said. &#8220;It will not require authorizing an app and will publish a &#8220;user wants product&#8217; story in the news feed.&#8221; He added that apps users authorize will likely be able to access the &#8220;wanted&#8221; products through the API, so Facebook could provide a universal wish list. &#8220;If Facebook allows sites to include prices and product data such as ISBN numbers, then it will become really powerful,&#8221; he added. Would you be interested in seeing a Want button on the site? How do you think it could impact the retail industry? Let us know in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/facebook-want-button/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/facebook-want-button/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Social Media Is Affecting Local Communities</title>
      <description>In light of Mashable's Social Media Day mission to celebrate the digital revolution, we asked you how social media impacts your local community. From disaster-affected regions using Twitter for community safety to local charities rallying donations from Facebook users, we received some inspired answers about the role of social media in your hometowns. Here are excerpts from the top five responses to our question: How does social media affect your local community? You can click on the respondent's name to see the answer in full. Mare Aehlich (Kenosha, Wisconsin) - "There are so many stories of how social media has impacted the community here, but two of the best are w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: community, smday, Social Media, social media day</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wits Come Out of Hiding for Tom Cruise, Katie Holmes Split</title>
      <description>In the five years since Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes married, they raised their 6-year-old daughter Suri and produced blockbusters (mostly his) and smaller films (mostly hers) alike -- and now they're calling it quits.</description>
      <link>http://www.dailynews.com/news/ci_20972440/tom-cruise-katie-holmes-divorcing-after-five-years?source=rss</link>
      <guid>http://www.dailynews.com/news/ci_20972440/tom-cruise-katie-holmes-divorcing-after-five-years?source=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome for iPhone, iPad: It&#8217;s Safari with Smart Extras [HANDS ON]</title>
      <description>Chrome for iOS is Here Chrome for iOS is here. Available for the IPhone and iPad, how does it compare to the third-party browser competition?Click here to view this gallery. As promised, Google's Chrome web browser is now available for iOS. We've spent some time playing with the app -- which you can download from the App Store now [iTunes link] -- and trying it out alongside Mobile Safari, iCab Mobile, Opera Mini and others. Understanding the Trade-Offs Because Apple restricts the way third-party web browsers can work with iOS, Chrome isn't substantially different from any other mobile web browser. In fact, it's basically just the UIWebView (geek speak for the basic Mobile Safari rendering engine) with a customized skin. That's not a bad thing -- Mobile Safari is a great mobile web browser -- but it mean that users have to accept a few trade-offs&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Browsers, chrome, chrome ios, Google, iOS apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/chrome-ios-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/chrome-ios-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Social Media Is Affecting Local Communities</title>
      <description>In light of Mashable's Social Media Day mission to celebrate the digital revolution, we asked you how social media impacts your local community. From disaster-affected regions using Twitter for community safety to local charities rallying donations from Facebook users, we received some inspired answers about the role of social media in your hometowns. Here are excerpts from the top five responses to our question: How does social media affect your local community? You can click on the respondent's name to see the answer in full. Mare Aehlich (Kenosha, Wisconsin) - "There are so many stories of how social media has impacted the community here, but two of the best are w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: community, smday, Social Media, social media day</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Geeky Wedding Gifts for the Happy Couple</title>
      <description>1. Geek Heart Emoticon These steel characters would look marvelous on a shelf. You just know the geeky newlyweds will totally "get" them. Cost: $19.99Click here to view this gallery.A wedding is a time for celebration, and a wedding between two geeks even more so. We have found 10 fabulous gifts that will let you congratulate the nerdy couple in true geek style. From personalized items to his 'n' hers matching sets, our gallery of geeky wedding gifts should give you plenty of inspiration to surprise the happy couple. SEE ALSO: Top 10 Wedding Dance Videos on YouTube Take a look through our selection above. Let us know in the comments below about any other geeky wedding presents you've seen. More About: accessories, features, gallery, geek, home, lifestyle, weddings</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/geeky-wedding-gifts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/geeky-wedding-gifts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
