<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Meets Instagram: What It Means for Your Brand</title>
      <description>Joshua Teixeira heads up the strategy discipline at Big Spaceship, helping shape engagements for active projects and prospective clients alike. Recent projects include work with clients like Crayola, Chobani, Google, Wrigley, General Electric, Urban Daddy, and Gilt Groupe. When it comes to Facebook&#8217;s $1 billion acquisition of Instagram, details are still coming into focus. In a public statement, Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg said that Instagram will continue to grow independently &#8212; but further details about how the platforms will eventually weave together have not been provided. Nevertheless, the Instagram/Facebook combo presents new challenges to and opportunities for marketers. Instagram is a place we go to communicate visually, to give friends a glimpse into our daily life &#8212; what we ate for lunch, which shoes we just bought, the view from the window at work. These posts not only fill our friends&#8217; feeds with beautifully filtered photos, but also with artfully masked suggestions and influence. As the popular photo platform gains steam, surpassing 30 million users, some companies are realizing that an artsy tilt-shift photo of the bag of chips you&#8217;re eating could be actually worth something. Close to 1 billion members strong, Facebook has a powerful paid advertising program. And its support for brands has grown immensely in the past few months, with the rollout of Timeline for Brands and fan-based ads. Meanwhile, Instagram is emerging as a much smaller, but very powerful user-supported platform that brands are just beginning to embrace. For brands, this acquisition is an opportunity to strengthen their digital ecosystems &#8212; by leveraging both platforms as a way to tell their stories, creating a more cohesive consumer experience and encouraging deeper engagement. Integration of Instagram into a brand&#8217;s Facebook communications has potential to create a more visual conversation via rich stories and conversations. The transparent personalities that brands have built thus far on Instagram could be fleshed out further by harnessing Facebook Timeline&#8217;s layout power to represent a brand&#8217;s lifespan of brand personification. SEE ALSO: How Brands Are Using Instagram to Reach New Audiences While Instagram doesn&#8217;t currently have an ad program, companies like Instagrid Network want to connect brands with Instagram users. By setting up programs that pay top Instagrammers to share photos of a brand&#8217;s products, inviting guest photographers to curate a brand&#8217;s feed, or promoting a certain hashtag, Instagrid is confident in its model to grow a brand&#8217;s following and establish the brand among influencers. As branded Instagram content begins to work its way into users feeds, the big question is whether people will mind (or notice). These paid endorsements will be unobtrusive, and will look exactly the same as every other photo populating your feed. As Instagram CEO Kevin Systrom says, &#8220;It doesn&#8217;t feel like advertising when you open Instagram &#8212; it feels like entertainment.&#8221; The idea of branded entertainment on Instagram has been an extremely successful tool for brands that operate their own accounts, such as Warby Parker and Anthroplogie, and Instagrid&#8217;s programs could help their accounts grow. However, these accounts have a transparency to them that disappears with users being paid to post images on their accounts, on the behalf of brands. For brands, this &#8220;product placement&#8221; model risks driving users away from them or Instagram in general, due to a perceived drop in authenticity and artistic integrity of the community. Both brands and users will be carefully monitoring what happens next. Facebook and Instagram need to maintain their independence and authenticity as separate platforms in order to be successful and not push users away. Marketing efforts need to be carefully designed with the end user in mind. The prospect of Facebook using its dominant presence to barge into users&#8217; intimately curated Instagram communities has backlash potential. However, we see an opportunity for positive social benefits than can subtly improve the Instagram user experience and make it more dynamic &#8212; such as in-app tagging, personal and community-sourced albums, or a unified desktop presence for Instagram photos. While this partnership will undoubtedly attract many new users to join the Instagram community, for brands, it&#8217;s important to keep in mind which channel is more relevant to the brand and its consumers. This acquisition can heighten the potential for success of branded content on Instagram, without affecting the artistic integrity of the platform. While initially it may fall on Zuck to get this right, brands bear the real responsibility for developing the new Instagram and keeping the focus on user engagement. If they can do that, it will be a pretty picture indeed. With Casey Roeder, strategist, Big Spaceship More About: Business, Facebook, instagram, Marketing, Social MediaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/facebook-instagram-brand/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/facebook-instagram-brand/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Klout Unveils Brand Pages</title>
      <description>Klout unleashed Brand Squads, its version of brand pages, into beta on Tuesday with Red Bull as its sole launch partner. The startup &#8212; which measures influence on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and Foursquare to assign Klout users scores from 0 to 100 &#8212; will gradually roll out more Brand Squads in the coming weeks and months. Each Squad will feature the brand&#8217;s logo, the list of the top 10 and top 100 influencers about the brand, an activity stream and any brand-specific deals offered through Klout&#8217;s Perks platform. &#8220;The bottom line is that we are creating a place where influencers can be recognized and have an impact on brands,&#8221; Klout spokeswoman Lynn Fox told Mashable. Companies have had success engaging with consumers and promoting products or services via brand pages on Facebook, Google+ and Twitter. Now, Klout wants to jump in the game to empower everyday brand advocates. For example, instead of Red Bull talking to fans or touting things as it does across social networks, it&#8217;s the other way around on Klout. &#8220;With Brand Squads, you will see a dynamic list of top influencers for each brand, watch conversations flow across social media, monitor information about a brand&#8217;s recent developments and earn access to special Perks,&#8221; Klout product manager David Temple said in an announcement. &#8220;If you&#8217;re one of Red Bull&#8217;s top advocates, they&#8217;ll keep you informed with a subscription to The Red Bulletin and make sure that you&#8217;ve had a chance to try their new Red Bull Total Zero by sending you a 4-Pack,&#8221; Temple says. &#8220;The very top influencers will get some sweet merchandise or even a VIP Red Bull experience, like a behind-the-scenes look at the X-Games.&#8221; How important do you think Klout&#8217;s Squads will be for brands? Sound off in the comments. BONUS: What Else Does Klout Have in Store for 2012? Looking ahead, Klout is still building scoring models for seven more services (YouTube, Instagram, Tumblr, Blogger, WordPress.com, Last.fm and Flickr) that have already been integrated onto Klout users&#8217; dashboards. Klout also plans to add Quora, Yelp, Posterous, Livefyre, Disqus, bit.ly and BranchOut. SEE ALSO: Klout Mobile App Is One Step Closer With Acquisition of BlockBoard Klout likely will continue improving its Topics feature (see screenshots below) and Klout Perks platform. The Topics feature, which rolled out in September and lets you gain insights on top influencers and +K recipients for specific content areas, got a visual update in December with a &#8220;sashes&#8221; and an &#8220;Add a Topic&#8221; button. Clickable Topics on Your Dashboard On your Klout dashboard, you can click on a topic to open its Topic Page. In December 2011, Klout rolled out sashes and an "Add a Topic" button. A blue sash goes to users with the most +Ks for any topic, while a gold sash is given to influencers based on Klout's algorithm. People who fall into both categories receive a blue-and-gold sash. Click here to view this gallery. More About: Brand pages, brands, Business, klout, red bull, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/klout-brand-squads-pages-red-bull/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/klout-brand-squads-pages-red-bull/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Innovator's Patent Agreement</title>
      <description>Cross-posted on the Twitter Engineering blog.One of the great things about Twitter is working with so many talented folks who dream up and build incredible products day in and day out. Like many companies, we apply for patents on a bunch of these inventions. However, we also think a lot about how those patents may be used in the future; we sometimes worry that they may be used to impede the innovation of others. For that reason, we are publishing a draft of the Innovator&#8217;s Patent Agreement, which we informally call the &#8220;IPA&#8221;.The IPA is a new way to do patent assignment that keeps control in the hands of engineers and designers. It is a commitment from Twitter to our employees that patents can only be used for defensive purposes. We will not use the patents from employees&#8217; inventions in offensive litigation without their permission. What&#8217;s more, this control flows with the patents, so if we sold them to others, they could only use them as the inventor intended.This is a significant departure from the current state of affairs in the industry. Typically, engineers and designers sign an agreement with their company that irrevocably gives that company any patents filed related to the employee&#8217;s work. The company then has control over the patents and can use them however they want, which may include selling them to others who can also use them however they want. With the IPA, employees can be assured that their patents will be used only as a shield rather than as a weapon.We will implement the IPA later this year, and it will apply to all patents issued to our engineers, both past and present. We are still in early stages, and have just started to reach out to other companies to discuss the IPA and whether it might make sense for them too. In the meantime, we&#8217;ve posted the IPA on GitHub with the hope that you will take a look, share your feedback and discuss with your companies. And, of course, you can #jointheflock and have the IPA apply to you.Today is the second day of our quarterly Hack Week, which means employees &#8211; engineers, designers, and folks all across the company &#8211; are working on projects and tools outside their regular day-to-day work. The goal of this week is to give rise to the most audacious and creative ideas. These ideas will have the greatest impact in a world that fosters innovation, rather than dampening it, and we hope the IPA will play an important part in making that vision a reality.- Adam Messinger, VP of Engineering (@adam_messinger)</description>
      <link>http://blog.twitter.com/2012/04/introducing-innovators-patent-agreement.html</link>
      <guid>http://blog.twitter.com/2012/04/introducing-innovators-patent-agreement.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prototype Apple Macintosh Computer Selling for $100,000 on eBay [PICS]</title>
      <description>Prototype Apple Macintosh 128 What just might be the oldest Mac computer in the world is up for bids on eBay. The asking price: $99,995.Click here to view this gallery.Among personal-computer enthusiasts, there are many rare and desirable models from years&#8217; past. The Apple Lisa. Steve Jobs&#8217;s NeXT computer. The Canon Cat. But there&#8217;s a machine selling on eBay right now that&#8217;s arguably the rarest of them all: a prototype of the original Apple Macintosh computer. As you might imagine for such a once-in-a-lifetime find, the prototype Mac 128k is commanding a hefty sum: The starting bid is $99,995. The auction only has hours left, but at least one person has made a bid for the super-rare machine. The seller, a longtime Mac enthusiast, told Mashable he found the machine in January via AppleFritter, a site dedicated to vintage Apple products. He bought the Mac from a person near Boston and says he paid a &#8220;significant amount of money&#8221; for it. &#8220;He was not advertising it for sale,&#8221; says Adam, who did not want to reveal his last name. &#8220;I threw him a message asking if he was interested in selling it. He had originally bought it for $500.&#8221; Once Adam got the machine, he worked furiously to get it working again. But there was a challenge: Apple designed the prototype to work with its proprietary disk format, Twiggy. Twiggy disks, with resemble old 5.25-inch floppy disks, were used with the Apple Lisa. However, the drives had a notoriously high failure rate, and Apple switched to Sony 3.25-inch disks for the production run of the Macintosh. Even though Adam had working Twiggy disks for his Lisa machines, they couldn&#8217;t coax his prize Mac to boot up. He suspects Apple made the prototype this way by design, so it wouldn&#8217;t work for anyone else. SEE ALSO: Steve Jobs Day: This Video Will Make You Cry &#8220;It might be a specific pre-release version of the Mac OS that will only boot this machine,&#8221; says Adam. &#8220;If anyone [has it], it would be one of the original Macintosh team back from 1983. Since this machine left Apple, it&#8217;s never booted up.&#8221; Since Adam can&#8217;t get it to work, the Mac is now open to anyone on eBay who has $100,000 to spare. Adam hopes whoever the new owner is can give it a home such an iconic machine deserves. &#8220;Because it&#8217;s the only one,&#8221; Adam says. &#8220;I don&#8217;t feel that I am the right person to own it, due to its historical significance. It&#8217;s very likely to be the world&#8217;s oldest Mac. In my heart, and in my gut, it should belong in a Smithsonian or a museum. &#8220;But I paid a lot of money for this computer. I&#8217;m not a rich person. I hope it&#8217;ll sell and make my money back and make a decent profit to make it worth my while.&#8221; Where would you like to see the prototype Mac end up? And how much would you pay for it? Share your thoughts in the comments. More About: apple, ebay, macintoshFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/apple-mac-prototype-ebay/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/apple-mac-prototype-ebay/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gfail! What the World Says When Gmail Goes Down</title>
      <description>Carrier Pigeons Some went retro.Click here to view this gallery. To the list of essential utilities we can&#8217;t live without &#8212; electricity, gas, water &#8212; you&#8217;d better add one more: Gmail. The free Google email service now has 350 million users in 54 languages. So when it experienced an outage that affected a small subset of users for around half an hour Tuesday, the resulting cacophony on Twitter read like the end of the world. According to Google, the problem affected roughly 2% of all Gmail users. (Anecdotally, that sounds about right &#8212; only one user in the Mashable office was affected.) But 2% of 350 million is still a whole lot of upset, especially when it comes to a service that seems to govern all its users&#8217; Instant Messages as well as vital email. Many services we can live without for 30 minutes of our work day; Gmail, apparently, is not one of them. (Heck, even if the electricity goes down in your building, you can still work from your 3G smartphone.) SEE ALSO: 9 Things You Need to Know About the New Gmail It may not be the case that all 7 million afflicted took to Twitter to voice their concerns, their stress, their withdrawal or their amusement, but it certainly felt like it. &#8220;#Gmail&#8221; became a trending hashtag, and &#8220;#Gfail&#8221; was surely not far behind. We&#8217;ve collected a somewhat random sampling of reactions to the service outage. Some put the problem in perspective; others less so. Check out the gallery above, and let us know in the comments below: Where were you when Gmail went down? More About: email, gmail, Google, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/gmail-went-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/gmail-went-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Payments May Replace Cash, Credit Cards by 2020 [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Experts believe that cash and credit cards could be a thing of the past by 2020, a new study suggests. A new study conducted by the Pew Research Center&#8217;s Internet &amp; American Life Project and Elon University&#8217;s Imagining the Internet Center revealed that the majority of survey respondents believe swiping mobile phones could replace cash and credit cards both online and in stores by smartphone and tablet users within the next decade. The study was conducted among a non-random sample of 1,021 technology stakeholders and critics in the mobile payments industry, from executives and Google and Microsoft to professors at distinguished universities nationwide. About 65% of respondents said they believe that by 2020 most consumers will have embraced and fully adopted the use of smart-device swiping for purchases they make, nearly eliminating the need for cash or credit cards. They also agreed that people trust and rely on personal hardware and software for transactions, and cash and credit cards will have mostly disappeared from many of the transactions that occur in advanced countries. However, about 33% said they do not trust devices with Near Field Communications technology (NFC) that allow users to swipe their phones to make a payment at checkout and believe mobile payments will not gain a lot of traction by 2020. SEE ALSO: Apple Patent Suggests &#8216;iWallet&#8217; Is Headed to the iPhone The report also found that embracing NFC technology will be slow due to a combination of privacy fears, a desire for anonymous payments, a lack of infrastructure to support widespread adoption and resistance from those companies with a financial stake in the existing payment structure. For those that believe mobile payments will become commonplace soon, many referenced how the movement is already booming in many parts of the world. &#8220;The 2020 date might be a bit optimistic, but I&#8217;m sure that this will happen,&#8221; said study participant Hal Varian, chief economist at Google. &#8220;What is in your wallet now? Identification, payment and personal items. All this will easily fit in your mobile device and will inevitably do so.&#8221; But not all experts were optimistic about the progression: &#8220;As much as I&#8217;d like to see a money-free world, I&#8217;m afraid the opportunities for the hackers and pirates are too great,&#8221; said one respondent. &#8220;I&#8217;m happy to buy my $2 Starbucks using my Android but I don&#8217;t know that we will ever feel secure enough to make much larger purchases that way.&#8221; Do you think we will be using mobile devices to pay for items instead of cash and credit cards by 2020? Will you feel secure doing so? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, coreay More About: mobile payments, near field communication, nfc, Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project, Pew Internet Center's Internet &amp; American Life Project, smartphones, tabletsFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/mobile-payments-2020/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/mobile-payments-2020/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Top Professionals to Follow on Twitter</title>
      <description>Dave Kerpen is the CEO of Likeable, a social media agency that has worked with more than 200 leading brands including 1-800-Flowers.com, Verizon, and Neutrogena. He is author of The New York Times best seller Likeable Social Media. Although many people enjoy keeping up with celebrities on Twitter, there are also dozens of professionals across other industries that are influential and worth following. We wish we could have mentioned more, but these 11 have especially nailed down how to be responsive, transparent, and relevant. The result: a group of some very successful influencers. Find out who they are. Top Fashion Designer: @xoBetseyJohnson Betsey Johnson&#8217;s presence on Twitter is nothing short of fun. She re-tweets content that&#8217;s interesting to her fans, effectively uses hashtags to promote her brand, and gives credit to her partners for helping cultivate her brand. No wonder her Twitter following is 220,000 strong.Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, youngvet More About: contributor, features, followers, TwitterFor more Media coverage:Follow Mashable Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/twitter-professionals/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/twitter-professionals/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Prometheus&#8217; Ad Shows Us the Robot We All Want [EXCLUSIVE]</title>
      <description>Fox is kicking the viral campaign Ridley Scott&#8217;s Prometheus up a notch with a brand new video and Mashable has the exclusive. The studio has crafted an awesome &#8212; and creepy &#8212; advertisement for &#8220;David,&#8221; the latest generation android from the fictitious Weyland Corporation. The ad introduces us to David, played by Michael Fassbender, who serves as the butler and maintenance man on the ship at the center of the film. Prometheus, which hits theaters on June 8, 2012, is said to have elements or &#8220;DNA&#8221; from Scott&#8217;s earlier film Alien. The film follows the crew of the spaceship Prometheus as they explore an advanced alien civilization while searching for the origins of humanity. To promote the film, Fox has worked hard to develop an intricate viral marketing campaign. In February, attendees at TED got to view a TEDTalk from the future, by way of a video set in 2023. That talk was given by Guy Pearce, who plays the CEO of the Weyland Corporation in the film. SEE ALSO: Ridley Scott&#8217;s &#8220;Prometheus&#8221; Teased in TEDTalk From the Future Last month, the first full-length trailer for Prometheus was shown during WonderCon and the live event was streamed through Facebook, Twitter and AMC Theater&#8217;s website. The trailer racked up more than 3 million views in its first few days in release. Fox is also putting a full-page advertisement for David in The Wall Street Journal. The studio also maintains the ProjectPrometheus website, which features insights into the fictitious Weyland Corporation and its own alternate-reality game. Fox has also teamed up with Verizon FiOS to offer an interactive tour of the Prometheus ship. Fans can view the ship at verizon.com/mission. The film&#8217;s social presence includes a Facebook page, as well as official Twitter and YouTube accounts. What do you think of the advertisement for &#8220;David?&#8221; Let us know in the comments. More About: david, prometheus, robots, trailerFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/prometheus-david-ad/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/prometheus-david-ad/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Tumblr&#8217; to Overtake &#8216;Blog&#8217; in Google Searches</title>
      <description>Just as Kleenex became a stand-in for &#8220;tissue&#8221; years ago, is &#8220;Tumblr&#8221; on its way to replacing &#8220;blog&#8221;? Google search results show that may be the case. By the end of 2012, there will be more people searching &#8220;Tumblr&#8221; than &#8220;blog,&#8221; according to Google&#8217;s data. Randall Munroe, creator of the popular web comic XKCD, first made the observation with his own chart. Munroe&#8217;s not the only one to note Tumblr&#8217;s ascendance. ComScore data show Tumblr got 21.8 million unique visitors in the U.S. in March, compared to 8.4 million in March 2011. Despite that surge in traffic, Tumblr CEO David Karp told Advertising Age last week that he has no desire to monetize the platform via an AdSense-like program: &#8220;Our attitude toward all this attention on Tumblr, which we could very easily throw a Google AdSense on and be profitable tomorrow &#8212; that&#8217;s so far down the list, I mean, we&#8217;re selling our desks to avoid that, it&#8217;s a complete last resort.&#8221; BONUS: How Tumblr Rekindled the Art of Animated GIFs 1. Osamu Tezuka "From a classic Osamu Tezuka short, parodying old cartoons -- an example of a GIF clip that stands alone effectively."Click here to view this gallery. Thumbnail courtesy of ozneo. More About: blog, tumblrFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/tumblr-blog-google-searches/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/17/tumblr-blog-google-searches/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Spends More On One Day of Lunch Than It Will On FCC Fine</title>
      <description>The FCC is fining Google $25,000 for impeding an investigation into personal e-mails and other data collected via the company&#8217;s Street View cars. But that&#8217;s far from a punitive fine for the search giant. In fact, it is less than the company spends on one day of lunch for its employees. Google generated more than $37.9 billion in revenue last year. It employees more than 32,000 full-time research, sales, administrative and operations workers, whom it famously provides with free food, drinks, snacks and ice cream. Even if the company is spending just $1 per day per employee to provide its &#8220;healthy and delicious dishes,&#8221; the FCC&#8217;s fine is no more of a hardship on the company than its daily lunch expense. Nevertheless, the government&#8217;s hands are tied. An FCC spokesperson told Mashable that $25,000, by both law and precedent, is the maximum fine the agency can give for impending an investigation. What, then, is Google&#8217;s incentive &#8212; or that of any large company &#8211;to cooperate with any such investigation? &#8220;There is something of the pain of embarrassment that goes with it,&#8221; John Simpson, a privacy advocate at Consumer Watchdog, tells Mashable. However, Simpson agrees the fine is miniscule &#8220;given the context.&#8221; In order to collect the photos you see when in Google Maps Street View, Google drove camera-equipped cars through streets. The cars also collected information about local wireless networks that improve location-based searches. The problem is that along with this data, the cars collected a snapshot of whatever data happened to be crossing those WiFi networks &#8212; whether it be an email message, a web search or something else. It&#8217;s not clear exactly how Google used this information or if it even looked at it. The company says collecting it was an accident, but that it was nonetheless legal. The FCC agreed with the later sentiment and did not fine Google for collecting the data. If it had found Google to be in violation, the FCC&#8217;s penalty would likely be a greater blow to Google&#8217;s reputation than its bank account. The highest settlement the FCC has reached in its history was $25 million, which Verizon paid after overcharging 15 million cellphone customers. For Google, that settlement would equate to lunch for a couple of months. Still, it&#8217;s just lunch. Authorities in Canada and Europe are still investigating Google&#8217;s Street Car data collection issue. A French privacy authority settled its case against the search giant in March for 100,000 euros, about $140,000 at the time. According to The New York Times, it was allowed a fine of up to just 150,000 euros by law. The Belgian government offered to settle with Google for 150,000 euros, or $215,000 at the time. European lawmakers are attempting to increase penalties for large companies that violate data collection laws. One proposed revision of Europe&#8217;s data protection law, The Times points out, allows violators to be fined up to two percent of their annual sales. For Google, that would be 758 million euros &#8212; which has to be enough lunch money for at least a decade. Should the U.S. fine Google more for privacy violations and investigation obstructions, accidental or otherwise? Let us know your take in the comments. More About: fcc, Google, privacyFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/google-fcc/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/google-fcc/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get more likes on Facebook</title>
      <description>More tanks. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
