<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
      <description>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition I don't say this often, butplease share this one. http://tellmetodrawsomething.tumblr.com/ https://twitter.com/#!/JeremiahMc From: weepingprophet Views: 309 14890 ratingsTime: 03:47 More in Film &amp; Animation</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XFGAQrEUaeU&amp;feature=youtube_gdata</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XFGAQrEUaeU&amp;feature=youtube_gdata</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of the Internet in a Nutshell [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>It is probably impossible to encapsulate every innovation and change that has come to the Internet since its inception more than two decades ago. But the interactive designers at Vizzuality and Hyperakt have come close, in this stunning and extensive graphic that debuted at Google I/O last week. The graphic provides an immersive walk down digital memory lane, from the earliest days of HTTP to recent developments in HTML5 and full screen APIs. It documents the birth of browsers like Safari and Firefox and even pinpoints moments in the life of Javascript and Flash. The interactive design shows the growth of digital life and culture, as well, analyzing how global Internet traffic has gr&#8230; Continue reading... More About: data, hyperakt, infographic, vizzuality</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/web-evolution-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/web-evolution-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Posts That Build Engagement on Facebook</title>
      <description>When Mark Zuckerberg &#64257;rst built Facebook, the purpose of it was to keep people connected with their friends. That was its &#64257;rst purpose. And it worked well. As Facebook grew, its purpose grew to accommodate businesses. Hence the addition of Facebook pages for brands. But many brand page admins make the mistake of thinking of Facebook users as &#8220;friends&#8221; who will look at company posts simply because a company posts them. That's not true, and it's not true because not all posts are created equal. Think of it this way, your business is not automatically friends with your audience. That only changes if you engage with them. Engagement on Facebook is re&#64258;ected in three forms: lik&#8230; Continue reading... More About: contributor, Facebook, features, Marketing, online marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-build-engagement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-build-engagement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#8217;s What Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;Want&#8217; Button Will Probably Look Like</title>
      <description>It's been said that Facebook is developing a new "Want" button that would allow you to add products to a virtual wish list, and now we have a glimpse at what the icon could look like. Tom Waddington, a web developer who recently found a disabled Want button included in Facebook's Javascript coding list of social plug-ins, told Mashable that the social network has been actively working on the feature. He embedded the code last week onto his personal blog and it has since turned from an error code into a clickable "Want" button. (See below for image). "The button has been updated since last week, so it's definitely been worked on," Waddington said. "This shows that it's still under&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, Facebook, Marketing, pinterest, social commerce, Social Media, spotify</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-want-button-icon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-want-button-icon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#8217;s What Facebook&#8217;s &#8216;Want&#8217; Button Will Probably Look Like</title>
      <description>It's been said that Facebook is developing a new "Want" button that would allow you to add products to a virtual wish list, and now we have a glimpse at what the icon could look like. Tom Waddington, a web developer who recently found a disabled Want button included in Facebook's Javascript coding list of social plug-ins, told Mashable that the social network has been actively working on the feature. He embedded the code last week onto his personal blog and it has since turned from an error code into a clickable "Want" button. (See below for image). "The button has been updated since last week, so it's definitely been worked on," Waddington said. "This shows that it's still under&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, Facebook, Marketing, pinterest, social commerce, Social Media, spotify</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-want-button-icon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-want-button-icon/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Social Media Is Affecting Local Communities</title>
      <description>In light of Mashable's Social Media Day mission to celebrate the digital revolution, we asked you how social media impacts your local community. From disaster-affected regions using Twitter for community safety to local charities rallying donations from Facebook users, we received some inspired answers about the role of social media in your hometowns. Here are excerpts from the top five responses to our question: How does social media affect your local community? You can click on the respondent's name to see the answer in full. Mare Aehlich (Kenosha, Wisconsin) - "There are so many stories of how social media has impacted the community here, but two of the best are w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: community, smday, Social Media, social media day</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Social Media Is Affecting Local Communities</title>
      <description>In light of Mashable's Social Media Day mission to celebrate the digital revolution, we asked you how social media impacts your local community. From disaster-affected regions using Twitter for community safety to local charities rallying donations from Facebook users, we received some inspired answers about the role of social media in your hometowns. Here are excerpts from the top five responses to our question: How does social media affect your local community? You can click on the respondent's name to see the answer in full. Mare Aehlich (Kenosha, Wisconsin) - "There are so many stories of how social media has impacted the community here, but two of the best are w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: community, smday, Social Media, social media day</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/social-media-local-communities/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moms Are Biggest Brand Boosters on Facebook [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Moms lead the pack when comes to liking brands on Facebook, according to a recent survey by Burst media. Fifty eight percent of moms follow or like brands on social media sites. The survey showed that moms are the group of consumers most likely to follow their favorite brands on social media. It also found that 2 in 3 readers learn about brands via "likes" from blogs, with moms and 18-34-year-olds particularly influenced by brand mentions. Sixty-six percent of blog readers answered that a promotion by a blogger influences their purchase decisions online. The survey, provided by Burst Media, uncovered some other interesting stats: 49% of respondents are loyal to brands online and occa&#8230; Continue reading... More About: brands, Facebook, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/moms-most-influenced-brand-likes-on-facebook-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/moms-most-influenced-brand-likes-on-facebook-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Android Phone Owners Use Their Devices [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>If you have a Samsung Galaxy-S and live in Sweden, chances are you like to talk on your mobile device using Bluetooth while on-the-go -- that's according to a recent study that shows Swedes use Bluetooth and wireless headsets more than people from any other country (47%). And owners of Samsung Galaxy-S phones use the most minutes per month of all Android devices (431). Tawkon, an Android app that measures how much radiation your phone is emitting, and by the company inneractive, which is a mobile app monetization exchange, created this infographic based on Tawkon's data for Android devices. This data was gathered from Tawkon's millions of daily data points over a period of several months&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, infographics, Mobile</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/how-android-phone-owners-use-their-devices-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/how-android-phone-owners-use-their-devices-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wikileaks publishing Syrian Govt email</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://wikileaks.org/syria-files/</link>
      <guid>http://wikileaks.org/syria-files/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch San Diego&#8217;s Fourth of July Fireworks Fail [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Call it a case of premature detonation. San Diego's Fourth of July fireworks show was supposed to last 15 minutes. Instead, all the projectiles went off in 30 seconds about five minutes before the show was supposed to start. Confused attendees waiting for the show to start were told that they'd already seen it and to head home. Authorities blamed a "technical difficulty" for the fizzle. Luckily, the moment is immortalized in video. Bonus: More fireworks fails below. More About: fourth of July, San Diego, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/san-diegos-fourth-of-july-fireworks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/san-diegos-fourth-of-july-fireworks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to Windows 8 Pro for $39.99</title>
      <description>We set out to make it as easy as possible for everyone to upgrade to Windows 8. Starting at general availability, if your PC is running Windows XP, Windows Vista, or Windows 7 you will qualify to download an upgrade to Windows 8 Pro for just $39.99 in 131 markets. And if you want, you can add Windows Media Center for free through the &#8220;add features&#8221; option within Windows 8 Pro after your upgrade. When you use Windows.com to purchase an upgrade to Windows 8 Pro, the Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant makes upgrading simple by walking you through the upgrade process step-by-step from purchase to download and then of course installation. The Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant will check to make sure your PC is ready for Windows 8. It will provide a detailed compatibility report that lets you know of anything you may have to address before or after the upgrade and outlines actions to take. It will also inform you of any application or device compatibility issues. It will ask you what you want to keep from your current Windows installation. You will be able to upgrade from any consumer edition of Windows 7 to Windows 8 Pro and bring everything along which includes your Windows settings, personal files, and apps. If you are upgrading from Windows Vista, you will be able to bring along your Windows settings and personal files, and if you are upgrading from Windows XP you will only be able to bring along your personal files. Of course, if you want to start fresh, you can choose to bring nothing along. Or if you prefer to format your hard drive as part of your upgrade experience, you can do so as long as you boot from media and then format your hard drive from within the setup experience for installing Windows 8, not prior to it. Once you purchase your upgrade, the Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant kicks off your download. It has a built-in download manager that allows you to pause and continue your download at any time as well as a check to ensure your download completes successfully. After your download finishes, you can choose to proceed with the upgrade (&#8220;Install now&#8221;) or install later either from your desktop or by creating your own media. If you choose to create your own media, you will be able to create your own bootable USB or .ISO file which can be burned onto a DVD for upgrade and backup purposes. If you prefer, you also have the option of purchasing a backup DVD for $15 plus shipping and handling. We believe that your upgrade experience in Windows 8 will be a breeze by offering a faster experience, a single upgrade path, and compatibility from prior versions of Windows. We&#8217;ve continued to listen to our customers and have expanded the ability to download to over 100 countries and 37 languages. We have simplified the Windows upgrade experience with the Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant which supports you during your upgrade with everything from selecting your language to pausing your download to built-in compatibility checks - it&#8217;s seamless. And if you&#8217;re an enthusiast you will have the flexibility to download and control how you upgrade. If you prefer to shop at a local store, a packaged DVD version of the upgrade to Windows 8 Pro will be available for $69.99 during this promotion. This upgrade promotion for Windows 8 Pro both online and at retail runs through January 31st, 2013. We wanted to share information about this upgrade promotion with you as we continue to drive toward the RTM milestone for Windows 8. We will of course have more to say and more details to provide closer to general availability. Oh, and by the way - if you&#8217;re not upgrading from a prior version of Windows and are building your own PC or installing Windows 8 in a virtual machine or a separate partition, you will be able to purchase and install the Windows 8 and Windows 8 Pro System Builder product.</description>
      <link>http://windowsteamblog.com/windows/b/bloggingwindows/archive/2012/07/02/upgrade-to-windows-8-pro-for-39-99.aspx</link>
      <guid>http://windowsteamblog.com/windows/b/bloggingwindows/archive/2012/07/02/upgrade-to-windows-8-pro-for-39-99.aspx</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
