<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>New York Auto Show: The Coolest Car Tech So Far</title>
      <description>Terrafugia's Transition Flying Car Here's that flying car you've been dreaming of your whole life. From aircraft company Aircraft company Terrafugia comes the Transition car, which touts four wheels, two wings and the ability fly two people anywhere.Click here to view this gallery. BMW&#8217;s much-hyped i8 Spyder may not be at the 2012 New York International Auto Show after all, but that doesn&#8217;t mean the event isn&#8217;t bursting at the seams with an impressive roster of snazzy new cars bristling with high-tech features. From the ultra-sleek, super fast SRT Viper sports car, to the Mercedes-Benz G-Class fuel-efficient SUV with a &#8220;magic sky&#8221; sun roof &#8212; to even a flying car &#8212; manufacturers pulled out all the stops with their latest designs during a Tuesday press preview. The New York Auto Show will be open to the public from April 6 until April 15. SEE ALSO: The Viper Sports Car Roars Back to Life With a New Name Which model is your favorite? Let us know in the comments. More About: cars, green, New York Auto Show</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/new-york-auto-show-tech/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/new-york-auto-show-tech/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hands On: Smart Pedometer Striiv Takes Fitness to Social Level</title>
      <description>Striiv launched on Wednesday its new touchscreen smart pedometer that not only tracks your steps and motivates you to walk, but also allows you to compete against friends in virtual races and challenges. The new social Striiv Smart Pedometer ($99.95) monitors your physical habits and creates personal challenges and goals based on your behavior. It also sends gentle reminders throughout the day to walk more, take the stairs and lead a healthier lifestyle. The built-in social component adds an extra layer of entertainment by allowing you to race against friends for real-life prizes, such as household chores or a cup of coffee. Don&#8217;t know anyone else with a Striiv? Play against virtual characters named Waddles, Sir Bacon and Walkatron. These competitions allow you to win trophies and collect points that can be redeemed in Striiv&#8217;s Sims-meets-FarmVille virtual world called Myland. Cashing in points will add in new characters to the game, as well as plants and structures. SEE ALSO: Disconnect: 5 Business Benefits of Working Out The device is a highly entertaining way to get more exercise without a rigid gym routine. It also comes with a detachable keychain holder, so it can fit nicely in your pocket as you walk. The downside, however, is that it doesn&#8217;t pick up on movements if it&#8217;s inside a purse or bag. It has to be on your person at all times. It&#8217;s also highly sensitive &#8212; much more so than your typical fitness app. If challenged to a competition that involves climbing stairs, you won&#8217;t be able to fake it by pretending your climbing stairs. This reinforces authenticity of your workouts and encourages you to do the actual work to get the credit. However, the device was a bit buggy during our tests. It took a while for to properly sync up with another Striiv and froze several times while trying to set up a race. In addition, it inaccurately logged the number of steps taken during a &#8220;city block&#8221; run by not counting any movement for several-second periods. Although you can compete against friends in real time, the challenge has to be accepted when in close proximity. However, you can start that race later on even if you aren&#8217;t in the same area. The device is now available at Striiv.com, Amazon.com, HSN.com and BestBuy.com What do you think of the Striiv Smart Pedometer? What smart fitness gadgets and apps do you use? Let us know in the comments. More About: fitness, striiv</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/striiv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/striiv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Lose Your Dream Job During the Interview Process</title>
      <description>Mona Abdel-Halim is the co-founder of Resunate, the makers of the Apply widget for startups. You can start attracting top talent free by getting an Apply widget for your company at Resunate.com/employers. Connect with Resunate on Facebook and Twitter. If you&#8217;ve been on the job search for a while, it&#8217;s likely you have a good idea of things you should be doing to land a new job, such as optimizing your resume or building your personal brand online. Of course, you can&#8217;t get the job if you don&#8217;t make a great impression on your interviewer or potential employer. But there are also plenty of ways you can ruin your chances of getting a new job. It may seem obvious, but you&#8217;d be surprised how many people kill their chances before they&#8217;ve even left their interview. If you&#8217;re hoping to land your dream job, here&#8217;s what not to do during the job hunt. 1. Blow Off the Phone Interview If your resume makes it past an employer&#8217;s applicant tracking system and impresses the hiring manager, it&#8217;s likely you&#8217;ll be invited for a phone interview. This is how employers whittle down their list of applicants to decide who they want to bring in for an in-person interview &#8212; so you need to be prepared and take the opportunity seriously. Here&#8217;s a great example of what not to do (courtesy of an anonymous employer via MyCrappyResume): &#8220;[I] had a couple of phone screens with clearly drunken candidates. Also had a candidate sweating profusely through interviews and going to the bathroom every 5 minutes. (Word to the wise &#8212; if you&#8217;re THAT sick, reschedule!) Needless to say, none of them were hired!&#8221; It&#8217;s also vital that you&#8217;re properly prepared for the interview. Sit in a quiet room without distractions, do your research beforehand and ensure you&#8217;re actually able to speak on the phone for the allotted time. One job candidate learned this the hard way: &#8220;I was asked to participate in a second phone interview while I was on vacation, and because I was very interested in the job, I obliged. Before I started to answer the first question, my phone completely died. I had no way of retrieving the phone number. Needless to say, I did not get the job.&#8221; 2. Talk About Other Job Opportunities It may sound like common sense, but some job seekers feel the need to be overly honest when interacting with potential employers. There&#8217;s always the chance that one opportunity might fall through, so don&#8217;t jeopardize one position because you think you might get another. Obviously, employers don&#8217;t like being rebuffed, particularly when they&#8217;ve spent a lot of time reviewing your material and preparing for the interview. Here are two real stories that are almost hard to believe: &#8220;Someone once started an interview with me by saying &#8216;Okay. So, just to set this straight, I did interview for another job that I&#8217;m probably going to take if I receive an offer.&#8217;&#8221; &#8220;During the interview, an alarm clock went off from a candidate&#8217;s briefcase. He took it out, shut it off, apologized and said he had to leave for another interview.&#8221; 3. Provide TMI Unfortunately, there are a lot of jobseekers who have had a tough time landing a new job. Whether you&#8217;re a new graduate, an older job seeker or one of the long-term unemployed, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve had your fair share of challenges on the hunt for a new position. Sharing these sob stories with employers, however, is not going to get you the job. One employer tells of an awkward interview situation that illustrates the point: &#8220;I once interviewed a woman and asked her standard interview questions, such as &#8216;What do you need from a boss?&#8217; To this question, she replied: &#8216;I need my boss to be my best friend. I&#8217;m so lonely. We just moved here a few months ago, and I haven&#8217;t made any friends. I need a friend.&#8217;&#8221; 4. Talk Negatively About Former Supervisors or Positions It&#8217;s easy to blame your former supervisor for issues you faced in the workplace. Sure, venting to a friend or family member can make you feel less angry, but do not bring it into a new job. Applicants who speak negatively about former positions, management or colleagues are not perceived positively by employers &#8212; it can often raise a red flag in their eyes if you&#8217;re so quick to dish the dirt. In one instance, a candidate spoke badly of customers to his interviewer and ruined his chances of landing the job: &#8220;I was interviewing a young man for a customer service position. He had worked at a hair salon, and in describing his experience there, he said, &#8216;I had to deal with a lot of old biddies.&#8217; Needless to say, that&#8217;s where his candidacy ended.&#8221; 5. Act Cocky Confidence is key on the job search, but cockiness is less than appealing. You certainly don&#8217;t want to sound like this jobseeker: &#8220;One time a candidate said he was so well-qualified that if he didn&#8217;t get the job, it would prove that the company&#8217;s management was incompetent.&#8221; What&#8217;s your biggest interview &#8220;don&#8217;t&#8221;? Let us know in the comments. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Web Designer at Popdust in New York Social Operations Manager at Vivaki Nerve Center in Chicago Manager, Public Relations at New Relic in San Francisco Image courtesy of iStockphoto, PinkTag, gulfix More About: features, job interviews, job search series, mashableFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/job-search-mistakes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/job-search-mistakes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the Digital World Killing Creativity? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Sure, you can use that smartphone to create an emotionally stirring Instagram of the waffles you had for brunch in mere seconds. But that same device can also serve as a ball and chain for the working world: emails constantly arrive, even during off hours; LinkedIn requests buzz after networking events; and has that important new contact followed you on Twitter yet? While our current age of digital disruption has opened a cornucopia of new casual creative endeavors, the networked generation&#8217;s ability to multitask &#8212; and the constant need for instantaneous action &#8212; may also be hindering creativity. Consider this: In a recent global study, three-quarters of respondents said their creative potential is being stifled. More than 60% of American said their education systems squelch creativity, and a majority of total respondents said pressure at work hurts creativity. Yet 80% of respondents worldwide said allowing creativity to flourish is critical to economic growth. Those numbers come from a recent survey of 5,000 adults in the United States, United Kingdom, Germany, France and Japan. The study was commissioned by software giant Adobe, and its results were announced Monday. SEE ALSO: How to Be Creative: The Science of Genius | Adobe Launches $50-a-Month &#8216;Creative Cloud&#8217; With CS 6 Given that Adobe just released the latest version of its wildly popular Creative Suite line of products including Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign, it&#8217;s no surprise the company would play up the need for a more hospitable climate for experimentation. But the study&#8217;s findings do indicate that people worldwide feel unfulfilled creatively. Check out the infographic below for the full picture. Do you think our increasingly digital lifestyle does more to help or hinder creativity? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, Clicknique More About: infographics, workFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/24/creativity-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/24/creativity-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Tips for Keeping Your Gamified Community Motivated</title>
      <description>Shannon Duffy is the president of marketing at Data.com, a Salesforce.com company. Follow her @sullytoduffy. Everyone agrees: Gamification is hot. So hot that the market is expected to hit $2.8 billion in revenue by 2016. Naturally, companies are taking a long look at how to capitalize on this trend. If you&#8217;ve done your homework and found that gamification is right for your business, the next step is enticing your community to become deeply involved. Here are four tips to get you started. 1. Define Motivation Ultimately, people play games for a chance to win, but winning means different things to different communities. The goal of a gamified community should be to make as many members meet their definition of success as possible. For example, a community may have a group responsible for adding a large amount of content to the community and another group concerned with confirming the content&#8217;s accuracy. These groups have disparate needs and goals so they will not be motivated by the same things. Any successful community will evaluate the individual needs of groups and determine how to best serve each one. Bottom line: Know what motivates the various groups in your community and feed those motivations. 2. Apply Incentives Once you know what motivates your community you can provide the right incentives to get users involved. A ranking system is important to many communities, but new or emerging players might be more invested in a monthly ranking contest. Applying goals, badges, and titles is also effective. In fact, it&#8217;s similar to how Xbox 360 has found success with achievements. This approach generally pushes members to want to go the extra mile to advance their standing in the community. For communities with a more professional focus, developing incentives around access to productivity tools is a good way to create engagement and help members reach business goals. Bottom line: Make rewards attainable, regular, relevant, and open to community groups. 3. Create MVPs Every successful community has a small number of members that carry the torch. They are the most invested and active members. They&#8217;ve contributed so much that they have attained a sense of ownership around the community. Since they feel like the community is their own, these are the loyalists that you can count on to maintain rules, champion the game, both off and online, and constantly contribute content and competition. Create specific groups for these MVPs that include special recognition and status in the community. This rewards their efforts and also makes them role models for other players. Retailers have done a particularly good job of rewarding loyalty with MVP status. For example, Gilt Noir, an ultra-exclusive membership level within the Gilt Groupe membership, gave its members dibs on high-end sales. This encouraged other Gilt Groupe members to try to reach this elite status. Bottom line: Create an MVP program to encourage continued involvement from your most active and important members. 4. Avoid Trouble Make sure to create community guidelines with a crystal clear code of conduct. This code should transparently demonstrate how players can achieve the goals they&#8217;re looking to meet without breaking the rules. It should also be clear that breaking the rules has a penalty. As a manager, you should also always be aware of player activity and discussion board fodder that may raise flags. If you see a problem brewing, interact with the player or players and address the issue before it disrupts the community. Bottom line: Define rules, make sure the community plays by them, and if a problem starts to take shape, address it as soon as possible. How do you use gamification to motivate communities? More About: Business, contributor, features, gamification, online communityFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/24/tips-motivating-gamified-community/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/24/tips-motivating-gamified-community/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Advertising: 5 DIY Tips for Small Businesses</title>
      <description>Zephrin Lasker is CEO of Pontiflex. Follow the company @Pontiflex. When it comes to digital advertising, small business owners (SMBs) must wade through a lot of industry jargon. Today, they have to make sense of words like SoLoMo, and tomorrow, they&#8217;ll be evaluating marketing options with terms such as InstaLikes. The good news is that if SMBs can look beyond these buzzwords, there are a number of DIY digital advertising options that can help them get new customers and grow their businesses in the burgeoning mobile space. In fact, there are several self-serve ad platforms like Twitter that work with advertisers of all sizes. What&#8217;s common among these solutions is that they make it easy for SMBs to go mobile. SEE ALSO: 7 Surprising Facts About Mobile Shoppers Going mobile makes sense now more than ever. According to a recent Borrell Associates Inc. survey, 48% of SMBs said they are &#8220;somewhat likely&#8221; or &#8220;very likely&#8221; to incorporate mobile into their advertising spending this year. Yet, navigating the self-service market can be tricky. Here are five tips on what to consider as you make that decision. 1. Go Local Mobile advertising has opened up a unique opportunity for SMBs. It allows them to target by geo-location and reach people as they&#8217;re looking at what&#8217;s around them. Even better, advertisers can target customers by zip code, which is particularly useful considering that most purchases are made in the immediate vicinity of one&#8217;s home or office. So, when evaluating advertising options, small businesses should choose solutions that allow them to target customers by a location size that is most relevant to their business. 2. Think Beyond the Click In the online world, Google AdWords has proven to be wildly successful for advertisers. Google launched AdWords so that businesses could pay only for clicks and also create, manage, and optimize campaigns themselves. While there&#8217;s no reason the mobile ad industry can&#8217;t have its own AdWords, it&#8217;s important to note that clicks don&#8217;t necessarily work in a mobile world. A recent Harris Interactive survey proved nearly half of mobile users clicked on a mobile ad by mistake, meaning nearly half of mobile advertising dollars are wasted. In other words, when advertising on mobile, SMBs should be wary of solutions that charge on a cost-per-click basis. 3. Advertise in Mobile Apps According to Flurry data published earlier this year, time spent on mobile apps is growing, with people spending more than an hour and half per day using them. Meanwhile, they&#8217;re spending less time on the mobile web. This data shows that people are becoming more and more engaged with apps. Couple that with a projection by IDC that more than 76.9 billion apps will be downloaded by 2014, and the message is simple: when thinking mobile advertising, think mobile apps. 4. Engage People with Relevant Deals According to another Harris Interactive survey, almost two-thirds of mobile app users prefer mobile ads that contain coupons, deals, or newsletters over commercial and video ads. So SMBs should try performance-branding solutions that engage people with deals and coupons. For the most impact, ads should also include a strong call to action and stress exclusivity. 5. Integrate Across Various Online Platforms People use mobile devices to interact with apps, read their emails, and engage with social media sites. This means SMBs should find one tool to engage people and follow-up with activities, such as email marketing, which can help drive in-store purchases, promote online sales, and increase their social footprint. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, TommL More About: contributor, features, mobile advertising, Small BusinessFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/diy-mobile-advertising-tips-smbs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/diy-mobile-advertising-tips-smbs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Obama Threatens to Veto CISPA Cybersecurity Bill</title>
      <description>The Obama administration has threatened to veto the controversial Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act (CISPA), if the bill passes through Congress in its current form. Such a scenario is, however, unlikely.</description>
      <link>http://www.digitaltrends.com/web/obama-threatens-to-veto-cispa/</link>
      <guid>http://www.digitaltrends.com/web/obama-threatens-to-veto-cispa/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a Social Network Helps Families Coping With Autism</title>
      <description>Autism Awareness Month may be coming to a close, but by using the social network MyAutismTeam, parents of children with autism spectrum disorder can spread awareness and find support throughout the year. MyAutismTeam is a part of the MyHealthTeams network, online communities for people living with or caring for those with chronic health conditions. On the network, users who share who is on their support teams &#8212; parents, specialists, businesses &#8212; with other users looking for the same. &#8220;One in two Americans suffers from a chronic condition or disease,&#8221; says Eric Peacock, co-founder and CEO of MyHealthTeams. &#8220;That includes everything from autism and ADHD to diabetes, Parkinson&#8217;s and breast cancer. What&#8217;s more, that number is expected to grow 42% in the next 10 years.&#8221; MyHealthTeams decided to focus on autism for its first network because one in 88 children in America is diagnosed with symptoms of autism. &#8220;Parents of children diagnosed with autism face enormous challenges and have to become autism and special needs experts practically overnight,&#8221; Peacock says. &#8220;Naturally, they want to connect with other parents and learn from them.&#8221; MyAutismTeam officially launched in December 2011, after several months of testing, growing the user base and improving the site. It opened in beta to users last June, beginning with just 30 parents in the San Francisco Bay Area. But when word got out, the site grew quickly. According to Peacock, MyAutismTeam hit 10,000 registered parents from all 50 states within four months. Today, it has more than 22,000 registered parents. MyAutismTeam believes it should be easy to find the best people around to help a parent when his or her child is diagnosed with autism. With MyAutismTeam, parents can get in touch with other parents, search a directory of more than 30,000 autism specialists and access a searchable Q&amp;A section of 600-plus questions (If a user wants to ask a new question, the answer rate is 97.5%, according to Peacock). The network has also partnered with Autism Speaks and Easter Seals, two organizations at the forefront of autism awareness and research. As a result, MyAutismTeam has been able to incorporate quite a large database of autism resources. &#8220;We&#8217;re becoming the Yelp for autism,&#8221; says Peacock. &#8220;If you want to find autism specialists recommended by other parents who have been in your shoes, this is the place to do it.&#8221; &#8220;Parents of children diagnosed with autism&#8230;have to become autism and special needs experts practically overnight. Naturally, they want to connect with other parents and learn from them.&#8221; James Vaughan, the father of an 11-year-old boy with autism in West Haven, Utah, says the help he has received from MyAutismTeam has been tremendous. &#8220;The life of an autism parent is often one that is a frustrating and long road,&#8221; Vaughan says. &#8220;MyAutismTeam provides a network where everyone is in the same boat&#8230;There is no other place in social media that can give a parent that complete, non-judgmental support, the helpful tips that keep us going, and the stories that give us hope during the most trying times.&#8221; Lara Marek&#8217;s fianc&#233; has three children: a 14-year-old boy diagnosed with Asperger&#8217;s syndrome and two 7-year-old twin girls, one of whom has autism spectrum disorder, and one who is neurotypical (that is, not on the autism spectrum). MyAutismTeam has allowed Marek to share with other parents her experiences and questions, and it gives her an outlet without fear of judgment. &#8220;The best thing anyone can do is learn about the things that impact his or her life,&#8221; says Marek, &#8220;and in my case I have to admit I had some misconceptions about autism. Acceptance is crucial no matter who we are. The more we can embrace what makes us different, the better off we are with self-appreciation.&#8221; MyHealthTeams is planning dozens of additional networks that will focus on other chronic conditions. MyBreastCancerTeam, for example, is scheduled to launch within the next few weeks. &#8220;It&#8217;s our mission to make sure it&#8217;s easy for those folks to find the best people around to help them,&#8221; says Peacock. &#8220;We love what we do and won&#8217;t stop until we help as many of them as we can.&#8221; Image courtesy of iStockphoto, bowdenimages. More About: features, health, Social Good, Social MediaFor more Social Good coverage:Follow Mashable Social Good on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Good channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/myautismteam/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/myautismteam/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Klout for iPhone Arrives, Shows Your Score Without Opening App</title>
      <description>Nearly four months after confirming plans to build a mobile app, Klout has just released an iPhone version and assured Android users that an app for them will eventually arrive. The Klout app lets people monitor their online influence on the go. The app icon, for example, displays a user&#8217;s Klout score instead of the number of notifications. Klout measures influence on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and Foursquare to assign Klout users scores from 0 to 100. &#8220;The main reason this app exists is to take your influence with you, so you know what your influence is no matter where you are,&#8221; Klout spokeswoman Lynn Fox told Mashable. Within the app, users can check their influential topics, +Ks received, a list of people who they influence, a list of people who influence them and other people&#8217;s profiles. Klout will also send push notifications. Unlike Klout&#8217;s browser platform, the app doesn&#8217;t allow people to give out +Ks yet, but that functionality is in the works. Users distribute +Ks to vouch for people&#8217;s expertise or knowledge on a certain topic (see gallery below). &#8220;The Klout app is customizable, allowing you to choose what notifications you will receive and what features you want to use,&#8221; reads the app&#8217;s description in the Apple Store. &#8220;If you wish, you can also turn off display of your the Score on the Klout icon.&#8221; Klout spent two months creating the app. The process began after the San Francisco-based startup acquired BlockBoard, an app that gives people a way to communicate with neighbors, and its &#8220;killer mobile app development team&#8221; in February. Previously, Klout had announced a Series C round of funding in January. At the time, CEO Joe Fernandez told Mashable: &#8220;There is definitely a mobile component to our plans and we are excited about having the resources to push forward with that vision.&#8221; Is the Klout app something you will download and use? What would you like to see the app do in the future? BONUS: What Else Does Klout Have in Store for 2012? Looking ahead, Klout is still building scoring models for seven more services (YouTube, Instagram, Tumblr, Blogger, WordPress.com, Last.fm and Flickr) that have already been integrated onto Klout users&#8217; dashboards. Klout also plans to add Quora, Yelp, Posterous, Livefyre, Disqus, bit.ly and BranchOut. SEE ALSO: Klout Unveils Brand Pages With Red Bull as Its Sole Launch Partner Klout likely will continue improving its Topics feature (see screenshots below) and Klout Perks platform. The Topics feature, which rolled out in September and lets you gain insights on top influencers and +K recipients for specific content areas, got a visual update in December with a &#8220;sashes&#8221; and an &#8220;Add a Topic&#8221; button. Clickable Topics on Your Dashboard On your Klout dashboard, you can click on a topic to open its Topic Page. In December 2011, Klout rolled out sashes and an "Add a Topic" button. A blue sash goes to users with the most +Ks for any topic, while a gold sash is given to influencers based on Klout's algorithm. People who fall into both categories receive a blue-and-gold sash. Click here to view this gallery. More About: Apple Store, apps, iphone apps, klout, mobile apps, online influence, Social MediaFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/klout-mobile-app-iphone/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/klout-mobile-app-iphone/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
