<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Interview: John Robb</title>
      <description>John Robb is an astronautical engineer turned US Air Force Special Operations pilot turned Forrester lead analyst turned startup CTO/COO turned military theorist and author, to oversimplify. His writing has heavily influenced my own (eg you&#8217;ll find his phrase &#8220;open source insurgency&#8221; several times in my novel Swarm.) He blogs at Global Guerrillas and edits Resilient Communities. Q: Your writing has focused on three themes: global guerrillas, resilient communities, and, more recently, drone disruption. Could you give the quick nutshell summaries of each of those? Sure. The general theme of my work is to be at the center of the information flow in the place the world is changing the fastest. I did that four times (tier 1 spec ops, the Internet, Internet Finance, blogging) in the past. I think these topics are where the change is happening fastest now: Global guerrillas (the blog and the book, Brave New War) is about open source warfare and systems disruption. Open source warfare is a new form of guerrilla warfare that works exceedingly well in the modern, connected environment. It&#8217;s loose and highly effective. It worked in Iraq during the insurgency and in Tunisia/Egypt to topple dictators. Systems disruption is about taking sabotage to a new level. Systems disruption is how individuals and small groups can topple critical networks with very small attacks. These attacks are so successful&#8211;I have plenty of examples&#8211;they can generate returns on investment over one million to one! This area of my work has lots of fans in US special operations, the CIA, the NSA, guerrilla groups around the world. Resilient communities is a topic where I spend most of my time. Why? There are two globally systemic threats we can&#8217;t solve. Finance and the environment. Both systems are deeply broken and they are going to do considerable damage to all of us over the next decades. The only way to get ready for that is to build networked resilient communities. Resilient Communities efficiently produce most (not all) of the food, energy, water, and products we use daily. These communities reduce our vulnerabilities to the future&#8217;s inevitable disruptions (that will damage/impoverish those that don&#8217;t transition), reduce complexity to a human scale, and improve the quality of our lives. Since these communities network with the global system, they don&#8217;t lose any of the complexity/value we enjoy in the current intellectual environment. My bet, and it is the reason I started the resilient community newsletter, is that the most successful, happiest people on the planet in twenty years will be living in resilient communities. Drones. Robots are transforming the US military and warfare. I&#8217;m a former military pilot. I have seen first hand what drones are doing to the Air Force. Already more than half of all of the people going through pilot training end up flying drones. There are more military drones flying right now than manned planes. We&#8217;ve also seen the development of the last manned fighter (the F-35) and I doubt anybody anywhere will produce a new one. Around the world, drones are being deployed permanently (eliminating the need for soldiers) and they are being used frequently (they kill thousands). Unfortunately, this makes sense. Drones are nearly costless. They don&#8217;t generate any public push back (no US casualties) and they are much less expensive than people (no retirement/health/etc.). They can also be controlled from Washington. What makes them really scary is how fast they are becoming autonomous, smaller, and less expensive. It&#8217;s easy to envision a 10 million drone swarm pacifying a 30 m person city in 20 years time (completely controlled by just a few people at the top). Q: A common assumption among all three, it seems, is that increasing economic and technical connectivity will lead to increasing military/political instability, which in turn will reveal the fragility of our existing infrastructure. What would you say to those who argue that this is excessively apocalyptic, and that the West&#8217;s existing society and infrastructure are already plenty robust? There&#8217;s a simple answer to that: the financial crisis of 2008 and the EU meltdown. Another is climate change, which is another runaway train of a disaster. Why aren&#8217;t these fixable? Finance and the environment are truly global systems and there isn&#8217;t anybody at the lever. Q: Technology and creativity are becoming increasingly crowdsourced: not just open-source software, but also Kickstarter, Thingiverse, Ushahidi, etc. Do you view these as steps in the direction of resilient communities, or do you think something qualitatively different needs to be done to get there? Yes. I think crowd funding is the wrong term. People don&#8217;t put money into just anything. They put money and time into things they care about. As such, this is more community financing than crowd financing. So, does community financing (via the JOBS act and other methods) make it easier to build resilient communities? Yes. Building out food, water, and energy infrastructure at the local level will require that type of financing. I think people are going to find that investing locally in these efforts is a much better way to fund a retirement than investing in broken financial products that have no intrinsic value. Q: Your writing deals extensively with &#8220;open-source insurgencies.&#8221; Can you give a couple of concrete example of those insurgencies, how they work, and how they&#8217;re enabled by modern technology? We had a hot open source insurgency in Iraq. Lots of different groups: Baathists that supported Saddam, Baathists that didn&#8217;t, nationalists, different flavors of Jihadi, criminals, tribal groups. All of them came together to develop an open source project: to fight the US occupation and keep the Iraqi government in a state of disarray. It worked for years, despite incredible odds. One of the reasons it worked so well is that the rate of innovation in open source insurgencies is extremely fast. IEDs (improvised explosive devices) designs improved extremely quickly. They were able to defeat US counter-measures weeks after they were deployed. Another example is Egypt (and the other insurgencies/protests of the Arab Spring). The reason the protest worked was that it used an open source framework. It didn&#8217;t have a fixed leadership cadre and its goals were extremely simple. The only people that were able to gain credibility as leaders were those people that moved the protest forward. If they tried to insert their own agenda, they were quickly discarded. Q: You believe drones, and in particular autonomous swarms of drones, will soon revolutionize warfare and military thought everywhere. How do you see this happening over the next ten years, and what milestones do you think will be reached along the way? It&#8217;s already underway. Drones already are killing thousands. They are so easy to use, they are the first option in any plan. Much of the rest of the military that isn&#8217;t directly employed in the service of deploying and managing drones, is an expensive legacy that will take years to scale down and mothball. Q: What steps do you think nation-states will take to ensure that drone military power will remain their exclusive preserve? (I&#8217;m thinking of Cory Doctorow&#8217;s The Coming War On General-Purpose Computing.) Do you think they&#8217;ll ultimately succeed, or will that technology metastasize to insurgents (open-source or other) and other non-state groups? If so, what will the geopolitical effects be? I personally believe that nation-states are in the process of becoming hollow shells of what they once were. Global systems are hollowing them out, reducing their ability to control events or their finances. Most states are going to end up being mere conduits for extracting wealth to send to the global financial system (think Greece, Ireland, and soon Spain). They won&#8217;t deliver any meaningful services and their focus will be on control of the countryside (probably through drones/robotics that makes it possible for people in Washington to non-lethally put down riots in LA with a flip of a switch). Also, will we see robotic pirates and terrorists? Yes, probably. So, given that this is a likely future, I&#8217;d rather have the genie out of the box and working on our side. Image: DronesHawks swarming over Panama City, by yours truly.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/28/interview-john-robb/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/28/interview-john-robb/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obama Campaign Posts Everything You Need to Know About Voting</title>
      <description>One key to running a successful political campaign is voter registration. Campaign staff on both sides of the aisle run voter registration drives at all sorts of real-world events &#8212; county fairs, baseball games and town festivals, just to name a few. The more citizens a campaign can sign up to vote, the logic goes, the bigger the pool of potential voters for that campaign&#8217;s candidate. Now, President Obama&#8217;s re-election campaign is looking to bring information about voter registration online via a new portal called &#8220;GottaVote,&#8221; billed as a one-stop shop for everything visitors need to know in preparation for Election Day. Upon arrival, the site automatically detects the U.S. state where a visitor lives, as voter registration laws can differ widely between states. GottaVote then provides four options: &#8220;get registered,&#8221; &#8220;what to bring,&#8221; &#8220;get reminders&#8221; and &#8220;vote.&#8221; Users can explore the site to find voter registration forms and instructions on filling them out, browse information about what they&#8217;ll need to bring to a polling place on Election Day and learn how to find the location of their local polling place. Online-only voting is not yet possible in the United States, so the best that GottaVote can do is help users print out a voter registration form and give them an address for mailing it to the proper local office. &#8220;Voting should be easy for every eligible voter. Simply put, that&#8217;s why today we&#8217;re launching GottaVote.org,&#8221; reads a blog post on the site. &#8220;When you have the information you need, no matter where you live, you can take the steps to make sure your vote is counted and your voice is heard come election day.&#8221; GottaVote users can also ask the Obama campaign their voting-related questions or submit a story about voting, giving the site an element of social interaction. The platform comes in a Spanish-language version as well &#8212; likely an acknowledgement of the importance of the Spanish-speaking community in this year&#8217;s presidential election. Many states have strict regulations around voter registration. Campaign staff aren&#8217;t allowed, for example, to ask a potential registrant about their political ideology before signing them up to vote. However, GottaVote is not without its partisan calls to action. A &#8220;Take Action&#8221; page encourages visitors to attend a voter registration &#8220;weekend of action,&#8221; a favorite event of the Obama campaign wherein thousands of voter registration drives are held simultaneously across the country. The site also asks lawyers to join the &#8220;victory council,&#8221; an all-volunteer legal team designed to &#8220;ensure that every eligible voter can vote on Election Day,&#8221; the site says. Obama campaign staff have derided some states&#8217; efforts to create voter identification laws, which they say are an attempt to disenfranchise Democratic blocs of voters &#8212; and GottaVote is likely a response to those laws. Proponents of tighter voter identification rules argue that they&#8217;re needed to prevent voter fraud. Do you think more Americans would register to vote if they could do it all online? Sound off in the comments below. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, plherrera More About: 2012 presidential campaign, barack obama, Politics, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/obama-voting-online/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/obama-voting-online/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Former Yahoo COO Who Almost Bought Facebook Shows Up on IPO Day</title>
      <description>Back in 2006, Facebook was only a shadow of the company it would become, tech giant Yahoo was attempting to buy the social network for $1 billion &#8212; and Dan Rosenweig was the man who got Zuckerberg&#8217;s handshake on that offer. Rosenweig the Chief Operating Officer of Yahoo from 2002 to 2007 &#8212; Facebook founder to acquire the company &#8212; an offer which Zuckerberg accepted at first, but declined after Yahoo lowered the price. &#8220;I&#8217;d like to think I was way ahead of the curve of most people, because they only had four million users and zero revenue and I did offer them a billion dollars,&#8221; Rosenweig said during a brief conversation with a group of journalists in the parking lot of Facebook HQ before heading off to a scheduled interview. &#8220;I assure you as ahead of the curve I thought I might have been, I don&#8217;t think anybody would have imagined all of this,&#8221; he said shortly after Facebook&#8217;s stock went up for sale Friday. Zuckerberg reportedly accepted Yahoo&#8217;s $1 billion offer with a handshake. Yahoo&#8217;s stock tumbled shortly after, and the company lowered its offer to $850 million &#8212; an offer which Zuckerberg refused. Yahoo had reportedly separated into two camps on the issue, one that believed in the future of Facebook, and another that thought a $1 billion investment in a network that was currently making no money was unwise. SEE ALSO: Facebook Opens at $42, Valued at $116.6 Billion Rosenweig built a relationship with Zuckerberg during the time Yahoo was considering the acquisition, and impressed him with his forward-thinking. When most people were still thinking about building single applications, Zuckerberg was thinking about building a platform. &#8220;He was talking about a platform before platform was cool,&#8221; says Rosenweig. &#8220;He had a vision for connecting people of all kinds.&#8221; At the time, Facebook was only available to college students &#8212; and only allowed them to connect to students at their own school. &#8220;He had pretty big ambitions, and I think it&#8217;s pretty clear he was way ahead of everybody &#8211;- and still is frankly.&#8221; Rosensweig described Facebook&#8217;s move to Menlo Park as representative of a rebirth in the area. &#8220;When I moved here 10 years ago this building was Sun Micro, and it&#8217;s sort of the changing of guard. Menlo went from Sun Micro, to being sold to Oracle, to now resurrecting it as Facebook.&#8221; SEE ALSO: The Early Hours of Facebook HQ on IPO Day Would Facebook would be following in the footsteps of the building&#8217;s previous tenant 10 years from now and moving out? &#8220;My guess is only if they need a bigger building,&#8221; Rosenweig said. The number of developers growing up today would only help grow companies like Facebook in the future, he added. &#8220;It&#8217;s an absolutely wonderful time to be in Silicon Valley &#8230; A lot more of these companies are generating revenue. A lot more are generating profits. That wasn&#8217;t the case 10 years ago.&#8221; More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, ipo, YahooFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/rosenwig-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/rosenwig-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Losing Its Monopoly on Users [REPORT]</title>
      <description>As Facebook becomes a public company Friday, trading at $42 per share and valued at $116.6 billion, new data suggests the company&#8217;s social media dominance may be in decline. Twice as many Facebook members use at least one additional social networking site in 2012 as they did at this time last year. Just released comScore data obtained by Mylife.com shows that 40% of Facebook users are on another social network, compared to 20% at this time last year. The most popular secondary social network for Facebook users is Twitter, which is used by 23.8% of Facebook account holders. LinkedIn comes in a close second, with 20.3% of Facebook users registered for the professional network. Some 16.6% of Facebook users are on Google+, 13.9% are on Tumblr and 12.% are on Pinterest. The data also shows that nearly 100% of Facebook users use an external email server. Yahoo Mail is most popular, used by 44% of Facebook members; followed by Gmail, used by 35.5%; and AOL Mail, used by 12.6%. Who&#8217;s Catching Up to Facebook? Facebook&#8217;s rapid purchase of Instagram for $1 billion, snatching the photo editing app our from under Twitter&#8217;s nose, proved that Mark Zuckerberg understands the importance of a mobile-first approach to social networking. In an amendment to the company&#8217;s S-1 filings April 23, Facebook explained that it made the acquisition &#8220;to enable users to increase their levels of mobile engagement and photo sharing.&#8221; Another recent comScore report found that Tagged was America&#8217;s most engaged social network. Its users visit 18 times a month, less than Facebook&#8217;s 36 average visits per month. However, each visit lasts 12.1 minutes, which is longer than Facebook&#8217;s average 10.9 minute visits. Does the rise of other social networks means Facebook is on the decline or is the social media powerhouse here to stay? Do mobile first networks have an advantage over Facebook? Sound off in the comments. BONUS: 10 Things Facebook Should Spend Its IPO Money On 1. Mobile Mobile isn't just the future for Facebook &#8212; it's the present, with many studies showing Facebook leads all other social apps by far. However, the Facebook experience on smartphones and tablets is lacking. The service's iPad app doesn't even include Timeline, and the Android app doesn't scale well for tablets. Facebook clearly needs to build out its mobile platform, adding both functionality and marrying the experience better with every smartphone it has a presence on. That, and start monetizing it.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-comscore-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-comscore-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Losing Its Monopoly on Users [REPORT]</title>
      <description>As Facebook becomes a public company Friday, trading at $42 per share and valued at $116.6 billion, new data suggests the company&#8217;s social media dominance may be in decline. Twice as many Facebook members use at least one additional social networking site in 2012 as they did at this time last year. Just released comScore data obtained by Mylife.com shows that 40% of Facebook users are on another social network, compared to 20% at this time last year. The most popular secondary social network for Facebook users is Twitter, which is used by 23.8% of Facebook account holders. LinkedIn comes in a close second, with 20.3% of Facebook users registered for the professional network. Some 16.6% of Facebook users are on Google+, 13.9% are on Tumblr and 12.% are on Pinterest. The data also shows that nearly 100% of Facebook users use an external email server. Yahoo Mail is most popular, used by 44% of Facebook members; followed by Gmail, used by 35.5%; and AOL Mail, used by 12.6%. Who&#8217;s Catching Up to Facebook? Facebook&#8217;s rapid purchase of Instagram for $1 billion, snatching the photo editing app our from under Twitter&#8217;s nose, proved that Mark Zuckerberg understands the importance of a mobile-first approach to social networking. In an amendment to the company&#8217;s S-1 filings April 23, Facebook explained that it made the acquisition &#8220;to enable users to increase their levels of mobile engagement and photo sharing.&#8221; Another recent comScore report found that Tagged was America&#8217;s most engaged social network. Its users visit 18 times a month, less than Facebook&#8217;s 36 average visits per month. However, each visit lasts 12.1 minutes, which is longer than Facebook&#8217;s average 10.9 minute visits. Does the rise of other social networks means Facebook is on the decline or is the social media powerhouse here to stay? Do mobile first networks have an advantage over Facebook? Sound off in the comments. BONUS: 10 Things Facebook Should Spend Its IPO Money On 1. Mobile Mobile isn't just the future for Facebook &#8212; it's the present, with many studies showing Facebook leads all other social apps by far. However, the Facebook experience on smartphones and tablets is lacking. The service's iPad app doesn't even include Timeline, and the Android app doesn't scale well for tablets. Facebook clearly needs to build out its mobile platform, adding both functionality and marrying the experience better with every smartphone it has a presence on. That, and start monetizing it.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-comscore-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-comscore-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Reasons Why the Facebook IPO Fell Flat</title>
      <description>Well, that was anticlimactic. After all the hullabaloo about Facebook&#8217;s IPO, this is how it ends, with a mere $0.23 jump in share price? That kind of movement is what happens after Procter &amp; Gamble announces a more absorbent type of Pampers. Yet it shouldn&#8217;t be all that surprising that Facebook&#8217;s opening day on the NASDAQ had all the excitement of a Matlock rerun. While no one knows exactly why Facebook landed with such a thud, there are a handful of good reasons that the company got poked by Wall Street. Among them: 1. It Was Priced Just Right Call it the Goldilocks theory. This assumes that a lot of thought went into that $38 price, and the reason that the stock didn&#8217;t double is that the esteemed underwriters at Morgan Stanley, J.P. Morgan Chase and Goldman Sachs did their job right and accurately priced the stock. That, however, depends on what your definition of &#8220;accurately&#8221; is. James Brau, professor of finance at Brigham Young University, says that over the past 40 years of IPOs, the average first-day pop is 18%. So, if Facebook was looking to perform along those lines, it should have priced its shares in the low 30s. In addition, underwriters don&#8217;t aim for a flat performance on the first day because of a practice called &#8220;leaving money on the table,&#8221; which rewards institutional investors for getting on board. Though that looks like a kickback of sorts, Brau says there&#8217;s no clear-cut reason why IPOs always factor leaving money on the table in. &#8220;There are at least 50 different academic studies I know of that that have 35 different theories,&#8221; Brau says. One popular theory is that it&#8217;s a way of rewarding such investors for honesty. The argument goes like this: During an IPO road show, the company and bankers are looking for an accurate read on what investors plan to spend. If such investors didn&#8217;t know that they would be rewarded for telling the truth, then they would intentionally low-ball the amount they intend to buy at. If an institutional investor thought that the stock should be worth $10, say, then they might say they&#8217;ll spend $8 to enjoy the ride on the opening day. 2. It&#8217;s NASDAQ&#8217;s Fault NASDAQ bungled Facebook&#8217;s opening, not offering the stock until 11:30 am EST, 30 minutes later than planned. In addition, the stock exchange didn&#8217;t finish filling orders for the stock for about two-and-a-half hours. Kevin Pleines, an equity market analyst with Birinyi Associates, says the resulting confusion didn&#8217;t do Facebook&#8217;s stock any favors. &#8220;It threw it a bit of a curve,&#8221; Pleines says. &#8220;It may have held it back a little bit.&#8221; 3. Investors Are Wary of Social Media Stocks The media may love the story of the scrappy twenty-something building a $100 billion company from his Harvard dorm, but investors have seen this movie before. Of the 19 social media IPOs of 2011, 82.4% were trading below their opening-day prices by year&#8217;s end. Only three were above their opening price. 4. It&#8217;s GM&#8217;s Fault General Motors landed a well-timed blow against Facebook on Tuesday, when reports surfaced that the company planned to pull all its advertising from Facebook because it wasn&#8217;t working. Though no other advertisers appear to have followed suit, the move didn&#8217;t reassure investors who were already nervous about Facebook&#8217;s first-quarter revenue slide and its admitted inability to transition its ad model to mobile. 5. It&#8217;s Overvalued Facebook&#8217;s valuation of $100 billion-plus, like most valuations, is based on expectations of future performance. In Facebook&#8217;s case, these expectations are wildly optimistic. After all, at its current valuation, Facebook is worth more than McDonald&#8217;s. The Golden Arches, with restaurants all over the globe, close-to 100% brand recognition and a proven business model, posted $27 billion in revenues last year and a $5.5 billion profit. Facebook made $1 billion on $3.7 billion in revenues. Not surprisingly, 79% of investors in a recent Bloomberg poll thought that Facebook was overvalued. As Espen Robak, the president of Pluris Valuation Advisors, told The Atlantic, Facebook&#8217;s valuation is plausible because of the company&#8217;s tremendous reach. But, as Robak told the publication, no one knows how Facebook will be able to monetize that reach. &#8220;Think of it this way,&#8221; said Robak. &#8220;Google has a pretty standard price-earnings ratio right now &#8212; around 15 to 20. That&#8217;s where Facebook will ultimately have to get. They need vastly larger profit. &#8220;How many more ads can they sell? Four times more in the next year? I don&#8217;t think so. They have to get revenues from somewhere else.&#8221; Robak thinks that maybe &#8212; just maybe &#8212; Facebook will be able to tap into its user data to provide a new solution to advertisers. 6. Retail Investors Are Taking a Wait-And-See Attitude If you&#8217;re an average joe, you probably couldn&#8217;t get your hands on a share of pre-IPO Facebook stock. So, the logical thing to do is wait until the hype dies down and then assess the stock. Pleines&#8217; research shows that waiting at least a month is a good idea. According to Pleines&#8217; data, no matter how well the recent social media IPOs did on opening day, their stocks were still down &#8212; across the board &#8212; after the first month. But it&#8217;s not just a social media thing: We may not remember it well, but Google&#8217;s stock languished for a month or more after its debut. &#8220;While Google did not trade lower in its first month of trading, it did trade back its original open price of $100,&#8221; Pleines wrote in a recent note to clients. &#8220;But after that it never looked back, trading as high as $196 over the next three months.&#8221; In other words, the question of Facebook&#8217;s true value wasn&#8217;t answered on Friday. In all likelihood, we won&#8217;t know for a few months at least. What do you think Facebook is really worth? Let us know in the comments. SEE ALSO: Facebook&#8217;s IPO Roadshow: We Give You the Video Highlights Image courtesy of iStockphoto, EdStock More About: Facebook, facebook ipoFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-ipo-flat-reasons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-ipo-flat-reasons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons QR Code Marketing Is Broken (and How to Fix It)</title>
      <description>Dan Wilkerson is a social media project manager at LunaMetrics, a Google Analytics certified partner that also specializes in social media, search engine optimization, and PPC. You can follow him on Twitter @notdanwilkerson or at @LunaMetrics. For years now, marketers, businesses and, well, everybody have touted QR codes as the next big thing. That&#8217;s largely because QR codes offered a glimmer of the future, a way to bring physical interactions into the much more malleable (and trackable) digital space. But despite the overwhelming push by marketers to stick a QR code on anything they are publishing, marketing, and eating (yes, eating), there&#8217;s been increasing skepticism about its real-world use. The skeptics have some pretty good facts on their side. In 2011, a Forrester Research study pegged adoption of QR codes by U.S. adults at 5%, up from a meager 1% the year before. Then, in April, a Temkin Group study found that only 24% of U.S. adults are using these codes, a statistic that is a little encouraging but still tepid. These figures coupled with some serious dismal marketing anecdotes might make you think QR codes are ineffective, and you&#8217;d be right. Here&#8217;s why. 1. Worthless Content From a marketing perspective, QR codes offer obvious value and they&#8217;re easy to create, cheap, trackable, and open up a world of possibilities for consumer-product interactions. From the consumer side, however, the value is not as clear. Scanning a code is cumbersome and costs the consumer time and effort. Plus, its value is unknown. Worse still, 90% of the time it&#8217;s a link to a website not optimized for mobile. Now you&#8217;ve frustrated the consumer and wasted their time, which creates negative sentiment. This is why you must provide the consumer with a valuable reason to scan the code. Consider a significant discount, the first chapters of a book, a free drink at the bar, even a space-specific YouTube video. What you don&#8217;t do is use it as a link to your website or Facebook page. That will only annoy your customer. 2. Consumer Awareness The biggest problem that QR codes have is that consumers consistently have demonstrated that they don&#8217;t have a clue what they are. An ArchRival study of college students found that out of 534 of our nation&#8217;s best and brightest, 78.5% didn&#8217;t know how to scan a QR code. Marketers are so excited by the potential and intrigued by the concept that they&#8217;ve totally forgotten that consumers are not marketers. Marketers watch ads, click sponsored tweets, and yes, scan QR codes because they have a natural curiosity and passion for brand marketing. But the average consumer needs a marketer to outline to them what action it is they are supposed to take. When it comes to a QR code that means tell them what it is. Consider including a simple list of instructions with a recommended app spelling out how to use the code itself. If you coupled that with compelling content, you&#8217;ll introduce consumers to the concept of QR codes as well as how to take advantage of them. 3. Value as a Medium The other consideration that is often ignored is the intrinsic value of the code as a piece of media itself. More often than not, QR codes are used as a simple link to a company website or specific landing page. The thought process being that it saves users the trouble of entering a complicated URL. This would be true if all a user had to do was wave their device over the code. However, let&#8217;s consider the user&#8217;s side of things. In order to scan a barcode, a user has to: 1. Get out their phone; 2. Unlock their phone; 3. Boot the app; 4. Get the code in focus and scan it. This is assuming they already have an app that scans barcodes. For most users, it&#8217;s faster to just search Google for whatever the code is giving them a shortcut to. To address this issue, use a six-to-ten-second guide as a rule of thumb for determining usefulness. If you&#8217;re not saving your target at least that much time, scrap the code. 4. Location, Location, Location Location is another important consideration. QR codes are showing up everywhere, on everything, with seemingly zero thought about context. (For some interesting use-cases, check out WTFQRCODES.) For instance, besides being impossible to scan, QR codes on highway billboards are dangerous and waste valuable visual real estate. A shortened URL, especially one created with a vanity URL shortener, would be easier and more effective. Likewise, QR codes on company vehicles don&#8217;t really make much of an impact either, and those are mostly going to be parked directly outside of your business anyways. And QR codes on subway ads are useless too since there&#8217;s no data connection for users to load your page. The examples only get stranger from there. The best solution is to walk through your implementation in a real-world scenario to make sure it will actually be useable. 5. Aesthetics QR codes are ugly. Worse still, they&#8217;re indistinguishable from codes used for industrial purposes. So a code on a product can be misinterpreted as a tracking barcode instead of a marketing outlet. The good news is they don&#8217;t have to be ugly. With a little Photoshop, you can round off the corners of the ugly blocks, giving a sleek feel to the code, and it will still scan. You can also generate codes with up to 30% redundancy, meaning you can remove 30% of the code and instead put your company logo or information about what it unlocks directly into the code. Use a URL shortener to make the code even more manageable and trackable in tools like Google Analytics. There are some limitations to this, since certain parts of codes are integral and can&#8217;t be deleted, but it really opens up the creative opportunities for some awesome design work. Better still, you can delete portions of the code to shape it into something else entirely, like a letter in your brand name, or even your logo. The gist is you can make it pretty. So now you know why your QR codes are a failure and how to fix them. Of course, many are quick to point out that NFC devices are on the horizon and will probably displace these ugly little blocks. Given the encouraging uptick in adoption and the low cost of implementation of QR, however, there&#8217;s reason to believe that they will become much more relevant before NFC is fully implemented. The guidelines above will help you make the most out of that opportunity. 1. Flying QR Codes "Look! In the sky! It's a bird! It's a plane! It's the dumbest thing I've ever seen in my life!"Click here to view this gallery.Do you think QR codes have a place in a marketing plan? Share your thoughts with us in the comments below. More About: contributor, features, mobile marketing, online marketing, QR CodesFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/reasons-qr-codes-are-broken/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/reasons-qr-codes-are-broken/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Reasons QR Code Marketing Is Broken (and How to Fix It)</title>
      <description>Dan Wilkerson is a social media project manager at LunaMetrics, a Google Analytics certified partner that also specializes in social media, search engine optimization, and PPC. You can follow him on Twitter @notdanwilkerson or at @LunaMetrics. For years now, marketers, businesses and, well, everybody have touted QR codes as the next big thing. That&#8217;s largely because QR codes offered a glimmer of the future, a way to bring physical interactions into the much more malleable (and trackable) digital space. But despite the overwhelming push by marketers to stick a QR code on anything they are publishing, marketing, and eating (yes, eating), there&#8217;s been increasing skepticism about its real-world use. The skeptics have some pretty good facts on their side. In 2011, a Forrester Research study pegged adoption of QR codes by U.S. adults at 5%, up from a meager 1% the year before. Then, in April, a Temkin Group study found that only 24% of U.S. adults are using these codes, a statistic that is a little encouraging but still tepid. These figures coupled with some serious dismal marketing anecdotes might make you think QR codes are ineffective, and you&#8217;d be right. Here&#8217;s why. 1. Worthless Content From a marketing perspective, QR codes offer obvious value and they&#8217;re easy to create, cheap, trackable, and open up a world of possibilities for consumer-product interactions. From the consumer side, however, the value is not as clear. Scanning a code is cumbersome and costs the consumer time and effort. Plus, its value is unknown. Worse still, 90% of the time it&#8217;s a link to a website not optimized for mobile. Now you&#8217;ve frustrated the consumer and wasted their time, which creates negative sentiment. This is why you must provide the consumer with a valuable reason to scan the code. Consider a significant discount, the first chapters of a book, a free drink at the bar, even a space-specific YouTube video. What you don&#8217;t do is use it as a link to your website or Facebook page. That will only annoy your customer. 2. Consumer Awareness The biggest problem that QR codes have is that consumers consistently have demonstrated that they don&#8217;t have a clue what they are. An ArchRival study of college students found that out of 534 of our nation&#8217;s best and brightest, 78.5% didn&#8217;t know how to scan a QR code. Marketers are so excited by the potential and intrigued by the concept that they&#8217;ve totally forgotten that consumers are not marketers. Marketers watch ads, click sponsored tweets, and yes, scan QR codes because they have a natural curiosity and passion for brand marketing. But the average consumer needs a marketer to outline to them what action it is they are supposed to take. When it comes to a QR code that means tell them what it is. Consider including a simple list of instructions with a recommended app spelling out how to use the code itself. If you coupled that with compelling content, you&#8217;ll introduce consumers to the concept of QR codes as well as how to take advantage of them. 3. Value as a Medium The other consideration that is often ignored is the intrinsic value of the code as a piece of media itself. More often than not, QR codes are used as a simple link to a company website or specific landing page. The thought process being that it saves users the trouble of entering a complicated URL. This would be true if all a user had to do was wave their device over the code. However, let&#8217;s consider the user&#8217;s side of things. In order to scan a barcode, a user has to: 1. Get out their phone; 2. Unlock their phone; 3. Boot the app; 4. Get the code in focus and scan it. This is assuming they already have an app that scans barcodes. For most users, it&#8217;s faster to just search Google for whatever the code is giving them a shortcut to. To address this issue, use a six-to-ten-second guide as a rule of thumb for determining usefulness. If you&#8217;re not saving your target at least that much time, scrap the code. 4. Location, Location, Location Location is another important consideration. QR codes are showing up everywhere, on everything, with seemingly zero thought about context. (For some interesting use-cases, check out WTFQRCODES.) For instance, besides being impossible to scan, QR codes on highway billboards are dangerous and waste valuable visual real estate. A shortened URL, especially one created with a vanity URL shortener, would be easier and more effective. Likewise, QR codes on company vehicles don&#8217;t really make much of an impact either, and those are mostly going to be parked directly outside of your business anyways. And QR codes on subway ads are useless too since there&#8217;s no data connection for users to load your page. The examples only get stranger from there. The best solution is to walk through your implementation in a real-world scenario to make sure it will actually be useable. 5. Aesthetics QR codes are ugly. Worse still, they&#8217;re indistinguishable from codes used for industrial purposes. So a code on a product can be misinterpreted as a tracking barcode instead of a marketing outlet. The good news is they don&#8217;t have to be ugly. With a little Photoshop, you can round off the corners of the ugly blocks, giving a sleek feel to the code, and it will still scan. You can also generate codes with up to 30% redundancy, meaning you can remove 30% of the code and instead put your company logo or information about what it unlocks directly into the code. Use a URL shortener to make the code even more manageable and trackable in tools like Google Analytics. There are some limitations to this, since certain parts of codes are integral and can&#8217;t be deleted, but it really opens up the creative opportunities for some awesome design work. Better still, you can delete portions of the code to shape it into something else entirely, like a letter in your brand name, or even your logo. The gist is you can make it pretty. So now you know why your QR codes are a failure and how to fix them. Of course, many are quick to point out that NFC devices are on the horizon and will probably displace these ugly little blocks. Given the encouraging uptick in adoption and the low cost of implementation of QR, however, there&#8217;s reason to believe that they will become much more relevant before NFC is fully implemented. The guidelines above will help you make the most out of that opportunity. 1. Flying QR Codes "Look! In the sky! It's a bird! It's a plane! It's the dumbest thing I've ever seen in my life!"Click here to view this gallery.Do you think QR codes have a place in a marketing plan? Share your thoughts with us in the comments below. More About: contributor, features, mobile marketing, online marketing, QR CodesFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/reasons-qr-codes-are-broken/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/reasons-qr-codes-are-broken/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Yahoo Killed Flickr and Lost the Internet [Exclusive]</title>
      <description>Web startups are made out of two things: people and code. The people make the code, and the code makes the people rich. Code is like a poem; it has to follow certain structural requirements, and yet out of that structure can come art. But code is art that does something. It is the assembly of something brand new from nothing but an idea. More &#187;</description>
      <link>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</link>
      <guid>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Facebook Snatching Defeat from the Jaws of Victory?</title>
      <description>For years, the conventional wisdom on Facebook has gone something like this: the social network is an unstoppable juggernaut. It commands more and more of our attention and, ultimately, our ad dollars. Mark Zuckerberg is an unimpeachable genius. His product is too popular to ever be replaced. But there&#8217;s something wrong with that picture &#8212; and it&#8217;s not just that anything labeled &#8220;conventional wisdom&#8221; is almost certain to be wrong in the long term. It&#8217;s that Mark Zuckerberg himself would likely disagree vehemently with all of it. Everything we&#8217;ve heard about Zuckerberg&#8217;s behavior inside Facebook says he lives in constant fear of catastrophic and irreversible decline. And with good reason. He is well versed in Silicon Valley lore &#8212; which insists, in the words of Andy Grove&#8217;s famous book, that only the paranoid survive. Things change fast around here; today&#8217;s Apple could be tomorrow&#8217;s Yahoo, and vice versa. Remember, this is the CEO who made a very sudden, very jumpy $1 billion purchase of Instagram &#8212; which may have been about to sell itself to Twitter &#8212; without consulting his board. This is the company that made an exhaustive list of 35 things that could kill it in its S-1 filing with the SEC. More to the point, it went back and amended that filing several times to make the picture it painted even bleaker. One of Facebook&#8217;s biggest problems is mobile: it hasn&#8217;t figured out how to make money from its smartphone-based users, so the more of us that check Facebook from our phones, the worse for Facebook&#8217;s average revenue per user (or ARPU, a very important financial metric for consumer companies). Guess what, the S-1 amendments said. More people are using our mobile apps than we thought. And our revenue is going down. SEE ALSO: Facebook: Here are the 35 Things That Could Kill Our Company But that doesn&#8217;t matter, right? Users love using Facebook. Advertisers are dazzled by its possibilities. And the coming IPO frenzy will erase all doubts and set the company on its way, just as it did with Google. That&#8217;s what I thought &#8212; until about a week ago. But a number of factors have made me less than certain on all three counts. Let&#8217;s take them one by one: Users love Facebook. Or more accurately, they did &#8212; until Timeline came along. As poll after poll has shown, Timeline is one of the least popular features Facebook has ever rolled out. The most recent study I could find, conducted in late March by online security firm Webroot, found that an astonishing 88% of users are &#8220;concerned&#8221; about the privacy implications of all the data that Timeline sucks in. Facebook announced Monday that the last few Timeline holdouts would be automatically switched over as of May 21. That&#8217;s it &#8212; no more old profiles. Timeline is mandatory. Will users learn to love the new layout? Or will they conclude that Facebook is getting too damn complicated &#8212; and spend their valuable time elsewhere? Ironically, the one place they can go for a Timeline-free Facebook experience: Facebook&#8217;s mobile apps. Down you go, ARPU. Advertisers are dazzled by its possibilities. Make that some advertisers. The ad world was buzzing Tuesday about the news that General Motors, one of the three biggest advertisers in the U.S., is pulling all of its Facebook ads, citing a lack of effectiveness. Granted, GM&#8217;s $10 million spend was a drop in the bucket of its $1.8 billion ad budget, not to mention Facebook&#8217;s $4 billion revenues. GM&#8217;s rivals, Ford and Chrysler, plan to stick around. But it does raise a troubling point: the effectiveness of Facebook ads is still unproven. The social network is a place we go to hang out with friends, and ads in that context can often seem a little creepy and intrusive, no matter the high standards Facebook holds them to. Retailers are already shutting Facebook stores. And there are plenty of reasons to doubt whether Facebook ads can ever be as effective as Google&#8217;s AdSense &#8212; which has the benefit of being in a better context, ie. when we&#8217;re actually looking for stuff. So could GM be ahead of the curve, rather than a stodgy old outlier? Either way, it&#8217;s about the last question Zuckerberg would want you to be debating in the last days before his big IPO. The IPO will erase all doubts, just as it did with Google. Ever since Facebook first revealed its surprisingly low IPO share price of $28 to $35, I felt the company was, to use sales parlance, pumping the buying temperature. If the price jumps on day one, that&#8217;s all you&#8217;ll read about in the headlines. Indeed, when Facebook recently bumped its initial share price, it seemed of a piece with that strategy &#8212; slowly raise the price of jumping in, and everyone will want on board before too long. But then came the report that the IPO roadshow was less successful than Facebook had hoped. Zuckerberg&#8217;s choice of clothing for the big investment bank meetings became the story &#8212; an admirable riposte to Wall Street, yes, but not likely to win you many friends among slicked-back fund managers. And IPOs are a risky business. For every Google, there is a Groupon. The Chicago-based daily deals site was all the rage before it went public, even turning down a generous buyout offer from Google. Then, a few months after IPO, its shares plummeted to below the initial asking price. The daily deals space? Not so hot right now. That&#8217;s the problem with pre-IPO hype. You have to deliver on it, and fast. If Facebook ends up worth less than the $100 billion valuation we&#8217;ve all been discussing for months &#8212; heck, even if it doesn&#8217;t jump much beyond that &#8212; the whispering campaign will start. The cracks in its facade &#8212; Timeline, ad engagement, the fact that nearly all of its growth is coming from outside the U.S. &#8212; will become more obvious. And Zuckerberg&#8217;s worst fears may well be realized. What&#8217;s your take on Facebook&#8217;s status? Let us know in the comments. 1. Competitors "Users increasingly engage with competing products." Image courtesy of Flickr, MukumburaClick here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, General Motors, groupon, Opinion, Zuckerberg</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/facebook-ipo-defeat-victory/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/facebook-ipo-defeat-victory/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook IPO: Here&#8217;s Why You Shouldn&#8217;t Buy Yet</title>
      <description>Everyone&#8217;s talking about the Facebook IPO &#8212; and for good reason. Facebook is currently valued at around $100 billion, though it made less than $4 billion in revenue last year. Still, if the social network with more than 901 million users plays its cards right, it could be the world&#8217;s first $1 trillion company by 2014. The Facebook IPO is slated for Friday. New investors can potentially buy around 421 million shares of Facebook stock at $38 a pop. The big question is: should you buy Facebook stock while it&#8217;s hot? Multiple financial experts told us no &#8212; at $38 per share, the stock is overpriced. Former NYU Stern School of Business finance professor Kenneth Froewiss believes adding Facebook to a portfolio early on is risky for experienced pros and investment amateurs alike. It&#8217;s like playing the lottery, he says. &#8220;Even for those individuals with above-average net worth, purchasing shares at an IPO, especially a &#8216;hot&#8217; one that has been widely hyped, is rarely a good idea,&#8221; Froewiss says. &#8220;Might someone on occasion reap a tremendous windfall by doing so? Yes, but then again, on occasion someone wins the lottery. That does not make the lottery a great investment in general.&#8221; Factors that can affect Facebook stock are legion. The current excitement about the company&#8217;s stock market debut doesn&#8217;t guarantee long-term interest or success. &#8220;In my experience this stock and its IPO has seen more enthusiasm than any other I have seen over my 40 years of investment experience,&#8221; says Lewis Altfest, Ph.D., CEO of NYC-based Altfest Personal Wealth Management. The social network&#8217;s success or failure may lie in its ability to conquer the mobile space &#8212; which is growing faster than the company is adapting. Post-IPO, Facebook will have to ramp up its mobile ads to push profits. Facebook reported $205 million in the first quarter of 2012 &#8212; down from December&#8217;s high of $302 million. &#8220;Revenue in the last quarter was actually off quarter-to-quarter,&#8221; Altfest says. &#8220;They have to deliver revenue growth. Over a longer period, they will have to deliver earnings.&#8221; Altfest advises average consumers wait at least six months. He warns in the following weeks after the IPO, demand will cause stock prices to stay high, which is normal for an IPO debut. But it may eventually fall. &#8220;Even in stocks there are laws of gravity,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Take a deep breath and come back in six months.&#8221; Joshua Gans, professor at University at Toronto&#8217;s School of Management, advises people do nothing instead. &#8220;All of the uncertainties surrounding Facebook will not get resolved in the six months,&#8221; Gans says. &#8220;We&#8217;ll only know a decade from now whether it has a permanent place in the economy like Microsoft.&#8221; Microsoft traded at $22 per share at its IPO in 1986. Now it&#8217;s $61 per share. SEE ALSO: Facebook Meets Wall Street: How the IPO Stacks Up With Tech&#8217;s Titans &#8220;There&#8217;s a scenario where Facebook clearly becomes the next Google or Apple, but there&#8217;s also a scenario where it simply does not and it ends up more like Yahoo,&#8221; Gans tells Mashable. A safer alternative is buying into an index fund such as the S&amp;P 500 instead of buying Facebook shares directly. Owners of an index fund can reap the benefits of the entire stock index doing well &#8212; without suffering sudden losses when a company&#8217;s stock tanks. &#8220;Facebook will eventually be included in that, and it will be part of an index fund and you can buy it that way,&#8221; Gans says. Some financial experts see Facebook as a good buy now. Lubos Pastor, finance professor at the University of Chicago, says it&#8217;s financially beneficial for investors to buy shares at IPO price. After the price of public shares rise, users have &#8220;historically earned subpar returns&#8221;, he says. &#8220;However, the poor average post-IPO returns have been driven mostly by small firms, so it is quite possible that a large firm like Facebook will turn out to be a good investment,&#8221; Pastor says. What do you hope Facebook has in store after going public? Sound off in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, blackred, Infographic by Statista More About: Business, Facebook, facebook ipo, Social MediaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/facebook-ipo-buy-or-not/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/facebook-ipo-buy-or-not/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Imp Connects Your Home Devices to the Internet</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;ve ever dreamed about connecting your entire home to the Internet &#8212; so that appliances could start by themselves or you could receive text message alerts to maintain housekeeping &#8212; it looks like your dream is ready to become a reality. Electric Imp calls itself &#8220;a complete solution to connect devices to the internet, wirelessly.&#8221; The start-up, founded by former team members of the iPhone and Gmail, came out with a line of programmable, pluggable network cards that look like SD cards &#8212; except each Imp card actually contains an embedded processor and WiFi antenna. By installing these Imp cards to your devices using circuit boards (which Imp sells), you&#8217;re able to connect them to an &#8220;Imp cloud,&#8221; through which you can control them and program them. Automated homes aren&#8217;t exactly new &#8212; for example, a student at UC Berkeley recently automated his dorm room. But Imp promises to be much easier than other current &#8220;Internet of Things&#8221; products. For one, Imp cards don&#8217;t require you to hook up all your devices to a central controller. Rather, you can control all your gadgets and appliances individually online. For example, as seen in the video, one theoretical application is having Christmas lights that flicker off when the water in your tree stand gets to below a certain level. Or, perhaps you could program water sprinklers to turn on when you notice that the weather is especially hot. Users can set up commands to program their Imp cards using a drag and drop graphical interface on Imp&#8217;s web-based software. We haven&#8217;t tested it ourselves yet, but anything drag and drop is fairly intuitive and presumably easy. In addition, as Gizmodo reported, connecting the Imp cards to your home or office WiFi network is not much trouble at all: &#8220;Getting the Imps to work with a WiFi network is super easy, and ingeniously done. You input the WiFi network name and password into the Electric Imp your phone (iOS or Android) and the app flashes light at a photosensor on the Imp card, using pulses of light to transfer the login. It. Was. Slick.&#8221; The varying sizes of Imp&#8217;s circuit boards makes it simple to install them in different-sized gadgets and appliances, and Imp is currently in talks with other manufacturers to make future devices Imp-ready right off the assembly line. Developer previews for the Imp card are slated for June. The cards will initially sell for $25, and it&#8217;s expected that a basic circuit board will sell for about $10. Would you be interesting in wiring your home with Imp cards? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail courtesy of LodgeNet More About: internet of things, lifestyle, technology</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/electric-imp/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/electric-imp/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
