<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The flipping point</title>
      <description>When people say, "The tipping point," they often misunderstand the concept in Malcolm's book. They're actually talking about the flipping point. The tipping point is the sum total of many individuals buzzing about something. But for an individual to start buzzing, something has to change in that person's mind. Something flips from boredom or ignorance to excitement or anger. It starts when the story of a brand or a person or a store or an experience flips in your head and it goes from good to bad, or from ignored to beloved. The flipping point doesn't represent the sum of public conversations, it's the outcome of an activated internal conversation. It's easy to wish and hope for your project to tip, for it to magically become the hot thing. But that won't happen if you can't seduce and entrance an individual and then another. Before the tipping point, someone has to flip. And then someone else. And then a hundred more someones. We resist incremental improvement in our offerings and our stories because it just doesn't seem likely that one good interaction or one tiny alteration can possibly lead to a significant amount of flipping. And we're right&#8212;it won't. The flipping point (for an individual) is almost always achieved after a consistent series of almost invisible actions that create a brand new whole. And the reason it's so difficult? Because you're operating on faith. You need to invest and apparently overinvest (time and money and effort) until you see the results. And most of your competition (lucky for you) give up long before they reach the point where it pays off.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/the-flipping-point.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/the-flipping-point.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How 7 Top Brands Are Using Facebook&#8217;s New Ad Tools</title>
      <description>The Facebook Marketing Series is presented by Webtrends, enabling real-time relevance across digital channels for more effective marketing. Learn about the new consumer dynamic in our webinar with Altimeter Group. View now. On Leap Day 2012, Facebook gathered all its marketing executives in New York City for a coming-out party of sorts for a slew of new ad products. To people outside the industry, the promise of new initiatives might appear a bit on the dull side. But for advertisers, anything that Facebook does for advertising is of interest. Among the products Facebook introduced were Premium on Facebook, Reach Generator, Offers and Logged Out ads. The company also asked brands to embrace a paradigm shift from advertising to &#8220;Stories,&#8221; Facebook&#8217;s preferred term for brand-related messages. Since that time, a few big brands have experimented with the new tools. Here are a few examples or, if you prefer, Stories. Is there a standout brand campaign that you enjoy? Let us know in the comments. 1. Premium Ads: Tide The Procter &amp; Gamble detergent brand Tide turned a PR event into advertising in March. The program started when officials used Tide to clean up the chemical residue on a racetrack after a big fire at a NASCAR course in March. Tide&#8217;s program, which included outreach on Twitter, public relations and search, also leaned heavily on Facebook&#8217;s Premium ad products. Tide used the format to draw attention to the brand&#8217;s role in the incident. As with other Premium ads, the status update went out across the network, but it was especially focused on Tide fans and friends of Tide fans. If you or your friend interacted with the Tide brand page, then you might have seen it in your News Feed. Tide&#8217;s initial post was a link to a Business Insider article about the event, which included photos of people hauling boxes of Tide to the scene. Tide used Premium on Facebook to blast the post and further boosted engagement with a post asking fans to fill in a caption for a photo of workers cleaning up the mess. Facebook says that the NASCAR ad had a 62% higher engagement rate than previous ads the brand has run. The premium buy also got the post in front of 1 million people, more than doubling the usual reach of a Tide post. (Tide has close to 2.8 million fans, but only a portion see a post at any given time.) Sarah Pasquinucci, external relations manager for North American fabric at P&amp;G, says the brand has experimented with other premium posts but can&#8217;t say how they perform versus standard Facebook ads. &#8220;We&#8217;re always looking to reach consumers in the right place at the right time in the right way,&#8221; she adds. 2. Premium and Logged Out Ads: Subway Subway used the new Premium and Logged Out ads on Facebook to highlight spokesman Blake Griffin. The sandwich chain ran an update that featured a video with fun outtakes of Blake on the log-out screen and used the Page ad unit to promote it. People interacted nearly 1 million times with the ads and video, which hit nearly 500,000 plays. As a result, Subway&#8217;s reach during the week-long campaign increased tenfold. Tony Pace, the SVP and CMO of the Subway Franchisee Advertising Trust Fund, says the brand takes a &#8220;test and learn&#8221; approach to Facebook advertising and jumped at the opportunity to do something different. Pace says the Stories, in this case, performed better than his expectations and were a good way to reward fans without alienating consumers. &#8220;People who are really into our brand are surprisingly happy to get lots of content from us,&#8221; he says. &#8220;This was a good way of rewarding folks that want to see a lot from us.&#8221; Pace says the Logged Out ad did well because the content was compelling. &#8220;If people are logging out, they probably don&#8217;t want to spend more time there unless it&#8217;s something really interesting,&#8221; he says. 3. Reach Generator: Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s and Dr Pepper The Unilever-owned ice cream brand Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s took advantage of Reach Generator to make sure all its fans got the latest updates. Reach Generator is designed to expose fans to updates they might not otherwise see. As Facebook noted back in February, the typical post on a brand site only reaches 16% of fans. With Reach Generator, Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s hit 98% of fans during a 28-day period and saw twice as much engagement. Another early adopter of Reach Generator, Dr Pepper, hit 83% of its 8 million U.S. fans over a 28-day period and saw a 140% jump in &#8220;People Talking About This&#8221; (PTAT) with the tool. 4. Offers: Einstein Bros. Bagels and Chili&#8217;s Einstein Bros. availed itself of another new Facebook ad product, Offers, with a buy-one-get-one offer from Feb. 29 through March 4. Some 32,000 people (out of 690,000 fans) took the chain up on its offer, and Einstein Bros. logged a &#8220;significant&#8221; spike in PTAT during that time. Offers is an evolution of &#8220;Check-in Deals,&#8221; a mobile-only Facebook product. With Offers, consumers can redeem the deals on their desktop or mobile, since they live on a Brand Page. Meanwhile, Chili&#8217;s ran an Offers promotion offering a free appetizer or dessert with an entree purchase for three days. The chain, which has 1.9 million Facebook fans, saw 433,773 people claim the offer &#8212; around 20% of whom were on Facebook. About 30% of redemptions also came from Facebook, which is about three times higher than average. 5. Logged Out Ads: Ford Ford tried its hand at a Logged Out ad on March 20. The video, a Mustang commercial, got more than 1 million plays and boosted Ford&#8217;s PTAT that day by 180%. Thomais Zaremba, digital marketing manager at Ford, says she wasn&#8217;t sure that people would stick around to watch an ad when they were logging out, but many did. &#8220;I was surprised,&#8221; she says, noting that the number of people who log out every day &#8212; 40 million &#8212; was way more than she thought. Zaremba hasn&#8217;t tried another Logged Out ad since, but plans to. Says Zaremba: &#8220;We&#8217;re always interested in testing new spaces.&#8221; Series presented by Webtrends The Facebook Marketing Series is presented by Webtrends. Have consumers taken control of brands? Do friends, reviews and social spheres have more influence than brand marketing? Customers are changing the dynamic of the sales funnel. Find out from the experts at Webtrends and Altimeter Group how a measurement strategy can deliver relevant messaging for greater conversions and revenue. Watch our webinar now. More About: facebook ads, Facebook brand pages, Facebook Marketing Series, features, mashable</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/brands-facebook-ad-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/brands-facebook-ad-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP MCA - YouTube</title>
      <description>scottm: 2nded: RT @Broughton500: i'm not a fan of Coldplay (quite the opposite) but this is a beautiful tribute to Adam Yauch http://t.co/ckkFNRBG</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/scottm/statuses/198728348560654336</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/scottm/statuses/198728348560654336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here&#8217;s the Best Time to Share on Pinterest</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;re doing most of your sharing on Pinterest from the office, you&#8217;re doing it wrong. The best time to share things on Pinterest is Saturday morning, according to data from Bitly, the URL shortening service. Hilary Mason, Bitly&#8217;s chief scientist, revealed the nugget during a talk at Mashable Connect in Orlando, Fla. Bitly keeps track of clicks on the links created by its users, and where they&#8217;re coming from, aggregating the data to create actionable information. In addition to the Pinterest factoid, Mason said a story&#8217;s half-life &#8212; the time it takes to receive half the clicks it will ever get &#8212; lasts 2.8 hours on Twitter, 3.1 on Facebook, 7 hours on YouTube and &#8220;longer&#8221; on StumbleUpon and Tumblr. Bitly also looks at usage of devices. Bitly says it&#8217;s seeing 12% of clicks coming from mobile devices. While all device use rises and falls based on wake/sleep patterns, most phones, tablets and computers follow similar patterns of use each day. One notable exception: Game consoles, which jump on Thursdays, something Mason attributed to college students using them to mainly watch YouTube videos. SEE ALSO: Behind the Design of Bit.ly&#8217;s Iconic Pufferfish Typically, content follows a &#8220;burst and decay&#8221; pattern, with a huge spike of clicks early in its life cycle that drops off rapidly, then slowly. The pattern can repeat as the content spreads to other networks or gets shared by influencers. As an example, Mason cited the recent video ad campaign by PopChips that had actor Ashton Kutcher in brown face, imitating an Indian man. The videos received several spikes of interest, including after a few prominent people suggested the ad was racist and again when the offensive ad was taken down. Bitly&#8217;s data also reveals which social networks command the most attention online. Based on preliminary research into what people share and what people click on, Bitly ranked the most attention-getting social networks: Facebook YouTube Soundcloud LinkedIn Twitter Blogspot Tumblr Vimeo Reddit For content creators, Mason had some pointed advice for better engaging an audience: create content with a community in mind. &#8220;Creating things that people want to tie into their identity is the best way to make them spread,&#8221; she said. Do you agree with Bitly&#8217;s conclusion that Pinterest is best used Saturday morning, or its ranked list of social networks? Have your say in the comments. BONUS: The Top Photos From Pinterest 1. Hands Picture by photographer Jorge Rimblas, posted via Edris Kim on Pinterest.Click here to view this gallery. Mashable Connect Sponsors Buddy Media is the social enterprise software of choice for eight of the world&#8217;s top ten global advertisers, empowering them to build and maintain relationships with their consumers in a connections-based world. The Buddy Media social marketing suite helps brands build powerful connections globally with its scalable, secure architecture and data-driven customer insights from initial point of contact through point of purchase. For more information, visit http://www.buddymedia.com. AT&amp;T is bringing it all together for our customers, from revolutionary smartphones to next-generation TV services and sophisticated solutions for multi-national businesses. For more than a century, we have consistently provided innovative, reliable, high-quality products and services and excellent customer care. For more, visit http://www.att.com. Barnes &amp; Noble College Marketing (BNCM) helps brands thrive on campus. It is a division of Barnes &amp; Noble College Booksellers, LLC., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Barnes &amp; Noble, Inc. that operates more than 640 college bookstores across the country, serving more than 4.7 million students and faculty members. BNCM has the on-campus access and student understanding to deliver superior marketing programs for its brand partners. BNCM&#8217;s capabilities include: experiential and event marketing; product sampling, sweepstakes and promotions; digital marketing (social, email, web); on-campus advertising and postering; and programs targeting freshmen, graduates, alumni and athletic event fans. Visit www.bncollegemarketing.com. Hiscox specializes in tailored insurance coverage for a range of professional services firms in industries like IT, marketing, consulting and more. Hiscox Insurance Company Inc. has been protecting clients for over 100 years and is rated &#8216;A&#8217; (Excellent) for financial strength by A.M. Best. We offer professional liability insurance, general liability insurance and other policies direct, either online or over the phone, with customized coverage starting from just $22.50/month. Visit hiscoxusa.com/smallbiz for a fast, free quote now. Webtrends powers digital marketing success. Webtrends is at the forefront of real-time digital marketing relevance and customer experience management through unified customer intelligence. Our industry-leading analytics across mobile, social and web enables marketers to optimize campaigns, maximize customer lifetime value and deliver highly relevant digital brand experiences in real-time. Webtrends dramatically improve digital marketing results for more than 3,500 global brands including, in EMEA and internationally, Lloyds Banking Group, Barclays, HSBC, ASOS, Orange, T-Mobile, Microsoft, BMW, Toyota, Play.com, AllSaints, The Telegraph, and many more. www.webtrends.com Definition 6 is a Unified Marketing Agency that creates brand experiences that unite brands and people in motion. Through imagination, innovation and insight, we execute ideas that deliver continued value across all brand interactions. For more information, please visit http://www.definition6.com. The Adobe Digital Marketing Suite is an integrated set of applications which allow businesses to gather customer insight and optimize advertising, conversion and retention efforts as well as the creation and distribution of content. For example, using the Suite, marketers can identify the most effective marketing strategies and ad placements as well as create relevant, personalized and consistent customer experiences across digital marketing channels, such as onsite, display, e-mail, social, video and mobile. The Suite enables marketers to automatically adjust to customer interactions and better maximize marketing ROI, which leads to a positive impact the bottom line. http://www.adobe.com/solutions/digital-marketing.html The leading resource for human resource and business leaders to explore and discuss the latest workforce and workplace trends including social innovation&#8212;providing the in-depth research and insights needed to adapt and take advantage of what&#8217;s next. www.shrm.org More About: bit.ly, Facebook, pinterest, social networks, stumbleupon, tumblr, Twitter, YouTubeFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/best-time-pinterest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/05/best-time-pinterest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#8217;s America&#8217;s Most Engaging Social Network? You&#8217;ll Be Surprised</title>
      <description>Try to guess America&#8217;s most engaging social network. Facebook? Wrong. Twitter? Wrong. Pinterest? Wrong again. According to comScore&#8216;s most recent social networking data, from the month of March, the San Francisco based site Tagged engages users like no other service. It was the only site to finish in the top two in both of comScore&#8217;s engagement metrics. Tagged users visited an average of 18 times each during March according to ComScore, second only to Facebook&#8217;s average of 36 visits per vistor. And each time a Tagged user visited the site, he or she stuck around for 12.1 minutes &#8212; which trailed only Tumblr (14.7 minutes) and beat out Facebook (10.9 minutes). Tagged co-founder and CEO Greg Tseng says he&#8217;s happy about ComScore&#8217;s March data, but that his company has been among America&#8217;s most engaging social networks for about a year now. The secret to Tagged&#8217;s success? A pivot Tseng and co-founder Johann Schleier-Smith made around the beginning of 2008. The longtime friends started Tagged in 2004, at the time angling it to be a Facebook-like social network for high schoolers. Eventually, however, Facebook expanded beyond a closed college network and allowed anyone over the age of 12 to join. &#8220;We took a hard look and decided we weren&#8217;t going to win,&#8221; Tseng says. &#8220;But we had found out a lot of our users were actually using Tagged to meet new people, so that led us to pivot into a new space called &#8216;social discovery,&#8217; where people use sites to make new social relationships.&#8221; As opposed to sites like Facebook, where people primarily organize and maintain relationships established offline, Tagged functions mostly as a portal to meet new people online for romance or simply friendship. The site&#8217;s algorithms encourage users to connect based on shared interests, tastes and hobbies. Tseng says Tagged&#8217;s 10 million core monthly active users form an average of 100 million new connections per month. The site has been profitable since 2008, and over the past year tripled its staff to a current count of more than 170. With social discovery as a whole seen by many to be a rising tide, Tseng believes Tagged&#8217;s success will continue to grow. &#8220;If I look out at the next five or 10 years, I really see social discovery as big as social networking &#8212; in some sense I think you can think of social discovery as the engine for social networking,&#8221; he says, referencing Dunbar&#8217;s number, which theorizes that humans can maintain an average of 150 connections at a time. &#8220;Facebook is the place where you maintain your current 150,&#8221; he says. &#8220;And Tagged will be the place where you refresh that 150.&#8221; Do you think social discovery is the next big thing? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci More About: social discovery, Social Media, social networking, tagged</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/tagged-most-engaging/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/tagged-most-engaging/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I unlocked the Madonna's MDNA: Super Bowl XLVI Halftime sticker on @GetGlue! #MDNA, @SNFonNBC http://t.co/0DDHWK0E</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a3.twimg.com/profile_images/1749375531/original-derekeb_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/derekeb"&gt;Derek Baird&lt;/a&gt;: I unlocked the Madonna's MDNA: Super Bowl XLVI Halftime sticker on &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/GetGlue" target="_blank"&gt;@GetGlue&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=MDNA" target="_blank"&gt;#MDNA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/SNFonNBC" target="_blank"&gt;@SNFonNBC&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://t.co/0DDHWK0E" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/0DDHWK0E&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/derekeb/status/166329572017713152"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://m.getglue.com/derekeb/stickers/madonna/madonnas_mdna_super_bowl_xlvi_halftime?ref=derekeb&amp;s=ts</link>
      <guid>http://m.getglue.com/derekeb/stickers/madonna/madonnas_mdna_super_bowl_xlvi_halftime?ref=derekeb&amp;s=ts</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gotye&#8217;s &#8216;Somebody That I Used To Know&#8217; Cracks YouTube&#8217;s All-Time Top 30</title>
      <description>Global smash hit &#8220;Somebody That I Used to Know&#8221; is closing in on 200 million YouTube views this week, making it one of the most-viewed clips ever on the 7-year-old platform. With 198 million views, the video from Belgian-Australian singer Gotye featuring Kimbra ranks No. 29, behind the likes of Justin Bieber, Jennifer Lopez, Lady Gaga, other artists and a few non-music videos (such as &#8220;Charlie bit my finger&#8220;). &#8220;Somebody That I Used to Know&#8221; &#8212; about memories of past relationships and breakups &#8212; premiered in July 2011 and swiftly became a chart-topper in Australia before soaring to No. 1 in more than a dozen countries. Only last month did the song claim the coveted crown on Billboards Hot 100 charts in the U.S. The achievement came after American Idol, Glee and The Voice aired covers of the song (watch them below) in April. That month Gotye and Kimbra also performed the track on Saturday Night Live. The single had already been high on the U.S. chart, but the mainstream appearances budged it to the top. Many Americans credit a band called Walk Off the Earth for putting the song on their radar. In January, Walk Off the Earth uploaded to YouTube a &#8220;Somebody That I Used to Know&#8221; cover, which now has 103 million views. SEE ALSO: &#8216;Eat It Don&#8217;t Tweet It&#8217; Music Video Mocks Food Pornographers [VIDEO] Flip through this gallery to hear the original, versions mentioned above, parodies and covers from YouTube heavyweights Ingrid Michaelson, PS22 Chorus, Boyce Avenue, Freak Morice, Peter Hollens and more. Original by Gotye featuring Kimbra Click here to view this gallery. More About: celebrities, Entertainment, Music, trending, viral videos, YouTubeFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/gotye-somebody-that-i-used-to-know-200-million-youtube-views/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/gotye-somebody-that-i-used-to-know-200-million-youtube-views/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MasterCard Unveils PayPass Wallet Services, A New Way To Pay</title>
      <description>MasterCard announced PayPass Wallet Services Monday, a new global offering that makes it easier and faster for customers to make purchases in stores and online, by allowing those purchases to be made with a single click or tap. &#8220;We think of MasterCard&#8217;s mission as using technology to make payments safer, simpler, smarter and this is just one of the ways we&#8217;re progressing against that mission&#8221; Ed McLaughlin, chief emerging payments office, MasterCard told Mashable. &#8220;We realize that when it comes to payments, no single wallet will rule them all. PayPass Wallet Services simplifies the shopping experience while providing flexibility and choice to merchants, banks and consumers,&#8221; says McLaughlin. PayPass Wallet Services has three components: PayPass Acceptance Network, PayPass Wallet and PayPass API which together are designed to streamline your shopping experience no matter how you shop. PayPass Acceptance Network: The PayPass acceptance network includes both online and contactless payments, and gives merchants a consistent way to accept electronics payments across multiple channels. NFC payments can be made in-store by tapping your mobile phone, and a new PayPass online element lets you check out at a retailer by clicking a PayPass button &#8212; automatically providing your shipping and payment information to a retailer without having to fill that information out each time you pay. PayPass Wallet: PayPass wallet enables banks, merchants and partners to white label their own wallets. Consumers can store payment and shipping information in one secure place including American Express, Discover, Visa and other branded credit, debit and prepaid cards. PayPass API: The PayPass API allows partners to connect their own wallets into the PayPass network, and lets those partners user MasterCard&#8217;s check-out, fraud detection and authentication services to allow their customers to make purchases wherever PayPass is accepted. MasterCard will make PayPass Wallet Services available to partners in the third quarter of 2012, initially in the U.S., Canada, U.K. and Australia later including other countries. MasterCard&#8217;s first partners for the project include big names like American Airlines and Barnes &amp; Noble. American will be integrating the PayPass Wallet into its mobile application, and Barnes &amp; Noble will be including the PayPass online checkout button on its website. &#8220;Consumers are at a pivotal point now where smartphone adoption has exploded and well over 50 percent of Americans own one,&#8221; says Marc Parish, vice president of retention and loyalty marketing for Barnes &amp; Noble. &#8220;The technology that will allow customers to make mobile payments at the point of sale has already begun to make a different, and Barnes &amp; Noble is proud to be leading retail in this technology shift&#8221; Other partners include Jagex, JB Hi-Fi, MLB Advanced Media (MLB.com), Newegg, Runningshoes.com, TigerDirect.com and Wine Enthusiast Companies. MasterCard is also working with financial institutions such as Citibank, Fifth Third Bank, and National Bank of Canada. A number of technology partners are also already on board. &#8220;MasterCard&#8217;s PayPass Wallet Services has the potential to streamline the payment process for consumers, whether they&#8217;re online or offline.&#8221; Mark Hung Research Director, Wireless at Garner told Mashable. &#8220;The open nature of the PayPass Wallet looks promising: besides allowing competitors&#8217; offerings to reside in the wallet (e.g., Visa, Amex, and Discover), the PayPass API allows other digital wallets to connect to MasterCard&#8217;s acceptance network as well,&#8221; says Hung. &#8220;It will be interesting to see when the full product will be launched, as well as the breadth of its partners that will be supporting this new initiative.&#8221; What do you think about MasterCard&#8217;s new PayPass Wallet services? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: mastercard, mobile paymentFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/mastercard-paypass/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/mastercard-paypass/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Play About To Pass 15 Billion Downloads? Pssht! It Did That Weeks Ago</title>
      <description>Way to blow your own horn, Google. Yesterday a newspaper in the UK, the Independent, ran a short item about how Google was about to reach an app milestone &#8212; 15 billion apps downloaded. So we reached out to Google to ask about this&#8230; and guess what? It already happened. A Google spokesperson, Gina Weakley Johnson, tells us the milestone was passed &#8220;a few weeks ago.&#8221; The last number that Google released with more public declaration was 11 billion downloads, when the store was still called the Android Market, which it announced during its Q4 2011 earnings in January. In April, when Google reported its Q1 2012 earnings, it didn&#8217;t mention downloads on Google Play, the newly-rebranded store. Apple reached 15 billion downloads in July 2011, and the most recent number for Apple is 25 billion downloads in March 2012. Doing the basic math, that roughly means that Google is seeing about 1 billion downloads of Android apps per month, while Apple is seeing about 1.25 billion app downloads per month. So there is still a gap in aggregated downloads between the two platforms, despite that fact that Google has nearly caught up with Apple in terms of total number of apps: Currently Google Play has some 500,000 apps, while Apple has 600,000 apps in its app store. There are other areas of disparity, it seems: Up to the end of January 2012, analyst Horace Dediu notes, Google has paid developers $320 million compared to $4 billion from Apple. On the other hand, there seems to be other evidence pointing to the fact that Apple&#8217;s download rate is slowing down: Fiksu, for example claims that Apple&#8217;s app download rate fell by 30 percent in March. For Google, the drive to have high volumes of app downloads is two-fold: it demonstrates to developers that this is an active and used platform, so that they continue developing for it. And it gives Google a bigger inventory from which it can potentially make more from advertising, which is the company&#8217;s real money spinner. Data revealed in the Oracle v. Google trial over Java patents last week pointed to how Google&#8217;s Android effort was money-losing throughout 2010. Documents in the same case also showed that Google projected that it would make a profit on its mobile effort in 2011 and beyond &#8212; although we don&#8217;t have updated figures from Google that testify to whether that has been the case or not. But those records also indicated that the vast majority of that revenue will be coming from advertising, with small but growing percentages also coming from app sales. In 2011, Google projected it would make $492.5 million in ads on Android with only $14.5 million in app sales. For 2012, Google projected $804.3 million in ad sales with only $35.9 million from app revenue. Figures from those documents also showed that Google expected a loss of $113 million in 2010 from Android and that it expected to have profits of $64 million in 2011; $248 million in 2012; and $548 in 2013.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/07/google-play-about-to-pass-15-billion-downloads-pssht-it-did-that-weeks-ago/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/07/google-play-about-to-pass-15-billion-downloads-pssht-it-did-that-weeks-ago/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing Gives Amputees Custom-Designed Legs [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>A San Francisco company called Bespoke Innovations is using 3D printing and modeling technology to give prosthetic limbs new life as custom-designed, wearable pieces of art. Here&#8217;s how it works: First, the company 3D scans both customers&#8217; natural and prosthetic legs. A 3D computer model is created, maintaining as body symmetry as possible between the two limbs. Then, the client begins directing the customization process of his or her new fairing. (A fairing is the prosthetic covering for an artificial limb.) Customers can choose from a range of patterns, templates and materials, and Bespoke is preparing to introduce an online tool for more experimentation. Finally, the specially-designed end result is produced using 3D printing technology. SEE ALSO: You&#8217;ll Download Physical Objects Sooner Than You Think, Thanks to Kids Like These It all adds up, Bespoke says, to prosthetic limbs that actually reflect their users&#8217; personalities and tastes. The custom fairings cost between $4,000 and $5,000, according to the company&#8217;s website. &#8220;We are working on this guy from Israel right now,&#8221; co-founder Scott Summit tells Bloomberg Businessweek. &#8220;We are designing a Porsche 911 aesthetic for him. It&#8217;s a really classic design with clean lines and timeless detailing. We just did three other legs for three guys in Germany, all to reflect their very distinct personalities.&#8221; Do you think this is a cool use of 3D printing technology? Where else do you want to see 3D printing tech applied for innovation? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy Bespoke Innovations More About: 3d printingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/3d-printing-gives-amputees-custom-designed-legs-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/3d-printing-gives-amputees-custom-designed-legs-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
