<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think Hockey '09: The Secret to Winning Puck Battles</title>
      <description>&lt;a href=http://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.cbc.ca/video/%23/Sports/CBC%27s%2520Hockey%2520Night%2520in%2520Canada/Think%2520Hockey/ID%3D1237582316&amp;source=video&amp;vgc=rss&amp;usg=AFQjCNHnwCoqV449QSCCGkSKpyCuLuxTmQ&gt;&lt;img src=http://2.gvt0.com/ThumbnailServer2?app=vss&amp;contentid=a6ba3e909dbd5216&amp;offsetms=1&amp;itag=w160&amp;hl=en&amp;sigh=__tnEi2mplI4diJ9yEOu5GxzmBqjk= width=160 height=120&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;John Stevens demonstrates the secret to winning puck battles. &lt;p/&gt;&lt;div style="color:green;font-size:smaller;"&gt;cbc.ca&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.cbc.ca/video/#/Sports/CBC's%20Hockey%20Night%20in%20Canada/Think%20Hockey/ID=1237582316</link>
      <guid>http://www.cbc.ca/video/#/Sports/CBC's%20Hockey%20Night%20in%20Canada/Think%20Hockey/ID=1237582316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brought Your Kids to Work? Send Us Your Photos</title>
      <description>Technology Editor Pete Pachal gives his son a tour of Mashable HQClick here to view this gallery. Thursday is &#8220;Take Our Daughters and Sons to Work&#8221; day. And at Mashable we celebrated in style: with puppies. Several Mashable sons and daughters join us for coloring, puppy playing, snacks, and plenty of pictures taken. And it wouldn&#8217;t be a day at Mashable without scooters or Nerf guns (or some combination of both). Our New York City headquarters is a very dog-friendly office, but it was great fun having the kids and the dogs together. Let&#8217;s just say there was a lot of running around &#8212; and there are going to be some pooped pups tonight. Check out our photos below to see what we got up to. Did you or your colleagues bring kids to your office? We&#8217;d love to see your photos! Tweet your office pics to @mashablehq with the hashtag #MashKids or you can submit through the photo widget at the bottom of the post. More About: community, mashableFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/take-your-kids-to-work-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/take-your-kids-to-work-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Tests Smaller Version of &#8216;Trending Articles&#8217; in Newsfeed</title>
      <description>Facebook is testing a smaller, less invasive version of the &#8220;Trending Articles&#8221; insert that began appearing in some users&#8217; Newsfeeds earlier this month. Now, instead of displaying a vertical block of stories &#8212; between three and six, from the screenshots we saw before &#8212; users see just one headline, accompanied by a thumbnail, source, introductory text and the name(s) of the friend(s) who have already read it. To see more Trending Articles, users can click an arrow in the upper-right hand corner. The change will undoubtedly result in less engagement but it does economize space in the Newsfeed. Less engagement may be bad for publishers and for Facebook, but most users will be pleased with the change, we expect. David Holley, who sent over the first screenshot below, called the original Trending Articles insert &#8220;obnoxious as hell&#8221; because it occupied so much space in his Newsfeed. He also pointed out those articles weren&#8217;t really trending &#8212; only one of his friends had read each of the articles highlighted in the section. Trending Articles before: Trending Articles now: It&#8217;s worth noting that Trending Articles only displays stories from social reading apps and websites that have integrated with Facebook&#8217;s Open Graph, a source familiar with the matter tells us. Publications that haven&#8217;t integrated will qualify for the additional exposure. Are you a fan of the new version of Trending Articles? Let us know in the comments. Front page thumbnail courtesy of iStockphoto, -Oxford- More About: Facebook, Media, trending articles</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/facebook-trending-articles-test/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/facebook-trending-articles-test/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get more likes on Facebook</title>
      <description>More tanks. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should You Combine Your Personal and Business Social Media Identities?</title>
      <description>The Social Media for Business Leaders Series is presented by by The Awareness Social Marketing Hub, the leading social media marketing software for marketers to publish, manage, measure and engage across all their social channels. Request a free trial here. If you&#8217;ve just got a new job and are now contemplating tagging your Twitter account with a shout-out to your new employer, consider the case of @Phonedog_Noah, a.k.a. Noah Kravitz. Kravitz, a blogger, chose his Twitter handle when he was employed by cellphone news and review website PhoneDog. But Kravitz left in 2010, and last year PhoneDog sued him for $340,000 for the 17,000 followers he kept after he left the position. It&#8217;s unclear if PhoneDog will get its way &#8212; a California court in February denied Kravitz&#8217;s motion to dismiss. Meanwhile, Kravitz told Mashable last December that he &#8220;would do it differently now.&#8221; While Kravitz&#8217;s case provides a clear reason to avoid meshing your professional and personal worlds via social media, it&#8217;s not always a bad idea. Consider, for instance, Aliza Licht, a blogger with 385,000 followers. But it&#8217;s a fair bet that few of those followers know who Licht is. That&#8217;s because she goes by the nom de plume (or maybe &#8220;nom de Twitter&#8221;) DKNY PR GIRL. Licht, who started the account in 2009, is credited with spawning imitators in the fashion industry, including Oscar de la Renta&#8217;s @OscarPRGirl. Licht, who had worked in PR at Donna Karan since 1998, kept her identity secret until last October, when she revealed it in the YouTube video below: Licht&#8217;s Twitter handle is sort of an amalgam of advertising and social media. DKNY PR GIRL is a character, as she freely acknowledges, and thus can be thought of as no different than Flo from Progressive Insurance. Yet, the Twitter account became popular because of Licht&#8217;s personality and her nearly 24/7 commitment to updating on the platform. &#8220;The account started anonymously because DKNY PR GIRL was envisioned as a &#8216;character,&#8217; hence the sketch,&#8221; Licht says, referring to the illustration on DKNY PR GIRL&#8217;s Twitter page. &#8220;But as soon as I started tweeting, I realized that Twitter was a conversation, and the voice needed to be consistent. Naturally, people started to realize DKNY PR GIRL was in fact, one girl, but yet it never really mattered &#8216;who&#8217; the person was &#8212; it was the personality and content that mattered. As time passed and the account became more popular, we realized the anonymity didn&#8217;t matter anymore either.&#8221; Despite her seamless integration with the persona, Licht has no illusions that she has any claims on DKNY PR GIRL. &#8220;DKNY PR GIRL has become synonymous with my name, however it belongs to the company,&#8221; Licht says. Another social media star who melded his online identity with his employer is Richard Binhammer, the director of strategic corporate communications, social media and corporate reputation management at Dell, who is better known by his Twitter handle @RichardatDell. &#8220;Dating back to 2006, when I first started work in the social media field for Dell, the linking of company and personal name to create @RichardatDell has made it clear, transparent and obvious who I am and that I represent Dell,&#8221; Binhammer says. &#8220;Obviously this was both a personal and professional decision that works for me, while also meeting Dell policies around disclosure and transparency.&#8221; As Binhammer notes, if you intended to be a public spokesman for a company in 2006, then it made sense to put your company&#8217;s moniker in your social profiles. However, in 2012, the standard practice is to be yourself and build a social media following, and then act as a hired gun for the companies you represent. A good example of this is Ben Rudolph, Microsoft&#8217;s chief evangelist, who goes by his given name on Twitter, though he uses @BenThePCGuy as his Twitter handle. Also, there are two fields of identification on Twitter: Your name and your handle; you can change both to whatever you would like (as long as it&#8217;s not already taken). Consider the case of Ben Smith, the former Politico editor, who joined BuzzFeed in January. When Smith left Politico, he changed his Twitter handle from @BenPolitico to @BuzzFeedBen, yet his name still appears as &#8220;Ben Smith.&#8221; He has kept his handle intertwined with his company, but remains his own personal brand on Twitter &#8212; as a result, the switch from one publication to another is seamless. The advantages of keeping your name are obvious. For Rudolph, if he ever left Microsoft, he would still be Ben Rudolph on Twitter, even if he became (for example) @BenTheSamsungGuy. &#8220;The way the workforce is changing, it&#8217;s probably a given that you&#8217;ll have to leave that employer at some point,&#8221; says Alexis Grant, a journalist and social media strategist. &#8220;I suppose you could technically change the handle when you do, but for branding purposes, it&#8217;s better to have a handle that&#8217;s all you, so you can keep it forever.&#8221; As the PhoneDog lawsuit demonstrates, that&#8217;s a major consideration. If your profession involves communicating with the public, then your Twitter following will be taken into account by future employers. Apparently, that&#8217;s worth quite a lot: the $340,000 lawsuit nets out to $2.50 per follower in Kravitz&#8217;s Twitter audience. Series presented by The Awareness Social Marketing Hub The Social Media for Business Leaders Series is presented by The Awareness Social Marketing Hub, the leading social media marketing software for marketers to publish, manage, measure and engage across all their social channels. The Awareness Social Marketing Hub is leveraged by companies of all sizes including MLB, American Cancer Society, and Starwood Hotels. Request a free trial here. Download a complimentary whitepaper from Awareness: Actionable Social Analytics: From Social Media Metrics to Business Insights. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, EricHood More About: features, mashable, Social Media, social media for business leaders series, social media marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/personal-professional-social-identity/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/personal-professional-social-identity/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Local Businesses Should Stop Focusing On Their Facebook Page</title>
      <description>All too often we see local businesses spend way too much time crafting their Facebook pages and trying to force engagement. Even if it does happen, it&amp;#039;s not the best way to spend their social media time. They have an advantage over big brands: touching the people.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/jd-rucker/493388/why-local-businesses-should-stop-focusing-their-facebook-page</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/jd-rucker/493388/why-local-businesses-should-stop-focusing-their-facebook-page</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children, Puppies and Webby Awards, Oh My!</title>
      <description>Mashable is very excited to be nominated for a Webby Award in the business category! Today is the final day to vote and we&#8217;d greatly appreciate your help. VOTE HERE FOR MASHABLEWhile we focus on staying on top of the latest business news, we also know how to have fun! Today, Mashable took part in &#8220;Take Your Child to Work Day.&#8221; In addition to our young guests, we also encouraged our staff to bring in their dogs. While our visitors were in the office, we enlisted them to help us in our Webby Award campaign. We&#8217;d love it if you could take a minute and vote for Mashable here. Thank you! More About: 2012 Webby AwardsFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/mashable-webby-award-vote-last-chance/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/mashable-webby-award-vote-last-chance/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Translate Draws 200 Million Users Each Month</title>
      <description>Google announced on Thursday that its popular language translator service Google Translate now boasts 200 million monthly users, and many of which are accessing it outside the U.S. and via mobile devices. The news &#8212; which comes just two days before Google Translate&#8217;s sixth anniversary &#8212; shows an increasing desire to communicate with others regardless of language, not only online but offline too. Google Translate allows users to access and interpret webpages on servers thousands of miles away. The company started to offer a basic translating service in 2001 for eight languages and later expanded to more languages in 2003. SEE ALSO: 20 Strange and Hilarious Google Street View Sightings &#8220;But at that time our system was too slow to run as a practical service&#8212;it took us 40 hours and 1,000 machines to translate 1,000 sentences,&#8221; Franz Och, principal scientist at Google, said in a company statement. &#8220;So we focused on speed, and a year later our system could translate a sentence in under a second, and with better quality. In early 2006, we rolled out our first languages: Chinese, then Arabic.&#8221; The service now offers 64 languages, including many with a small web presence such as Bengali, Yiddish and Esperanto. In addition to the 200 million monthly active users on translate.google.com, consumers are also accessing Google Translate in other ways, such as via Chrome, mobile apps and YouTube. More consumers are also accessing Google Translate while traveling than ever before. The company reported its mobile traffic to the service has more than quadrupled year over year. Meanwhile, more than 92% of traffic from Google Translate comes from international users outside the U.S. Usage is so high that it translates the equivalent of 1 million books each day. &#8220;We imagine a future where anyone in the world can consume and share any information, no matter what language it&#8217;s in, and no matter where it pops up,&#8221; Och said. &#8220;We already provide translation for webpages on the fly as you browse in Chrome, text in mobile photos, YouTube video captions, and speech-to-speech &#8220;conversation mode&#8221; on smartphones. We want to knock down the language barrier wherever it trips people up, and we can&#8217;t wait to see what the next six years will bring.&#8221; Thumbnail via iStockphoto, franckreporter. BONUS: 10 Places You&#8217;re Not Allowed to See on Google Maps 1. The Royal Residence, The Netherlands The Royal Palace of Amsterdam in the Netherlands -- called Koninklijk Paleis Amsterdam -- joins a long list of places blurred on Google Maps related to the Dutch royal family, including the Royal Stables and another residence called Huis ten Bosch.Click here to view this gallery. More About: apps, chrome, Google, google translate, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/google-translate-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/google-translate-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ditto&#8217;s 3D Virtual Fitting Tech Makes It Possible to Try on Glasses Online</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Ditto Quick Pitch: Try on and purchase glasses online. Genius Idea: 3D virtual fitting technology lets you determine whether a pair of glasses flatters your face before making a purchase. Some things are easier to buy online than others. A refill of your favorite toothpaste is a no-brainer. A t-shirt from a brand you buy from frequently will probably fit you. Sunglasses? You might have an idea that square frames flatter your face better than round ones, but it&#8217;s largely going to be a crapshoot. Ditto, a retail startup launching Thursday, has developed 3D virtual fitting technology designed to help you find glasses that suit your face. By recording a short video on your webcam, you can create a 3D version of yourself, or &#8220;Ditto,&#8221; that you can then use to try on different pairs of glasses with a scrollable, 180-degree view. You can even put together side-by-side snapshots of yourself in different glasses and connect to Facebook to get advice from your friends before making a purchase. The imaging isn&#8217;t perfect, but it&#8217;s better than many of the other virtual fitting applications we&#8217;ve seen. &#8220;Eyewear has the lowest online penetration of any retail category; just 2.9% of all eyewear is bought online,&#8221; Ditto cofounder and CEO Kate Endress says of her desire to enter the category. &#8220;People don&#8217;t want to buy eyewear online because the fit is too difficult. We&#8217;re solving that problem, letting people shop for glasses from designers they already love.&#8221; The Mountainview, CA-based startup raised $3 million in a funding round led by August Capital in September. Series Supported by Microsoft BizSpark The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark, a startup program that gives you three-year access to the latest Microsoft development tools, as well as connecting you to a nationwide network of investors and incubators. There are no upfront costs, so if your business is privately owned, less than three years old, and generates less than U.S.$1 million in annual revenue, you can sign up today. More About: Ditto, eyewear, retailFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/ditto/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/ditto/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 3.3.2 (and WordPress 3.4 Beta 3)</title>
      <description>WordPress 3.3.2 is available now and is a security update for all previous versions. Three external libraries included in WordPress received security updates: Plupload (version 1.5.4), which WordPress uses for uploading media. SWFUpload, which WordPress previously used for uploading media, and may still be in use by plugins. SWFObject, which WordPress previously used to embed Flash content, and may still be in use by plugins and themes. Thanks to Neal Poole and Nathan Partlan for responsibly disclosing the bugs in Plupload and SWFUpload, and Szymon Gruszecki for a separate bug in SWFUpload. WordPress 3.3.2 also addresses: Limited privilege escalation where a site administrator could deactivate network-wide plugins when running a WordPress network under particular circumstances, disclosed by Jon Cave of our WordPress core security team, and Adam Backstrom. Cross-site scripting vulnerability when making URLs clickable, by Jon Cave. Cross-site scripting vulnerabilities in redirects after posting comments in older browsers, and when filtering URLs. Thanks to Mauro Gentile for responsibly disclosing these issues to the security team. These issues were fixed by the WordPress core security team. Five other bugs were also fixed in version 3.3.2. Consult the change log for more details. Download WordPress 3.3.2 or update now from the Dashboard &#8594; Updates menu in your site&#8217;s admin area. WordPress 3.4 Beta 3 also available Our development of WordPress 3.4 development continues. Today we are proud to release Beta 3 for testing. Nearly 90 changes have been made since Beta 2, released 9 days ago. (We are aiming for a beta every week.) This is still beta software, so we don&#8217;t recommend that you use it on production sites. But if you&#8217;re a plugin developer, a theme developer, or a site administrator, you should be running this on your test environments and reporting any bugs you find. (See the known issues here.) If you&#8217;re a WordPress user who wants to open your presents early, take advantage of WordPress&#8217;s famous 5-minute install and spin up a secondary test site. Let us know what you think! Version 3.4 Beta 3 includes all of the fixes included in version 3.3.2. Download WordPress 3.4 Beta 3 or use the WordPress Beta Tester plugin.</description>
      <link>http://wordpress.org/news/2012/04/wordpress-3-3-2/</link>
      <guid>http://wordpress.org/news/2012/04/wordpress-3-3-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Samsung Stage &#8216;Wake Up&#8217; Protest at Australian Apple Store? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>A group of black-clad protesters recently gathered outside an Apple store in Sydney, Australia, and shouted &#8212; apparently to the customers inside &#8212; to &#8220;wake up.&#8221; The stunt is suspected to be part of Samsung&#8216;s campaign to promote the Galaxy S III smartphone. Captured on video by blogger Nate &#8220;Blunty&#8221; Burr and reported by Australian site Mumbrella, a black bus with the words &#8220;Wake Up&#8221; prominently painted on the side pulled up beside the Apple Store. Several people wearing black clothing then exited the bus, held up signs that also said &#8220;Wake Up&#8221; and, to hammer the point home, they all shouted the phrase over and over again. In addition, the words &#8220;Wake Up&#8221; are visible beneath the huge swimming pool of Bondi Icebergs, a well-known sports club in Sydney. There are also reports of several billboards with the words in Australia, and this Australian website, clearly tied to the same campaign, is counting down to &#8230; something. SEE ALSO: Behold the Exynos 4 Quad, the Chip That Powers Samsung Galaxy S3 The site is reportedly registered to New Dialogue, a company that is now known as the Sydney ad agency Tongue. Given the rate of the countdown, it should run to zero in about nine days. That matches up closely with an event Samsung has planned May 3 in London. Samsung has already teased the Galaxy S III (although not directly) with another ad, which implied that iPhone owners are sheep. Samsung took a similar tack with its Super Bowl ad to promote the Samsung Galaxy Note. What do you think of this new campaign? Is it clever or off the mark? Share your thoughts in the comments. More About: apple, Apple Store, samsung, Samsung Galaxy S III</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/wake-up-samsung/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/wake-up-samsung/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
