<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Money and Mobile Commerce [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;re over the age of 20, you&#8217;ve likely used a credit card, counted change and maybe even written a check. But is all that about to change? Mobile payment hasn&#8217;t become the de facto method of financial transactions just yet, but it is projected to overtake those archaic checkbooks and bank notes you&#8217;ve been lugging around. Three types of mobile payments dominate the marketplace today: m-commerce (uses a mobile browser and online wallets), m-payments (uses mobile apps), and m-wallets (replaces your entire wallet). Furthermore, consumers can access several forms of transaction on their mobile devices, including scannable barcodes, mobile coupons and self-checkout. SEE ALSO: How PayPal Here Stacks Up Against Other Mobile Payment Options But are consumers ready to wholeheartedly adopt the latest in mobile payment technology? Adults who are unbanked, for instance, may face a barrier to mobile transactions &#8212; there are currently 17 million unbanked adults in the U.S. But many smartphone users welcome the convenience of mobile payments (87% in the UK), while others worry about the privacy factor (79% in Asia). Still, 49% of consumers in the U.S. found shopping on a smartphone awkward. Then again, many people found paper checks awkward and credit cards confusing the first time around. Where do you fall in the mobile payment debate? What kinds of transactions do you handle on your smartphone? Let us know your thoughts in the comments below. More About: apps, Business, infographics, Mobile, mobile payments</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/future-of-mobile-payments/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/future-of-mobile-payments/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huntsy: A Smart Dashboard for Your Job Search</title>
      <description>Ask any job seeker, and he&#8217;ll tell you that looking for a job is, in and of itself, a job. It&#8217;s time-consuming to prep your cover letter, tweak your resume, follow up and plan your interview, especially when you&#8217;re applying for multiple positions. Sure, you could make an intense, color-coded spreadsheet &#8212; but most of us aren&#8217;t that Type A. That&#8217;s where Huntsy comes in &#8212; it&#8217;s like HootSuite for your job search. Huntsy&#8217;s dashboard offer&#8217;s a bird&#8217;s eye view (hence the owl logo) of your job hunt, offering a bird&#8217;s-eye view of your professional prospects. &#8220;People are applying to many different places &#8212; Huntsy is our way to make it easy for them,&#8221; says Cezary Pietrzak, Huntsy&#8217;s director of marketing. &#8220;The category is just so dusty.&#8221; Huntsy&#8217;s cleaning it off with a slick UI and an organized and social approach to the intimidating job search. You can create an account via your Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn profiles (or create a new login if you eschew connecting via social sites), and then install the bookmarklet or Chrome extension into your browser. As you sift through job listings &#8212; on a company&#8217;s website, the Mashable job board, LinkedIn, Krop, CareerBuilder, Github, Monster and more &#8212; you can click the Huntsy bookmarklet to save exciting prospects. A Huntsy widget will push down in the browser and fill out the necessary details &#8212; company, title and job description &#8212; by extracting it from the job listing. The bookmarklet in action Once you click &#8220;Add to Huntsy,&#8221; the job will be added to your dashboard, which looks like this: The dashboard Within the dashboard, you can schedule interviews and follow-ups, receive reminders to send thank-you notes, uncover professional connections at various companies (if you linked your social networks) and, most importantly, apply to jobs directly. If you&#8217;re applying to some jobs in marketing and others in PR, Huntsy can save several versions of your resume and a few different cover letters, letting you emphasize certain strengths and experiences for various positions. When you submit your application, your resume is included in the email as a unique, downloadable link. No longer must you feel as though your application has been thrust into a black hole, never to be seen by human eyes, because you&#8217;ll receive a notification the moment someone downloads your resume. This feature enables you to have great timing with a follow-up email, since you&#8217;ll know that your resume is fresh in the recruiter&#8217;s mind. (The application email also BCC&#8217;s Huntsy, so the dashboard can track your actions throughout the application process and help you stay on top of each step.) If you&#8217;re diligent about using Huntsy, then the email notifications and &#8220;today&#8217;s tasks&#8221; could keep you top of your application process, especially if you&#8217;re applying to more than a handful of positions. Pietrzak says Huntsy&#8217;s streamlining can save job seekers two to four hours per week, in addition to helping the hunt stay organized and productive. &#8220;You start to have a sense of what&#8217;s going on in your job search,&#8221; says Pietrzak of Huntsy&#8217;s guidance tools. Plus, the way Huntsy breaks the application process into small steps makes the user feel like he is &#8220;getting somewhere&#8221; something every step of the way &#8212; a valuable feature, since the job search often can be daunting and overwhelming. The site launched less than a month ago and has signed up more than 5,000 users, who are spending 10 minutes on the site per session, says Pietrzak. And many of them are coming back &#8212; 40% of the visitors are returning, suggesting that they are in fact using Huntsy with some regularity to manage and streamline their job search. The team is working to perfect the functionality and add new features, including calendar integration (for all of those reminders and interview dates) and linking with Google+. Since it&#8217;s still new, the bookmarklet can be a little buggy and tends to not fully extract all of the details for some jobs, but a simple copy-and-paste can load everything into your dashboard. Huntsy is based in New York and was born out of the QLabs hacker community, where the team shares office space with Turntable.fm and Nestio, a Huntsy-esque dashboard for the apartment search. Does Huntsy sound like it&#8217;d be a useful tool for your job search? Let us know in the comments. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Junior Web Designer at Control Group in New York Art Director at 2tor in Hyattsville, Md. Chief Blogger at NVIDIA in Santa Clara, Calif. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, JulNichols More About: features, Huntsy, job search series, jobsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/huntsy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/huntsy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huntsy: A Smart Dashboard for Your Job Search</title>
      <description>Ask any job seeker, and he&#8217;ll tell you that looking for a job is, in and of itself, a job. It&#8217;s time-consuming to prep your cover letter, tweak your resume, follow up and plan your interview, especially when you&#8217;re applying for multiple positions. Sure, you could make an intense, color-coded spreadsheet &#8212; but most of us aren&#8217;t that Type A. That&#8217;s where Huntsy comes in &#8212; it&#8217;s like HootSuite for your job search. Huntsy&#8217;s dashboard offer&#8217;s a bird&#8217;s eye view (hence the owl logo) of your job hunt, offering a bird&#8217;s-eye view of your professional prospects. &#8220;People are applying to many different places &#8212; Huntsy is our way to make it easy for them,&#8221; says Cezary Pietrzak, Huntsy&#8217;s director of marketing. &#8220;The category is just so dusty.&#8221; Huntsy&#8217;s cleaning it off with a slick UI and an organized and social approach to the intimidating job search. You can create an account via your Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn profiles (or create a new login if you eschew connecting via social sites), and then install the bookmarklet or Chrome extension into your browser. As you sift through job listings &#8212; on a company&#8217;s website, the Mashable job board, LinkedIn, Krop, CareerBuilder, Github, Monster and more &#8212; you can click the Huntsy bookmarklet to save exciting prospects. A Huntsy widget will push down in the browser and fill out the necessary details &#8212; company, title and job description &#8212; by extracting it from the job listing. The bookmarklet in action Once you click &#8220;Add to Huntsy,&#8221; the job will be added to your dashboard, which looks like this: The dashboard Within the dashboard, you can schedule interviews and follow-ups, receive reminders to send thank-you notes, uncover professional connections at various companies (if you linked your social networks) and, most importantly, apply to jobs directly. If you&#8217;re applying to some jobs in marketing and others in PR, Huntsy can save several versions of your resume and a few different cover letters, letting you emphasize certain strengths and experiences for various positions. When you submit your application, your resume is included in the email as a unique, downloadable link. No longer must you feel as though your application has been thrust into a black hole, never to be seen by human eyes, because you&#8217;ll receive a notification the moment someone downloads your resume. This feature enables you to have great timing with a follow-up email, since you&#8217;ll know that your resume is fresh in the recruiter&#8217;s mind. (The application email also BCC&#8217;s Huntsy, so the dashboard can track your actions throughout the application process and help you stay on top of each step.) If you&#8217;re diligent about using Huntsy, then the email notifications and &#8220;today&#8217;s tasks&#8221; could keep you top of your application process, especially if you&#8217;re applying to more than a handful of positions. Pietrzak says Huntsy&#8217;s streamlining can save job seekers two to four hours per week, in addition to helping the hunt stay organized and productive. &#8220;You start to have a sense of what&#8217;s going on in your job search,&#8221; says Pietrzak of Huntsy&#8217;s guidance tools. Plus, the way Huntsy breaks the application process into small steps makes the user feel like he is &#8220;getting somewhere&#8221; something every step of the way &#8212; a valuable feature, since the job search often can be daunting and overwhelming. The site launched less than a month ago and has signed up more than 5,000 users, who are spending 10 minutes on the site per session, says Pietrzak. And many of them are coming back &#8212; 40% of the visitors are returning, suggesting that they are in fact using Huntsy with some regularity to manage and streamline their job search. The team is working to perfect the functionality and add new features, including calendar integration (for all of those reminders and interview dates) and linking with Google+. Since it&#8217;s still new, the bookmarklet can be a little buggy and tends to not fully extract all of the details for some jobs, but a simple copy-and-paste can load everything into your dashboard. Huntsy is based in New York and was born out of the QLabs hacker community, where the team shares office space with Turntable.fm and Nestio, a Huntsy-esque dashboard for the apartment search. Does Huntsy sound like it&#8217;d be a useful tool for your job search? Let us know in the comments. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Junior Web Designer at Control Group in New York Art Director at 2tor in Hyattsville, Md. Chief Blogger at NVIDIA in Santa Clara, Calif. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, JulNichols More About: features, Huntsy, job search series, jobsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/huntsy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/huntsy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a genius tactic to encourage users to buy your app: http://t.co/lTXJixd9</title>
      <description>This is a genius tactic to encourage users to buy your app: http://t.co/lTXJixd9</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/jakemarsh/status/200267322848579584</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/jakemarsh/status/200267322848579584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Heart-Warming Animal Friendships Captured on YouTube</title>
      <description>1. A Tiger and an Alsatian The cartoons would have you believe that cats and dogs are natural born enemies, but that's certainly not the case for this tiger and zookeeper's Alsatian. Look out for a cute bonus when the tiger's cub gets in on the action.Click here to view this gallery.There&#8217;s something special about interspecies animal friendships, perhaps because they demonstrate that if animals can put aside their differences, there&#8217;s no reason we humans can&#8217;t do the same. We&#8217;ve gathered 10 outstanding videos that showcase unusual animal kingdom friendships between dogs and primates, hippos and tortoises, and even cats and birds. SEE ALSO: 10 Funniest Sketch Comedy Channels on YouTube Have a browse through the video gallery and let us know in the comments below which critter buddies tugged at your heartstrings. Thumbnail image courtesy of Flickr, Michelle Gow More About: animals, galleries, gallery, videos, viral videos, YouTubeFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/animal-friendships-videos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/animal-friendships-videos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Obama Wants Campaign Song Requests for Spotify Playlist</title>
      <description>President Obama will now take your song requests. President Obama&#8217;s team has set up a page on BarackObama.com for voters to submit potential campaign songs that could be added to his Obama 2012 Supporter Picks playlist on Spotify. &#8220;As we head into rally season, what music gets you fired up?&#8221; the page asks. &#8220;Submit your favorite tracks below, and you could see them on the Obama 2012 Supporter Picks playlist on Spotify.&#8221; Spotify is a music streaming site that gives users free access to millions of tracks on their computers and mobile devices. It also allows users to create playlists, see what their friends are listening to and to download third-party apps to discover everything from song lyrics to recommendations. SEE ALSO: Obama Supports Gay Marriage, ABC Breaks News Online Obama&#8217;s team is no stranger to using Spotify to get the word out about his campaign and connecting with supporters. In February, they introduced their first playlist which featured songs from a variety of artists, from Bruce Springsteen and Earth Wind &amp; Fire to No Doubt, Florence + The Machine and Sugarland. It also featured &#8220;Let&#8217;s Stay Together&#8221; by Al Green, which Obama sang a few weeks earlier at the Apollo Theater in New York. In other presidential news, Obama also declared his support for same-sex marriage in an interview with ABC News Wednesday. Which songs do you think are good for political campaigns? Let us know in the comments. More About: Facebook, Mobile, Music, president obama, spotify, Twitter, U.S. presidential electionFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/09/president-obama-wants-campaign-song-requests-for-spotify-playlist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/09/president-obama-wants-campaign-song-requests-for-spotify-playlist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Debunks Reports of 55,000 Hacked Accounts</title>
      <description>Hackers claiming to be affiliated with the hacktivist group Anonymous claimed this week to have accessed and published the details of about 55,000 Twitter accounts. But Twitter said Tuesday those claims are largely bogus, and that the group mostly posted duplicate information or username and password information for suspended spam accounts. An anonymous Pastebin user posted five extremely long pages of alleged Twitter usernames and passwords to the text storage site on Monday. (Here are pages one, two, three, four and five.) The hacking news aggregator Airdemon.net reported the supposed breach on Tuesday, beginning to fuel speculation around the web of a massive successful attack on Twitter&#8217;s servers. Airdemon said celebrity accounts were among those compromised, and also claimed to have information from a &#8220;Twitter insider&#8221; confirming the attack. Responding to a Mashable comment request Tuesday afternoon, however, a Twitter representative debunked the notion of a hugely successful breach but said the company is still investigating the situation. The list of accounts posted to Pastebin contains more than 20,000 duplicates and information for many spam accounts that have already been suspended, a spokesperson told Mashable in an email. Furthermore, Twitter says, many of the usernames and passwords do not in fact appear to linked to one another, rendering them essentially useless. Twitter has sent out password resets to accounts that may have been affected and encourages other concerned users to visit the network&#8217;s Help Center to change their passwords and review security settings. Do you believe Twitter that hackers&#8217; claims to have leaked credentials for 55,000 accounts are overblown, or do you worry your security was compromised? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, sodafish More About: anonymous, hackers, hacking, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/twitter-hacked-accounts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/08/twitter-hacked-accounts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best and Worst Times to Share on Facebook, Twitter</title>
      <description>Want your link to get the most traction on Twitter? Post it on a Monday between 1:00 p.m. and 3:00 p.m. ET. Link shortening and tracking service bit.ly has released new data on the best and worst times to share links on popular social networks, from Facebook and Twitter to blogging site Tumblr. The company revealed that posting links to Twitter between the hours of 1:00 p.m. and 3:00 p.m. ET will give you the highest click rank, especially on days earlier in the week. Meanwhile, sending a tweet with a link after 8:00 p.m. should be avoided &#8212; as should posting links after 3:00 p.m. on Fridays. The half-life of a link posted to Twitter is about 2.8 hours, according to bit.ly. However, Facebook&#8217;s optimal posting times are slightly different than Twitter. Links sent between 1:00 p.m. and 4:00 p.m. get the most traction, with Wednesday at 3:00 p.m. being the best time to post on Facebook all week. Links posted after 8:00 p.m. and before 8:00 a.m. on Facebook also don&#8217;t get the most clicks. Similar to Twitter, bit.ly recommends not posting the links you want to go viral during the weekend. &#8220;While traffic starts to increase around 9:00 a.m., one would be wise to wait to post until 11am,&#8221; bit.ly said in a blog post on its site. &#8220;Traffic from Facebook fades after 4:00 p.m.&#8221; Meanwhile, Tumblr has a much different usage pattern than Facebook and Twitter. It&#8217;s suggested to wait until at least 4:00 p.m. ET. to post important content, and posts that go up after 7:00 p.m. get the most clicks during a 24-hour period. It&#8217;s also suggested that Friday evenings are a key time to post on Tumblr &#8212; a time bit.ly recommends avoiding on Facebook and Twitter. Bit.ly traffic from Tumblr peaks between 7:00 p.m. and 10:00 p.m. on Monday and Tuesday, with similar traffic on Sunday, according to the study. &#8220;It&#8217;s easy to see that just like your neighborhood restaurants, each social network has its own culture and behavior patterns,&#8221; bit.ly noted in the blog post. &#8220;By understanding the simple characteristics of each social network, you can publish your content at exactly the right time for it to reach the maximum number of people.&#8221; Do you notice a difference in engagement when posting at different times? Let us know in the comments what works best for you. More About: bit.ly, Facebook, Social Media, trending, tumblr, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/09/best-time-to-post-on-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/09/best-time-to-post-on-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: Watney 'settles the score' with Doral</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502#42063502"&gt;&lt;img align="left" border="0" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/NBCSports/Components/Video/_NEW/s_nbc_glf_wgccadillacwatneyintv_110313_4x3.thumb.jpg" alt="March 13: Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)" style="margin:0 5px 5px 0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;</description>
      <link>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</link>
      <guid>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Map Shows Where You&#8217;d Be If You Dug a Hole Through the Earth</title>
      <description>Remember that favorite childhood question: if you could dig a hole so deep in your backyard that you would end up on the other side of the world, where would you be? Australia? China? One Google Maps-based website figures out where you would end up, if such a thing were possible. It turns out that if you&#8217;re digging from most of the continental U.S., you&#8217;d end up swimming somewhere in the Indian Ocean. AntipodeMap.com allows you can see which location is exactly halfway around the world from where you are. Double click or move the top map to your region to see which area is diametrically opposite to your current location. SEE ALSO: 10 Places You&#8217;re Not Allowed to See on Google Maps The site defines two antipodal points as being connected by a straight line through the dead center of the Earth. For example, New York City&#8217;s antipodal point is in the Indian Ocean, just southwest of Perth, Australia. San Francisco&#8217;s antipodal point is southeast of Madagascar, off the African coast. Which location is halfway around the world from where you are right now? Let us know in the comments. BONUS: 12 Mysterious Google Maps Sightings 1. The Badlands Guardian This natural formation in Alberta, Canada is known as the Badlands Guardian and looks strikingly similar to a native American wearing a headdress. If you look close enough, it looks like he's wearing a pair of earphones, but that section is actually a man-made road and oil well.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Google, Google MapsFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/antipodes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/07/antipodes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For the more nerdy amongst us: HTML9 Responsive Boilerstrap JS http://t.co/eG4cFmRQ</title>
      <description>Percolate: For the more nerdy amongst us: HTML9 Responsive Boilerstrap JS http://t.co/eG4cFmRQ &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://html9responsiveboilerstrapjs.com/</link>
      <guid>http://html9responsiveboilerstrapjs.com/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
