<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook IPO: It&#8217;s Set for May 18 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Facebook&#8217;s long-awaited Initial Public Offering is happening in just two and a half weeks time, the Wall Street Journal reports Tuesday. Citing the usual anonymous sources familiar with the matter, the Journal says Facebook will begin its IPO roadshow on Monday May 7. That&#8217;s when companies traditionally make the rounds of mutual funds, large banks and other major investors looking for multi-million dollar stakes. (We&#8217;ve reached out to Facebook for official confirmation.) The name of the IPO roadshow game is to explain why your stock will be such a good buy, although in Facebook&#8217;s case that shouldn&#8217;t be too hard. (Our advice: just show them this video, and you&#8217;ll be done in 150 seconds.) Facebook CEO and founder Mark Zuckerberg will only be present for some of the roadshow, say the sources; COO Sheryl Sandberg will handle the rest, along with CFO David Ebersman. (We&#8217;re hoping Sandberg still gets to finish work at 5:30pm.) The roadshow will wrap up pretty quickly, and then it&#8217;s on to the IPO itself, apparently set for Friday May 18. As we&#8217;ve written before, the IPO should shift $10 billion worth of Facebook stock, leaving the social network with an overall valuation of $100 billion &#8212; and turning Zuckerberg, who owns a controlling stake of voting shares, into one of the world&#8217;s richest men. Someone else who will be watching the IPO closely: Kevin Systrom, founder of Instagram. We&#8217;ve already noted that the $1 billion Facebook purchase of his app made Systrom worth $400 million on paper, but we&#8217;ve since learned that much of that $1 billion deal was for Facebook stock. A wildly successful IPO could theoretically make Systrom a billionaire, albeit at a much lower level than Zuckerberg. So now it&#8217;s finally happening, what are your thoughts on the Facebook IPO? Will the social network be wildly overvalued, or find its true level? Let us know in the comments. Additional Facebook IPO Coverage Facebook IPO Reveals How It Made $3.71 Billion in 2011 10 Giant Things Less Valuable Than Facebook Zuckerberg to Potential Shareholders: Facebook Is on a Social Mission Facebook IPO Filing Flings Open the Social Network Kimono Facebook: Zynga Generates 12% of Our Revenue and We Need Them Sheryl Sandberg Was Facebook&#8217;s Best-Paid Employee in 2011 2004: First Offers Turned Down Facebook launches with humble beginnings that most people have seen dramatized in The Social Network by now. It was a small social site backed by only a little money, and limited just to the undergrads at Harvard. Right out of the gate, Facebook turned down offers from an unknown investor and Friendster, each offering $10 million. This was, of course, when the company was still called TheFacebook. Image courtesy of Flickr.Click here to view this gallery. Thumbnail image courtesy of Katrina.Tuliao and Crunchies2009 via Flickr More About: Facebook, ipo, mark zuckerbergFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/facebook-ipo-may-18/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/facebook-ipo-may-18/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh yeah, this looks epic - new trailer for Batman The Dark Knight Rises released http://t.co/uVHg1sMk</title>
      <description>Neal Mann: Oh yeah, this looks epic - new trailer for Batman The Dark Knight Rises released http://t.co/uVHg1sMk &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=g8evyE9TuYk</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=g8evyE9TuYk</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Adds Organ Donor Option to Timeline</title>
      <description>Facebook on Tuesday unveiled an organ donor status option for Timeline, a move designed to help more than 114,000 people in the U.S. and millions more around the world who are waiting for a live-saving heart, kidney or liver transplant. &#8220;Many of those people &#8212; an average of 18 people per day &#8211;- will die waiting, because there simply aren&#8217;t enough organ donors to meet the need,&#8221; Facebook notes in a blog entry explaining the move. &#8220;Medical experts believe that broader awareness about organ donation could go a long way toward solving this crisis.&#8221; As the video above explains, designating yourself as an organ donor is easy. All you need to do is go to your Timeline, click on &#8220;Life Event&#8221; and then &#8220;Health &amp; Wellness.&#8221; Then, you&#8217;ll see the option for &#8220;Organ Donor.&#8221; At that point, you can add when and where you registered and your personal story. For those who aren&#8217;t organ donors, Facebook is providing a link to the appropriate registry. As with other Timeline entries, you can make your organ donor status public or private. The move, which Facebook had alluded to on Monday, comes as the 901 million-strong social network has adopted more socially conscious policies of late, including an anti-bullying initiative and a referral system for friends expressing suicidal thoughts.More About: Facebook, Social Good</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/facebook-organ-donor/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/facebook-organ-donor/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How You Could Build a Hit iPhone App Without Learning to Code [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>So you&#8217;ve got a great idea for an iPhone app. It&#8217;s fresh, it&#8217;s useful and no one&#8217;s ever done it before. Except there&#8217;s just one major hitch &#8212; you can&#8217;t write a line of code to save your life. But coding illiteracy could soon become less of an issue for wannabe iOS app developers if a startup called RadicalFlow achieves its mission. The company says it needs $75,000 to make the vision real for everyone and is taking to Kickstarter to raise funding. With donations open until May 26, RadicalFlow had raised about $3,500 at time of writing. RadicalFlow is a web-based HTML5 tool. &#8220;Think of it like opening Photoshop or Powerpoint with a blank slate ready for your creative input,&#8221; reads a portion of the company&#8217;s Kickstarter pitch. You design the interface, add buttons and create interaction, while RadicalFlow handles the backend heavy lifting. Then, once you&#8217;ve built your iPhone, iPad or iPod touch app, the company touts an added bonus &#8212; a platform to publish your product without having to obtain an Apple developers account. The Brooklyn-based company says meeting its funding goal will help fill out its development and design team, pay for server costs and legal fees, and support a marketing and promotional push. It also plans to add porting ability to Android devices in the near future. But you don&#8217;t need to be a coding noob to benefit from RadicalFlow. Advanced features will enhance what you can alredy do on your own, according to the company&#8217;s Kickstarter pitch. A desire to make app-building easier for coders and non-coders alike is actually how RadicalFlow was born. The tool was founded by a trio of longtime iOS app makers who write that &#8220;all of the work related to RadicalFlow comes out of our need to create tools that would make our lives easier, both on the design and development side.&#8221; Do you think RadicalFlow is a cool idea? Will you contribute to its Kickstarter campaign? Check out its full video pitch below and let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci More About: app development, apple, apps, iOS, iphone, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/iphone-app-radical-flow-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/iphone-app-radical-flow-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Mobile Trends Brands Need to Watch</title>
      <description>Jonathan Gardner is director of communications at Vibrant Media. He has spent his career at the nexus of media and technology, having worked in communications around the world. Follow him @thejongardner. If you let your imagination run wild, innovations such as Google&#8217;s Project Glass suggest there will come a time when we&#8217;ll no longer converse with each other, but instead exchange data like a bunch of GPS-enabled cyborgs. While that may not be quite how it plays out, a highly-connected future is definitely on its way. Already, data shows that more than one third of American teens own an iPhone and the one-tablet-per-child initiative is a mainstay in South Korean and Thai schools. It&#8217;s easy to see what life will look like for the next generation of consumers, but will marketers be prepared? That will largely depend on whether they&#8217;ve considered these five post-mobile trends. 1. Augmented Reality Look in the mirror and what do you see? Today&#8217;s weather? Your day&#8217;s appointments? Then you must have the latest mirror from Cybertecture, a Hong Kong firm that&#8217;s making tomorrow&#8217;s smart homes a reality today. We may not all have money to burn on a high-tech mirror, but brands are certainly looking at ways to capitalize on this technology and make it the norm. For example, the wizards at Corning provided an inspiring look at how touch screens made of glass might soon be seamlessly integrated into our environments. Brands such as Starbucks are already seeing strong revenue from their mobile AR program. 2. The New Biotech When I say biotech, I mean data comes from everywhere, including from within. Companies like FitBit and Nike are finding new ways to record and utilize that data. For now, they seem to be focused on helping athletes (and wannabes) build better workouts, but it&#8217;s only a matter of time before brands begin to look more closely at how such data might be used to develop new customer relationships. Nike has already opened its FuelBand API to allow music platforms to experiment with incorporating personal physical data. As these technologies gain traction and developers look at new ways to leverage information, one day soon we could see insurance companies providing discounts to individuals who share their device data. This would be the equivalent of auto insurers, such as Progressive, offering savings to drivers who share their driving behavior. 3. Consumer-Controlled Media One of the most interesting trends we&#8217;ve seen is the fragmentation of ownership. Technology has empowered the masses, and they&#8217;re leveraging that power in new ways. If brands want to remain relevant to their audiences, they&#8217;re going to have to engage in these contexts and in a media landscape where the traditional publishing model no longer exists. In this not-too-distant future we will watch all of our programming online in whatever form that takes. And we will engage with media that we create (not what the media &#8220;owners&#8221; create) or remix, re-purpose, and pass along. 4. Multi-Platform Marketing Consumers don&#8217;t think in silos, so neither should your company. Prepare your brand to work on multiple platforms. As you do that, consider what unique aspects of your offering, your history, and products will resonate with the consumer of the future? Communicate your brand's essence through new channels and devices, in an integrated, cohesive manner. But be aware of how and when they want to interact with brands, and the new possibilities to bring them value and not just marketing noise. 5. Innovation Without Borders Brands and products are no longer geographically confined in the way they once were, and neither are marketing campaigns. Big brands are increasingly tapping into local talent and culture, testing new approaches in one market, and re-purposing them elsewhere. Coca-Cola took the best of gamification, Shazam, and the second-screen experience and ran with it in China. Tesco is testing out interactive mobile shopping experiences in Seoul that the U.S. is not quite ready for, technologically or socially. It is clear that in the near future, brands will pitch locally but think globally. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, hocus-focus More About: Augmented Reality, contributor, corporate brands, features, mobile marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/mobile-trends-brands-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/mobile-trends-brands-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Twitter Nearly Ruined Obama&#8217;s Secret Trip to Afghanistan</title>
      <description>President Barack Obama is on an unannounced trip to Kabul, Afghanistan, to sign a post-war agreement with Afghan President Hamid Karzai &#8212; but Twitter almost let the cat out of the bag, causing the White House to scramble to keep the president&#8217;s whereabouts secret. Early Tuesday morning, a local Afghan news station tweeted that Obama landed in Afghanistan aboard Air Force One, according to Buzzfeed Politics. The problem with the tweet? The journey was supposed to be kept secret for security reasons. If an enemy of the U.S. got ahold of Obama&#8217;s itinerary, it could give them advance notice to set up some kind of attack on the president. The tweet was first noticed in the American media by The Huffington Post&#8216;s Joshua Hersh. Is this right? RT @TOLOnews BREAKING: United States President Barack Obama has arrived in Kabul to meet Afghan President Hamid Karzai. &#8212; Joshua Hersh (@joshuahersh) May 1, 2012 The U.S. Embassy in Kabul quickly tweeted a denial of TOLO&#8217;s report, while the White House reached out to members of the press to quell the rumors. Reports that President Obama is in Kabul are false. &#8212; U.S. Embassy Kabul (@USEmbassyKabul) May 1, 2012 But Hersh kept on the story. The whole is he or isn&#8217;t he game continues! RT @Pressistan: All roads leading to Wazir akbar khan, US embassy blocked by police &#8212; Joshua Hersh (@joshuahersh) May 1, 2012 Eventually, The Associated Press broke the story: Obama did indeed land in Afghanistan on an unannounced visit. BREAKING: President Obama in Afghanistan on an unannounced trip to sign agreement on US post-war role. &#8212; The Associated Press (@AP) May 1, 2012 The Afghan station that originally tweeted the report, TOLOnews, has since deleted that tweet and replaced it with a report that the original story was false. Obama will address the nation from Afghanistan at 7:30 p.m. ET Tuesday. His speech can be watched live at WhiteHouse.gov. Images courtesy of Flickr, DVIDSHUB More About: afghanistan, barack obama, Politics, Twitter, US, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/obama-afghanistan-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/obama-afghanistan-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spitting Lady Interrupts TV News Report [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Some videos exist simply to go viral. In the above video, a woman interrupts a taped segment for WCIU-TV, an independently and locally owned, programmed and operated station based out of Chicago, and spits repeatedly on the ground in front of the camera. SEE ALSO: Secret Sauce &#8212; What Does It Take to Create a Viral Video? Apparently, the woman has a cold, but it isn&#8217;t catching. What&#8217;s the strangest thing you&#8217;ve seen on local news? Let us know in the comments. More About: viral, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/spitting-lady-chicago/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/spitting-lady-chicago/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movember: How Mustaches and Social Media Raise Awareness for Men&#8217;s Health</title>
      <description>Name: Movember Big Idea: Every November, men around the world grow a mustache &#8212; a &#8220;Mo&#8221; &#8212; to raise funds and awareness for men&#8217;s health issues, such as prostate cancer. The global campaign is driven largely by social media, online awareness platforms and a mobile app. Why It&#8217;s Working: Individuals grow mustaches and mobilize friends and family to donate online &#8212; through a &#8220;Mo Space.&#8221; Movember dominates social media chatter during November, and mentions of &#8220;prostate cancer&#8221; and &#8220;getting checked&#8221; increase, suggesting that Movember does in fact mobilize men to see a doctor. Aside from encouraging men to be proactive about their health, the 2011 Movember campaign raised more than $14.5 million for men&#8217;s health research. &#8220;We as men don&#8217;t feel comfortable talking about our health,&#8221; says Garone, explaining why he and a few friends launched Movember in 2004. For the 30 days in November, men are asked to grow a &#8220;Mo&#8221; &#8212; the oft-awkward facial hair &#8220;generates so much conversation&#8221; that it raises awareness and millions of dollars for men&#8217;s health. At launch in 2004, social networks were minimal, but the rise of the social web has led to a snowball effect online. &#8220;Over the last two years, we&#8217;ve seen an acceptance of social media,&#8221; which helps to accelerate the amplification of the Movember messaging. says Garone. During Movember 2011, the U.S. Twitter handle @Movember saw 13,404 mentions, and &#8220;Movember&#8221; was part of 937,817 social media conversations. On one&#8217;s Mo Space, a &#8220;Mo Bro&#8221; is encouraged to post updates about mustache growth, which is shared to his social networks on Facebook and Twitter, contributing to these conversations and helping to build a passionate community. Beyond Facebook and Twitter, the Movember campaign also utilizes a mobile app and viral videos to take fundraising to the next level. Thanks to social and digital savvy, Movember has grown into a global movement that spawned more than a million mustaches last November, helping to net more than $14.5 million. Check out the video above to see Adam Garone, founder and chief executive of Movember, talk mustaches and social media. Series presented by GE The World at Work is powered by GE. GE Works focuses on the people who make the things that move, power, build and help to cure the world. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, selimaksan More About: features, health, mashable, movember, Social Good, World at WorkFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/movember-adam-garone-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/movember-adam-garone-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Is Exploring a Premium Version, CEO Suggests</title>
      <description>Twitter might be developing a premium version of its service, CEO Dick Costolo indicated on stage at Wired&#8216;s business conference in New York City Tuesday afternoon. An audience member asked Costolo whether Twitter would ever introduced a &#8220;pro&#8221; version for individual users. Costolo refused to confirm that Twitter was working to develop one, but did suggest that it was an idea the company was exploring. Costolo said he imagined a product with &#8220;lightweight controls&#8221; for users. &#8220;Our designers and engineers would define how that would work. I don&#8217;t know what it will look like,&#8221; he said. He offered no further details about what the premium product might look like, nor whether Twitter is developing any premium offerings for brands. What would you like to see in a pro version of Twitter? Let us know in the comments. More About: dick costolo, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/twitter-pro-service/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/twitter-pro-service/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Most-Followed Users on Instagram [PICS]</title>
      <description>25. Jason Mraz Username: Jason_Mraz Followers: 363,621 Number of Pictures: 254Click here to view this gallery. The big guns on Instagram have seen their number of followers spike tremendously since the startup exited its iPhone-only stage and released its much-anticipated Android app on April 3. Up until that point, Instagram had been downloaded 27 million times and only two users had more than 1 million followers &#8212; pop stars Justin Bieber and Selena Gomez. Days later, Facebook bought the photo-sharing app for $1 billion, attracting massive attention to Instagram. Instagram now approaches 50 million downloads, and three more users are in the 1-million-followers club. SEE ALSO: Meet @TextInstagram &#8212; Instagram Without Photos | Animation Mocks Instagram Fans The gallery above counts down the app&#8217;s 25 most-followed users, excluding Instagram&#8217;s account, which has 1.8 million followers. What are some of your favorite users to follow? Let us know in the comments. Images from Statigr.am; numbers from Web.Stagram More About: apps, celebrities, Entertainment, features, instagram, justin bieber, Lists, mobile apps, photography, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/instagram-most-followers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/instagram-most-followers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jack White Concert Asks Viewers to Create Digital Photo Mosaic</title>
      <description>Fans of White Stripes rocker Jack White and his newly released solo album, Blunderbuss, will get to revel in an interactive live streamed concert Friday night starting at 9 p.m. ET. Thirteen cameras will capture the action on stage at Webster Hall in New York City, and viewers tuning into the live stream online or on their mobile devices will get to pick one of three camera angles: black-and-white, balcony and director&#8217;s cut. The show is part of the American Express Unstaged concert series, which began in 2010 and has since attracted 70 million live stream views on YouTube and Vevo for artists such as Coldplay, Sugarland, Duran Duran and Arcade Fire. Each concert pairs an artist with a well-known director (such as John Legend with Spike Lee and Mary J. Blige with Adam Shankman). &#8220;It&#8217;s a bit like a soccer match &#8212; there was no set list.&#8221; White roped in filmmaker and actor Gary Oldman, who was busy Friday in the control room melding his vision with White&#8217;s for the live stream. &#8220;It&#8217;s a bit like a soccer match &#8212; there was no set list,&#8221; Oldman told reporters before peppering White with compliments. &#8220;He&#8217;s a sweetheart.&#8221; Viewers can participate during the live stream in several ways. For example, they will be tasked with creating a digital mosaic by submitting photos of themselves. Doing so unlocks five never-before-seen portraits of White shot by Oldman. Fans also can engage in a public chat within the live stream or on Twitter with the hashtag #AmexUNSTAGED. Black-and-white camera shots come into play because Oldman wants to evoke a 1960s ambiance. Oldman also got rid of the camera that soars above the crowd and stage to avoid making the concert look like American Idol, he said: &#8220;I can&#8217;t stand that.&#8221; Typically, the concerts coincide with the artists&#8217; album releases. White&#8217;s Blunderbuss came out Tuesday. BONUS: Jay-Z Rocks SXSW at AmEx Twitter Event Most recently on the music front, American Express had rapper take the stage at South by Southwest during an event to promote its new Twitter-based discounts program. Jay-Z Performs at SXSW A sea of camera phones lit up Jay-Z's free concert Monday night at South by Southwest during an event for American Express's new Twitter-based discounts program. Although the show at Austin City Limits Live was reserved for AmEx cardholders with SXSW badges, American Express offered a livestream to the masses. The footage is still available to watch here. AmEx pimped its recently announced Twitter initiative, which allows AmEx members to sync their cards to their Twitter account for hashtag-related savings, at the concert venue. Photo by Brandon FullerClick here to view this gallery. More About: american express, celebrities, Entertainment, Gary Oldman, jack-white, Live Stream, Music, White StripesFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/jack-white-live-stream-american-express/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/jack-white-live-stream-american-express/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
