<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Confirmed: Google Glasses Use a Trackpad [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Remember that odd-looking Google Glasses prototype the search giant has been pushing since April &#8211; and that co-founder Sergey Brin has been wearing to practically every event since? Well, now we know a little bit more about how they work, courtesy of an unusual source: California Lieutenant Governor and former San Francisco mayor Gavin Newsom. The one big mystery about Project Glass, the internal Google name for the glasses, is how you navigate through the items you see on their tiny screen. Was the glasses technology sophisticated enough, we wondered, that it could track your eye movements and sense where you were looking? Or did it simply use a trackpad on the side of the glasses, as several sources have suggested? Now we know the answer for sure, thanks to Brin and Newsom: it&#8217;s just a trackpad. Newsom had Brin as a guest on his Current TV show. The episode will air this Friday, but Current has released a short extract, which you can see in the video above. Brin takes a picture of Newsom with the glasses, and then swipes through what appears to be a picture gallery using the large black area on the right of the glasses. When he hands them over to Newsom &#8212; who just became the first known non-Googler in the world to take a look at Project Glass &#8212; Brin tells him &#8220;don&#8217;t touch the pad on the side.&#8221; Watch closely and you&#8217;ll see the trackpad appears to swipe in two directions &#8212; side to side to view the picture gallery, and up or down to exit and enter the gallery. Newsom was apparently impressed with the result. &#8220;The image was remarkably clear,&#8221; he told Wired. &#8220;You can easily forget you have them on, and sense the capacity of use in the future.&#8221; (He would not say, however, whether he would wear the glasses himself.) One mystery remains: how do the Google Glasses take snapshots in the first place? What is operating the shutter? Is that, perhaps, controlled by eye movements? Newsom asked, but unfortunately Brin didn&#8217;t respond. Does this video convince you one way or another about Project Glass? Are you more or less likely to wear this thing? Let us know in the comments. More About: Google, project glass</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/google-glasses-trackpad/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/google-glasses-trackpad/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F50: A Different Kind Of Tech Conference</title>
      <description>Faster than you can say &#8220;Can I borrow your copy of &#8216;How To Win Friends And Influence People,&#8217;&#8221; it&#8217;s tech conference season again. There hasn&#8217;t been a week during the month of May where I haven&#8217;t attended a tech conference or traveled to something tech conference-related. And judging by Techmeme&#8217;s events calendar the state of affairs only gets worse as we get deeper into summer. Between Disrupt NYC last week, D10 tomorrow, NY Founders and Le Web London in June, Allen &amp; Co, Sun Valley in July, the CrunchUp in August and TechCrunch Disrupt in San Francisco in September, the tech community is pretty much spending the next couple of months checking in and out of airports on Foursquare, Path, Instagram or whatever their social/mobile/local drug of choice currently is. In between this barrage of formal tech conferences, I briefly popped into F50 earlier this month &#8230; Founders Fund&#8217;s first attempt at a tech conference, F50 is the ultimate &#8220;un-conference,&#8221; where fifty of the technology industry&#8217;s &#8220;most promising&#8221; engineers and entrepreneurs were brought together on the Hawaiian island of Lanai. Founders Fund partner Bruce Gibney called it, &#8220;intellectual exchange without the structural nightmare that&#8217;s gone up around it&#8221; and INC magazine dubbed it, &#8220;The Most Exclusive Tech Conference Ever?&#8221; The elite group of fifty technologists were hand-picked by the Founders Fund partners and sent invites to save the dates between Friday May 11th and Sunday the 13th. Those from out of town were flown out to SF and put up for Thursday night at the Westin St. Francis Hotel, and both the East Coasters and the West Coasters were picked up by black car or bus and taken to Oakland&#8217;s Private Airport on Friday. There they met the other F50ers for the first time, in addition to about a dozen Founders Fund friends and mentors, trading in their fancy steel invites for a spot on one of two planes. None of the attendees knew exactly who else was on the trip or who they were flying with prior to their arrival and the group didn&#8217;t even know their destination as they boarded the jets. The seating on the private flight was arranged, and upon each seat was a personalized engraved iPad, complete with a .pdf deck of photos and bios of the rest of the attendees. While Founders Fund won&#8217;t let me publish the full list, it was very thorough and ran the gamut of world-changing innovators &#8212; from a guy with a serious plan to cure Cancer to a rocket engineer to a 3-D printer with a gaggle of rockstar computer scientist thrown in for good measure. Also worth noting: Founders Fund footed the bill for the entire fifty, turning the traditional model of &#8220;conference as a business&#8221; onto its axis (Note: As the only press invited I flew in coach and Aol paid most of my way). &#8220;Invest early and often&#8221; at its most extreme. Aboard the incoming flight, the menu was geek-themed, and guests could choose from the paleo friendly &#8220;Contemporary Nerd&#8221; (Filet Mignon and Tomato Basil salad), &#8220;Classic Nerd&#8221; (Pizza Pockets, Chicken Nuggets, Pringles and Red Bull) and &#8220;Vegan&#8221; (Pasta with Grilled Vegetables in an herbed Olive oil) meals. I guess whoever set up the menu thought vegan was nerdy enough to stand on its own. In order to encourage interaction between the attendees, Founders Fund made everyone switch seats halfway through the flight. In addition, Founders Fund partner Auren Hoffman, who has an obsession with questions apparently, had written out an ice-breaker question tailored to each attendee&#8217;s interest next to the iPads, like &#8220;What could be invented if energy were freely available everywhere?,&#8221; How will the human body change over the next thirty years, and how should we change it?&#8221; and &#8220;What turns human passion into money?&#8221; (Mine, which Hoffman handed to me the next night, was appropriately enough, &#8220;What makes you weird?&#8221;). After the very informal in-flight networking, the plane landed on the Hawaiian island of Lanai, and, finally finding out their destination, the fifty were driven to the Four Seasons, where they disembarked, picked up a simple swag bag filled with orange flip-flops and F50 t-shirts, and were herded to a dinner where the conversations between these brilliant young minds were spearheaded by either a Founders Fund member or mentor at each table. &#8220;I had more great conversations per hour than I&#8217;d had in years,&#8221; Hoffman later told me. The mentors, who flew in on a different plane along with Founders Fund partners Peter Thiel, Ken Howery, Luke Nosek, Brian Singerman, Bruce Gibney and Sean Parker included Yelp&#8217;s Russell Simmons, Palantir&#8217;s Stephen Cohen, World Economic Forum CTO Brian Behlendorf, and Airtime co-founder Joey Liaw. From what I heard the mentors really didn&#8217;t feel like there was that much difference between them and the attendees &#8212; as in, both groups were just as in awe of each other and eager to partake in dialogue. In lieu of the artifice of talks or anything even remotely structured the next morning, the attendees were given the option of going snorkeling or off-roading in jeeps, and those that chose snorkeling got to explore the ocean floor with industry visionaries like Parker and Thiel. Because this was Hawaii, some of the group even informally went golfing, on a whim. To give you a sense of how casual everything was, when I arrived in Lanai, Island Air informed me that it had lost my baggage and I was stuck wearing my default airplane outfit to the conference: a Coachella hoodie, a pair of cut-off shorts, ballet slippers and a tank top. When I asked the hotel guest reception whether or not my attire was appropriate for dinner, they responded, &#8220;Yeah, everyone else is also dressed like you.&#8221; I ended up buying a Hawaiian themed dress from the gift shop anyways. I arrived at the dinner 15 minutes late, and immediately one of the F50 kindly helped me get situated. My table was a cornucopia of super-impressive people, to my right Eben Bayer, a entrepreneur who is trying to make mushrooms &#8220;the new plastic&#8221; with his company Ecovative design, to my left Founders Fund partner Gibney, and across from me was child prodigy Taylor Wilson &#8212; a kid who created nuclear fusion in his garage at 14 and currently owns one of the largest private collections of radioactive materials in the US. At 18, Taylor wasn&#8217;t yet old enough to drink the wine and margaritas being offered to the table. He really wasn&#8217;t missing out on much, we insisted. Sometimes I like to think of the technology industry like what high school would have been like if the nerds were actually cool, and this exactly was the vibe at F50. The next morning when I donned my swag shirt to breakfast (I still didn&#8217;t have normal clothes) I came across a girl who was also wandering aimlessly about the Four Seasons, also looking for the F50 breakfast, I assumed. Ariel Garten was slight and about as un-intimidating as possible until she opened her mouth to respond to my cliche, &#8220;And what do you do?&#8221;question. &#8220;Thought-controlled computing,&#8221; was her answer and it made me do a double take. As CEO of InteraXon industries, Garten is making hardware products that can be controlled by the human mind (Seriously). She is also part owner of a Fashion Boutique in her native Canada. &#8220;I can pick any one person here and they&#8217;ll be amazing,&#8221; she quipped as we headed to breakfast. &#8220;Neither haphazard tossings of business cards nor random people&#8217;s elevator pitches blessed the event, where, profoundly brilliant people exchanged world-changing ideas,&#8221; said attendee Meredith Perry (who, as the founder of Ubeam, is working on a ground-breaking wireless phone charger), who I got to know over a breakfast buffet replete with scrambled eggs, bacon and mangoes and more. Perry set F50 in a league apart from other tech conferences, &#8220;[It] was small enough so that people felt intimate and uninhibited, and unstructured enough so that violent ideation could unfold &#8230; The relationships formed between the eager minds in attendance will lead to future-changing partnerships.&#8221; And indeed I already know of one (off-the-record for the moment) partnership to stem from the event &#8212; just weeks or so after. &#8220;The real &#8220;results&#8221; of the F50 weekend won&#8217;t materialize for several years,&#8221; Perry said. So who exactly were the chosen fifty? &#8220;We asked our friends to identify the smartest, most entrepreneurial people they knew who were not already directly known to Founders Fund,&#8221; Founders Fund partner Gibney told me, &#8220;And then we made sure that these were people who wanted to go out and change the world &#8211; people who hadn&#8217;t succumbed to irony, boredom or cynicism, but had a real plan for how to make things better through technology .. The result &#8230; really was one of the half dozen most fun and interesting things I&#8217;ve participated in (and this in a week that includes the FB IPO and a Falcon 9 launch).&#8221; Whether or not any of the F50 will actually end up changing the world remains to be seen, but the conference has already proven to be the gift that keeps on giving for many (and I have a slew of new, smart friends in my inbox). The bonds forged between attendees through a mere couple of days were strong enough that when the plane that was supposed to take us back to the mainland broke down, one attendee remarked, &#8220;Well if you&#8217;re going to be stuck on a deserted island, it might as well be with these people.&#8221; Another said goodbye to a new friend thusly, &#8220;Good luck with saving the world and curing cancer and everything.&#8221; Indeed. Images via: Jason Purtorti and Michael Solana</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/28/f50/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/28/f50/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women&#8217;s Health Contest Opens Up Pinterest to Advertisers</title>
      <description>Pinterest may not allow advertisers on its platform yet, but that&#8217;s not stopping some third-party publishers from hosting campaigns on the rapidly growing social network. On Friday, Women&#8217;s Health will launch its first advertiser campaign on Pinterest. The magazine will invite readers to create &#8220;Sparkling Summer&#8221; Pinterest boards incorporating images from the advertiser, Forevermark Diamonds, for a chance to receive a trip to a Women&#8217;s Health party in the Hamptons later this summer. We&#8217;ve seen a number of these kinds of contests on Pinterest in the past, but never on behalf of another advertiser. Social media has proven difficult territory for many advertisers. Followers and fans often react negatively to the kind of blatant sponsored messages that appear in other media, such as print and radio. As such, magazines&#8217; social media accounts have remained largely in the hands of editorial departments, which use those accounts to build their audiences and drive traffic to their websites. To integrate advertising into social media managed by magazines thus requires a degree of creativity. Women&#8217;s Health is hoping that the prize is enough to compensate for the appearance of what is clearly sponsored content in the newsfeeds of their Pinterest followers. The key, says Women&#8217;s Health publisher Laura Frerer-Schmidt, is to &#8220;offer prizing that really brings the Women&#8217;s Health experience to life for our audience.&#8221; Women&#8217;s Health has already sold another social media campaign around its July/August issue to Procter &amp; Gamble. For two weeks, the magazine will encourage its more than 1 million Twitter followers to engage with &#8220;a series of Twitter parties&#8230; [that] will unlock special content and prizing for our audience&#8221; related to the Olympics, says Schmidt. In a similar vein, Elle has launched an advertiser-sponsored trend guide on its Facebook page. How open are you to third-party advertisements from the brands you follow? Are they acceptable so long as there&#8217;s a tangible benefit, such as a contest prize, involved? More About: Advertising, magazine, Media, pinterest, Social Media, women's health</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/womens-health-pinterest-advertising/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/womens-health-pinterest-advertising/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women&#8217;s Health Contest Opens Up Pinterest to Advertisers</title>
      <description>Pinterest may not allow advertisers on its platform yet, but that&#8217;s not stopping some third-party publishers from hosting campaigns on the rapidly growing social network. On Friday, Women&#8217;s Health will launch its first advertiser campaign on Pinterest. The magazine will invite readers to create &#8220;Sparkling Summer&#8221; Pinterest boards incorporating images from the advertiser, Forevermark Diamonds, for a chance to receive a trip to a Women&#8217;s Health party in the Hamptons later this summer. We&#8217;ve seen a number of these kinds of contests on Pinterest in the past, but never on behalf of another advertiser. Social media has proven difficult territory for many advertisers. Followers and fans often react negatively to the kind of blatant sponsored messages that appear in other media, such as print and radio. As such, magazines&#8217; social media accounts have remained largely in the hands of editorial departments, which use those accounts to build their audiences and drive traffic to their websites. To integrate advertising into social media managed by magazines thus requires a degree of creativity. Women&#8217;s Health is hoping that the prize is enough to compensate for the appearance of what is clearly sponsored content in the newsfeeds of their Pinterest followers. The key, says Women&#8217;s Health publisher Laura Frerer-Schmidt, is to &#8220;offer prizing that really brings the Women&#8217;s Health experience to life for our audience.&#8221; Women&#8217;s Health has already sold another social media campaign around its July/August issue to Procter &amp; Gamble. For two weeks, the magazine will encourage its more than 1 million Twitter followers to engage with &#8220;a series of Twitter parties&#8230; [that] will unlock special content and prizing for our audience&#8221; related to the Olympics, says Schmidt. In a similar vein, Elle has launched an advertiser-sponsored trend guide on its Facebook page. How open are you to third-party advertisements from the brands you follow? Are they acceptable so long as there&#8217;s a tangible benefit, such as a contest prize, involved? More About: Advertising, magazine, Media, pinterest, Social Media, women's health</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/womens-health-pinterest-advertising/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/womens-health-pinterest-advertising/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oops: BBC Mistakes &#8216;Halo&#8217; Logo For United Nations Emblem [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>The BBC got ahead of itself last week &#8212; by a few hundred years. In a segment about the international community&#8217;s efforts in conflict-torn Syria, the BBC wanted to show the logos of human rights group Amnesty International and the United Nations. It got the right Amnesty logo, but in place of the UN emblem, it used that of the &#8220;United Nations Space Command,&#8221; a fictional government agency from the popular Halo video game series. &#8220;BBC News makes every effort to ensure the accuracy of all images broadcast, however very occasionally mistakes do happen,&#8221; a BBC spokesperson told Eurogamer. &#8220;Unfortunately an incorrect logo was used during a segment on last week&#8217;s News at One bulletin and we apologise to viewers for the mistake.&#8221; According to the Halo Nation wiki, the UNSC &#8220;serves as the military, exploratory, and scientific agency of the Unified Earth Government,&#8221; which was formed in the twenty-second century. In that case, the BBC should&#8217;ve saved this story for later &#8212; quite a bit later, really. For reference, here&#8217;s the actual UN logo, adopted on October 20, 1947 &#8212; in the twentieth century, for those keeping track at home: More About: bbc, halo, Video, viral, World, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/bbc-halo-logo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/bbc-halo-logo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bit.ly Rolls Out Confusing Redesign, iPhone App</title>
      <description>Link shortening and tracking service bit.ly got a major makeover on Monday. It offers a slew of new features to help make link sharing more dynamic &#8212; from bookmarks and profiles, to its first-ever iPhone app. Although the new tools will surely add more depth to the service, the layout has left many of its most dedicated users confused about how to shorten a link &#8212; which most of us would consider to be bit.ly&#8217;s raison d&#8217;etre. Bit.ly &#8212; which has more than 25 billion links saved since 2008 and gets about 300 million link-clicks each day &#8212; launched a redesign to not only expand its presence but give users more curation power. Among the most notable of the new tools is a profile page and what the company is calling &#8220;bitmarks,&#8221; which are similar to bookmarks. &#8220;Bitmarks are the interesting links you collect across the web &#8212; a hard to find recipe, an article, an awesomely hysterical video,&#8221; the company wrote on its blog. &#8220;It&#8217;s anything that you find and want to save and maybe even want to easily share. You can organize them into bundles based on a theme or share them with your friends via Facebook, Twitter and email. You decide whether each bitmark gets published to your public profile or saved privately, so that only you can see it.&#8221; SEE ALSO: The Best and Worst Times to Share on Facebook, Twitter When searching for bitmarks, you can see instant results based on the URL, title and notes as you type in keywords. Bitmarks can be added to a personal profile and can be made private or public. You can also save and share from its new Chrome extension, bitmarklet or via its iPhone app. The free iPhone app allows you to (finally) share and shorten links easily while on the go. The app also provides access to your bitmarks and saved pages to view in offline mode. The move is also part of an effort to see what others are sharing across various social networks such as Twitter and Facebook in one place. Bit.ly has already integrated those sites into the service; you have long been able to log in to bit.ly by using your Facebook or Twitter account. Bit.ly bundles is also not a new feature &#8212; it was first introduced in 2010 as a way to curate topical or related collections of links &#8212; but now you can collaborate and edit along with friends. Although the service&#8217;s new features will make the site more dynamic, it&#8217;s no longer intuitive to shorten a URL. Some people took to Twitter to discuss their frustration with the new layout. I literally do not know how to shorten a link on the new bit.ly, nice job guys! &#8212; Anthony De Rosa (@AntDeRosa) May 29, 2012 To convert a link, click on the &#8220;add a bitmark&#8221; link on the top right corner of the homepage and then click &#8220;save&#8221; (or &#8220;save and share,&#8221; if you wish to share). Then click on the &#8220;i&#8221; icon under your bitmarks section to copy and paste the shortened URL. What do you think of the new site features? Are you confused by the layout? Let us know your opinion in the comments. More About: apps, bit.ly, Facebook, TwitterFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/bit-ly-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/bit-ly-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Insanely Clickable Banner Ads</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s no secret that at one in 1,000, the average click-through rate for banner ad is rather pitiful. Think of other things with similar probabilities. For instance, over the course of your life, you have a one in 3,000 chance of getting struck by lightning. Despite the challenging odds, a few intrepid ad executives still see banners as promising terrain. The fact that display ads are often seen as a backwater controlled by direct-response marketers doesn&#8217;t daunt such modern day Mad Men, who think they can redefine the medium and, yes, even get readers to click. The 10 examples below show that banners need not be boring. 1. Ikea To make the case that you can fit a lot of Ikea products in your house or apartment, the Swedish furniture giant ran a banner in April that featured 2,800 items.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Advertising, apple, banner ads, IKEA</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/28/10-insanely-clickable-banner-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/28/10-insanely-clickable-banner-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bad Tech Etiquette To Avoid at Work</title>
      <description>Angie Reed is a VoIP expert and Switchvox UC Product Marketing Manager at Digium, the creator and sponsor of Asterisk, the world&#8217;s most widely used open source communications software. Follow her @switchvox and read her blog. Technology has simplified communications for most businesses, but the increased use of conference calls, video conferencing, and instant messaging has created a new list of off-putting behaviors that could land your business in an awkward situation. SEE ALSO: HOW TO: Handle an Employee&#8217;s Controversial Online Behavior Here&#8217;s a list of some pet peeves that would definitely make Emily Post cringe, and how to avoid them. Instant Message 1. Knock before entering. Most people know better than to barge into someone&#8217;s office or cubicle. The same applies to using IM. Before launching into a conversation, send a polite &#8220;ping&#8221; asking if the person is available for a quick chat. If you are on the receiving end, learn to say no if you can&#8217;t be interrupted and offer the person an alternative time to talk. 2. Keep it short. IM works best for quick questions and updates. If the message is complicated, and takes more than a few sentences, pick up the phone or get out of your chair and walk down the hall to discuss. 3. Hang the &#8220;Do Not Disturb&#8221; sign. If you are unavailable then simply set your status to invisible, away, or out to lunch. Video Conferencing 1. Video conferencing is more widely used in recent years in an effort to save on travel costs. It&#8217;s best to always assume the microphones and the cameras are on. That means don&#8217;t do or say anything you don&#8217;t want on camera. 2. Sit still, please. You may know someone who constantly fidgets. You may even have threatened to tie them to a chair during a videoconference. Simply put, excessive movements can be extremely distracting to others on the conference, so avoid rocking, pacing, or making dramatic gestures. 3. Avoid bright, flashy, patterned clothing. Play it safe, wear neutral tones in solid patterns. Speakerphone 1. Don&#8217;t place someone on speaker without first telling all parties involved in the call, and don&#8217;t assume everyone knows who is on the call. An obvious solution is to use a conferencing feature that prompts attendees to announce themselves when they arrive. 2. Mute your phone if you dial in from a public area, or if you need to multi-task while on a call. There is nothing worse than feeling like the person on the other end of the line is not engaged. 3. Refrain from having side conversations while participating on calls. It makes it difficult for those on the call to understand the dialogue if there is more than one conversation taking place in the conference room. 4. Avoid loud snacks, smacking of gum, slamming of office drawers, crying babies, barking dogs or basically any noise that will be magnified and hinder communication with other participants. 5. Don&#8217;t shout into the speakerphone. Today&#8217;s high-definition phones are particularly sensitive and you may come across louder than you intend. And, if you decide to move the phone around the room, keep in mind that the audience on the other side will hear it. Smartphone 1. Don&#8217;t use your speakerphone. If you assumed that using the speakerphone on a cell phone was something that only happens on reality TV, think again. It seems to be a growing trend among many cell phone users &#8212; and an annoyance for anyone standing close by. While it&#8217;s fine that you can work from just about anywhere now, don&#8217;t make everyone else part of your work day. 2. Be careful what you saw in public. For starters, you never know who might be listening when you happen to be discussing confidential information about, say, customers. It&#8217;s a bad idea all around and most of the time the people near you don&#8217;t want to hear it. Believe it or not, some people are at Starbucks for the coffee. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, AVAVA More About: contributor, features, instant message, smartphone, video conferencingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/28/bad-tech-etiquette-work/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/28/bad-tech-etiquette-work/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac's Live Lip-Dub Proposal</title>
      <description>On Wednesday, May 23rd, 2012, I told my girlfriend to meet me at my parent's house for dinner. When she arrived I had stationed my brother to sit her in the back of an open Honda CRV and give her some headphones. He "wanted to play her a song"... Wha</description>
      <link>http://vimeo.com/42828824</link>
      <guid>http://vimeo.com/42828824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes On Pinterest: How People Look at Your Boards</title>
      <description>Pinterest doesn&#8217;t just look different than other social networks &#8212; it&#8217;s looked at in a different way, too. While most websites draw users&#8217; gazes toward the left-hand side of the page, participants in a recent eye-tracking study for Mashable instead shifted their eyes from the top down the middle of the page. They also spent relatively less time looking at profile information than their counterparts who looked at Facebook pages. The study, which was conducted by EyeTrackShop, used the webcams of 600 participants to track their eye movements as they looked at top category and brand Pinterest pages for 10-second intervals. They answered a quick survey about each page after viewing it. Here are some more interesting observations from the results: Top pins pop. Pins that were front and center were seen by the highest percentage of viewers. Faces attract attention. As with most social media sites, respondents looked at faces on Pinterest at more than objects. Profile information isn&#8217;t always as noticeable as profile content. Profile image and information may dominate attention on Facebook, but on Pinterest fewer people noticed it than noticed content. The percentage of people who looked at profile information at the top of brand pages in the study was the same or lower than that of the pages&#8217; most-looked-at pins. On average, this info was looked at second, not first. Brand pages are just as popular as category pages. Participants were slightly more likely to say brand pages made them want to repin stuff, recommend the page to friends and tell their friends about it. More of them also said the pages were definitely inspiring and had good pieces of advice. People like brands better after viewing their Pinterest pages. The majority of participants said that viewing a brand&#8217;s page improved their opinion about the brand and said they were more likely to purchase something from it. Take a look at the findings from each category and brand page in the study, and let us know your observations in the comments. Pinterest Homepage Red on the heat map indicate areas that received the most attention. The graph on the right shows results from a survey that each study participant filled out after viewing the page.Click here to view this gallery. -center -random order, not like fb and other social media pages More About: EyeTrackShop, pinterest</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/pinterest-eye-tracking-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/pinterest-eye-tracking-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ModCloth Launches Clothing Collection of User-Generated Designs</title>
      <description>ModCloth, an online retailer of affordable women&#8217;s clothing and accessories, has launched a private label collection made up mostly of designs submitted and voted upon by its Facebook community. The retailer posted a call for design sketches on its blog and social channels in late November. ModCloth cofounder and chief creative officer Susan Gregg Koger then narrowed the pool of 1,900 entries to 90, and put them to a vote on ModCloth&#8217;s Facebook page in December. The winners &#8212; a diverse lot that includes high school students, aspiring fashion designers and costumers &#8212; were announced later that month, and now those pieces are available for purchase on ModCloth&#8217;s website. The collection is a step up from ModCloth&#8217;s Be the Buyer Program, which invites shoppers to vote and leave feedback on a rotating selection of samples from emerging designers. Both are part of the company&#8217;s mission to involve customers in the production process, and have done much to foster an engaged, evangelistic community. Another collection of user-generated designs has already been voted upon, and will launch in September. A third, holiday-themed contest will be announced this summer. More About: community, fashion, modcloth, retailFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/modcloth-user-generated-fashion-label/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/modcloth-user-generated-fashion-label/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>94% of U.S. Wineries Are On Facebook, 73% on Twitter</title>
      <description>94% of American wineries surveyed by ABLE Social Media Marketing are on Facebook and 73% are on Twitter. The study, done in December 2011, shows that American wineries are active in social media and that it's producing results. 47% of US wineries said that Facebook helps them generate sales (72% sell wine on their website). While this study focuses on wineries only, companies in other industries should take note of these results. The study by ABLE covered both American and French wineries, but the French statistics aren't as impressive. For example only 53% of French wineries surveyed are on Facebook, compared to the 94% of US wineries. Facebook and/or Twitter? Drilling down into the Facebook statistics some more, 50% of American wineries (but only 18% of French wineries) have more than 500 fans on Facebook. ABLE identified two reasons for the success of American wineries on Facebook: 49% of American wineries (19% of French) have a dedicated marketing manager who creates and publishes content on social networks. 30% of American wineries have been using Facebook ads to promote their winery (only 7.6% of French wineries). Aside: 3.8% of American wineries listed "my children" as their Facebook managers. Goes to show that family ties in SMB's is still important! It's interesting to see the wine industry using Facebook and Twitter for different reasons. According to the study, Facebook is the superior social media platform for generating sales (48% for Facebook vs. 28% for Twitter). But Twitter is seen as better at capturing media attention (53% for Twitter vs. 32% for Facebook). That kind of statistic is good news for Facebook's IPO investors, who've been spooked by the media into thinking that Facebook will have trouble growing revenue. 72% of American wineries and 69% of French wineries say they will be increasing their activity on Facebook in 2012. Twitter isn't seen as so important, with 61% of American wineries and 45% of French wineries saying they will increase their activity on Twitter in 2012. Other Social Networks Another interesting statistic is which wine-focused social networks US wineries use. Snooth is the most popular, with 33% of respondents on there. Note that nearly 53% aren't on any niche wine network. I'm somewhat surprised by that, because I'm a user of a couple of wine apps - Snooth and Drync - and I'd like to think that wineries are active on them. They should be updating their data on the popular apps and trying to woo the most passionate wine consumers (because connoisseurs are more likely to be using these niche apps than other people). As for other types of social networks, nearly 54% of American wineries have claimed or created a profile on Yelp, 40% on Google Places and 30% on Foursquare. 285 American wineries and 243 French ones participated in the study. The full report is embedded below.</description>
      <link>http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/94-of-us-wineries-are-on-facebook-73-on-twitter.php?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+readwriteweb+%28ReadWriteWeb%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/94-of-us-wineries-are-on-facebook-73-on-twitter.php?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+readwriteweb+%28ReadWriteWeb%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
