<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>New Definitions of Content, the Rise of Mobile Marketing, and a Customer Care Manifesto | Social Media Today</title>
      <description>Here's a review of stuff I found interesting in the last few weeks. I hope you do, too. If not, maybe you should reconsider your plans. According to IBM&#8217;s annual State of Marketing report, 34% of companies are planning mobile marketing campaigns in the next year. According to the MediaPost article, that represents the fastest planned adoption of a new marketing tactic in the five years since IBM started collecting its data. About a quarter of brands are currently running mobile ads, while nearly half have focused on building out their mobile presence. Forty-five percent have deployed mobile apps. Some 800 pieces of branded content were entered at Cannes this year. A tenth made the final cut, but only a quarter of those are what you would consider traditional entries, like a TV series. The rest? Well, the rest was made possible by the increasing ease with which anyone can innovate and create content. For instance, there was the song performed by members of the Colombian military with Morse code built in so the hidden message of hope could be detected by 16 hostages with radio access. And, according to Scott Donaton&#8217;s Advertising Age account, &#8220;From Tunisia came The Return of Dictator Ben Ali, which used posters of an ousted leader to spark fears of his return, spurring previously apathetic citizens to vote.&#8221; As for the work that ultimately wins, Donaton says he hopes it will show the way forward &#8220;to a place where content isn&#8217;t a separate discipline but infiltrates all forms of communication, with brands tapping the raw power of stories to move people, fuel desire, change perceptions and drive actions.&#8221; As the understanding of what content is evolves, businesses need to keep pace. Do you have the support you need to unleash creativity in your organization? Nike launched a Twitter campaign in the UK that wouldn&#8217;t have raised many eyebrows. A couple Manchester united players tweeted endorsements on Nike&#8217;s behalf. Yawn, right? But the Advertising Standards Authority said the tweets didn&#8217;t make it clear that these were paid endorsements (or, in bureaucratic language, the players didn&#8217;t make it clear the messages were &#8220;identifiable as marketing communications.&#8221; As a result, the campaign was banned, according to a BBC report. One tweet, from Wayne Rooney, read, &#8220;My resolution - to start the year as a champion, and finish it as a champion&#8230;#makeitcount gonike.me/makeitcount.&#8221; The other was similar. Only one complaint was all it took to launch the investigation that led to suspensions of the footballers&#8217; accounts. The U.S. Department of Defense has issued a report (PDF) that &#8220;lays the groundwork for future strategies that will harness mobile technology within military and high-security establishments,&#8217; accordin got an IBM SmartPlanet story. &#8220;This strategy is not simply about embracing the newest technology,&#8221; says the Pentagon&#8217;s CIO Teri Takai; &#8220;it is about keeping the DoD workforce relevant in an era when information and cyberspace play a critical role in mission success.&#8221; Once again, the military is most likely a step or two ahead of your employer. Advertising Age reports that sponsored story ads that show up on mobile news feeds are getting more clicks than the same ads showing up on your full-sized computer mmonitor. More than 7 million Facebook impressions were served during a 10-day period for 12 companies running fan acquisition campaigns, the article explains. &#8220;The click-through rate for mobile ads amounted to 0.79%, compared to 0.148% average across all five placements studied: mobile, desktop news-feed only, desktop only (comprised mainly of right-rail ads), news-feed only (desktop and mobile) and the &#8220;control&#8221; group (uniform bids made across placements). The click-through rate for desktop-only news-feed ads falls roughly in themiddle at 0.327%.&#8221; At the same time, Reuters is reporting that Facebook has given in to complaints that likes are showing up as ads without the permission of the user; you&#8217;ll now be able to control whether your posts become sponsored stories. That&#8217;ll cost Facebook more than $100 million in lost revenue. Socialbakers, the social media and digital analytics company, used LeWeb London as the platform to launch its Socially Devoted manifest, which aspires to be the industry standard for customer care. The goal: improved response rates and times, according to a ZDNet article. A manifesto is a declaration of beliefs or motivations, which you&#8217;ll find when you click a link that reads, &#8220;Learn What is Socially Devoted.&#8221; This manifesto declares that 65% of customer questions should be answered (compared to the current 30% rate), and that 10-30 minutes is appropriate (versus the current 24-hours). The database is what&#8217;s interesting here, though. You can see total number of fans, answers to questions, response times and rates of companies in a variety of industry, ranked by most or least responsive. (Volkswagen de Mexico is the most responsive auto company, for instance.) How cool can Facebook be if your grandmother and Uncle Stew are there? A USA Today article claims that teens are fleeing Facebook in favor of newer sites. They prefer to check in on Foursquare and like Pinterest for browsing, for example. The article offers no evidence to support its claim other than a decline in the year-over-year growth rates in unique visits to the social network. Still, it&#8217;s not hard to believe, yet I would argue that they&#8217;re adding these new sites but not shutting down or vacating their Facebook accounts. Between getting what they need to know from notifications and using mobile apps instead of the website, it&#8217;s no surprise that growth rates are slowing. As much as a teen may not want some great-aunt seeing their own photos, they do want to stay current on friends-and-family activities. While some may be quitting Facebook altogether, most are shifting their activities elsewhere while keeping an eye on Facebook, too.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/shelholtz/564357/friday-wrap-6-new-definitions-content-rise-mobile-marketing-customer-care-manifesto?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Social+Media+Today+%28all+posts%29</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/shelholtz/564357/friday-wrap-6-new-definitions-content-rise-mobile-marketing-customer-care-manifesto?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Social+Media+Today+%28all+posts%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Posts That Build Engagement on Facebook</title>
      <description>When Mark Zuckerberg &#64257;rst built Facebook, the purpose of it was to keep people connected with their friends. That was its &#64257;rst purpose. And it worked well. As Facebook grew, its purpose grew to accommodate businesses. Hence the addition of Facebook pages for brands. But many brand page admins make the mistake of thinking of Facebook users as &#8220;friends&#8221; who will look at company posts simply because a company posts them. That's not true, and it's not true because not all posts are created equal. Think of it this way, your business is not automatically friends with your audience. That only changes if you engage with them. Engagement on Facebook is re&#64258;ected in three forms: lik&#8230; Continue reading... More About: contributor, Facebook, features, Marketing, online marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-build-engagement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-build-engagement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wikileaks publishing Syrian Govt email</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://wikileaks.org/syria-files/</link>
      <guid>http://wikileaks.org/syria-files/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20+ Beautiful Camera-Themed iPhone Cases</title>
      <description>Vintage Camera Case This classic-looking, colorful option is available in pink, red, beige and mint. Cost: $16Click here to view this gallery. Has your iPhone become your primary camera? Then why not get a case that celebrates it? There are a wide variety of camera-themed iPhone cases, covers, skins and decals available. Spanning eras from twin lens reflex cameras to retro-styled compacts, right through to cases that are designed for fans of current iPhone photography apps, we have a wide selection for you to peruse. SEE ALSO: 10 Cassette Cases for Your iPhone Take a look through our hand-picked choices in the gallery above. Let us know in the comments below which case best suits your iPhotography style. More About: cameras, features, Gadgets, gallery, iphone, iphone accessories, iphone cases, iphotography, Mobile, photography, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/iphone-camera-cases/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/iphone-camera-cases/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Stay on Top of Social Media</title>
      <description>To be successful in social media and community management you need to keep track of the constant changes to that ecosystem. That's because everything you know about Facebook, Twitter, and other social spaces today will somehow be different in six months. Layouts will be altered, features will be added or removed, and new social networks may pop up. So how should you keep track of all these moving parts? Here are six tips for staying on top of social media. 1. Blogs There are hundreds of blogs focused on social media. Keep it simple by signing up to RSS feeds and spend twenty minutes every morning catching up on your social media news. Stick to blogs that are updated daily and focus&#8230; Continue reading... More About: contributor, features, Marketing, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/social-media-education/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/social-media-education/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art fears business fears art</title>
      <description>The artist says, "that sounds like business, and I want nothing to do with it. It will corrupt me and make me think small." The businessperson says, "art is frightening, unpredictable and won't pay." Because the artist fears business, she hesitates to think as big as she could, to imagine the impact she might be able to make, to envision the leverage that's available to her. And because the businessperson fears art, she holds back, looks for a map, follows the existing path and works hard to fit in, never understanding just how vivid her new ideas might be and how powerful her art could make her. There's often a route, a way to combine the original, human and connected work you want to do with a market-based solution that will enable it to scale. Once you see it, it's easier to call your bluff and make what you're capable of.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/07/art-fears-business-fears-art.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/07/art-fears-business-fears-art.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Stay on Top of Social Media</title>
      <description>To be successful in social media and community management you need to keep track of the constant changes to that ecosystem. That's because everything you know about Facebook, Twitter, and other social spaces today will somehow be different in six months. Layouts will be altered, features will be added or removed, and new social networks may pop up. So how should you keep track of all these moving parts? Here are six tips for staying on top of social media. 1. Blogs There are hundreds of blogs focused on social media. Keep it simple by signing up to RSS feeds and spend twenty minutes every morning catching up on your social media news. Stick to blogs that are updated daily and focus&#8230; Continue reading... More About: contributor, features, Marketing, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/social-media-education/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/07/social-media-education/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Android Phone Owners Use Their Devices [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>If you have a Samsung Galaxy-S and live in Sweden, chances are you like to talk on your mobile device using Bluetooth while on-the-go -- that's according to a recent study that shows Swedes use Bluetooth and wireless headsets more than people from any other country (47%). And owners of Samsung Galaxy-S phones use the most minutes per month of all Android devices (431). Tawkon, an Android app that measures how much radiation your phone is emitting, and by the company inneractive, which is a mobile app monetization exchange, created this infographic based on Tawkon's data for Android devices. This data was gathered from Tawkon's millions of daily data points over a period of several months&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, infographics, Mobile</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/how-android-phone-owners-use-their-devices-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/how-android-phone-owners-use-their-devices-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://www.zefrank.com/zesblog/archives/2012/07/a_conversation.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.zefrank.com/zesblog/archives/2012/07/a_conversation.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
      <description>A Conversation With My 12 Year Old Self: 20th Anniversary Edition I don't say this often, butplease share this one. http://tellmetodrawsomething.tumblr.com/ https://twitter.com/#!/JeremiahMc From: weepingprophet Views: 309 14890 ratingsTime: 03:47 More in Film &amp; Animation</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XFGAQrEUaeU&amp;feature=youtube_gdata</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XFGAQrEUaeU&amp;feature=youtube_gdata</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of the Internet in a Nutshell [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>It is probably impossible to encapsulate every innovation and change that has come to the Internet since its inception more than two decades ago. But the interactive designers at Vizzuality and Hyperakt have come close, in this stunning and extensive graphic that debuted at Google I/O last week. The graphic provides an immersive walk down digital memory lane, from the earliest days of HTTP to recent developments in HTML5 and full screen APIs. It documents the birth of browsers like Safari and Firefox and even pinpoints moments in the life of Javascript and Flash. The interactive design shows the growth of digital life and culture, as well, analyzing how global Internet traffic has gr&#8230; Continue reading... More About: data, hyperakt, infographic, vizzuality</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/web-evolution-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/web-evolution-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RoboCop Is Back &#8212; This Time With a Viral Trailer [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Do you love the '80s? Good news: RoboCop is coming back. But the '80s didn't have viral videos to help market new flicks. That's why, this time around, the sci-fi film -- slated for release in the summer of 2013 -- is getting the hype ball rolling early with a fictitious website that recently launched for the evil OmniCorp company. The video above lives over on that site, but the YouTube version above has already racked up more than 50,000 views since Saturday. Will you go see the new RoboCop? Let us know in the comments. More About: Movies, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/08/robocop-viral-trailer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/08/robocop-viral-trailer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
