<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Releases Final Mac OS X Mountain Lion to Developers</title>
      <description>Mac users, are you looking forward to getting your hands on the latest Mac OS X -- version 10.8, also known as Mountain Lion? You won't have to wait long. Apple released the final developer version of the operating system, known as a Gold Master, on Monday. Barring small technical issues and tweaks, this is the same version that will be released to the public -- and it's right on schedule. When can you download it, exactly? If you're a developer, right now. Otherwise, Apple has said the $19.99 Mountain Lion upgrade will be available online by the end of July. SEE ALSO: Apple Unveils Mac OSX Mountain Lion: So Long iChat, Hello Twitter The company hasn't specified an actual&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, mac osx mountain lion</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/apple-releases-final-mac-os-x-mountain-lion-to-developers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/apple-releases-final-mac-os-x-mountain-lion-to-developers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Essential Social Media Cheat Sheets</title>
      <description>Getting around a social media site is not always easy. For some users, it's a matter of getting used to social media. For others, the issue is keeping up with constant updates and changes to features, privacy settings, and account specifications. This, of course, is why social media cheat sheets exist. Cheat sheets are basically infographics that can give a user a simple rundown of various features and how to use them. Here's a roundup of great cheat sheets for the most popular social networking sites. Google+1. Google+ Cheat Sheet by Simon Laustsen This is a nice little cheat sheet that covers what most users are probably going to need. For example, you'll know how to crea&#8230; Continue reading... More About: contributor, features, Marketing, online marketing, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/social-media-cheatsheets/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/social-media-cheatsheets/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create an Awesome Infographic [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>What better way to show companies how to create an engaging infographic than through outlined steps in the form of an infographic? A new infographic by Infographic Labs -- first published by Performancing.com -- highlights the best practices of developing a creative way to get the word out about new data. As the amount of information we consume on the Internet grows and attention spans decrease thanks to a bevvy of distractions from email to Facebook, market research firms and other companies are packaging new data in visual ways. In some cases, infographics even go viral. SEE ALSO: 20 Reasons to Switch to Google+ [INFOGRAPHIC] From how to pick color schemes and graphics to appro&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, infographics, Marketing, research</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/how-to-create-an-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/how-to-create-an-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gymkhana FIVE: Watch Ken Block Perform Mind-Blowing Car Stunts Around San Francisco [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Ken Block on Monday released the latest edition of his automotive video shenanigans with Gymkhana Five: The Ultimate Urban Playground, San Francisco.</description>
      <link>http://www.autoweek.com/article/20120709/CARNEWS01/120709866</link>
      <guid>http://www.autoweek.com/article/20120709/CARNEWS01/120709866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ouch! Baseball Fan Drilled With Foul Ball While Checking Facebook [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>You know those guys you see at the baseball game who spend the whole time head-down in their smartphones? Here's a bit of karmic retribution from the baseball gods. This gentleman says he was checking in on Facebook at a recent game between the Reds and Padres when he didn't notice a foul ball headed his way until it drilled him in the chest. Luckily he wasn't seriously hurt, and keeps a good attitude about it in an interview with a ballpark reporter. Check out the video above for a cautionary tale and consider it a public service message courtesy of Mashable and Major League Baseball. More About: Facebook, sports, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/baseball-fan-hit-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/baseball-fan-hit-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judge: Samsung's Galaxy Tab Isn't Cool Enough To Be Confused With iPad (AAPL)</title>
      <description>By Sam Oliver Published: 08:24 AM EST (05:24 AM PST) A U.K. judge has found that the Samsung Galaxy Tab doesn't infringe on Apple's design patents, and added that it isn't "cool" enough to be confused with the design of the iPad.Judge Colin Birss ruled on Monday in London that consumers weren't likely to confuse the Galaxy Tab and iPad, according to Bloomberg. As a result, Samsung was found to not be infringing on Apple's patents."(Samsung's tablets) do not have the same understated and extreme simplicity which is possessed by the Apple design," Birss said in his ruling. "They are not as cool."The judge found that Samsung's products were distinctive from Apple, as they are thinner and have "unusual details" on the back. The ruling is different from a decision in the U.S. last month, where Apple won a temporary injunction barring sales of Samsung's Galaxy Tab 10.1.U.S. District Court Judge Lucy Koh found that Samsung did in fact infringe on Apple's design patents. She ruled that Samsung "does not have a right to compete unfairly by flooding the market with infringing products." While Apple didn't find the same success in the U.K., the iPad maker does have 21 days to appeal the decision issued on Monday by Judge Birss.Previously, Apple has successfully argued for temporary injunctions in Australia and Germany. Samsung dodged the German injunction by releasing a slightly-redesigned Galaxy Tab 10.1N. Meanwhile, the Australian ban was overturned last November.</description>
      <link>http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/12/07/09/uk_judge_says_samsung_tablet_not_cool_enough_to_be_mistaken_for_ipad.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/12/07/09/uk_judge_says_samsung_tablet_not_cool_enough_to_be_mistaken_for_ipad.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next Twitter for iPhone Version to Bring Interactive Tweet View</title>
      <description>Twitter is preparing a major new version of its iPhone app, which will include an interactive tweet view, enhanced notifications and more, 9to5Mac reports. The info comes through leaked release notes which bring a detailed list of all the new features in the next Twitter for iPhone version, 4.3. These include a more interactive tweet view experience, letting you see content previews, videos and images within tweets containing links to "partner websites," as well as the ability to choose whether you want to receive push notifications when certain people tweet. Other improvements include highlighted tweets about selected events, autocomplete in the Connect tab, and the ability to t&#8230; Continue reading... More About: iphone, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/twitter-iphone-update/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/twitter-iphone-update/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Launches Gay Rights Campaign &#8216;Legalize Love&#8217;</title>
      <description>Google wants to further gay rights across the world, launching a new campaign called "Legalize Love" on Saturday. The tech giant hopes to advance marriage rights for gay, lesbian and bisexual people in countries where it has offices, beginning in Poland and Singapore. Google exec Mark Palmer-Edgecumbe introduced the campaign at the Global LGBT Workplace Summit in London, reports dot429. "We want our employees who are gay or lesbian or transgender to have the same experience outside the office as they do in the office," Palmer-Edgecumbe said. "It is obviously a very ambitious piece of work." Google plans to develop relationships between companies and support grass-roots camp&#8230; Continue reading... More About: activism, gay rights, Google</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/08/google-gay-legalize-love/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/08/google-gay-legalize-love/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The false choice of mediocrity</title>
      <description>Too often, we're presented with choices that don't please us. We can pick one lousy alternative or the other. And too often, we pick one. I was struck by Apple's choice to put a glass screen on the original iPhone. Just six weeks before it was announced, Steve Jobs decided he wanted a scratchproof glass screen. The thing is, this wasn't an option. It wasn't possible, reliable, feasible or appropriately priced. It couldn't be done with certainty, and almost any other organization would have taken it off the list of appropriate choices. It was unreasonable. And that's the key. Remarkable work is always not on the list, because if it was, it would be commonplace, not remarkable.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/07/the-false-choice-of-mediocrity.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/07/the-false-choice-of-mediocrity.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Search: Google Offers Free Online Classes</title>
      <description>Everyone knows how to do a simple Google search, but do you know how to read pages in languages you've never studied or track down the location of a friend's picture they took on vacation ages ago? Google wants to show you more tips on how to get the most out of its search results. The search engine giant will be offering a free online, community-based course starting on Tuesday that teaches people different search strategies to find what they need faster and more efficiently. Google -- which first opened registration for the class in June -- will offer six different 50-minute courses called "Power Searching with Google" over the next two weeks. Classes can be taken at your own&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Google, Google Hangouts, google search, SEO</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/google-search-classes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/google-search-classes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Search: Google Offers Free Online Classes</title>
      <description>Everyone knows how to do a simple Google search, but do you know how to read pages in languages you've never studied or track down the location of a friend's picture they took on vacation ages ago? Google wants to show you more tips on how to get the most out of its search results. The search engine giant will be offering a free online, community-based course starting on Tuesday that teaches people different search strategies to find what they need faster and more efficiently. Google -- which first opened registration for the class in June -- will offer six different 50-minute courses called "Power Searching with Google" over the next two weeks. Classes can be taken at your own&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Google, Google Hangouts, google search, SEO</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/google-search-classes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/09/google-search-classes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>37 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>More About: Business , COMMUNICATIONS , Features Week In Review , Social Media , Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/08/digital-media-resources-47/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/08/digital-media-resources-47/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
