<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Tech This Week [PICS]</title>
      <description>1. Flower-Shaped Solar Satellite This elegantly shaped satellite has controllable mirrors that gather sunlight around the clock, turning that sunlight into energy and then sending it back to Earth with an onboard microwave transmitter. Sound far-fetched? Not to NASA, which is funding this spectacular idea. The basic design of the unit is underway, and miniature prototypes to test the concept are in the offering. But there's no word on when such a satellite will be ready to begin generating power from space. [via DVICE]Click here to view this gallery. Putting our reviewers&#8217; hats on this week, we got our hands on four exaggerated examples of state-of-the-art tech, including a laughably enormous television, a monster camera, a whole-house digital video recorder and a world-class workstation shoehorned inside a 27-inch monitor. But even that wasn&#8217;t enough. As is our wont, we peered into the future at a lovely flower-shaped solar satellite, thought we were in the future when we saw an HD broadcast system that you can carry anywhere, discovered a hard drive whose astonishing speed gives us a peek at what all computers will soon be able to do and lusted after a unique timepiece that was the darling of the tech industry this week. SEE ALSO: Previous editions of Top 10 Tech This Week Enjoy those future-forward objects and a lot more on Top 10 Tech This Week &#8212; the most concentrated, efficient and exciting tech coverage on (and off) this planet. Here&#8217;s last week&#8217;s Top 10 Tech. More About: cars, Gadgets, Tech, Top 10 TechFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/top-10-tech-this-week-25/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/top-10-tech-this-week-25/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter tried to buy Instagram, but Facebook pipped it to the post</title>
      <description>Facebook may have secured the $1 billion acquisition of Instagram last week but it appears it wasn&#8217;t the only social network that was interested in the service, with a recent New York Times report suggesting that Twitter was also looking to in the running. According to sources that were familiar with the deal, Twitter co-founder and Instagram investor Jack Dorsey had attempted to secure the purchase of the photo-sharing service in the months before the Facebook deal, but ultimately failed. The NYT writes: Mr. Systrom may have lost one connection in the deal: Mr. Dorsey of Twitter. His company, according to several people briefed on the matter, had expressed interest in buying Instagram in recent months. Mr. Dorsey once used Instagram daily to send photos to Twitter, but he has not been back since the deal was announced, perhaps a sign that he is not happy to see it in the hands of a competitor. A Twitter spokeswoman declined to comment. Dorsey was one of a number of angels that invested in Instagram in February 2011. He joined Chris Sacca, Baseline Ventures, Benchmark Capital and Adam D&#8217;Angelo in a $7 million Series A round. Dorsey may be frustrated at Instagram&#8217;s decision to join Facebook but he will of course have seen a return from the $1 billion acquisition as a result of his earlier investment in the company. He joins Instagram&#8217;s nine employees (with co-founder and CEO Kevin Systrom reporting netting $400 million) and twelve other investors in cashing in from the deal. It also begs the question of whether Twitter&#8217;s interest in the service helped push the purchase price up to the one billion mark. Systrom says has said that the service &#8220;is not going away&#8221; and that the company will be working with Facebook to evolve the service and build the network. He says that you will also continue to be able to share to other social networks, presumably including Twitter, and that the app will keep all of its features. Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg said that the company would continue to build on Instagram&#8217;s strengths, rather than just absorbing its features, ensuring that Instagram will stay independent from its owner. The company wants to spread the app and &#8216;brand&#8217; to more people. Instagram will also retain the ability to post to other networks, not just share photos on Facebook and to keep followers and following lists separate as well. Since the buyout, Instagram&#8217;s winning streak appears to be showing no signs of slowing, with the service appearing to have hit the 40 million user mark just ten days after its Android application launched. When the app hit Google Play, the service already had 30 million users and within a day the Android app saw more than more than a million downloads. Soon after its 1 million download milestone, it hit 5 million Android downloads in six days, making it one of the biggest Android app launches of all time. In comparison, the iOS version of the app took about six months to reach 5 million users. Even the iOS app saw some love, becoming the most popular free app on the App Store for the first time, surpassing its new owner&#8217;s own app: Facebook. Twitter has neglected to comment on speculation, but many were surprised that Twitter had not moved to secure one of the hottest mobile app properties to bolster its growing service. It now appears the company did, but wasn&#8217;t able to secure the deal.</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/twitter/2012/04/14/twitter-tried-to-buy-instagram-but-facebook-pipped-it-to-the-post/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/twitter/2012/04/14/twitter-tried-to-buy-instagram-but-facebook-pipped-it-to-the-post/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Doodle Pays Homage to Street Photographer Robert Doisneau</title>
      <description>Today&#8217;s Google Doodle features photographs from the famed French photographer Robert Doisneau on his 100th birthday. Born April 14, 1912, Doisneau was one of the original street photographers &#8212; he wandered the streets of Paris snapping away with his Leica camera decades before thousands of Brooklyn&#8217;s hipsters would do the same throughout Williamsburg. Doisneau picked up street photography at the age of 16. He entered the world of professional photography in a creative graphics studio and was later hired by French carmaker Renault. After being fired, he became a professional photojournalist and never looked back. He served as a war photographer during World War II and was appointed a Knight of the French Legion of Honor before he died in 1994. &#8220;Le baiser de l&#8217;h&#244;tel de ville (Kiss by the Town Hall),&#8221; a photograph of lovers kissing in the streets of Paris taken in 1950, became his most famous work. Doisneau was once sued by a couple that mistakenly believed themselves to be the pair in the photograph, because French law dictates that a person owns the copyright to their own likeness. Doisneau won the case after revealing that he asked a different couple for permission to take the photograph. &#8220;Lovers kissing in the street, those couples are rarely legitimate,&#8221; he said while explaining why he didn&#8217;t take the shot without permission. What do you think of today&#8217;s Doodle? The Christmas Google Doodle Each package gets larger with a mouse-over, and a click on it returns search results pertinent to a specific country or the particular items featured in a scene. This one is from December 24, 2010.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Google, google doodle, photography, trendingFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/google-doodle-robert-doisneau/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/google-doodle-robert-doisneau/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Outdo Your Competitors</title>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the American Express OPEN Forum, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business. Do you ever feel like there&#8217;s a competitor around every corner? Budding entrepreneurs often hesitate to follow their business dreams because they believe their target market is already so saturated that there simply is no more room to absorb any new entrants. However, savvy small business owners can make it in a crowded field, even one filled with a couple of 800-pound gorillas. The key to your business&#8217; success doesn&#8217;t hinge on finding a completely empty field, but how you define your company and its place in the market. Here are four easy ways to set yourself apart from the din of voices in your industry. Do you have any tips for making it in a crowded market? Let us know in the comments. 1. You Don&#8217;t Have to Reinvent the Wheel Many first-time entrepreneurs make the mistake of thinking they need to blaze a new trail to be successful. Of course, the market always needs innovators, but a business doesn&#8217;t necessarily have to be disruptive in order to succeed. Rather than struggling to come up with a brand new idea, take a look at your target industry and see where there&#8217;s a void to be filled. Then, figure out the best possible way to service that need and run with it. Starbucks wasn&#8217;t the first company to sell coffee, but they did revolutionize the coffee shop by selling an experience along with a caffeine fix. These days there may be more than 17,000 Starbucks all over the world, but other coffeehouses around the country are finding a niche. From Smokey Row in Des Moines, Iowa, to Rock City Caf&#233; in Rockland, Maine, local coffee shops are succeeding by promising more than a cup of coffee and a place to sit. They&#8217;re tapping into some of the most primal elements &#8212; community, connectedness, security and comfort. Your product and service may be similar in many aspects to that of the competition, except for a few defining factors &#8212; and those are the key to everything. You should be good (or great) at all the basics, and then put your energy and focus on being exceptional at what makes you different. 2. Customer-Centric Companies Win When trainer Chris Stevenson wanted to open a fitness center in Southern California, many questioned the decision. Here he was, in the heart of the recession, starting a business in an area that was already saturated with multiple boutique gyms and two large, corporate, chain fitness centers competing for the same customers from the same nearby neighborhoods. Yet despite contending against huge chains with deep pockets and big advertising budgets, Stevenson Fitness is hugely successful today. Why? Chris focused on creating a one-of-a-kind culture at his company that defies people&#8217;s expectations of what a fitness center can be. There&#8217;s no snootiness, intimidation or pretentiousness at Stevenson Fitness. Yes, it offers top-caliber facilities and a great range of classes, but what sets Stevenson Fitness apart is the friendly, approachable personality of the entire staff. The tag line &#8220;Your community, your gym&#8221; says it all. His company continues to grow because customers love what Chris&#8217;s company gives them. No matter how big your business gets and how much staff you bring on, I always advise business owners and top management to stay as close to their customers as possible. Talking to customers one-on-one is the best way to truly take the pulse of the market, customer needs and just how your company is doing. 3. Don&#8217;t Compete on Price Eager to attract customers, many small businesses feel the only way they can compete in a crowded market is to undercut the competition on price. I have to admit that my husband and I fell into this same trap with our company &#8212; we dropped our prices to unsustainable levels. Our business grew, customers were happy, more customers came in, yet we were nearly losing money with every new order. This happens to many small businesses in crowded markets. They find themselves running as fast as they can, yet they are still barely bringing in enough money to keep their operations afloat. Faced with this situation, what we did do? We repositioned from competing on price to competing on service. In a saturated market, someone will always be able (or willing) to absorb a lower cost than you. You&#8217;ll need to find a new way to stand out; for us, this was by offering personal service. We began providing free business consultations to everyone who wanted one. We increased our customer service. We even increased our prices to support the higher service levels, and we saw sales and repeat business rise. The key was defining who we were and what made us different, and then focusing on being as exceptional as possible in those differentiating areas. 4. Saturation Can Mean Strength A competitive and crowded industry indicates that customer demand exists, and that the market is viable. If you carve your own niche, there will be room for your business. If you&#8217;re considering starting a business, don&#8217;t be disheartened if a lot of other companies are already offering a similar kind of product or service. You should still look before you leap and do your research on how you can stand out, but don&#8217;t let the idea of a saturated market stand in your way. More Small Business Resources From OPEN Forum: - Should Small Businesses Follow Everyone Back on Twitter? - Are You Falling into the Pricing Trap? - How to Innovate for Top Social Media Sites Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Maliketh, fotosipsak More About: Business, competition, features, mashable, open forumFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/business-beat-competitors/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/business-beat-competitors/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CEO Bloggers: To Blog or Not to Blog</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: Contributor Ashkan Karbasfrooshan is the founder and CEO of WatchMojo, he hosts a show on business and has published books on success. Follow him @ashkan. &#8220;Where do you get the time to write so much as a company CEO, and more importantly, shouldn&#8217;t you be closing deals or doing something more useful?&#8221; Fair enough. Do What Comes Naturally To You Some entrepreneurs are technologists, others are salespeople, a few are storytellers. The best coders don&#8217;t stop coding even if they run the company. The best cooks never stop cooking even when they open their restaurant. Musicians are always jamming no matter what. Similarly, a storyteller doesn&#8217;t put the pen down because he&#8217;s in pursuit of profit, too. He finds a way to marry the two. If you enjoy writing and happen to be the CEO, then it&#8217;s a marriage made in heaven if you can balance your duties. Regardless of your craft, once you&#8217;re an entrepreneur, you&#8217;re the eternal cheerleader, finding yourself shilling one thing or another. It comes with the territory. When it comes to writing articles &#8211; be it on industry publications or on your company/personal blog &#8211; it&#8217;s actually ineffective to come across as a booster. You&#8217;re better off developing your voice as a contrarian that highlights the macro opportunity in a more realistic and sober way. If you can pull that off, writing will pay dividends, but you will have to address the odd doubter who may wonder if you&#8217;re wasting your time writing. The Obvious Reasons for Blogging #1 &#8211; Own Thyself Anthony Robbins put it best when he said: &#8220;We&#8217;re defined by the stories we tell ourselves.&#8221; Indeed, in a world where others&#8217; perception of you is a function of a Google query, you need to own your online presence, especially as we move away from the Algorithm to an increasingly social world. #2 &#8211; Influence, Authority, and Brand Value is driven by goodwill (defined simply as the value of your brand). Brand building is an exercise done through B2B and B2C initiatives. B2B tools include trade advertising, press releases, the conference circuit as well as writing about the industry you&#8217;re in (and as the CEO of a startup, lessons in entrepreneurship and management, as well). You are competing with many others, some of whom the press will be more enamored with. PR is one of the tools in your arsenal to level the playing field. However, the industry&#8217;s three worst-kept secrets are: - Press releases are ineffective and generally viewed as noise. - Blogs are always looking for more content, so they tend to welcome new guest authors. - Traditional industry publications are seeing their resources reduced, so they will rely on social media and writers on blogs more than ever, creating an opportunity for you to land on big name websites. In any case, once they decide to start writing, initially many executives offer their worldview on their company blogs. This is a sound strategy early-on as you test the waters and hone your style and skill. Before long, publishing on your own blog yields diminishing returns as you won&#8217;t cut through the clutter. As you migrate to publishing on third-party sites, you have to invest the time to embrace and learn the sites&#8217; editorial voice. Then, once you clear that hurdle, you face a cynical audience that assumes you&#8217;re merely shilling. To win them over, you need at least three things: impartiality, authority and repetition, but oftentimes to accomplish any success you need to invest way too much time. It certainly is worth it though, in ways you may find surprising. Less Well-Known Benefits of Becoming the Chief Pontificator #3 &#8211; Leave Your Staff Alone The cardinal sin many CEOs make is micromanaging and suffocating talented employees. Worst even, many try to manage what they don&#8217;t understand. This isn&#8217;t always a result of ego or bad faith. True, some CEOs have a tendency to think they are the lord&#8217;s gift to management and their &#8220;hands-on&#8221; experience knows no boundaries and as such they over-extend themselves. But frequently it&#8217;s because they&#8217;re bored. #4 &#8211; Bide your time Everything takes longer than anticipated. You submit a proposal, then wait. You ask one of your lieutenants to work on something, then wait. More often than not, CEOs find themselves waiting even though few would be considered patient. As such, CEOs look for things to focus their attention to. Effective blogging will keeping a CEO busy and avoid him from micromanaging staff and lieutenants, allowing even the best of teams the time and freedom to do their job. Externally, conventional wisdom suggests that you spend all of your time closing deals. But, the fact is: blogging will be the best lead generator you can imagine, and the point isn&#8217;t to sign as many deals as possible, it&#8217;s to sign the right deals under the right terms. Developing a reputation as an industry leader will enable that. #5 &#8211; Efficiency CEOs field the same questions and repeat answers to multiple stakeholders all the time. Verbal communication is undervalued these days, but people don&#8217;t listen, so sending an article that you wrote (and one that was published on a leading and respected publication) is a powerful way to convey the message. Blogging is also far more efficient and effective than attending conferences. As one industry acquaintance once told me, conferences are akin to AA meetings where you sit around and realize everyone else has the same problems you do. Pick an industry, any industry &#8211; chances are that if you compare the speaker and panelists you will find the same people across the board. Writing on a big platform allows you to reach far more people than attending conferences will, and it will save you tens of thousands of dollars. #6 &#8211; Shutting Up The best part of writing so much is that when you meet people, there&#8217;s a good chance they&#8217;ve read your work, so you can shut up and listen, letting others do the talking because you don&#8217;t need to shill and give them your pitch. #7 &#8211; Learn To publish, you not only need to research your topic, but you need to distill a lot of information into a coherent and cohesive argument or summary. But the true learning starts after you press publish and readers chime in via email, in the comments section and on counter-posts. Yes, Writing is Risky (but so is eating shellfish, get over it) A word to the wise: - You want to avoid giving your team the impression that you&#8217;re communicating through [the Word]Press (even when you are). - People will misinterpret you. That&#8217;s their problem, not yours. But be prepared for it. - You can divulge too much (perhaps, but no one really cares about you that much anyway). - Sure, it&#8217;s nice to build your personal brand, but the focus ought to be on the company &#8211; 100% of the time. There are risks, but writing is one way to strike balance against the rigors of entrepreneurship. After all, if you wake up in the morning and are greeted with bad news, don&#8217;t worry too much because you&#8217;re bound to get worst news later on in the day. And if ever you are greeted with some good news, enjoy it cause it won&#8217;t last, something is bound to go awry. That&#8217;s the startup life. It&#8217;s the end result that matters most (while the journey is a learning experience to you, too). Writing gives you the perspective to be able to see through the trees. To quote Steve Jobs, &#8220;you can&#8217;t connect the dots looking forward&#8220;, but provided writing comes naturally to you, then over time you look back and realize why it always made sense. When it&#8217;s said and done, blogging is a means to an end, so long as it helps you accomplish your objectives, keep writing no matter what some may say. Eventually you realize you no longer need to blog. Then, you can put the pen down and step away from the machine, (or not).</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/14/ceo-bloggers-to-blog-or-not-to-blog/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/14/ceo-bloggers-to-blog-or-not-to-blog/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lunching with strangers: The rise of social meals</title>
      <description>I never expected to pay to lunch with a bunch of strangers. I&#8217;m increasingly cynical about social media and the new social-local-mobile startups, which seem to emerge daily. The craze of collaborative consumption is no exception. From sharing your apartment, to sharing your car, and even to sharing your home-cooked meals, collaborative consumption offers technology that helps you share your goods and experiences. Social eating startups are one flavor currently flooding the collaborative consumption space, with names such as GrubWithUs, LetsLunch, and local DC startup Wednesdays.com. Although I&#8217;m addicted to going out for lunch, the reasons to use Wednesday.com escaped me. What was wrong with the people I was lunching with regularly? However, the technology angel on my shoulder encouraged me to be open-minded. So when an email arrived from Wednesdays.com inviting me to a &#8220;Lean Startup Club Lunch,&#8221; I signed-up. The lunch was billed as a way to discuss the previous night&#8217;s Lean Startup Club meeting (&#8220;Love&#8217;d it? Share your opinion of yesterday&#8217;s meetup with your fellow LSCers over lunch!&#8221;). I imagined meeting a group of diverse people who spanned generations, race, and gender, yet were all interested in entrepreneurship. I had two practical problems here. First, I wasn&#8217;t going to attend the meet-up. Second, at that time I hadn&#8217;t actually read Eric Ries&#8217; The Lean Startup (which I since have, and is worth picking-up). But the lunch was being hosted at a local Turkish restaurant, and the half Turkish side in me required me to hit sign-up. Five other people confirmed for the lunch, which meant five people who could quiz me on my non-existent knowledge of Lean Startup. Not surprisingly, the lunch was on a Wednesday. On my way there, I worried about how I would recognize the other &#8220;social lunchers.&#8221; Thankfully, when I got to the restaurant I noticed a guy who looked similarly confused. We quickly acknowledged our mutual Wednesdays.com connection. Doug Naegele is the founder of infieldhealth, a company he&#8217;s boot-strapped to date, has customers, and is looking to hire in the coming year. He&#8217;s a community leader in mobile health, regularly speaking at various mHealth conferences and events around DC. Soon after, Ben Willman came up and introduced himself. Seeing two awkward guys at a table talking about technology presumably caught his attention. Ben was clearly the most knowledgeable about Lean Startup. He was working on ClientHat to help make virtual assistants more efficient, and told us about his process for customer development as well as his intense customer interviews. It seemed as though he had talked with every virtual assistant on eLance. Even though five others had RSVP&#8217;d, only two had shown up at this point. Right as we were ordering, Todd Fisk came in and quickly joined the table. His startup was chartme.net, an iPad app that allows you to build beautiful charts of any data you want. You could use it to chart your running times, how much you&#8217;ve put in your 401(k), or anything else that might be worth tracking. Todd also didn&#8217;t seem to have read Eric&#8217;s book, but he was interested in how people were integrating its general principles into their work. We had each paid a set $14.55 to sign-up, which included the restaurant&#8217;s lunch special, gratuity, and a $3.50 service fee to Wednesdays.com. The restaurant was semi-aware of what was going on, and gave us a menu of things to pick from. I had an amazing falafel sandwich and hummus sampler, which I enjoyed as I semi-deftly avoided exposing my non-knowledge of Eric&#8217;s new book. I came into the lunch excited for an example of forced serendipity. I assumed that it would be a way to meet people from various points and facets of life, connected merely by our theoretical passion for a book about startup companies. I was wrong. The pre-selection filter that we voluntarily put ourselves through&#8211;our willingness to use a social eating startup, and our interest in a lunch discussing Lean Startup&#8212;resulted in a group of people shockingly similar. Four guys talking about technology is not exactly Earth-shattering. Will I spend future lunch hours eating with strangers from Wednesday.com? To my pride&#8217;s chagrin, yes. While I had brought the wrong expectations, it was a way to take myself out of my usual group of friends and lunch buddies and discover new people to learn from. And if collaborative consumption startups lead me to new experiences and new people, I&#8217;ll ease off the skepticism. Jandrie Lombard, mehmetcan via shutterstock</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/04/14/lunching-with-strangers-the-rise-of-social-meals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/04/14/lunching-with-strangers-the-rise-of-social-meals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest Users: What&#8217;s the World&#8217;s Most Beautiful Country? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>The world has fallen in love with Pinterest, the social network with beautiful images at its core. Now Pinterest users get to decide where they most love in the world. A crowdsourced project created by travel site First Choice &#8212; living in an interactive HTML5 infographic &#8212; is asking globally-minded Pinterest users which country is the world&#8217;s most beautiful. First Choice hopes the competition will awaken a desire for travel among users. You can vote on Twitter or Pinterest for your favorite country, and share the reason behind your choice. When you explore the graphic, you can see the pins submitted for other countries and learn why others voted for them as most beautiful. As we published this, the UK was winning the infographic contest, with the U.S. in 6th place. That could change many times over, however. An added perk to participation: a chance to win a DSLR camera. Do you have a travel board on Pinterest? Does using the site encourage you to travel? More About: infographic, non-profits, pinterest, Social GoodFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/pinterest-infographic-travel/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/pinterest-infographic-travel/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retro Digital Cinema Camera Is a Hit on Kickstarter [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Meet the Digital Bolex D16, a small hand-held video camera inspired by the cinema-quality Bolex cameras popular in the 1960s and &#8217;70s. The Digital Bolex mimics 16mm film, which essentially provides independent filmmakers an affordable alternative to shoot high-quality, raw images that aren&#8217;t compressed. The project has raised more than $262,000 on Kickstarter.com. The first 100 backers will receive the Bolex D16 for $2,500 &#8212; a $800 discount, says inventors Elle Schneider and Joe Rubinstein. The Kickstarter fund will help the creators develop the cutting-edge camera technology further. &#8220;Think of the difference between a blocky, low-res JPEG image you find online, and a smooth high-res photographic print in a gallery,&#8221; Rubinstein said on the Kickstarter page. &#8220;That&#8217;s the difference between compressed, normal video footage and raw. It&#8217;s a big difference.&#8221; The Digital Bolex D16 prototype shoots completely in raw format files. The filmmaker can then adjust color balance, contrast, white balance and more without diminishing the quality of images. The camera has a side crank that is easily programmable to control frame rates or other camera functions. The D16 offers high-quality resolution (comparable to the HD-quality of the new iPad). Its creators claim the D16 is the first truly cinema camera featuring RAW, uncompressed video recordings. The camera stores data on dual CF cards. &#8220;There is no camera on the market that offers affordable RAW quality to consumers and independent filmmakers,&#8221; Rubinstein said. Would you back or purchase a Digital Bolex D16? Tell us in the comments. Image courtesy of Kickstarter, Joe Rubinstein More About: camera, kickstarter, Raw, VideoFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/digital-bolex/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/digital-bolex/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 7 Mashable Comments of the Week</title>
      <description>Out of all the stories from this past week, none drew a bigger response from our readers than Facebook acquisition of Instagram. The Monday announcement prompted many users of the photo-sharing app to delete the app altogether. Mashable reader Trager Jonnes understood the outrage that some Instagram users felt about the acquisition &#8220;given FB&#8217;s history of awful privacy controls and commercial use of personal information.&#8221; In addition to our community&#8217;s reaction to the Instagram acquisition, readers also continued the discussion about employers asking interviewees for their Facebook login information. Mashable commenter rjsinc added his opinion that &#8221;your personal time has nothing to do with your work for most jobs.&#8221; At Mashable, we&#8217;re always on the lookout for thoughtful, insightful comments that add to our story or further the discussion. Take a look at this week&#8217;s top comments and let us know what you think. Amber Gordon, Gary Reed, Chris Sully, Trager Jonnes Instagram users threatened to leave after it was announced that Facebook acquired the network. Comments originally seen on Many Instagram Users Already Heading for the ExitsClick here to view this gallery. If you haven&#8217;t commented on a Mashable article before, check out Mashable Follow, our content curation and social tool, as well as our comment guidelines to learn more. We&#8217;d love for you to join the conversation. More About: community, top commentsFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/top-comments-april-14-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/top-comments-april-14-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Things That Waste Your Time at Work [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Aside from the time you purposefully waste at work &#8212; checking Facebook or playing Draw Something, as the kids do &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of other stuff that can slow you down at the office. The productivity of a &#8220;knowledge worker&#8221; (read: non-farmer) hinges on communication and the ability to locate information quickly. VoIP communications company Fonality conducted a survey to find out which mundane office tasks suck the most time out of the day. Pinpointing and compiling all those wasted man hours could save companies some substantial coin. The folks at social performance management tool Rypple compiled the infographic below based on that data. The top time stealer? Trying to contact customers or colleagues. Duplicate or unwanted information (including spam) ranks highly as well. SEE ALSO: The Internet Is Ruining Your Brain [INFOGRAPHIC] The study also proposes that &#8220;unified communications&#8221; (UC) solutions can reduce much of this waste, though it&#8217;s difficult to determine by how much. &#8220;Calculating the potential cost savings for a UC implementation is an inexact science at best. Each company has different needs. And UC implementations do not consist of an exact set of components,&#8221; the report reads. Still, it doesn&#8217;t take a rocket scientist to see that cloud computing is one way to mitigate certain time sucks. What factors waste your precious time at work? Can they be overcome with better technology? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail courtesy of iStockphoto, daneger More About: Business, infographics, productivity, workFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/wasting-time-work/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/wasting-time-work/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix&#8217;s Unlimited Employee Vacation Policy: Why It Works</title>
      <description>Netflix employees have one less things to keep track of: the amount of vacation days they take. Co-founder Reed Hastings recently told Bloomberg Businessweek that Netflix has an unlimited vacation policy. In an effort to separate itself from bureaucratic corporations, Netflix, with its 900 employees, abandoned the typical vacation allotment to opt for a sky&#8217;s-the-limit plan. Keeping vacation unlimited, said Hastings, requires mature, responsible employees who care about high-quality work. Netflix has a &#8220;freedom and responsibility culture,&#8221; Hastings told the publication in an article entitled, &#8220;How To Set Your Employees Free.&#8221; Hastings said Netflix gauges success by focusing on what employees get done, not on how many days they worked. The CEO does make sure to be a good role model and takes vacations, where he can do some creative thinking. Hasting explained how the idea evolved: &#8220;My first company, Pure Software, was exciting and innovative in the first few years and bureaucratic and painful in the last few before it got acquired. The problem was we tried to systemize everything and set up perfect procedures. We thought that was a good thing, but it killed freedom and responsibility. After the company was acquired, I reflected on what went wrong.&#8221; The pressure to hang onto one&#8217;s job in a bad economy, and smaller staffs at some organizations, have caused many workers to push themselves to burnout mode. Now, it seems, there may be a growing focus on employees regaining a work-life balance. SEE ALSO: Sheryl Sandberg Leaves Work at 5:30 Every Day &#8212; And You Should Too Netflix isn&#8217;t the only company that has jumped on the all-you-want vacation bandwagon. IBM has a famously flexible time-off policy &#8212; letting employees leave early and take a day off on short notice, just so long as they have a handle on their workloads. Numerous startups and innovative companies working in the tech space are beginning to see the benefits of ditching vacation limits and promoting personal responsibility. What do you think about unlimited vacation policies? Does your employer offer a flexible or unlimited vacation policy? Tell us in the comments. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, Crisma&#8236; More About: IBM, netflix, reed hastings, trending, vacationFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/netflix-unlimited-vacation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/netflix-unlimited-vacation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RT @lucymarcus: RT @theJeremyVine: "Perhaps the best BBC News caption you will ever, ever see http://t.co/IXJnOYIb&#8221; (via @seb_sears)</title>
      <description>Kysen: RT @lucymarcus: RT @theJeremyVine: "Perhaps the best BBC News caption you will ever, ever see http://t.co/IXJnOYIb&#8221; (via @seb_sears) &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://yfrog.com/ntrwojrj</link>
      <guid>http://yfrog.com/ntrwojrj</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
