<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Facebook Account Archive Now Includes Friend Requests, IP Addresses</title>
      <description>Facebook has upgraded its &#8220;Download Your Information&#8221; feature with several new categories of information. The feature, which can be found in Facebook Account Settings, was first introduced in October 2010, enabling users to download an archive of their entire account history. The info included photos, posts, messages, friend lists and chats. Now, when you download your information from Facebook, you&#8217;ll also get your previous names, friend requests, and even IP addresses you logged in from. The archive still doesn&#8217;t include your friends&#8217; photos and status updates, other users&#8217; personal info and comments you&#8217;ve made on other people&#8217;s posts. The feature will be rolling out gradually, Facebook says, promising even more categories of information available for download in the future. BONUS: How the Facebook Profile Has Changed 2005 - The Facebook Back in the days when The Facebook was only available to select networks, the News Feed didn't exist. Users hopped between profiles like this one.Click here to view this gallery. More About: download your information, Facebook, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/12/facebook-account-history/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/12/facebook-account-history/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Look: Samsung Galaxy Player 3.6</title>
      <description>The new Samsung Galaxy Player 3.6 looks strikingly similar to an Android smartphone, but the device is actually the latest media player to grace the growing category. The good news, however, is that it can even make calls and send text messages via Bluetooth. The device &#8212; which runs on Gingerbread 2.3.6 &#8212; is like many media players on the market today, with solid audio quality and a collection of apps. But what&#8217;s especially interesting about the Samsung Galaxy Player 3.6 is that it can be tethered to a phone with Bluetooth 3.0 to send and receive calls. This feature might be appealing for those that want to avoid paying for another phone and adding to monthly bills. To make use of this feature, you&#8217;ll have to turn to an alternative service such as Google Voice and be connected via Wi-Fi at the same time. From a design perspective, the device boasts a plastic body, 3.6-inch screen, 480 x 320 resolution display and a single-core Cortex A8 1GHz processor. Weighing in at 3.9 ounces, it is 0.3 ounces heavier than a classic iPod Touch yet feels less sturdy. The $149 device is also less expensive than the iPod Touch ($199), but the plastic body &#8212; compared to the iPod Touch&#8217;s stainless steel casing &#8212; makes it not surprising that it&#8217;s listed at a lower price point. However, the interface is easy to navigate and it&#8217;s also laid out intuitively. Sound quality is also crisp and clean. Sound is also crisp and clean. Other features include a rear-facing camera lens and a whole collection of apps, including FM radio, maps, Gmail, Google search and Social Hub. The Samsung Galaxy Player 3.6 is available now at Best Buy. Do you think there is still a need for media players or should all phones incorporate these types of capabilities? Let us know in the comments. More About: apple, iPod Touch, media players, samsung, smartphones</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/samsung-galaxy-player-36/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/samsung-galaxy-player-36/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone-Friendly Watch Gets $500,000 Kickstarter Funding in a Day</title>
      <description>Hey iPhone users: how many times a day do you take your beloved device out of your pocket just to check the time, change the tune, check email or see who&#8217;s calling? What if we wore some kind of notification device on our wrists &#8212; let&#8217;s call them watches &#8212; that could connect to your iPhone to do all of the above and more? And what if it didn&#8217;t cost an arm and a leg? Smart watches aren&#8217;t exactly a new notion. In the past year we&#8217;ve seen and reviewed several: the InPulse, the WiMM One and the oddly-named I&#8217;m Watch. But they were all powered by Android, or connected to Android smartphones only. iPhone owners were out of luck &#8212; until Wednesday, when a new smart watch by the guy behind InPulse (Eric Migicovsky, above) hit funding site Kickstarter. Dubbed the Pebble, it&#8217;s the first smart watch that can form a meaningful, long-lasting relationship with your iOS device, as well as Android. And it&#8217;s nothing if not popular. The Kickstarter campaign asked for $100,000 in funding; it got that in the first two hours. By day&#8217;s end, the device had more than $500,000 in pledges. What&#8217;s so smart about the Pebble? Well, for starters, it doesn&#8217;t try to reinvent the wheel. Other smart watches offer color screens as if they&#8217;re trying to be a mini-smartphone. The Pebble lets your iPhone do all the heavy lifting. Its simple e-paper display &#8212; much like the original Kindle &#8212; is viewable even in direct sunlight, which is pretty necessary for a watch. It is also releasing its software kit to developers, so they can create their own iPhone app-linking apps. Out of the box, you&#8217;ll be able to see incoming emails and calls, track your run and your bike ride via your phone&#8217;s GPS, as well as use your watch as a remote for the music app on your phone. That feature alone seems worth the asking price &#8212; which, by the way, will be $149. Check out the video below for more, and let us know in the comments: would you wear this? More About: inPulse, iphone, kickstarter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/iphone-watch-pebble-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/iphone-watch-pebble-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why CEOs Should Allow Facebook in the Workplace [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Many CEOs forbid use of social media at work, but recent research shows that web surfing leads to increased productivity. This Keas infographic explores the benefits of social media in the workplace, showing that social connections make people happier and a brief recess involving Internet-browsing increases productivity. An Academy of Management experiment gave three groups of people &#8212; a control group bundling sticks, a group taking an Internet-free break and a group browsing the Internet for 10 minutes &#8212; the simple task of highlighting as many letter A&#8217;s as they could among 2,000 words of text. The three groups then had their mental exhaustion measured. Those browsing the Internet were 16% more productive than the Internet-free break group and 39% more productive than the control group. SEE ALSO: 37 Productivity Tips for Working From Anywhere The study concludes that taking a break, particularly one spent browsing the Internet, should be encouraged by employers hoping to increase productivity. Do you use Facebook at work? Does it negatively or positively affect your concentration? Sound off in the comments. More About: Facebook, workplaceFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/facebook-workplace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/facebook-workplace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get more likes on Facebook</title>
      <description>More tanks. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DRAMATIC SURPRISE ON A QUIET SQUARE</title>
      <description>(18 votes - 1 comment - 127 views)YT: "To launch the high quality TV channel TNT in Belgium we placed a big red push button on an average Flemish square of an average Flemish town. A sign with the text "Push to add drama" invited people to use the button. And then we waited"</description>
      <link>http://music.videosift.com/video/So-they-installed-a-Push-to-add-drama-button-in-Belgium</link>
      <guid>http://music.videosift.com/video/So-they-installed-a-Push-to-add-drama-button-in-Belgium</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today&#8217;s Top Stories: Sony Confirms Layoffs, DOJ Sues Apple</title>
      <description>Welcome to this morning&#8217;s edition of &#8220;First To Know,&#8221; a series in which we keep you in the know on what&#8217;s happening in the digital world. Today, we&#8217;re looking at three particularly interesting stories. Sony Confirms 10,000 Layoffs In Major Reorganization Sony has confirmed it plans to cut 10,000 jobs globally by the end of 2012. The company has laid out a major reorganization plan, projecting it will result in net sales of 6 trillion yen ($74 billion) and an operating income margin of 5% in its electronics business by 2014. DOJ Sues Apple Over Ebook Price Fixing Yesterday&#8217;s report that the Department of Justice plans to sue Apple and five major publishers over ebook price fixing has turned out to be true. &#8220;As a result of this alleged conspiracy, we believe that consumers paid millions of dollars more for some of the most popular titles,&#8221; said Attorney General Eric Holder. Samsung Galaxy Tab 2 7.0 Is Coming to the U.S. on April 22 Samsung has announced the launch dates for its two upcoming Android tablets: Samsung Galaxy Tab 2 7.0 and Samsung Galaxy Tab 2 10.1. The smaller tablet is coming on April 22, with pre-orders opening on April 12. The Galaxy Tab 2 10.1 is coming on May 13, with pre-orders starting May 4. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, mattjeacock More About: apple, eBook, features, first to know series, Galaxy Tab 2, mashable, samsung, sonyFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/12/todays-top-stories-sony-confirms-layoffs-doj-sues-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/12/todays-top-stories-sony-confirms-layoffs-doj-sues-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smartphone Sales to Hit 1 Billion Mark in 2014 [STUDY]</title>
      <description>The brokerage also expects Apple, the world's top smartphone maker, to gain the most</description>
      <link>http://macdailynews.com/2012/04/12/credit-suisse-smartphone-unit-sales-to-hit-1-billion-mark-in-2014-apple-to-gain-the-most/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wordpress%2FxhfA+%28MacDailyNews%29</link>
      <guid>http://macdailynews.com/2012/04/12/credit-suisse-smartphone-unit-sales-to-hit-1-billion-mark-in-2014-apple-to-gain-the-most/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+wordpress%2FxhfA+%28MacDailyNews%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram Aftermath: It&#8217;s Time For Entrepreneurs To Go All In</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: Adeo Ressi is founding member at TheFunded and The Founder Institute. Follow him on Twitter @adeoressi. Q: What does the Instagram acquisition mean for startups? A: A LOT. At the close of 2011, there was a lot of uncertainty for startups. Stock market fluctuations, underwhelming talent acquisitions (&#8220;acqui-hires&#8221;), and structural investment problems threatened the prospects for startups. But what a difference a few weeks can make. The passage of crowdfunding legislation in the US coupled with the $1 billion acquisition offer of Instragram, signals the beginning of a full startup boom. In preparation for the good times, venture capitalists have started to raise new fund money at their pre-crash highs. Two and a half years ago, Mint.com was acquired for $170 million, and everyone thought that was an amazing deal following the great recession. Now, a fledgling company with a small team gets acquired for $1 billion. My best guess is that it is about to get crazy. And, only fools sit on the sidelines. Many strong and older entrepreneurs that I know are wealthy today because they made intelligent decisions during the dot-com bubble of the late &#8217;90s. Success was not easy then, and it will not be easy now, either. But, the likelihood of a great outcome is much higher in a boom. There are a lot of newly minted entrepreneurs that pursue their dream company in a half-hearted way. You may tinker with your idea while toiling at a day job. You may refuse to put in the work required to recruit the best talent. You might be afraid of launching an imperfect product. Or, you may put a mediocre effort into fundraising. However, if you want to take advantage of a boom cycle and reap the rewards, you need to slide all of your chips on to the table. You need to go all in. And, you need to play smart. Every move that you take and every bet that you make needs to have the best odds of success. You can&#8217;t enter the game too late, either. If what I predict happens, very soon you will start to read about more and more crazy deals. When &#8220;crazy&#8221; becomes the new normal, the opportunity will have already passed you by. So, let me get really specific. As an entrepreneur, you have a decision to make. Ask yourself, &#8220;is this my boom?&#8221; If your answer is &#8220;yes,&#8221; then you have a lot of work to do. Look around you. If everyone that you deal with is not top-notch, from cofounders to vendors, fire them immediately and bring on the best. Now. Right now. Seriously. Now. To really win during a boom, you need to play at the top level, and the winners in every boom always have the best talent. Always. Is it your time? Is this your boom? [image via flickr/V1LL14N]</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/11/instagram-all-in/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/11/instagram-all-in/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a simpler, more beautiful Google</title>
      <description>More than 170 million people have upgraded to Google+, enjoying new ways to share in Search, Gmail, YouTube and lots of other places. It's still early days, and there&#8217;s plenty left to do, but we're more excited than ever to build a seamless social experience, all across Google. A critical piece of this social layer is a design that grows alongside our aspirations. So today we&#8217;re introducing a more functional and flexible version of Google+. We think you&#8217;ll find it easier to use and nicer to look at, but most importantly, it accelerates our efforts to create a simpler, more beautiful Google.Navigation you can make your own One of the first things you&#8217;ll notice is a new way to get around the stream. Instead of static icons at the top, there&#8217;s a dynamic ribbon of applications on the left. This approach comes with lots of perks, but some of our favorites include:You can drag apps up or down to create the order you want You can hover over certain apps to reveal a set of quick actions You can show or hide apps by moving them in and out of &#8220;More&#8221; Taken together, these powers make it easier to access your favorites, and to adjust your preferences over time. We've also built the ribbon with the future in mind, giving us an obvious (and clutter-free) space for The Next Big Feature, and The Feature After That. So stay tuned.Conversations you&#8217;ll really care about Once you&#8217;ve upgraded to Google+, it&#8217;s easy to share with your circles from just about anywhere. We&#8217;re dreaming bigger, though. We're aiming for an experience that fuses utility with beauty&#8212;one that inspires you to connect with others, and cherish the conversations that unfold. Today&#8217;s update is an important step in this direction, including:Full bleed photos and videos that'll make you really proud to post A stream of conversation "cards" that make it easier to scan and join discussions An activity drawer that highlights the community around your content Simply put, we're hoping to make sharing more awesome by making it more evocative. You know that feeling you get when a piece of art takes your breath away, or when a friend stops by with unexpected gifts? We want sharing to feel like that, every single time.A new home for hanging out Google+ Hangouts uses live video to bring people together, and the results range from heartwarming to breathtaking to music-making. Today we're adding a dedicated Hangouts page that creates even more opportunities to connect in person, including:An always-updated list of invitations from the people in your circles Quick access to every public and On Air hangout, for those times when you want to meet someone new, or watch a live broadcast A rotating billboard of popular hangouts, pro tips and other items you don&#8217;t want to miss By highlighting all the hangouts you can join, all over the world, it&#8217;s now easier to spend time together&#8212;even be there for each other. And with efforts like hangout apps already underway, you can expect more hangouts in more places in the future.Getting there from here Today's Google+ update extends beyond navigation, the stream and hangouts. For instance: there's a new Explore page that shows what's interesting and trending across the network. And a new profile with much bigger photos. And a new chat list that puts your friends front and center. And a whole lot more. We're rolling out all of these improvements over the next few days, so please check back if you don't see them yet. In the meantime, you can visit this overview to learn more. By focusing on you, the people you care about, and the stuff you&#8217;re into, we&#8217;re going to continue upgrading all the features you already know and love&#8212;from Search and Maps to Gmail and YouTube. With today&#8217;s foundational changes we can move even faster&#8212;toward a simpler, more beautiful Google.Posted by Vic Gundotra, Senior Vice President</description>
      <link>http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/04/toward-simpler-more-beautiful-google.html</link>
      <guid>http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/04/toward-simpler-more-beautiful-google.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google+ Rolls Out New Look</title>
      <description>Google announced on Wednesday that it is rolling out a significant redesign for its social networking platform Google+, which will allow users to create a more customized experience on the site. The company said it will introduce a variety of new features to the site in the next few days, from customizing apps and the navigation bar to more flexibility with profile pages and pictures. In addition, the update introduces a new Explore page that posts what&#8217;s interesting and trending across the site. Google also noted that the social network now boasts more than 170 million users since it&#8217;s 2011 launch. Google+ will now offer profile pages that will include bigger photos, a la Facebook&#8217;s Timeline, and feature a chat list that puts friends front and center on your page. Another major update involves how users can navigate around the news stream. Instead of static icons at the top, there&#8217;s a ribbon of apps on the left. The ribbon allows users to drag apps up or down to create the order, hover over certain apps to reveal a set of quick actions and show or hide apps by moving them out of the section. &#8220;Taken together, these powers make it easier to access your favorites, and to adjust your preferences over time,&#8221; Google senior vice president Vic Gundotra wrote on Google&#8217;s Official Blog. &#8220;We&#8217;ve also built the ribbon with the future in mind, giving us an obvious (and clutter-free) space for The Next Big Feature, and The Feature After That. So stay tuned.&#8221; A dedicated Hangouts page has also been added to the site, so people can have quick access to public and On Air video chat hangouts. This will allow Google+ users to meet new people and watch live broadcasts, as well as enter new rooms via a rotating billboard of Hangouts. &#8220;It&#8217;s still early days, and there&#8217;s plenty left to do, but we&#8217;re more excited than ever to build a seamless social experience, all across Google,&#8221; Gundotra said. What do you think of the redesign? Do you think Google+ will ever be able to compete with Facebook? Let us know in the comments. More About: Google, google plus hangouts, Google Plus profiles</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/google-plus-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/google-plus-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
