<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[from heyjude] Know and show what you got! - TwentyFeet - TwentyFeet Wiki</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; The performance post for twitter is a cool way to recap your last week for your followers and friends. &lt;p&gt; It's for free. You can do that with your "forever free" twitter account. It contains the changes in your key twitter metrics. We will only post positive changes (e.g. a growing number of followers). The "My week on twitter"-post is published at the beginning of the week automatically (only for authorized accounts and if you choose so).</description>
      <link>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</link>
      <guid>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn 4x Better for B2B Leads than Facebook or Twitter</title>
      <description>I presented at the LinkedIn #B2BConnect 2012 event on April 17, 2012 in Mumbai, India. A few weeks ago as I was preparing my talk, I asked my friends at HubSpot if they had any data on the effectiveness of LinkedIn that I could share with my audience. Rebecca Corliss came through with some awesome new data which I am releasing for the first time here.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/davidmeermanscott/493633/linkedin-4x-better-b2b-leads-facebook-or-twitter-says-hubspot-study</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/davidmeermanscott/493633/linkedin-4x-better-b2b-leads-facebook-or-twitter-says-hubspot-study</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Timeline Changed the Way We See Brand Profiles. Here&#8217;s How</title>
      <description>When Facebook launched Timeline for brands last month, it wasn&#8217;t just marketers&#8217; social media strategies that got turned upside down. The new format also changed the way consumers experience brands on Facebook. In a webcam eye-tracking study for Mashable by EyeTrackShop, participants spent less time looking at Wall posts and ads and more time looking at the cover photo on brands&#8217; timelines than they did on their old Facebook Walls. &#8220;The new Facebook Timeline limits the effective branding space, and the top portion of the page must be effectively utilized,&#8221; suggest the study&#8217;s authors. SEE ALSO: Here&#8217;s How People Look at Your Facebook Profile &#8212; Literally EyeTrackShop recorded eye movements of 30 participants as they were shown brand profiles &#8212; before and after being converted to timeline &#8212; from the Dallas Cowboys, Good Morning America, &#8220;The Muppets&#8221; and Pepsi in 10-second intervals. What participants looked at on each webpage, for how long and in what order is recorded in the images below. Results suggests a few ways our perception of Brands on Facebook has changed: Ads on Facebook Timeline are less visible than ads on Facebook Brand Pages. While 30%-40% of study participants looked at ads on brand Timeline pages, 80% looked at them on Brand Pages. In both cases, ads placed higher up on the page fared better than those below them. Cover photos are the new Facebook Wall (at least as far as attention goes). On brand pages, Wall posts were the star attraction. Viewers on average looked at them first and for the longest amount of time. On the brand Timelines, however, viewers always looked at the cover photo first. In all but one case, they spent a longer time looking at it than at Timeline content. Everyone will notice your cover photo. It&#8217;s larger than anything else and at the top of the page for a reason, and 100% of viewers looked at it. On average, they saw it in 0.5 seconds or less. Meanwhile, only 65% to 92% of viewers noticed profile photos on Brand Pages. Viewers see Timeline content last. In every case, viewers looked at either the left or right column of Timeline content last &#8212; after ads, navigation buttons and brand logos. Information that was invisible is now a focal point. Facebook moved the number of Likes, events and apps to prime top-and-center territory. It now gets more attention than when it was listed on the right-hand side of the page. In the case of Good Morning America, for instance, the show&#8217;s 585,000 Likes went from being completely ignored on its Brand Page to being the biggest attention-getter on its Timeline. Cover photos with faces attract the most attention. Good Morning America and &#8220;The Muppets&#8221; have cover photos with faces, whereas the Dallas Cowboys and Pepsi do not. The cover photos with faces attracted more attention. Take a look at the results of the study in the gallery, and let us know your own observations in the comments. Dallas Cowboys: Visual Attention Level Areas that were looked at most are shown in red on the heat map. In the Timeline, viewers concentrated more of their time at the top of the page.Click here to view this gallery. More About: EyeTrackShop, Facebook, facebook timeline, MarketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/facebook-timeline-eyetrack-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/facebook-timeline-eyetrack-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Hilarious &#8216;Avengers&#8217; Parodies [VIDEOS]</title>
      <description>1. The Avengers (on a budget) What happens when you combine a few friends, some homemade superhero costumes and a few special effects? This hilarious, low-budget version of The Avengers.Click here to view this gallery.The Avengers theatrical release is May 4, and the film is starting to receive a lot of buzz on social media. But these fans aren&#8217;t just talking about the movie while they wait &#8212; they&#8217;re playing the parts themselves. These iconic comic book characters have long been childhood heroes to many. Some are so enthusiastic about the film, they&#8217;ve created parody trailers and spoofs in anticipation. Who knew so many people liked to dress up as superheroes with their friends? SEE ALSO: The Avengers AR App Turns You Into a Superhero From the high-quality, edited trailers to the low-budget, hilarious camera tricks, we&#8217;ve assembled eight of the funniest Avengers parodies that YouTube has to offer. Which group do you think pulled off The Avengers team best? Let us know in the comments. More About: Entertainment, features, Film, humor, YouTubeFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/avengers-parodies/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/avengers-parodies/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK ISPs must block The Pirate Bay</title>
      <description>Five major UK internet service providers are ordered by the High Court to prevent users from accessing popular file-sharing site The Pirate Bay.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-17894176</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-17894176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teen Demands Seventeen Magazine Publish Non-Photoshopped Spread</title>
      <description>Another teen is using Change.org to make her voice heard. This time, it&#8217;s 14-year-old Julia Bluhm, who has rallied more than 7,000 signatures on a petition calling for Seventeen Magazine to print one unaltered photo spread in each of its monthly issues. &#8220;I&#8217;m a teenage girl, and I know how it feels to think you&#8217;re not good enough,&#8221; Bluhm says. &#8220;I want girls to be able to feel good about themselves, and being able to relate to the images in the magazines we read will help.&#8221; Bluhm, a ballet dancer from Maine, hopes Seventeen will follow Glamour&#8216;s lead, which recently announced it would stop altering images of models to make them look thinner. The 8th grader&#8217;s petition says Seventeen should use its platform to promote positive body images to its teenage readers. &#8220;Seventeen Magazine is supposed to be a relatable magazine, right? How can we relate to computer altered photos?&#8221; Bluhm says. &#8220;Seventeen is popular with my friends and lots of teen girls. If they agree to print one unaltered spread a month, they could start a trend that will help so many girls like me feel better about their bodies.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Facebook Campaign for &#8216;Bald Barbie&#8217; Gains Steam Bluhm, who describes herself as a feminist and an activist, blogs for the SPARK Movement, a girl-led movement fighting the sexualization of women in the media. Another Change.org campaign started by Michigan teen Katy Butler, petitioning the MPAA to change the rating of Bully, amassed more than half a million signatures last month. While Bluhm&#8217;s petition still has a long way to go before reaching the hundreds of thousands of signatures threshold, it joins a growing social media conversation about the promotion of positive body image. Tumblr and Pinterest have recently updated their policies regarding the promotion of pro-anorexia content. Is it the responsibility of teen-focused magazines to use their platforms to promote positive body image for young woman? Let us know in the comments if Bluhm has it right. BONUS: 15 Photoshopped Transformations of Celebs and Models hr&gt; Fergie Click here to view this gallery. More About: change.org, online activism, online petition, seventeenFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/seventeen-photoshop-petition/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/seventeen-photoshop-petition/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom Tower: 11 Beautiful Instagram Photos of NYC&#8217;s Tallest New Building</title>
      <description>1. John de Guzm&#225;n This clever eye trick resulted in a stunning photo. In the caption, de Guzm&#225;n says he's "building hope."Click here to view this gallery.A steel beam was secured to One World Trade Center Monday, making it officially the tallest building in New York City. The tower now stands at 1,271 feet, and users on Instagram have been sharing their view of the building from all over New York, using the hashtags #WTC1 and #FreedomTower. Once finished, the building will be 1,776 feet have 104 floors, including 71 office floors with 3 million square feet of space. We&#8217;ve gathered 10 great photos of the building, from right in front, to a lovely view of the skyline from Staten Island. Take a look, and please share your own pics in the comments. Image courtesy of mdose More About: features, instagram, new york city, picsFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/one-world-trade-center-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/one-world-trade-center-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips for Great Content Curation</title>
      <description>Steven Rosenbaum is the CEO of Magnify.net, a real-time video curation engine for publishers, brands, and websites. He&#8217;s also the author of Curation Nation. You&#8217;ve heard the buzz word &#8212; curation &#8212; being thrown around like it&#8217;s a gadget we all know how to work. In reality, good content curation isn&#8217;t as simple as pushing a share button. It&#8217;s actually a combination of finding great content and following some simple best practices on how to successfully share that content. If you&#8217;re a curator looking for some boundaries in what feels like the Wild West, here are five best practices to consider. 1. Be Part of the Content Ecosystem Be part of the content ecosystem, not just a re-packager of it. Often, people think of themselves as either creators or curators as if these two things are mutually exclusive. What a curator really should do is embrace content as both a maker and an organizer. The most successful curators include sites like The Huffington Post, that embrace the three-legged-stool philosophy of creating some content, inviting visitors to contribute some content, and gathering links and articles from the web. Created, contributed, and collected &#8212; the three &#8216;c&#8217;s is a strong content mix that has a measurable impact. Why? Because your visitors don&#8217;t want to hunt around the web for related material. Once they find a quality, curated collection, they&#8217;ll stay for related offerings. 2. Follow a Schedule Audiences expect some regularity, and they&#8217;ll reward you for it. It doesn&#8217;t need to be a schedule that you can&#8217;t keep up with. If you want to curate three new links a day, and write one big post a week, that&#8217;s a schedule. Make sure to post at the same time each week. This is so readers know when to expect new material from you. Consistency and regularity will also bring you new users, and help you grow a loyal base of members who appreciate your work. A good example of someone who gets why a schedule makes a difference is Jason Hirschhorn via his MediaReDEF newsletter. He never misses a publish date. 3. Embrace Multiple Platforms It used to be that your audience came to you. Not anymore. Today content consumers get their information on the platform of their choosing. That means you should consider posting short bursts on Tumblr, images on Pinterest, video on YouTube, and community conversations on Facebook. And don&#8217;t leave out established sites and publishers. If your audience hangs out on a blog, you may want to offer that publication some guest posts or even a regular column. Essentially, you have to bring your content contributions to wherever your readers may be. 4. Engage and Participate Having a voice as a curator means more than creating and curating your own work. Make sure you&#8217;re giving back by reading others and commenting on their posts. A re-tweet is one of the easiest ways to help build relationships with fellow bloggers and curators. And your followers will appreciate that you&#8217;ve pointed them to good content. One word here, I never hit an RT without clicking through to read what I&#8217;m recommending. You can also lose followers if you don&#8217;t put in the effort to recommend material that you really think merits their attention. 5. Share. Don&#8217;t Steal. Take the time to give attribution, link backs, and credit. The sharing economy works because we&#8217;re each sharing our audiences, and providing the value of our endorsements. If you pick up someone&#8217;s work and put it on your blog, or mention a fact without crediting the source, you&#8217;re not building shared credibility. You&#8217;re just abusing someone else&#8217;s effort. The important thing to realize is that we&#8217;re increasingly living in a world of information overload. So when people choose to listen to you it&#8217;s because you&#8217;re able to separate signal from noise. You provide a clear, contextually relevant voice within the topic or topics that you create and curate. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, JamesBrey More About: content curation, contributor, features, online marketing, Web curation</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/tips-great-content-curation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/tips-great-content-curation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mashable Weekend Recap: 41 Stories You Might Have Missed</title>
      <description>The weekend flew by here at Mashable, where we encountered a variety of stories and topics. Taking those topics and creating features, reviews, roundups, videos and posts for you resulted in this burgeoning Mashable Weekend Recap. Missed all the fun? Understandable, especially when there was a wonderful slate of mid-spring weekend activities happening all over the world. Not to worry, because all the stories we covered over the past couple of days are easy to find, right here on this page. So go out there and make it another productive and enjoyable week, but begin by starting things off right with these 40 memorable and engaging stories we published for you over the weekend: News &amp; Opinion Essentials Future of TV Apps, A Sensitive and Popular Topic [VIDEO] Top 10 Tech This Week [PICS] Magazines Get Serious About Ecommerce Historic Navy Ship and CIA Barge to be Auctioned for $100,420 5 Startups Using Tech To Do Good Do People Really Want Self-Driving Cars? [VIDEO] Apple &#8216;Sidesteps&#8217; Billions in Corporate Taxes, NY Times Reports Interest in Pinterest Reaches a Fever Pitch [INFOGRAPHIC] Where CISPA&#8217;s Going: Everything You Need to Know 8 New Apps You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss Researchers Create Glare-Free Self-Cleaning Glass [VIDEO] How Samsung Became The World&#8217;s Top Handset Vendor Winklevoss Twins Start Up a Venture Capital Firm [VIDEO] The iPhone Almost Had a Physical Keyboard [REPORT] The Hobbit&#8217;s 48 FPS Format Ruins Film&#8217;s Artistry, Previewers Complain Google Maps Adds More 3D Goodness with Parallax Views [VIDEO] Apple Flirting with Epix for Streaming Video From 3 Major Studios [VIDEO] Women Are More Likely Than Men to Have a Blog, Facebook Profile [STUDY] At the White House Correspondents&#8217; Dinner, Tech is in the House Free Online Human Translation Service Takes On Babelfish, Google Translate Forget Emoticons &#8212; Skype Wants You to Use &#8216;Humoticons&#8217; HelloFax Turns Google Drive Into a Fax Machine George Zimmerman&#8217;s Website Closes After He Raises $204,000 Watch Leonard Nimoy Welcome Space Shuttle Enterprise to New York [VIDEO] Jack White Concert Asks Viewers to Create Digital Photo Mosaic Falling Bear Fallout: Student to Sue School Paper over Viral Photo Yahoo Escalates Patent War With Facebook Helpful Resources Students Studying Abroad: Take Advantage of Video Job Interviews/a&gt; 7 Easy Ways to Speed Up Your Business Computers 51 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed How to Leverage Applicant Tracking Systems To Land a Job Top 6 Mashable Comments This Week 5 Tips for Great Content Curation How to Maximize Your Facebook Engagement SEE ALSO: All the Weekend Recaps Ever Published Weekend Leisure 25 Most-Followed Users on Instagram [PICS] 12 Funniest &#8216;Animals Being Dicks&#8217; [GIFS] JoeyBra: The Perfect Under-the-Shoulder Smartphone Holder? [VIDEO] Pok&#233;mon Art Tumblr Reimagines 151 Original Characters [PICS] Top Health and Fitness Apps to Improve Your Workout and Diet [INFOGRAPHIC] Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week Google Maps Cube Game is Live Now, You Should Play It Here&#8217;s last week&#8217;s Weekend Recap. More About: Weekend recap</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/weekend-recap-52/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/weekend-recap-52/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brydge Turns Your iPad Into a Laptop [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>A new iPad case is attempting to blur the lines between laptop and tablet. Called Brydge, the special case has a built-in keyboard that transforms your iPad into a more laptop-like device capable of performing many of the same functions you know and love from your traditional computer. Made out of aerospace-grade aluminum, the case looks and feels like your iPad. Rather than look like your iPad shoved in a case, the two are designed to fit together in such a way that looks like they&#8217;re two parts of the same device. The hinge on the case holds your iPad in place, and gives you 180 degrees of positioning much like you have with a traditional laptop screen. When you&#8217;re done using your tablet, you can close the case to put your iPad to sleep and protect the screen while you travel. Brydge connects to your iPad via Bluetooth, and special hot keys on the keyboard perform different functions on your iPad. The keyboard charges through a USB connection. An optional feature for Brydge &#8211; and one that isn&#8217;t available on some comparable keyboard cases &#8211; is built-in stereo speakers. So, when you&#8217;re watching a movie or listening to tunes you can do so at a higher volume than you might be able to using just the iPad. Brydge is currently trying to raise money for its first manufacturing run on Kickstarter. The company estimated it needs $90,000 for a first run of the case, and has 39 days to go before it reaches that goal. What do you think about the iPad case? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Brydge, ipad, keyboard</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/brydge/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/brydge/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple spits out Android option from Chomp app navigator</title>
      <description>It's taken a bit longer than we expected, but following Apple's acquisition of app search engine Chomp, the Android option has now been cut out from its homepage. We're now left with the choice between iPhone and iPad categories, alongside existing shortcuts for popular freebies and apps on sale, in a few efforts to cut through Cupertino's 600,000-strong app selection. Hit up the source to give it a run for yourself.Apple spits out Android option from Chomp app navigator originally appeared on Engadget on Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:41:00 EDT. Please see our terms for use of feeds.Permalink TUAW | Chomp | Email this | Comments</description>
      <link>http://www.engadget.com/2012/04/30/apple-drops-android-from-chomp/</link>
      <guid>http://www.engadget.com/2012/04/30/apple-drops-android-from-chomp/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
