<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Wings 2.0 Trailer Is Awesomely Retro [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Tiny Wings is a fun iOS game that eschews the anger of another avian franchise for the underdog appeal of a bird that can't fly. We especially like that it's easy to play with just one hand (great for subway commutes). If that wasn't enough to get us looking forward to the next version of the game, this excellent trailer has done the trick. From the punch-card game track to the fairly game-accurate movements to the fun ending, it's got us putting alerts in our calendar for July 12 -- the date of the release. What do you think of the Tiny Wings 2.0 trailer? Share your thoughts in the comments. BONUS: 10 Games for iPhone You Can Play With One Hand More About: games, iOS, iphone, Tiny Wings, videos, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/tiny-wings-2-trailer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/tiny-wings-2-trailer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>British Airways Borders On Creepy With &#8220;Know Me&#8221; Google Identity Check</title>
      <description>British Airways is using Google Images to develop passenger dossiers for checking people out as they come through the gate. Now that&#8217;s what you call customer service. At least that&#8217;s British Airways spin. Privacy advocates have a different take. According to The Evening Standard, the airline is facing considerable backlash today after it announced a plan to launch a program called &#8220;Know Me.&#8221; The new intelligence tool uses Google Images to find pictures of passengers for staff to use so they can approach them as they arrive at the terminal or plane. In many respects, British Airways is doing what they have been told to do. Go to any vendor conference these days and you will hear executives talk about the power of social. A favorite theme: how to draw analysis from customer data, social streams and the Web. That&#8217;s exactly what British Airways is doing. The plan is to collect data from its own systems and that from Google and other sources. Here&#8217;s what Jo Boswell, head of customer analysis at BA had to say: &#8220;We&#8217;re essentially trying to recreate the feeling of recognition you get in a favourite restaurant when you&#8217;re welcomed there, but in our case it will be delivered by thousands of staff to millions of customers. This is just the start &#8212; the system has a myriad of possibilities for the future.&#8221; Ray Wang, principal analyst at Constellation Research said in an interview today that it&#8217;s pretty basic.This would all be okay if passengers had some clue about what personal data British Airways planned to use. &#8220;Before you put a program together like KnowMe it&#8217;s only right to ask passengers for permission first,&#8221; Wang said in an interview today. &#8220;Otherwise it&#8217;s borderline creepy.&#8221; British Airways maintains it is developing a service that will allow it to offer a new level of personal service. But without trust, there is nothing. &#8220;When companies and brands seek to put new customer experiences together, they have to figure out how their customers wish to be engaged,&#8221; Wang said. &#8221;They should also give customers control over what data they want to share and what data the company has on them. That&#8217;s how you build trust. and trust is the new social currency.&#8221;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/05/british-airways-borders-on-creepy-with-know-me-google-identity-check/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/05/british-airways-borders-on-creepy-with-know-me-google-identity-check/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What If You Could Combine the iPhone and the Samsung Galaxy S III Into One?</title>
      <description>Regardless of what your expectations of Apple's upcoming next-generation iPhone are, there's probably a feature or two you've seen on Android devices which you'd like to see on the iPhone as well. Some, like a memory card slot, have been desired by users for what seems like an eternity, but Apple wouldn't budge. However, one can always dream, and now that dream has been turned into a 3D rendering that looks quite desirable. The iSung Galaxy V, as the folks from Techradar have imagined it, is -- simply put -- the best of both worlds; an iPhone and the Galaxy S III melded into one device. It has features such as NFC, ultra-shutter, a memory card slot and iPhone's singular butto&#8230; Continue reading... More About: iphone, iSung, Samsung Galaxy S III</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/isung/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/isung/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Is Our Planet: Spectacular View of Earth From the ISS</title>
      <description>Tomislav Safund&#382;i&#263;, an 18-year old photography and video enthusiast from Croatia, has knitted together a wonderful time-lapse video of Earth viewed from the International Space Station. The video, accompanied with some chillout music, turns the spectacular photos from NASA's Image Science &amp; Analysis Laboratory into an exciting ride over our planet. SEE ALSO: Amazing Eclipse Time Lapse Shows the Sun Like You&#8217;ve Never Seen It Check out Tomislav's other time-lapse videos over at his Vimeo profile. What are your favorite time-lapse videos? Share your faves in the comments! More About: Earth, NASA, space, time-lapse, Tomislav Safund&#382;i&#263;, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/this-is-our-planet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/this-is-our-planet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Planning Mobile Ad System That Tracks Users' Apps [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Facebook is planning to roll out a new mobile advertising strategy that targets users based on which apps are installed on their phones, according to a report from the Wall Street Journal. Facebook engineers are said to have created software that can track what apps a user has downloaded. By using this information, Facebook can determine other apps that may appeal to them, serving up ads for those apps in the news feeds on their phones or tablets. Typically, Facebook users only see ads in the news feed from brands they&#8217;ve &#8220;Liked,&#8221; but this system would serve app ads whether they&#8217;ve liked the brand or not. If Facebook indeed ends up sing app-tracking software, it would likely be extremely controversial &#8212; both for the nature of the information and for the allowing of uninvited ads. Facebook has never before tracked apps on users&#8217; devices. The Journal writes this is a way for Facebook to increase mobile revenue and tap into the potential profits to be made from the many apps that connect to its site. Instead of a purely impressions-driven model, the app-tracking system would involve Facebook getting a cut of every app sold, though impressions might factor in for free apps. Facebook&#8217;s been focusing on the potential of mobile ads, especially after its IPO when investors and Facebook said mobile could get in the way of the company&#8217;s growth. In June, the social network announced Facebook Sponsored Stories that allow advertisers to purchase ads especially for mobile devices. Recently, several studies showed Facebook&#8217;s mobile ads are performing better than desktop ads, perhaps making Facebook eager to test new mobile ad strategies. What do you think of this potential new mobile ad strategy by Facebook? Sound off in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/facebook-mobile-ads-apps/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/facebook-mobile-ads-apps/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Access Is a Human Right, Says United Nations</title>
      <description>The United Nations Human Rights Council yesterday for the first time backed the right to free expression on the internet. &#8220;This outcome is momentous for the Human Rights Council,&#8221; said U.S. ambassador Eileen Donahoe, adding, &#8220;It&#8217;s the first ever U.N. resolution affirming that human rights in the digital realm must be protected and promoted to the same extent and with the same commitment as human rights in the physical world.&#8221; China and Cuba joined the council&#8217;s consensus, despite the fact that authorities in both countries regularly limit internet freedom.</description>
      <link>http://thinkprogress.org/security/2012/07/06/511827/un-internet-human-right/?mobile=nc</link>
      <guid>http://thinkprogress.org/security/2012/07/06/511827/un-internet-human-right/?mobile=nc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Access Is a Human Right, Says United Nations</title>
      <description>Is Internet access and online freedom of expression a basic human right? The United Nations' Human Rights Council unanimously backed that notion in a resolution passed Thursday. The resolution says that all people should be allowed to connect to and express themselves freely on the Internet. All 47 members of the Human Rights Council, including notoriously censorship-prone countries such as China and Cuba, signed the resolution. China's support for the resolution came with the stipulation that the "free flow of information on the Internet and the safe flow of information on the Internet are mutually dependent," as Chinese delegate Xia Jingge told the Council in a sign that the country&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Arab Spring, censorship, human rights, internet, United Nations, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/internet-human-right/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/internet-human-right/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Tab Engagement Down 53% Since Timeline Launch</title>
      <description>Facebook's Timeline redesign profoundly altered the appearance and the function of brand Pages. It's also significantly affected the degree to which fans interact with tabs, which point you to different content at the top of the page. According to data provided to Mashable by PageLever, tab engagement has dropped off 53% since brand Pages began adopting Timeline. The findings were drawn from approximately 500 Pages with more than 10,000 fans apiece. You can see tab engagement begin to decline on Feb. 28, the day brands were able to opt-in to Timeline. There's a steeper leading into March 30, the day all Pages were forced to convert. The regular spikes you see in the chart are&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, Facebook brand pages, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-tab-engagement-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/05/facebook-tab-engagement-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Search Gets Smarter, Adds Autocomplete</title>
      <description>In the age of Google Instant, where we expect search results to complete themselves before we&#8217;re done typing, Twitter&#8217;s search feature has long seemed a little slow and dumb. Can&#8217;t it guess at what search term or person you&#8217;re looking for? Can&#8217;t it autocorrect your spelling? Can&#8217;t it just search among the tweets of people you follow? Well, now you can do all of that, in theory. The microblogging service took the wraps off a new smarter search product Friday, after teasing us late Thursday with a brief announcement that search and discovery on Twitter was about to change &#8220;forever.&#8221; The changes, which are rolling out to all users on mobile Twitter and Twitter.com, fall into three categories. First, there&#8217;s the Google Instant-like guessing. &#8220;Search autocomplete shows you the most likely terms for your query as you enter it &#8212; especially useful if you&#8217;re trying to follow the hashtag for an event or you&#8217;re looking for a certain Twitter account,&#8221; writes engineer Frost Li on the Twitter blog. &#8220;You can select your query from the drop-down menu even before you finish typing it.&#8221; Search autocomplete will also correct your spelling if there&#8217;s a common search term with slightly different letters &#8212; a feature Google has boasted for years. Secondly, Twitter says, search is about to get a lot smarter when it comes to related terms, hashtags and accounts. &#8220;If you search for a topic for which people use multiple terms,&#8221; says Li, &#8220;we will provide relevant suggestions for terms where the majority of that conversation is happening on Twitter.&#8221; And finally, once your search is complete, you have a new option to narrow it down: click on tweets from people you follow. This will appear next to the regular search filter options, &#8220;top&#8221; and &#8220;all.&#8221; In other words, if you want to forget the rest of Twitter exists outside your circle of follows, the company just made it a lot easier. Is smarter Twitter search working for you yet? Let us know in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/twitter-search-autocomplete/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/twitter-search-autocomplete/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Search Gets Smarter, Adds Autocomplete</title>
      <description>In the age of Google Instant, where we expect search results to complete themselves before we&#8217;re done typing, Twitter&#8217;s search feature has long seemed a little slow and dumb. Can&#8217;t it guess at what search term or person you&#8217;re looking for? Can&#8217;t it autocorrect your spelling? Can&#8217;t it just search among the tweets of people you follow? Well, now you can do all of that, in theory. The microblogging service took the wraps off a new smarter search product Friday, after teasing us late Thursday with a brief announcement that search and discovery on Twitter was about to change &#8220;forever.&#8221; The changes, which are rolling out to all users on mobile Twitter and Twitter.com, fall into three categories. First, there&#8217;s the Google Instant-like guessing. &#8220;Search autocomplete shows you the most likely terms for your query as you enter it &#8212; especially useful if you&#8217;re trying to follow the hashtag for an event or you&#8217;re looking for a certain Twitter account,&#8221; writes engineer Frost Li on the Twitter blog. &#8220;You can select your query from the drop-down menu even before you finish typing it.&#8221; Search autocomplete will also correct your spelling if there&#8217;s a common search term with slightly different letters &#8212; a feature Google has boasted for years. Secondly, Twitter says, search is about to get a lot smarter when it comes to related terms, hashtags and accounts. &#8220;If you search for a topic for which people use multiple terms,&#8221; says Li, &#8220;we will provide relevant suggestions for terms where the majority of that conversation is happening on Twitter.&#8221; And finally, once your search is complete, you have a new option to narrow it down: click on tweets from people you follow. This will appear next to the regular search filter options, &#8220;top&#8221; and &#8220;all.&#8221; In other words, if you want to forget the rest of Twitter exists outside your circle of follows, the company just made it a lot easier. Is smarter Twitter search working for you yet? Let us know in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/twitter-search-autocomplete/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/twitter-search-autocomplete/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just How Interested Is the World in SEO? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>How big is the SEO industry on the Internet? Really big, according to a new infographic by Spanish-based SEO service provider BlueCaribu. In fact, the infographic reveals that 3.5 people look up the term "SEO" on Google each second and 9.1 million web users are digging up information on the topic each month. People are getting their information about search engine optimization (SEO) from a variety of ways. There are 863 million websites worldwide that mention the term "SEO" and 164,000 YouTube videos are indexed with the topic. Google Shows Startups How to Master SEO in 10 Minutes [VIDEO] Los Angeles may be the number one city in the U.S. to search for SEO, but India is the top c&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, Google, google search, SEO</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/seo-information-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/seo-information-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just How Interested Is the World in SEO? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>How big is the SEO industry on the Internet? Really big, according to a new infographic by Spanish-based SEO service provider BlueCaribu. In fact, the infographic reveals that 3.5 people look up the term "SEO" on Google each second and 9.1 million web users are digging up information on the topic each month. People are getting their information about search engine optimization (SEO) from a variety of ways. There are 863 million websites worldwide that mention the term "SEO" and 164,000 YouTube videos are indexed with the topic. Google Shows Startups How to Master SEO in 10 Minutes [VIDEO] Los Angeles may be the number one city in the U.S. to search for SEO, but India is the top c&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, Google, google search, SEO</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/seo-information-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/06/seo-information-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
