<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>New York Times To Launch New Website in China</title>
      <description>The New York Times is making a business move towards China, opening a Chinese language news website and a Sina Weibo account. Unlike its American version, the Chinese edition of the New York Times will have no paywall. Eileen M. Murphy, vice president of corporate communications for the New York Times, told Mashable that offering an unpaid site, at least in the beginning, is &#8220;consistent with what we do when we start new ventures.&#8221; &#8220;We want this new site to be found,&#8221; she said, while adding that there are no current plans to put up a paywall in the future. New York Times&#8217; Chinese site will launch in beta on Thursday morning local time. Its URL will be http://cn.nytimes.com/ &#8220;The goal of the new site is to provide China&#8217;s growing number of educated, affluent, global citizens with high-quality coverage of world affairs, business and culture,&#8221; said the New York Times in a statement. &#8220;The site will be edited specifically for readers in China, presenting translations of the best of The Times&#8217;s award-winning journalism alongside original work by Chinese writers contributing to The Times.&#8221; The site will cover global affairs, business and culture with about 30 articles per day, all in Chinese. About two-thirds of the content will be translated pieces and one-third will be content from local reporters, although that model could change over time. It will be advertising supported, with luxury brands including Ferragamo, Bloomingdales and Cartier signed up to appeal to the Chinese New York Times&#8216; audience. Content will be hosted on servers located outside of China, which Murphy pointed out is how other non-Chinese news website also operate. Using foreign servers gives websites the ability to work around local laws in the censorship-heavy country. &#8220;The Times will dictate the content on the site,&#8221; said Murphy. &#8220;We&#8217;ve made no deal with the Chinese government, we&#8217;re aware that there&#8217;s that kind of history and they may block stories or sites,&#8221; adding they hope that&#8217;s something they won&#8217;t have to content with. China&#8217;s access to information on the Internet is tightly controlled by its government. Facebook, Twitter and YouTube are not allowed in the country due to the &#8220;Great Firewall of China.&#8221; But that doesn&#8217;t mean citizens don&#8217;t want to access this information. When the country&#8217;s firewall crashed in 2011 for less than two days, citizens logged on to Google+ to complain that their government &#8220;doesn&#8217;t represent the Chinese people.&#8221; Typically, people in countries with restrictive access to the Internet use VPNs, Virtual Private Networks, to access blocked sites while keeping the user undetected. Chinese Internet users using VPNs can tunnel under the national firewall and use banned sites as if they were in another country that allows those sites. Traffic is encrypted so the Chinese government&#8217;s censors cannot see what content users are viewing. Last year, Internet users in China reported poor connectivity while visiting sites such as Google while using a VPN, the Guardian reported. It was suspected that the Chinese government was involved. Do you think the Chinese government will attempt to stop citizens from accessing the New York Times&#8217; new site? Tell us in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/new-york-times-china/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/new-york-times-china/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Orbitz, Mac Users Steered to Pricier Hotels</title>
      <description>Orbitz has found that people who use Apple's Mac computers spend as much as 30% more a night on hotels, so the online travel agency is starting to show them different, and sometimes costlier, travel options than Windows visitors see.</description>
      <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304458604577488822667325882.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</link>
      <guid>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304458604577488822667325882.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineers Build Speech Algorithm To Detect Parkinson&#8217;s [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Parkinson's is a neurological disease that spreads quickly and is difficult to diagnose. About 6 million people worldwide are affected by the incurable disease. A sophisticated test to diagnose Parkinson's in patients early would lead to better treatment and an eventual cure. A team of engineers are betting on a voice-based test for Parkinson's -- built to be as accurate as clinical tests. This week, TED Fellow and mathematician Max Little announced the launch of Parkinson's Voice Initiative at TEDGlobal 2012. SEE ALSO: TEDGlobal: Social Media Sparks Visions of a Radically Open Future Currently, the team of mathematicians and engineers are as&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Mobile, parkinson's disease, Tech, tedglobal</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/parkinsons-voice-initiative/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/parkinsons-voice-initiative/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today Is Not the Future; 'Back to the Future' Hoax Fools the Web</title>
      <description>Remember that Back To The Future scene where the DeLorean is set to a future date? Despite what you've seen on Facebook, it's not today.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/back-to-the-future-hoax/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/back-to-the-future-hoax/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Women Still Can&#8217;t Have It All | The Atlantic | Jun. 21, 2012 | 51 Minutes (12,949 words)</title>
      <description>A call for women and men to have a more honest conversation about work-life balance: "Today, however, women in power can and should change that environment, although change is not easy. When I became dean of the Woodrow Wilson School, in 2002, I decided that one of the advantages of being a woman in power was that I could help change the norms by deliberately talking about my children and my desire to have a balanced life. Thus, I would end faculty meetings at 6 p.m. by saying that I had to go home for dinner; I would also make clear to all student organizations that I would not come to dinner with them, because I needed to be home from six to eight, but that I would often be willing to come back after eight for a meeting. I also once told the Dean&#8217;s Advisory Committee that the associate dean would chair the next session so I could go to a parent-teacher conference. "After a few months of this, several female assistant professors showed up in my office quite agitated. 'You have to stop talking about your kids,' one said. 'You are not showing the gravitas that people expect from a dean, which is particularly damaging precisely because you are the first woman dean of the school.' I told them that I was doing it deliberately and continued my practice, but it is interesting that gravitas and parenthood don&#8217;t seem to go together."</description>
      <link>http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/07/why-women-still-can-8217-t-have-it-all/9020/?single_page=true</link>
      <guid>http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/07/why-women-still-can-8217-t-have-it-all/9020/?single_page=true</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We know what you're doing... A social networking privacy experiment by Callum Haywood</title>
      <description>Disclaimer: All data is pulled directly from Facebook, it is not censored, and it is publicly accessible via the Graph API. I cannot be held responsible for any persons actions as a result of using this experiment. All attempts have been made to ensure the accuracy and reliability of the information provided on this website. However, the information is provided "as is" without warranty of any kind. Callum Haywood does not accept any responsibility or liability for the accuracy, content, completeness, legality, or reliability of the information contained on this website. No warranties, promises and/or representations of any kind, expressed or implied, are given as to the nature, standard, accuracy or otherwise of the information provided in this website nor to the suitability or otherwise of the information to your particular circumstances. We shall not be liable for any loss or damage of whatever nature (direct, indirect, consequential, or other) whether arising in contract, tort or otherwise, which may arise as a result of your use of (or inability to use) this website, or from your use of (or failure to use) the information on this site. This website provides links to other websites owned by third parties. The content of such third party sites is not within our control, and we cannot and will not take responsibility for the information or content thereon. Links to such third party sites are not to be taken as an endorsement by Callum Haywood of the third party site, or any products promoted, offered or sold on the third party site, nor that such sites are free from computer viruses or anything else that has destructive properties. We cannot and do not take responsibility for the collection or use of personal data from any third party site. In addition, we will not accept responsibility for the accuracy of third party advertisements. If you see any posts on here that are yours and you want them removing, delete them from Facebook first, then they will stop appearing here (may take up to an hour), or contact me to block any posts by you from appearing.</description>
      <link>http://WeKnowWhatYoureDoing.com</link>
      <guid>http://WeKnowWhatYoureDoing.com</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hey, Pass Me a Beer, Milwaukee Style [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Summer just arrived, and I don&#8217;t know about you, but we&#8217;re getting awfully thirsty for some brewskis around here. This video shows you how it&#8217;s done here in Milwaukee (home of your humble narrator). We don&#8217;t waste any time getting a cold one in our hands to start the weekend right. &#8220;Hey, Pass Me a Beer&#8221; is a YouTube masterpiece by MrMatthewVEVO, and I can tell you first-hand: It exemplifies the awesomeness that is Milwaukee and the cheesehead state. What about all that spilled beer when these two cool dudes open the severely jostled cans? As long as the Brewers win, we can patiently ignore any spillage. If the Brewers lose? Well, it&#8217;s time to get out the chainsaw to open those beers for even more wanton spillage. There&#8217;s plenty more where that came from &#8212; after all, we&#8217;re in Brew City!</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/pass-me-a-beer-video/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/pass-me-a-beer-video/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today Is Not the Future; 'Back to the Future' Hoax Fools the Web</title>
      <description>Remember that Back To The Future scene where the DeLorean is set to a future date? Despite what you've seen on Facebook, it's not today.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/back-to-the-future-hoax/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/back-to-the-future-hoax/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Sparks Visions of a Radically Open Future</title>
      <description>TED Global is underway in Edinburgh, Scotland, with a lineup of more than 70 speakers set to offer their visions of &#8220;radical openness&#8221; (the theme of this year's conference) across disciplines as diverse as corporate governance, global security and education. The conference was kicked off by Dan Tapscott, who in 2003 authored &#8220;The Naked Corporation,&#8221; which called for new levels of corporate transparency and accountability -- a novel idea at the time, when you consider there was no Facebook, Twitter or YouTube. In his talk, Tapscott defined what he sees as the four key principles for an open world: transparency, collaboration, sharing and empowerment. Offering examples&#8230; Continue reading... More About: crowdsourcing, open source, TED, ted global</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/ted-global-radical-openness/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/ted-global-radical-openness/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build &#8212; and Keep &#8212; an Engaged Audience [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Every web publisher -- and especially content marketer -- yearns for an engaged and loyal audience. But with the sheer volume of noise, clutter and -- well, content -- online it can be hard to figure out how to reach people and keep them coming back for more. The content marketing agency BlueGlass knows a lot about how to do this well. They've run successful campaigns for clients including eBay, Conde Nast and Greatist. Now BlueGlass is ready to share some of its secrets with Mashable readers. The company produced this exclusive infographic to run down some of the ways you too can build an engaged audience online. Here are a few quick tips: Make sure you have a gripping headline, ke&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/how-to-build-an-engaged-audience-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/how-to-build-an-engaged-audience-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judge Stops U.S. Sales of Samsung Galaxy Tab 10.1, Samsung Appeals</title>
      <description>U.S. District Judge Lucy Koh has approved Apple's request for a preliminary injunction in the U.S. against Samsung&#8217;s Galaxy Tab 10.1. "Although Samsung has a right to compete, it does not have a right to compete unfairly, by flooding the market with infringing products," Koh wrote on Tuesday. Apple filed a motion for a preliminary injunction in May 2012, claiming Samsung's Galaxy Tab 10.1 infringes on an iPad-related patent. Apple has also filed a similar motion against Samsung's Galaxy S III in June. The judge's order becomes effective after Apple posts a $2.6 million bond as protection against damages suffered by Samsung if the injunction is later overturned. It's importan&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, lawsuit, samsung, Samsung Galaxy Tab 10.1</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/preliminary-injunction-samsung-galaxy-tab-10-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/preliminary-injunction-samsung-galaxy-tab-10-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judge Stops U.S. Sales of Samsung Galaxy Tab 10.1, Samsung Appeals</title>
      <description>U.S. District Judge Lucy Koh has approved Apple's request for a preliminary injunction in the U.S. against Samsung&#8217;s Galaxy Tab 10.1. "Although Samsung has a right to compete, it does not have a right to compete unfairly, by flooding the market with infringing products," Koh wrote on Tuesday. Apple filed a motion for a preliminary injunction in May 2012, claiming Samsung's Galaxy Tab 10.1 infringes on an iPad-related patent. Apple has also filed a similar motion against Samsung's Galaxy S III in June. The judge's order becomes effective after Apple posts a $2.6 million bond as protection against damages suffered by Samsung if the injunction is later overturned. It's importan&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, lawsuit, samsung, Samsung Galaxy Tab 10.1</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/preliminary-injunction-samsung-galaxy-tab-10-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/27/preliminary-injunction-samsung-galaxy-tab-10-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
