<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday's Mini-Report</title>
      <description>Borderland BeatUpdated 4:25 p.m. - A House committee voted Wednesday along party lines to cite Attorney General Eric Holder for contempt, capping a mounting and contentious fight between congressional Republicans and the Obama administration over a gun-running controversy in Mexico.I thought of some cool captions-but I will leave it to your imaginationsRep. Darrell Issa pressed ahead with a committee vote Wednesday to hold Attorney General Eric Holder in contempt of Congress, despite an eleventh-hour move by President Obama to assert executive privilege over the Fast and Furious documents at the heart of the dispute. The announcement touched off a caustic debate on the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee that lasted well into the afternoon, as Democrats accused Issa of prosecuting a "political witch hunt" and Republicans stepped up their criticism of Holder's "stonewalling" over the Fast and Furious probe. Even for Washington, the tone at the hearing was decidedly bitter and accusatory. The House Oversight and Government Reform Committee was first informed of the president's decision to assert executive privilege in a letter Wednesday morning, shortly before the contempt vote was scheduled. Issa said committee staff are evaluating the letter but described the move as too little, too late as he and other GOP lawmakers questioned the basis for the assertion. "This untimely assertion by the Justice Department falls short of any reason to delay today's proceedings," Issa said. The chairman said, "We and the American people need answers sooner, not later."Lawmakers on the panel reconvened Wednesday afternoon following a brief recess, with a vote on the contempt resolution presumably still on the table for later in the day. Lawmakers first took up, and voted down, several Democratic amendments to the contempt resolution. They did, however, approve a GOP amendment designating Obama's executive privilege claim as inappropriate. The debate over the amendments capped an intense debate in which virtually every lawmaker on the committee weighed in. 'We and the American people need answers sooner, not later.'- Rep. Darrell Issa, R-Calif.Democrats roundly voiced disappointment with the proceedings, describing them as politically motivated and avoidable. They pleaded with Issa to seriously consider Obama's executive privilege claim -- the first Obama has asserted -- and some said Holder was being punished for withholding internal documents he shouldn't be turning over anyway. Republicans praised Issa for pressing ahead, describing the vote as entirely unavoidable considering the department's alleged refusal to cooperate. They frequently invoked the name of Brian Terry -- Fast and Furious-linked guns were found at the murder scene of the Border Patrol agent. And Issa indicated he was waiting for a more detailed explanation from the White House, and a letter from Obama himself, before even considering changing course based on the executive privilege claim. Issa also accused the Justice Department of trying to compel the committee to close its investigation in exchange for documents it hasn't yet seen. "I can't accept that deal. No other committee chairman would," he said. But Issa's Democratic counterpart, Rep. Elijah Cummings, D-Md., fired back that Holder never made such a demand -- a Justice official also refuted Issa's claim -- and said the attorney general had come to the committee in "good faith" to try and work out an agreement. Cummings said the upcoming contempt vote has "diminished" the prestige of the panel. "For the past year, you've been holding the attorney general to an impossible standard," he said, addressing Issa. "Mr. Chairman, it did not have to be this way. It really didn't." Rep. Carolyn Maloney, D-N.Y., added that she was "horrified" by the panel's looming vote, calling it a "political witch hunt" and accusing Republicans of "overruling" the president. If the vote proceeds, Republicans have more than enough votes on committee to pass the contempt resolution. However, Holder would not be considered held in contempt of Congress unless and until the full House approves the measure. The move by Holder and Obama to lock down some requested documents only complicates the fight over the botched anti-gunrunning operation between the legislative and executive branches. After Holder made the request to Obama via letter on Tuesday, Deputy Attorney General James Cole wrote to Issa, R-Calif., on Wednesday informing him that the president has granted the request. "We regret that we have arrived at this point, after the many steps we have taken to address the committee's concerns and to accommodate the committee's legitimate oversight interests regarding Operation Fast and Furious," Cole wrote. "Although we are deeply disappointed that the committee appears intent on proceeding with a contempt vote, the department remains willing to work with the committee to reach a mutually satisfactory resolution of the outstanding issues."Obama's decision pertains to documents from February 2011 and afterward examining how Justice officials learned about the Fast and Furious probe. Holder, in his letter to Obama requesting he assert executive privilege, said those documents pertain to the "deliberative process" on how to respond to congressional and media inquiries. White House Communications Director Dan Pfeiffer slammed committee Republicans later Wednesday, saying in a statement that: "Instead of creating jobs or strengthening the middle class, congressional Republicans are spending their time on a politically motivated, taxpayer-funded election-year fishing expedition."Wednesday's developments follow a flurry of activity Tuesday, as Holder tried to negotiate a way to avert the contempt proceedings. Issa had earlier indicated a willingness to postpone the vote after Holder indicated a willingness to make compromises and supply some documents in response to House Republicans' subpoena. But Issa told reporters after a roughly 20-minute meeting with Holder Tuesday that the attorney general instead briefed them on the documents in lieu of delivering them. Issa told Fox News that Holder didn't provide "anything in writing."Issa further said during the committee meeting Wednesday that the purpose of the probe "has never been to hold the attorney general in contempt." He said the committee had an aide on Capitol Hill all night in the hope that the Justice Department might send over documents to the panel. The failed Fast and Furious operation attempted selling thousands of guns to arms dealers along the U.S.-Mexico border to trace them to leaders of drug cartels. However, many of them showed up in crime scenes. Congressional investigators have been trying to determine if and when high-level Justice officials knew about problems with the operation. After a day in which their son's name was repeatedly invoked, Terry's parents Josephine and Kent Terry also released a statement Wednesday afternoon expressing disappointment with the administration's latest actions. "Attorney General Eric Holder's refusal to fully disclose the documents associated with Operation Fast and Furious and President Obama's assertion of executive privilege serves to compound this tragedy. It denies the Terry family and the American people the truth," they said. The Department of Justice has adamantly defended its response. Holder said Issa rejected what he thought was "an extraordinary offer." Holder called for the Capitol Hill meeting late Monday in a possible attempt to make a deal with Issa and avoid the contempt vote. "We offered the documents that we thought would resolve the subpoenas," he said. "The ball is in their court." The contempt vote in the oversight committee will likely pass considering Republicans outnumber Democrats 22 to 16. GOP House leadership has given Issa the green light to proceed how he sees fit, sources told Fox News, which suggests the vote would reach the House floor. Issa had demanded to see a trove of documents on the controversial Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives operation. He also wants to know who prepared a now-retracted letter from Feb. 4, 2011, in which the department claimed the U.S. did not knowingly help smuggle guns to Mexico, including those found where Terry was killed. Issa wrote back to Holder later Monday requesting he deliver roughly 1,300 documents pertaining to the Feb. 4 letter. The letter also stated Holder needed to deliver a description of all the documents he will not produce. full text of letter deputy ColeDear Mr. Chairman: After you rejected the Department's recent offers of additional accommodations, you stated that the Committee intends to proceed with its scheduled meeting to consider a resolution citing the Attorney General for contempt for failing to comply with the Committee's subpoena of October 11, 2011. I write now to inform you that the President has asserted executive privilege over the relevant post-February 4, 2011, documents. We regret that we have arrived at this point, after the many steps we have taken to address the Committee's concerns and to accommodate the Committee's legitimate oversight interests regarding Operation Fast and Furious. Although we are deeply disappointed that the Committee appears intent on proceeding with a contempt vote, the Department remains willing to work with the Committee to reach a mutually satisfactory resolution of the outstanding issues. Over the last fourteen months, the Department has provided a significant amount of information to the Committee in an extraordinary effort to accommodate the Committee's legitimate oversight interests. The Department has provided the Committee with over 7,600 pages of documents and has made numerous high-level officials available for public congressional testimony, transcribed interviews, and briefings. Attorney General Holder has answered congressional questions about Fast and Furious during nine public hearings, including two before the Committee. The Department has devoted substantial resources to responding to these congressional inquiries. In addition, upon learning of questions about the tactics used in Fast and Furious, the Attorney General promptly asked the Department's Acting Inspector General to open an investigation into the operation. This investigation continues today. We expect that the Inspector General's report will further help the Department to understand how these mistakes occurred and to ensure that they do not occur again. Finally, the Department has instituted a number of significant reforms to ensure that the mistakes made in Fast and Furious are not repeated. For example, a directive was issued to the field prohibiting the flawed tactics used in that operation from being used in future law enforcement operations. Leadership and staffing at ATF and the Arizona U.S. Attorney's Office were reorganized, and ATF instituted new policies to ensure closer supervision by ATF management of significant gun trafficking cases. The Criminal Division refined its process for reviewing wiretap authorization requests by its Office of Enforcement Operations. And component heads were directed to take additional care to provide accurate information in response to congressional requests, including by soliciting information directly from employees with detailed personal knowledge of the subject matter at issue. The Committee's original report accompanying its contempt resolution identified three "main categories" of interest: (1) "Who at Justice Department Headquarters Should Have Known of the Reckless Tactics"; (2) "How the Department Concluded that Fast and Furious was 'Fundamentally Flawed"'; and (3) "How the Inter-Agency Task Force Failed." Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, U.S. House of Representatives, Report at 39-40 (June 15, 20 12). With respect to the first category, the thousands of pages of documents and other information we have provided establish that the inappropriate tactics used in Fast and Furious were initiated and carried out by personnel in the field over several years and were not initiated or authorized by Department leadership. We have also provided the Committee with significant information with respect to the third category. In a revised report issued late last week, the Committee has made clear that these categories will not be the subject of the contempt vote. See Report at 41. Rather, the Committee has said that the contempt vote will address only the second category, "How the Department Concluded that Fast and Furious was 'Fundamentally Flawed." See Report at 42; Letter for Eric H. Holder, Jr., Attorney General, from Darrell E. Issa, Chairman at 1-2 (June 13, 2012) ("Chairman's Letter"). In this regard, your letter of June 13 stated that the Committee is now "focused on" "documents from after February 4, 2011, related to the Department's response to Congress and whistleblower allegations" concerning Operation Fast and Furious, in order to "examine the Department's mismanagement of its response to Operation Fast and Furious." !d. The Committee has explained that it needs these post-February 4 documents, including "those relating to actions the Department took to silence or retaliate against Fast and Furious whistleblowers," so that it can determine "what the Department knew about Fast and Furious, including when and how it discovered its February 4 letter was false, and the Department's efforts to conceal that information from Congress and the public." Report at 33. The Department has gone to great lengths to accommodate the Committee's legitimate interest in the Department's management of its response to congressional inquiries into Fast and Furious. The information provided to the Committee shows clearly that the Department leadership did not intend to mislead Congress in the February 4 letter or in any other statements concerning Fast and Furious. The Department has already shared with the Committee all internal documents concerning the drafting of the February 4 letter, and numerous Department officials and employees, including the Attorney General, have provided testimony, transcribed interviews, briefings, and other statements concerning the drafting and subsequent withdrawal of that letter. This substantial record shows that Department officials involved in drafting the February 4 letter turned to senior officials of components with supervisory responsibility for Operation Fast and Furious - the leadership of ATF and the U.S. Attorney's Office in Arizona - and were told in clear and definitive terms that the allegations in Ranking Member Grassley's letters were false. After the February 4 letter was sent, such assurances continued but were at odds with information being provided by Congress and the media, and the Attorney General therefore referred the matter to the Acting Inspector General for review. As the Department's review proceeded over the next several months, Department leaders publicly indicated that the facts surrounding Fast and Furious were uncertain and that the Department had significant doubts about the assertions in the February 4 letter. For example, at a House Judiciary Committee hearing on May 3, 2011, the Attorney General testified that the Department's Acting Inspector General was reviewing "whether or not Fast and Furious was conducted in a way that's consistent with" Department policy, stating "that's one of the questions that we'll have to see." The next day, May 4, 2011, in response to a question from Senator Grassley at a Senate Judiciary Committee hearing about allegations that ATF had not interdicted weapons, the Attorney General said, " I frankly don' t know. That's what the [Inspector General's] investigation . . . will tell us." As you have acknowledged, Department staff reiterated these doubts during a briefing for Committee staff on May 5, 2011. Testifying before the Committee in June 2011, Ronald Weich, Assistant Attorney General for Legislative Affairs, acknowledged that "obviously allegations from the ATF agents . . . have given rise to serious questions about how ATF conducted this operation." He added that "we're not clinging to the statements" in the February 4 letter. In October 2011, the Attorney General told the Committee that Fast and Furious was "fundamentally flawed." This statement reflected the conclusion that Department leaders had reached based on the significant effort over the prior months to understand the facts of Fast and Furious and the other Arizona-based law enforcement operations. The Attorney General reiterated this conclusion while testifying before Congress in November 2011. The Department's many public statements culminated in the formal withdrawal of the February 4 letter on December 2, 2011. The Department has substantially complied with the outstanding subpoena. The documents responsive to the remaining subpoena items pertain to sensitive law enforcement activities, including ongoing criminal investigations and prosecutions, or were generated by Department officials in the course of responding to congressional investigations or media inquiries about this matter that are generally not appropriate for disclosure. In addition to these productions, we made extraordinary accommodations with respect to the drafting and subsequent withdrawal of the February 4 letter, producing to the Committee 1,364 pages of deliberative documents. And we accepted your June 13 letter's invitation to "mak[ e] a serious offer" of further accommodation in hopes of reaching " an agreement that renders the process of contempt unnecessary." Chairman's Letter at 2. Specifically, we offered to provide the Committee with a briefing, based on documents that the Committee could retain, explaining further how the Department's understanding of the facts of Fast and Furious evolved during the post-February 4 period, as well as the process that led to the withdrawal of the February 4 letter. See Letter for Darrell E. Issa, Chairman, from Eric H. Holder, Jr., Attorney General at 1 (June 14, 2012). We also offered to provide you with an understanding of the documents that we could not produce and to address any remaining questions that you had after you received the briefing and the documents on which it was based. We believe that this additional accommodation would have fully satisfied the Committee's requests for information. We are therefore disappointed that the Committee has not accepted our offer and has chosen instead to proceed with the scheduled contempt vote. As I noted at the outset, the President, in light of the Committee's decision to hold the contempt vote, has asserted executive privilege over the relevant post-February 4 documents. The legal basis for the President's assertion of executive privilege is set forth in the enclosed letter to the President from the Attorney General. In brief, the compelled production to Congress of these internal Executive Branch documents generated in the course of the deliberative process concerning the Department's response to congressional oversight and related media inquiries would have significant, damaging consequences. As I explained at our meeting yesterday, it would inhibit the candor of such Executive Branch deliberations in the future and significantly impair the Executive Branch's ability to respond independently and effectively to congressional oversight. Such compelled disclosure would be inconsistent with the separation of powers established in the Constitution and would potentially create an imbalance in the relationship between these two.co-equal branches of the Government. In closing, while we are deeply disappointed that the Committee intends to move forward with consideration of a contempt citation, I stress that the Department remains willing to work toward a mutually satisfactory resolution of this matter. Please do not hesitate to contact this office if we can be assistance. Sincerely, James M. Cole Deputy Attorney General Sources: Business Insider and Fox Business</description>
      <link>http://www.borderlandbeat.com/2012/06/obama-invokes-executive-power-to-block.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.borderlandbeat.com/2012/06/obama-invokes-executive-power-to-block.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holder Contempt Vote: How Congress Reacted on Twitter</title>
      <description>The House Oversight and Government Reform Committee voted 23-17 along party lines Wednesday afternoon to hold Attorney General Eric Holder in contempt of Congress. The charge says Holder withheld documents related to a botched plan to track gun trafficking. The plan, dubbed Operation Fast and Furious, involved allowing weapons to be sold to known drug traffickers in Mexico with the goal of eventually tracking them to cartel bosses. The operation is largely considered a failure; most of the guns have yet to be recovered, and high-level arrests have not been made. Fast and Furious became publicly known after guns sold under the program were used in the killing of Brian Terry, a U.S.&#8230; Continue reading... More About: barack obama, congress, darrell issa, eric holder, fast and furious, Politics, Social Media, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/fast-and-furious/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/fast-and-furious/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Words With Friends&#8217; and &#8216;Draw Something&#8217; Coming to Windows Phone 8</title>
      <description>Words With Friends and Draw Something -- two Zynga games that have dominated iOS and Android mobile gaming markets are coming to the Windows 8 Phone platform. Microsoft announced the new operating system at the Windows Phone Summit on Wednesday in San Francisco. Microsoft closed the conference by announcing more than 100,000 apps on the Windows Phone Marketplace. The social games will be available for download in the Windows Marketplace. Top games on the Windows Phone are Angry Birds, Battleship, Fruit Ninja and Final Fantasy. SEE ALSO: Microsoft Reveals Windows Phone 8 Zynga released Words With Friends in July 2009. Mobile gamers went crazy for the Scrabble-like mobile crosswor&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Draw something, games, Gaming, Windows Phone 8, words with friends</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/windows-phone-8-games/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/windows-phone-8-games/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Integrates With WordPress: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Integrates With WordPress: WordPress publishers can now &#8220;easily integrate Facebook features, such as social publishing and mentions, through the new Facebook for WordPress plugin.&#8221; Publishers can use social plugins as WordPress widgets to share the Facebook Activity Feed, Recommendations, Comments Box and Customizable Like, Subscribe and Send buttons."Once the plugin is installed, you can cross-post content published to WordPress to your Facebook Timeline and the Facebook Pages you manage. You can also mention the names of Pages and friends as you post to further distribute your content."Twitter Rolls Out Tailored Trends: &#8220;In order to show emerging topics that matter more to you,&#8221; Twitter is improving their algorithms to &#8220;tailor Trends based on your location and who you follow on Twitter.&#8221; This new feature will impact how marketers can use Twitter.If you don't wish to see tailored Trends, but instead want to see a more general list of Trends, just change your location on Twitter.com.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:What kind of traffic is Pinterest driving to your site?What do you think of the new Facebook integration for WordPress?What&#8217;s your &#8220;feeling&#8221; about Facebook?Experience More Expanded Tweets: &#8220;When you expand Tweets containing links to partner websites, you can now see content previews, view images, play videos and more.&#8221;More companies like the the New York Times are partnering with Twitter to deliver rich content inside tweets.Facebook Opens the App Center: The App Center is a &#8220;place for people to find great social apps on the web and mobile.&#8221;The App Center helps high-quality apps grow by promoting those that people enjoy most.Bitly Shares Keyboard Shortcuts: Bitly users can &#8220;pick up some speed while performing some of the most common actions&#8221; with these shortcuts.Keyboard shortcuts for Bitly ninjas.Klout&#8217;s iPhone App Gets a Big Update: There are several new features. Users can now enter any Twitter handle and quickly find that user&#8217;s Klout score.With this new upgrade, users can endorse anyone's influence by swiping a finger across one of their Topics.Facebook Announces a New Ad Exchange: &#8220;Facebook announced a new &#8216;real-time bidding&#8217; ad exchange system for buying ads on the network.&#8221;Here are some social media tools worth noting:Konekt.me: An online platform that makes it extremely simple to build and curate a portfolio of your best work online.Konekt.me features include an easy-to-use, content-specific uploader, customizable collections and an interactive CV/resume feature that help you link your content and experience.Likester: A Facebook advertising tool to help Facebook users, companies and advertisers organize and explore over half a billion Facebook Likes.Check out the other pages your Facebook fans also like.Learnist: Essentially Pinterest with a focus on education. All learning boards are created by users and feature educational material.Unlike Pinterest, you are not limited to posting images on Learnist. You can also post articles, websites and videos.Chill: A video sharing site that allows you and your friends to watch videos together on your own computers while interacting in real time through Facebook."Chill is designed to make video sharing beautiful, simple and contextual."LoveIt: A visual sharing space that allows users to share their finished shopping excursion with the public, privately share the deals they got, and collaboratively plan their next shopping trip.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6FAOJXnPW3sAnd don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-integrates-with-wordpress-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-integrates-with-wordpress-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Facebook Know Your Love Secrets? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Like to keep your love life under wraps? Be careful if you're on Facebook. This infographic shows how much the social network can predict.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/facebook-love-secrets/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/facebook-love-secrets/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Rainbow is Back: Can it Do for the iPad What it Did for TV?</title>
      <description>Reading Rainbow began its 26-year run on PBS as a way to combat summer mind decay. Now it's taking the same goal to a different medium. "What were [kids] doing in the 80s? Sitting in front of the television," explains Levar Burton, who hosted the show. "So we went where they were to steer them back in the direction of where we wanted them to go." While television still accounts for the largest amount of children's screen time, it's not the only screen in town anymore. About half of children under 8 have access to some sort of mobile device. Kids are on tablets, and, as of Tuesday, so is Reading Rainbow. The new iPad app incorporates classic Reading Rainbow segments, 16 new video&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Levar Burton, Reading Rainbow</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/reading-rainbow-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/reading-rainbow-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behold: The First Video Taken with Google Glasses</title>
      <description>Google has debuted the first video taken with its new set of eyewear from its Project Glass project. And for those of you who haven&#8217;t been keeping up, Project Glass&#8217; sci-fi-looking glasses allow a person to do many of the same things you do with your smartphone, except without the need of a separate device. The eyewear will display user interfaces for different programs, allow you to snap pictures, and as we said, even record live video that is likely to cause nausea in some people upon viewing. Over the past week, Google co-founder Sergey Brin and others from the company have been field testing the eyewear, and taking pictures to show off what it can do in a real life setting. We&#8217;ve embedded the video below of a Google employee performing flips on a trampoline. Let us know what you think in the comments. Photo via Google Filed under: offBeat, VentureBeat</description>
      <link>http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/25/google-glasses-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</link>
      <guid>http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/25/google-glasses-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ever Imagined a World Without Internet? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Steve Carrell may be seeking a friend for the end of the world, but here at Mashable, we're more concerned with the end of the Internet. Can you imagine it? Instead of an iPad, you'd be clutching a weighty $1,200 Encyclopedia Brittanica as you rock yourself to sleep. And instead of tweeting with pals halfway around the world, we'd be licking stamps that would total $6.3 trillion in the United States alone. We're cringing at the thought. SEE ALSO: The Internet Is Ruining Your Brain [INFOGRAPHIC] Online Education created this graphic detailing the nightmare that would be the world without Internet. Sure, we're grateful to the World Wide Web for giving us all the joy of narcoleptic ca&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, internet, Social Media, Tech, trending, web</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/world-without-internet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/world-without-internet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Are the Real Online Influencers? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>As the web's capacity for pageviews increases, marketers are becoming less interested in reaching as many people as possible, and more interested in reaching the right people. According to Deanna Brown, the CEO of Federated Media, that's why context is so important -- the ability serve high volumes of advertising continues to expand, but the real value for a brand is to surround its message with the right context so that it reaches the most influential people among customers. Yet, while most marketers agree that reaching influencers is important, they question how to measure influence and how to determine the most influential people online in the first place. Are you influential if you&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, influencers, infographics, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/influence-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/influence-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Attributes of Content That Inspire Action</title>
      <description>Posted by DanielTynskiThis post was originally in YouMoz, and was promoted to the main blog because it provides great value and interest to our community. The author's views are entirely his or her own and may not reflect the views of SEOmoz, Inc. Anyone who says &#8220;you can lead a horse to water, but you can&#8217;t make it drink&#8221; is probably not a marketer. And yet, this is something a lot of content marketing initiatives get wrong. Sure, the target audience may be making it to your content in droves, but leading people to your content is only step one. As a marketer, you already know getting your visitors to perform an action is crucial to the success of any marketing initiative. Content marketing is no different. Tracking measurable actions (like newsletter subscribers, social shares, leads, clicks, and sales) tied to your content is crucial to gauging its efficacy. Here is where most people get lost: They are creating content that isn&#8217;t leading people to perform measurable actions. Every piece of content you publish should be crafted with this in the forefront of your mind. If you&#8217;re not doing this, you&#8217;re wasting your time. Ask yourself these questions: What action do you want people to take after reading your content? Which piece of past content inspired the highest number of these actions? What elements of this content do you think contributed to its success? Below is a breakdown of eight elements that inspire action and how to add them into your content. You should be purposefully weaving these elements into your content. At the end of this post, I&#8217;ve included an evaluation rubric for you to consistently measure if your content incorporates these attributes. The Elements of Impactful Content So how do you create content that leads your audience to perform a desired action? Simply slapping a call-to-action at the end isn&#8217;t enough. Chances are your past content successes contained many, if not all, of the same attributes. Including these following elements throughout your content will help move people to action. 1. Provocative Does your content flip conventional wisdom on its head? Easily confused with controversy, being provocative is about more than raising eyebrows. Provocative content ignites emotion by pushing boundaries and challenges the status quo. Example: Reinventing the Toilet Non-profits are masters at using provocation to incite action. To raise awareness around poor sanitation conditions, the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation put together a stellar content marketing campaign about, wellpoop. Using a combination of infographics and kinetic typography videos, they packaged content that is shocking, frankly discusses a taboo subject, and makes the viewer think differently about something as pedestrian as a toilet. Makes you want to donate, right? 2. Visionary Are you causing a &#8220;Eureka moment&#8221; for the reader? Visionary content puts into words a frustration, realization, or need that the reader has, but may not have been fully aware of or seen properly verbalized previously.Example: 15 Things You Should Give Up to Be Happy This virally successful article didn&#8217;t reinvent the wheel (or the toilet), but rather, it produces a &#8220;why didn&#8217;t I think of that?&#8221; reaction. This was a simple list of things the reader probably had never connected with making them less happy in life. The title of this post is also provocative (one doesn&#8217;t associate giving things up with happiness) and no doubt greatly contributed to its viral success. Just take a look at the social shares in the screenshot below the title to see how many actions this piece spawned. 3. Differentiated Are you rehashing what others have already said? Differentiated content presents a completely original idea or discusses a tired topic in a new fashion or format. This is uncommon to most content and one of the toughest attributes to master.Example: The Noob Guide to Online Marketing Instead of being yet another &#8220;ultimate guide&#8221; blog post, this comprehensive resource combined expert knowledge with a visually-compelling format. And the accompanying infographic is anything but typical; it&#8217;s meant to be printed out and used as a checklist (you can rip the &#8220;cogs&#8221; off of the wheel as you complete each task). 4. Relevant Does your content appeal to your target audience? Content should be related to your brand without being an overt sales pitch. If you do go off topic, you&#8217;re doing so from the perspective of your vertical.Example: Nature Valley Trail View Nature Valley understood that a map of where you could buy granola bars wouldn&#8217;t be compelling (except for someone who was really into granola bars). But what is compelling to active people (the target audience of a mobile snack) is a map where you can take virtual tours through America&#8217;s national parks. There is no mention of granola bars in this virtual map, save for the subtle branding of the Nature Valley logo. This type of content is exactly what all businesses should be doing: providing your target audience with resources of entertainment relevant to their interests and lifestyle. They also posted a blog about how they created this project, another source of content that would be of interest to their target audience. 5. Timely Are you one of the first to cover hot topics? Even if you aren&#8217;t trying to break news, you should be incorporating current trends and news into your content. Leverage news items your audience is naturally talking about or seeking more information about.Example: From Pump Pains to Pink Slips My company, BlueGlass Interactive, created this infographic with Forbes which covered how rising gas prices affect unemployment, elections, and the stock market. We took a topic in the forefront of many people&#8217;s minds and made it compelling through data visualizations. 6. Demonstrates Mastery Are you positioning your brand as a thought leader? Masterful content offers an unparalleled depth of insight. It expands on complex ideas and shows a comprehensive analysis on the topic unlikely to be found from other sources.Example: Local Search Ranking Factors If you asked for a resource on local search, chances are you&#8217;d be directed to this mammoth survey of local search experts. Every year, David Mihm polls local search thought leaders about the ranking factors that drive Google&#8217;s Local Search algorithms and releases a new volume after each survey. Creating this type of resource (and continuously updating it) can position your brand as a top authority in your niche. 7. Can Be Delivered On Do you provide the solution? Content should intrigue the reader about your brand, and make them feel they have an unmet need only your brand can fill.Example: Dollar Shave Club You&#8217;ve probably heard the phrase &#8220;unique selling proposition,&#8221; but have rarely seen it in true form. Dollar Shave Club built their entire campaign on the very thing that no other competitor can offer: one dollar for razors mailed to you each month. With a unique selling proposition this strong, the viewer is almost forced to take action and sign up for the club. It doesn&#8217;t hurt that the video is hilarious, only adding to the uniqueness of the brand. 8. Narrative Are you telling a story with a clear beginning, middle, and end? Content with a strong narrative takes the reader on an exciting journey full of surprises and leads to a call-to-action of value for the brand. It&#8217;s cohesive, easy to understand, and inspires action related to the story.Example: Water Changes Everything Using another example from a non-profit, this motion graphic video from Charity Water takes the viewer on a treacherous journey. It illustrates how people without access to clean drinking water collect water and the repercussions of the struggles they face. It then presents a solution to the problem at hand, explaining how a specific dollar amount can contribute to helping the issue. Using the Content Evaluation Rubric I&#8217;ve put together an evaluation rubric that grades content on the above eight attributes.Content Evaluation Rubric Periodically measuring your content against this rubric will allow you to see if your content is incorporating these elements. After reading through your content, give each attribute a score of 1-5. It will be next to impossible to get a perfect 100%, but the great thing about this rubric is it will challenge you to include these elements in all of your content. I recommend going through both your old popular content and your content that flopped to see how they fare on this rubric. Which attributes were strong or weak? You can adjust the rubric to give more weight to the attributes that resonated most with your audience in the past. You can also customize the rubric to match the types of content you produce. For example, if you are primarily creating evergreen content, you can remove the &#8220;timely&#8221; attribute. Conclusion It&#8217;s tempting to chase viral success and create content that only produces traffic spikes and social shares. If you&#8217;re only creating content with this in mind, you may find yourself producing content that is completely unrelated to your business, not reaching the right audience, and not getting your visitors to perform the actions you hope. Sign up for The Moz Top 10, a semimonthly mailer updating you on the top ten hottest pieces of SEO news, tips, and rad links uncovered by the Moz team. Think of it as your exclusive digest of stuff you don't have time to hunt down but want to read!</description>
      <link>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/8-attributes-of-content-that-inspires-action?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/8-attributes-of-content-that-inspires-action?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owning Your Content In Search: Google Now Makes It Easier To Link Your Website To G+</title>
      <description>Last year, Google announced an initiative to give authors on the Web greater ownership over their content and more visibility in search. Google Authorship, as its known, has changed consistently since launch, as the company experiments with the best ways to authenticate authors and give them proper attribution. Unfortunately, up to this point, the authentication process has been fairly convoluted. Rick DeJarnette&#8217;s post last week illustrates that clearly. There are a lot of steps and blog platforms like WordPress, for example, require additional configuration to enable authentication. It&#8217;s been confusing users to the detriment of the service. The process, however, is evolving. It&#8217;s gone from adding code to your site&#8217;s pages to something that&#8217;s more automatic. As part of this, Google announced today that it&#8217;s made it a lot easier to link your website to your Google+ page. Whether or not users like it, Google search was always going to get more social. Innately, people trust recommendations from their friends more than they do from strangers, or algorithms. As Kevin Gibbons recently pointed out, Google Authorship is essentially Google&#8217;s way of bringing together personalized search with its social search &#8212; your social graph, in this case brought to you by Google+. There are a whole mess of reasons why Google Authorship is important. For starters, it lets those who create the web&#8217;s content claim that content and make it their own, adding their name and image next to the byline of their articles, blogs, etc. That makes their content stand out. With few exceptions, content creators want to have their personal brand attached to their links &#8212; it&#8217;s good for business. For Google, social media and author authentication help them measure the influence (and trustworthiness) of content and links and, ideally, serve better results. If results have been authenticated with authorship &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8220;owned&#8221; by personal and company brands &#8212; searchers get better results and advertisers spend more knowing they&#8217;re getting more bang for their buck. But, &#8220;I don&#8217;t use G+, no one outside of Google does, so why would I do that?&#8221; you cry. Well, it makes it easier to have your authorship show up in search as a result. By god, reader! Own your content! Dennis Troper explains that linking your site to G+ means that: &#8220;Your recent posts can appear in lots of relevant places across Google. For example: When users search for your brand, an excerpt from a recent Google+ post may appear to the right of search results.&#8221; Now, page owners can link their sites in a few steps: 1) Visit your Google+ page, open its profile, and click &#8216;Edit profile&#8217; 2) On the About tab, save your website URL, then click the new button, &#8216;Link website&#8217; 3) Follow the instructions for adding a short line of code to your website&#8217;s homepage, then click &#8216;Test website&#8217; According to Troper, if the set up goes as planned, users will then see a confirmation message. Then, after a day or two, &#8220;the link between your website and your Google+ page will be active, and a check icon will appear next to your URL on your profile.&#8221; That means you&#8217;re good to go. Typepad said in a blog post today that it, too, has been working with Google to make authentication easier for its users. It&#8217;s a little bit more complicated than just adding your site to G+, but it&#8217;s still pretty straightforward. Find those steps here. More on Google Authorship here.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/12/google-authorship/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/12/google-authorship/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
