<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>WikiLeaks Founder Julian Assange Seeking Asylum at Ecuador Embassy</title>
      <description>Ecuador says Wikileaks founder Julian Assange is seeking asylum at its embassy in London</description>
      <link>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/ecuador-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-seeking-asylum-embassy-16604854</link>
      <guid>http://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/ecuador-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-seeking-asylum-embassy-16604854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ebook Sales Surpass Hardcover for First Time in U.S.</title>
      <description>American publishers are now bringing in more revenue from ebooks than hardcover books, according to a report published by the Association of American Publishers (AAP). The figures, which were posted on GalleyCat on Friday, show that net sales revenue from ebooks exceeded that of hardcover books in the first quarter of the year: a first. The data was compiled from 1,189 publishers and did not include children's books. Collectively, adult ebooks brought in $282.3 million in Q1. That's an impressive 28.4% increase from the same period a year ago. Young adult and children's ebooks performed even better, catapulting 233% to $64.3 million. Sales of adult hardcover books grew too, but more mo&#8230; Continue reading... More About: amazon, barnes&amp;noble, ebooks, Kindle, Media, publishing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/ebook-hardcover-sales/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/ebook-hardcover-sales/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Dads Are Plugging In, Getting Social [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do you consider yourself to be a &#8220;digital dad?&#8221; If you use social media to connect with your kids or other parents, count yourself as part of this savvy group. With Father&#8217;s Day around the corner, Euro RSCG Worldwide asked 1,000 dads across the U.S. how the Internet and social media has affected their parenting style, dividing the respondents into groups of &#8220;digital dads&#8221; and &#8220;Average Joes.&#8221; The survey shows dads are plugging in just as much as their teens. In fact, 62% of digital dads say they&#8217;re more tech-savvy than the average 15-year-old. Similarly, more than three-quarters of digital dads and 57% of Average Joes use Facebook, YouTube, Twitter and other sites to monitor their kids&#8217; interactions on the web. While you may think those watchful eyes create friction between parents and teens, the study finds just the opposite. &#8220;Social media is now providing new ways to engage with your family, and also is bringing families closer together,&#8221; says Tom Morton, chief strategy officer, New York and co-chief strategy officer, North America. In the same sentiment, digital dads are forming their own online communities &#8212; 64% have used social media to connect with other parents. Those dads are also sharing more as 52% have written about a parenting experience on the web, and 66% have posted a photo of their child on a social networking site or blog. SEE ALSO: 10 Father&#8217;s Day Gifts For Geeky Dads The survey also finds that the majority of fathers think their kids are smarter as the result of new technology and greater access to information, but they are increasingly becoming less proficient in the English language. Around 76% of digital dads and 68% of Average Joes agree that kids who grow up without access to the Internet are at a serious disadvantage. But those same dads say increasing technology can distract kids, impairing their ability to communicate face to face. And while &#8220;ttyl&#8221; and &#8220;ur&#8221; may be faster to text, dads think this is hurting their kids&#8217; ability to read and write English at expected levels. Check out the infographic below, and tell us how you&#8217;re a &#8220;digital dad&#8221; in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/digital-dads-are-plugging-in-getting-social-infographic/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/digital-dads-are-plugging-in-getting-social-infographic/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s the State of Social Media in Asia?</title>
      <description>Asians are the most active social media users in the world: Agree or disagree? A study by Burson-Marsteller showed that social media usage in the Asia-Pacific region went through the roof in the past years, showing growth rates ranging from 107% (South Korea) to 12,305% (Vietnam). More than half of the region's population is active online, with Facebook the most popular social network. Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Japan and South Korea all have larger online populations than Australia. In China, more than half a billion people surf the web. [More from Mashable: Fort Collins and Ottawa Proclaim June 30 Social Media Day] But going beyond statistics, what do those numbers mean? Are Asians really as attuned to social media as the surveys say? How differently do people in Asia use social media as compared to the U.S.? Join us today for a Google+ hangout at 10:00 a.m. ET with Timothy Tiah of Malaysia, Carlo Ople and Rosario Juan of the Philippines, and Aakar Anilof Nepal as we chat about social media trends in Asia in celebration of the upcoming Social Media Day on June 30. Read on to learn more about Social Media Day and find a Meetup near you, and let us know in the comments what social media looks like where you live. [More from Mashable: Celebrate Social Media Day With Mashable in the Bay Area] Whether you've had your event planned for months or are now inspired to get one started, we want to know: What are your plans for Social Media Day 2012? Share with us in the comments how you'll be recognizing the connected generation come June 30th. We look forward to celebrating with you! This story originally published on Mashable here.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/whats-state-social-media-asia-095140499.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/whats-state-social-media-asia-095140499.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Words that Simply Don't Exist in English</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://sobadsogood.com/2012/04/29/25-words-that-simply-dont-exist-in-english/</link>
      <guid>http://sobadsogood.com/2012/04/29/25-words-that-simply-dont-exist-in-english/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Sephora Is Betting Big on Digital Shopping</title>
      <description>It's no longer enough to be a social brand. In order to survive in today's business world, organizations must transform themselves into social businesses. One of the emergent trends we're tracking is the move from social to experiential, where social media plays one part in the greater production of everyday customer engagement. It's not just about technology -- it's about technology enabling experiences that provide real value to customers, and helping them share that value with their communities. Sephora is one of the brands that's leading the way in shaping digital experiences for its customers. The company recently invested in an entirely n&#8230; Continue reading... More About: brands, entrepreneurship, experience, revolutiontv, Social Media, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/19/revolution-sephora/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/19/revolution-sephora/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft's new Windows 8 Tablet: "Welcome to Microsoft Surface."</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en/us/default.aspx</link>
      <guid>http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en/us/default.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Big Brands Create Social Media Campaigns</title>
      <description>Ad execs who work for brands that regularly advertise during the Super Bowl often say they begin planning for the following year shortly after the winning team heads to the locker room. But for Fiat, it only took a mere five to six weeks to put together a social media campaign built around its Super Bowl ad. Coca-Cola's social campaign for Coke Zero, "Make It Possible," took about six months to create. Meanwhile, Ford's "Doug" spokespuppet campaign took about a year from inception to the bitter end. How did it happen? Fiat went to its social media agency, Ignite, asked it to come up with ideas and then picked the best one. Ford also relied on its agency, Team Detroit, for ideation. Bu&#8230; Continue reading... More About: coca cola, features, ford, mashable, social media for business leaders series, social media strategy</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Big Brands Create Social Media Campaigns</title>
      <description>Ad execs who work for brands that regularly advertise during the Super Bowl often say they begin planning for the following year shortly after the winning team heads to the locker room. But for Fiat, it only took a mere five to six weeks to put together a social media campaign built around its Super Bowl ad. Coca-Cola's social campaign for Coke Zero, "Make It Possible," took about six months to create. Meanwhile, Ford's "Doug" spokespuppet campaign took about a year from inception to the bitter end. How did it happen? Fiat went to its social media agency, Ignite, asked it to come up with ideas and then picked the best one. Ford also relied on its agency, Team Detroit, for ideation. Bu&#8230; Continue reading... More About: coca cola, features, ford, mashable, social media for business leaders series, social media strategy</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups, This Is How Design Works &#226;&#8364;&#8220; by Wells Riley</title>
      <description>A guide to understanding digital %26 physical product design for startups</description>
      <link>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</link>
      <guid>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Unveils Surface Tablet</title>
      <description>The star of Microsoft&#8217;s mystery Monday unveiling has been revealed: Surface, a Windows tablet. "It was always clear that what our software could do would require us to push hardware, sometimes where our partners hadn't envisioned," Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer said at the event. "Much like Windows 1 needed the mouse, we wanted to give Windows 8 its own hardware." Microsoft announced the mysterious event just last week, simply telling press, "This will be a major Microsoft announcement &#8212; you will not want to miss it." The event was so secretive, in fact, that we only learned where the event would be held -- LA&#8217;s Milk Studios -- hours before it kicked off. Milk has offices both&#8230; Continue reading... More About: microsoft</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/microsoft-unveils-surface/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/microsoft-unveils-surface/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Usage Patterns of Depressed College Students</title>
      <description>Switching quickly from Spotify to email to Facebook can be a telltale sign of depression. A recent study extensively correlates specific web habits, such as jumping between different applications, with depression. The study by Missouri University of Science and Technology associates observed how 216 university undergraduates surfed the web for a month. About 30% of the students had depression, according to the Center for Epidemiological Studies Depression Scale, an official screening test for the mental condition. These numbers match the national average. Depression affects about 10% to 40% of the national population of college students at one time. More than 90% of U.S. college stude&#8230; Continue reading... More About: college, Facebook, health, internet, Social Media, social networking</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/19/depression-internet-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/19/depression-internet-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
