<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Email Signatures Spoof Mocks Silly Sign-Offs [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>If you know someone with an insanely stupid email signature (maybe even yourself), this video is for you. Just in time for Independence Day, College Humor spoofs the U.S. Founding Fathers and the Declaration of Independence in this parody riddled with email faux pas. Culprits include signatures that are too long or too colorful and include tacky quotations or unrelated attachments, among other common annoyances. SEE ALSO: Overly Attached Girlfriend Returns With Medley of Stalker Songs Thomas Ian Nicolas from American Pie, Jim O&#8217;Heir from Parks and Recreation and Mark Deklin from TV are featured in this comedic skit.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/declaration-of-email-spoof/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/declaration-of-email-spoof/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anderson Cooper: "The Fact Is, I'm Gay."</title>
      <description>Last week, Entertainment Weekly ran a story on an emerging trend: gay people in public life who come out in a much more restrained and matter-of-fact way than in the past. In many ways, it's a great development: we're evolved enough not to be gob-smacked when we find out someone's gay. But it does matter nonetheless, it seems to me, that this is on the record. We still have pastors calling for the death of gay people, bullying incidents and suicides among gay kids, and one major political party dedicated to ending the basic civil right to marry the person you love. So these "non-events" are still also events of a kind; and they matter. The visibility of gay people is one of the core means for our equality. All of which is a prelude to my saying that I've known Anderson Cooper as a friend for more than two decades. I asked him for his feedback on this subject, for reasons that are probably obvious to most. Here's his email in response which he has given me permission to post here: Andrew, as you know, the issue you raise is one that I've thought about for years. Even though my job puts me in the public eye, I have tried to maintain some level of privacy in my life. Part of that has been for purely personal reasons. I think most people want some privacy for themselves and the people they are close to. But I've also wanted to retain some privacy for professional reasons. Since I started as a reporter in war zones 20 years ago, I've often found myself in some very dangerous places. For my safety and the safety of those I work with, I try to blend in as much as possible, and prefer to stick to my job of telling other people&#8217;s stories, and not my own. I have found that sometimes the less an interview subject knows about me, the better I can safely and effectively do my job as a journalist. I've always believed that who a reporter votes for, what religion they are, who they love, should not be something they have to discuss publicly. As long as a journalist shows fairness and honesty in his or her work, their private life shouldn't matter. I&#8217;ve stuck to those principles for my entire professional career, even when I&#8217;ve been directly asked &#8220;the gay question,&#8221; which happens occasionally. I did not address my sexual orientation in the memoir I wrote several years ago because it was a book focused on war, disasters, loss and survival. I didn't set out to write about other aspects of my life. Recently, however, I&#8217;ve begun to consider whether the unintended outcomes of maintaining my privacy outweigh personal and professional principle. It&#8217;s become clear to me that by remaining silent on certain aspects of my personal life for so long, I have given some the mistaken impression that I am trying to hide something - something that makes me uncomfortable, ashamed or even afraid. This is distressing because it is simply not true. I&#8217;ve also been reminded recently that while as a society we are moving toward greater inclusion and equality for all people, the tide of history only advances when people make themselves fully visible. There continue to be far too many incidences of bullying of young people, as well as discrimination and violence against people of all ages, based on their sexual orientation, and I believe there is value in making clear where I stand. The fact is, I'm gay, always have been, always will be, and I couldn&#8217;t be any more happy, comfortable with myself, and proud. I have always been very open and honest about this part of my life with my friends, my family, and my colleagues. In a perfect world, I don't think it's anyone else's business, but I do think there is value in standing up and being counted. I&#8217;m not an activist, but I am a human being and I don't give that up by being a journalist. Since my early days as a reporter, I have worked hard to accurately and fairly portray gay and lesbian people in the media - and to fairly and accurately portray those who for whatever reason disapprove of them. It is not part of my job to push an agenda, but rather to be relentlessly honest in everything I see, say and do. I&#8217;ve never wanted to be any kind of reporter other than a good one, and I do not desire to promote any cause other than the truth. Being a journalist, traveling to remote places, trying to understand people from all walks of life, telling their stories, has been the greatest joy of my professional career, and I hope to continue doing it for a long time to come. But while I feel very blessed to have had so many opportunities as a journalist, I am also blessed far beyond having a great career. I love, and I am loved. In my opinion, the ability to love another person is one of God&#8217;s greatest gifts, and I thank God every day for enabling me to give and share love with the people in my life. I appreciate your asking me to weigh in on this, and I would be happy for you to share my thoughts with your readers. I still consider myself a reserved person and I hope this doesn&#8217;t mean an end to a small amount of personal space. But I do think visibility is important, more important than preserving my reporter&#8217;s shield of privacy. Me too. (Photos courtesy of Anderson Cooper and CNN.)</description>
      <link>http://andrewsullivan.thedailybeast.com/2012/07/anderson-cooper-the-fact-is-im-gay.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+andrewsullivan%2FrApM+%28The+Daily+Dish%29</link>
      <guid>http://andrewsullivan.thedailybeast.com/2012/07/anderson-cooper-the-fact-is-im-gay.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+andrewsullivan%2FrApM+%28The+Daily+Dish%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anderson Cooper: "The Fact Is, I'm Gay."</title>
      <description>Last week, Entertainment Weekly ran a story on an emerging trend: gay people in public life who come out in a much more restrained and matter-of-fact way than in the past. In many ways, it's a great development: we're evolved enough not to be gob-smacked when we find out someone's gay. But it does matter nonetheless, it seems to me, that this is on the record. We still have pastors calling for the death of gay people, bullying incidents and suicides among gay kids, and one major political party dedicated to ending the basic civil right to marry the person you love. So these "non-events" are still also events of a kind; and they matter. The visibility of gay people is one of the core means for our equality. All of which is a prelude to my saying that I've known Anderson Cooper as a friend for more than two decades. I asked him for his feedback on this subject, for reasons that are probably obvious to most. Here's his email in response which he has given me permission to post here: Andrew, as you know, the issue you raise is one that I've thought about for years. Even though my job puts me in the public eye, I have tried to maintain some level of privacy in my life. Part of that has been for purely personal reasons. I think most people want some privacy for themselves and the people they are close to. But I've also wanted to retain some privacy for professional reasons. Since I started as a reporter in war zones 20 years ago, I've often found myself in some very dangerous places. For my safety and the safety of those I work with, I try to blend in as much as possible, and prefer to stick to my job of telling other people&#8217;s stories, and not my own. I have found that sometimes the less an interview subject knows about me, the better I can safely and effectively do my job as a journalist. I've always believed that who a reporter votes for, what religion they are, who they love, should not be something they have to discuss publicly. As long as a journalist shows fairness and honesty in his or her work, their private life shouldn't matter. I&#8217;ve stuck to those principles for my entire professional career, even when I&#8217;ve been directly asked &#8220;the gay question,&#8221; which happens occasionally. I did not address my sexual orientation in the memoir I wrote several years ago because it was a book focused on war, disasters, loss and survival. I didn't set out to write about other aspects of my life. Recently, however, I&#8217;ve begun to consider whether the unintended outcomes of maintaining my privacy outweigh personal and professional principle. It&#8217;s become clear to me that by remaining silent on certain aspects of my personal life for so long, I have given some the mistaken impression that I am trying to hide something - something that makes me uncomfortable, ashamed or even afraid. This is distressing because it is simply not true. I&#8217;ve also been reminded recently that while as a society we are moving toward greater inclusion and equality for all people, the tide of history only advances when people make themselves fully visible. There continue to be far too many incidences of bullying of young people, as well as discrimination and violence against people of all ages, based on their sexual orientation, and I believe there is value in making clear where I stand. The fact is, I'm gay, always have been, always will be, and I couldn&#8217;t be any more happy, comfortable with myself, and proud. I have always been very open and honest about this part of my life with my friends, my family, and my colleagues. In a perfect world, I don't think it's anyone else's business, but I do think there is value in standing up and being counted. I&#8217;m not an activist, but I am a human being and I don't give that up by being a journalist. Since my early days as a reporter, I have worked hard to accurately and fairly portray gay and lesbian people in the media - and to fairly and accurately portray those who for whatever reason disapprove of them. It is not part of my job to push an agenda, but rather to be relentlessly honest in everything I see, say and do. I&#8217;ve never wanted to be any kind of reporter other than a good one, and I do not desire to promote any cause other than the truth. Being a journalist, traveling to remote places, trying to understand people from all walks of life, telling their stories, has been the greatest joy of my professional career, and I hope to continue doing it for a long time to come. But while I feel very blessed to have had so many opportunities as a journalist, I am also blessed far beyond having a great career. I love, and I am loved. In my opinion, the ability to love another person is one of God&#8217;s greatest gifts, and I thank God every day for enabling me to give and share love with the people in my life. I appreciate your asking me to weigh in on this, and I would be happy for you to share my thoughts with your readers. I still consider myself a reserved person and I hope this doesn&#8217;t mean an end to a small amount of personal space. But I do think visibility is important, more important than preserving my reporter&#8217;s shield of privacy. Me too. (Photos courtesy of Anderson Cooper and CNN.)</description>
      <link>http://andrewsullivan.thedailybeast.com/2012/07/anderson-cooper-the-fact-is-im-gay.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+andrewsullivan%2FrApM+%28The+Daily+Dish%29</link>
      <guid>http://andrewsullivan.thedailybeast.com/2012/07/anderson-cooper-the-fact-is-im-gay.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+andrewsullivan%2FrApM+%28The+Daily+Dish%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why You're Probably Working an Extra Two Months This Year</title>
      <description>Looking forward to that July 4 holiday? Of course you are. But be honest: what are the chances you&#8217;re going to sneak a look at your work email at some point during the day, just in case? A new survey from mobile security firm Good Technology confirms what we already knew &#8212; that Americans&#8217; work-life balance is going from bad to worse. The stats read like a depressingly familiar roll call of what&#8217;s wrong with our hectic connected existence. Some 68% of us check work email before 8 a.m., with half of us doing so before our heads leave the pillow. (The average check-in time of the 1,000 randomly-selected respondents: 7:09 a.m.) At the other end of the day, 69% of us can&#8217;t slip into slumber unless we&#8217;ve checked that old work email one last time. But perhaps the most eye-popping part of the survey is how much all that extra time adds up to. Simply by answering work-related calls and emails when we&#8217;ve left the office, the average respondent is working an extra seven hours a week. That adds up to 365 hours a year. Assuming eight-hour days and five-day weeks, that&#8217;s around two months per year of unpaid overtime &#8212; and you&#8217;re putting it in voluntarily. Bad news for you, good news for your manager, right? Not so much. Another lesson these workplace studies teach us is the law of diminishing returns. The more you&#8217;re &#8220;on,&#8221; the faster you burn out, and the greater the likelihood that you&#8217;ll make a mistake. SEE ALSO: Tell-Tale Signs an Employee is Overworked [INFOGRAPHIC] Deep down, it seems, we all know this. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re drawn to stories about Facebook&#8217;s COO leaving work at 5:30pm, for example, or a New York Times op-ed this weekend, which encouraged greater awareness of what it called &#8220;the busy trap.&#8221; Is your work life bleeding into your home life? What, if anything, can we do about it? Let us know in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/overtime-at-home/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/overtime-at-home/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Remix of Your Favorite Comedians Is No Joke [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>NOTE: The language in the video above may be NSFW. From Louis C.K. to Mitch Hedberg, comedy's most famous standup acts have been remixed, thanks to YouTube's Official Comedy channel. The channel has subtly revealed what's hiding up its digital sleeve, introducing a slew of web series earlier this week. The video above is just one of its special projects. More About: comedy, humor, Louis C.K., mashup, remix, viral, viral videos, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/comedians-remi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/comedians-remi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mashable Weekend Recap: 18 Stories You Might Have Missed</title>
      <description>Just in case you missed our weekend full of fun, frolic and serious reporting, we've gathered it all together for you all in one handy place. It's the Weekend Recap, giving you all the news, features and helpful hints -- presented in the form of a concentrated list for your perusal. There's no better way to start off your summer than browsing all the goodness we brought to you over the past few days -- so have at it, and then go out there and make it your best week yet. Editor's Picks 8 Reasons Why Summer Is a Great Time to Job Hunt How We&#8217;ll Really Use Google Glass [SUNDAY COMICS] 8 Top Comments on Mashable This Week Top 10 Twitter Pics This Week Remembering Nora&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Weekend recap</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/weekend-recap-61/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/weekend-recap-61/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Nexus Q: Ready for Party Fouls, Not Prime Time [REVIEW]</title>
      <description>Google is calling the Nexus Q the &#8220;world&#8217;s first social media streamer.&#8221; When connected to your TV, this $299 ball can be used to stream tunes and videos from your favorite (Gingerbread or higher) Android device. If you have Android-toting friends over, you can also give them the ability to control the Q and play their own music and videos. Set to ship in mid-July, the Q is much more expensive than most music and media streaming devices. And sad to say, it isn't worth it. The Q is fun to play with, but it also has some significant flaws. Looking Good When Google designed the Q, it was looking to create something that you&#8217;d want to display on a bookshelf or beside&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, Google, Nexus Q</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/google-nexus-q-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/google-nexus-q-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to Windows 8 Pro for $39.99</title>
      <description>We set out to make it as easy as possible for everyone to upgrade to Windows 8. Starting at general availability, if your PC is running Windows XP, Windows Vista, or Windows 7 you will qualify to download an upgrade to Windows 8 Pro for just $39.99 in 131 markets. And if you want, you can add Windows Media Center for free through the &#8220;add features&#8221; option within Windows 8 Pro after your upgrade. When you use Windows.com to purchase an upgrade to Windows 8 Pro, the Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant makes upgrading simple by walking you through the upgrade process step-by-step from purchase to download and then of course installation. The Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant will check to make sure your PC is ready for Windows 8. It will provide a detailed compatibility report that lets you know of anything you may have to address before or after the upgrade and outlines actions to take. It will also inform you of any application or device compatibility issues. It will ask you what you want to keep from your current Windows installation. You will be able to upgrade from any consumer edition of Windows 7 to Windows 8 Pro and bring everything along which includes your Windows settings, personal files, and apps. If you are upgrading from Windows Vista, you will be able to bring along your Windows settings and personal files, and if you are upgrading from Windows XP you will only be able to bring along your personal files. Of course, if you want to start fresh, you can choose to bring nothing along. Or if you prefer to format your hard drive as part of your upgrade experience, you can do so as long as you boot from media and then format your hard drive from within the setup experience for installing Windows 8, not prior to it. Once you purchase your upgrade, the Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant kicks off your download. It has a built-in download manager that allows you to pause and continue your download at any time as well as a check to ensure your download completes successfully. After your download finishes, you can choose to proceed with the upgrade (&#8220;Install now&#8221;) or install later either from your desktop or by creating your own media. If you choose to create your own media, you will be able to create your own bootable USB or .ISO file which can be burned onto a DVD for upgrade and backup purposes. If you prefer, you also have the option of purchasing a backup DVD for $15 plus shipping and handling. We believe that your upgrade experience in Windows 8 will be a breeze by offering a faster experience, a single upgrade path, and compatibility from prior versions of Windows. We&#8217;ve continued to listen to our customers and have expanded the ability to download to over 100 countries and 37 languages. We have simplified the Windows upgrade experience with the Windows 8 Upgrade Assistant which supports you during your upgrade with everything from selecting your language to pausing your download to built-in compatibility checks - it&#8217;s seamless. And if you&#8217;re an enthusiast you will have the flexibility to download and control how you upgrade. If you prefer to shop at a local store, a packaged DVD version of the upgrade to Windows 8 Pro will be available for $69.99 during this promotion. This upgrade promotion for Windows 8 Pro both online and at retail runs through January 31st, 2013. We wanted to share information about this upgrade promotion with you as we continue to drive toward the RTM milestone for Windows 8. We will of course have more to say and more details to provide closer to general availability. Oh, and by the way - if you&#8217;re not upgrading from a prior version of Windows and are building your own PC or installing Windows 8 in a virtual machine or a separate partition, you will be able to purchase and install the Windows 8 and Windows 8 Pro System Builder product.</description>
      <link>http://windowsteamblog.com/windows/b/bloggingwindows/archive/2012/07/02/upgrade-to-windows-8-pro-for-39-99.aspx</link>
      <guid>http://windowsteamblog.com/windows/b/bloggingwindows/archive/2012/07/02/upgrade-to-windows-8-pro-for-39-99.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anderson Cooper: I'm gay</title>
      <description>Anderson Cooper's famously private life just became Monday morning's latest breaking news. He is, in his own words, "gay, always have been, always will be" and he "couldn't be any more happy, comfortable with myself, and proud."</description>
      <link>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/anderson-cooper-reveals-gay-i-happy-comfortable-proud-article-1.1106314?localLinksEnabled=false</link>
      <guid>http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/anderson-cooper-reveals-gay-i-happy-comfortable-proud-article-1.1106314?localLinksEnabled=false</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Black boxes' to monitor all internet and phone data - Channel 4 News</title>
      <description>channel4.com Internet and mobile phone companies are preparing to install "black boxes" to monitor all internet and phone traffic to and from the UK, and decode encrypted messages including bank transactions. posted by friends: (1) @alasdairtweets: "Once the Gmail is sent&#8230;a government-approved 'black box' will decrypt the message". Amazing political tech-stupidity: http://t.co/GceWkqwK 30.06.2012 20.13.59 posted by friends of friends: (1) @wikileaks: WE WARNED YOU: UK "black boxes" to decrypt ALL your Facebook/Gmail http://t.co/hZ9fDAN9 http://t.co/VbtzzePg http://t.co/HlF29S74 30.06.2012 23.27.04 @wikileaks: Black boxes to monitor all internet traffic from UK ISPs http://t.co/hZ9fDAN9 Don't totalitarianism? ACT: https://t.co/xWcNxCbG 30.06.2012 23.11.27</description>
      <link>http://www.channel4.com/news/black-boxes-to-monitor-all-internet-and-phone-data</link>
      <guid>http://www.channel4.com/news/black-boxes-to-monitor-all-internet-and-phone-data</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media Player VLC Now Available for Android as Beta</title>
      <description>VideoLAN's popular media player VLC, known for being able to crunch almost any media file without the need for external codecs, has made its way to Android in beta form. VLC plays "most multimedia files as well as discs, devices, and network streaming protocols," claims VideoLAN. However, this version is not stable, and is primarily intended for power users and hackers. As VideoLAN puts it, "it might kill your kitten, destroy your house and start the mayan apocalypse." VLC for Android beta is available for free over at Google Play. More About: android, Google Play, VideoLAN, vlc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/vlc-android-beta/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/vlc-android-beta/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise Of The Enterprise &#8220;Toys&#8221;</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: This post was written by guest contributor Aaron Levie, CEO and co-founder of Box.net. You can read his previous posts here. The enterprise software market has been uncharacteristically turbulent of late. Beyond several hefty funding rounds and well-performing IPOs, the ecosystem has experienced some major consolidation with SAP&#8217;s purchase of SuccessFactors and Ariba, Oracle&#8217;s acquisition of RightNow and Taleo, and even IBM&#8217;s multiple cloud additions. All totaled, we&#8217;ve seen more than $10 billion in enterprise cloud consolidation over the past three quarters. But Microsoft&#8217;s $1.2 billion acquisition of Yammer is a little different. Not just because it underscores the importance of social in the enterprise and cements Yammer&#8217;s rapid rise to more than a billion dollars in value. Rather, it&#8217;s different because it signals the severity of the disruption occurring in enterprise software &#8211; disruption that will make it very difficult for incumbent vendors to hold on, and disruption that&#8217;s coming from entirely new places and in new ways. Yammer began as an internal communication tool built specifically for employees at Geni, David Sacks&#8217; preceding company. Explicitly modeled off of Twitter, it allowed people to post and respond to ideas and keep track of each other&#8217;s activities. Its thesis was unassuming at first: traditional enterprise communication sucks, and a very simple port of what we experience in our personal lives into the enterprise could address a massive problem. But when Yammer took the top prize at TC50 in 2008, it wasn&#8217;t uniformly praised, and in some cases was completely misunderstood. Was it a Twitter competitor? How useful would it really be? Many analysts, pundits, and enterprises initially balked, dismissing it simply as an enterprise &#8220;toy.&#8221; But Yammer capitalized on its early traction, parlaying the service into a much broader social platform for workplace sharing and communicating, with the social enterprise space eventually exploding into a billion dollar market in just a couple of years. And these social &#8220;toys&#8221; quickly became a critical part of enterprise IT strategy &#8211; something that was not lost on Microsoft, nor on salesforce.com, which started building out Chatter. And the public markets have noticed as well, valuing Jive at $1.3 billion. Who would have thought that something as simple as status messages shared between colleagues would evolve to become such an important strategic product for Microsoft and the enterprise? But this is exactly how most disruptive innovations start: seemingly innocuous and grossly misunderstood at the onset. And by the time the misconceptions are corrected, it&#8217;s too late for the legacy players. The toys are no longer toys; they&#8217;re contenders. First they&#8217;re &#8220;toys,&#8221; then they&#8217;re solutions Students of the Innovator&#8217;s Dilemma know that a new technology starts out being just &#8220;good enough.&#8221; Often, an early solution only serves a niche part of the market with limited requirements. This naturally shields it from the incumbents&#8217; radar, but what starts out as a nascent product attacking an unprofitable or unattractive market segment can quickly mature into a disruptive solution that becomes more than adequate for a broader population. What is remarkable is the predictability and consistency of the incumbents&#8217; response to these new technologies. The first sign that an important disruption is occurring is the incumbent writing off the new innovation as just a toy. It&#8217;s an age-old exercise, going back as far as Western Union&#8217;s failure to see the value in telephones, classically stating, &#8220;what use could this company make of an electrical toy?&#8221; More recently, when the iPhone was introduced, Microsoft&#8217;s stance was that it &#8220;doesn&#8217;t appeal to business customers because it doesn&#8217;t have a keyboard which makes it not a very good email machine.&#8221; Of course, this turned out to be an unlucky predication, and the Redmond giant is now powering similarly consumerized devices for the enterprise sans keyboards. Fast-forward to today, and Larry Ellison is playing the same game with cloud ERP vendor Workday, dismissing it as frail and not ready for big customers. I&#8217;m sure that Workday&#8217;s customers &#8211; Flextronics, Sallie Mae and Kimberly-Clark &#8211; would argue that point. And by all accounts, Workday is just getting started. You&#8217;d think Ellison would have learned the game by now, having intimately watched Salesforce grow from a small, burgeoning company to an $18 billion player in a little over a decade, attracting a number of large customers at Oracle&#8217;s expense. And of course, when Salesforce was emerging, analysts and pundits claimed that it &#8220;doesn&#8217;t compare well at all with other large CRM packages like Siebel and PeopleSoft.&#8221; Which was true at the time. But customers don&#8217;t just buy what you&#8217;ve built today; they&#8217;re buying what you&#8217;ll have in the future. It&#8217;s easy for incumbents &#8211; and everyone else &#8211; to forget how broadly and rapidly these solutions can evolve. Some of the most &#8216;powerful&#8217; enterprise software on the market today started out as mere wedges, later transforming into meaningful and substantial platforms. Particularly for enterprises, it&#8217;s far better to evolve from something simple after learning about customer demands, than to pare down something insanely complex. And this is precisely the dilemma that traditional vendors are now facing. Much of the enterprise&#8217;s existing technology is too stale and cumbersome to support the needs of workers today. And most legacy vendors simply can&#8217;t update their technology fast enough to compete in a world where business is changing overnight. To capitalize on this void, new solutions &#8211; built with fundamentally different models, architecture, and DNA &#8211; are rapidly emerging. Attack of the &#8220;Toys&#8221; &#8220;Yammer has gotten it right with its viral adoption model,&#8221; Steve Ballmer said of the acquisition. Yammer&#8217;s rise to prominence and purchase underscores a number of critically important trends disrupting software today. Its virality, simplicity, and freemium business model represent important levers for startups looking to take on much larger, far better resourced traditional players. Today, nearly every internet-connected, employed individual is a potential user and buyer of enterprise tools. And by making these tools accessible to users with just a few clicks, enterprise software providers can reach markets at a scale and speed that were impossible in the client-server paradigm. Across mobile and web, new solutions will emerge that help workers connect and communicate better with their customers, analyze business data, gain new clients, manage their payroll and expenses, and more. Which is precisely why we&#8217;re seeing more investment in the enterprise software space than consumer internet, chasing hundreds of billions of dollars that are now up for grabs in enterprise IT spend. At Box, we regularly talk with Global 2000 CIOs whose organizations now rely on dozens of applications that only cropped up in the past couple of years. This pace of adoption wasn&#8217;t possible in any previous technology era; the way software was both designed and implemented prohibited it. In the past, each new application required new infrastructure and new competencies, making organizations wary of new additions to the stack. It was far &#8220;easier&#8221; to buy your technology for a select few vendors. But that&#8217;s simply not possible today, given the heterogeneity of enterprise environments and diversity of new tools that users are bringing into work on their own. Consequently, today&#8217;s technology buyers have become more comfortable with the mix-and-match approach to enterprise IT, and now managing another mobile app or cloud solution is a far more incremental, trivial exercise. And unsurprisingly, the cycles of disruption are accelerating. Given increasingly lower barriers to distribution, less conservative buyers, and rapidly changing business demands, we&#8217;re going to see unprecedented change in enterprise technology moving forward. Yammer produced a billion dollar outcome in less than four years. Following suit, we&#8217;re already seeing a new crop of companies initiate the next wave of disruption, like Base, Domo, CloudOn, GoodData, Asana, MixPanel, Zapier, PiCloud, DotCloud, intercom.io, PlanGrid (Box is an investor through /bin) and many others. Initially, many will be written off by the legacy players as too simple to be important. But as they rise, we&#8217;ll see software categories created, remade and destroyed. Some of these apps, of course, will invariably go the way of Yammer, and be snapped up by incumbents. Others, however, will remain independent, evolve to the needs of large enterprises, and turn into leaders that define the next generation of enterprise software. And then they, too, will have to defend their positions against the next wave of &#8220;toys.&#8221;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/01/rise-of-the-enterprise-toys/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/01/rise-of-the-enterprise-toys/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
