<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX</title>
      <description>Scary Mommy: I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it comes to buying local, you can't get much closer than in your "Under Pants." http://t.co/mvDAzrxY</title>
      <description>Doug French: When it comes to buying local, you can't get much closer than in your "Under Pants." http://t.co/mvDAzrxY &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kh7baLix8m/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kh7baLix8m/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU</title>
      <description>Tom Murphy: Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Things on Your LinkedIn Profile That Shouldn&#8217;t Be on Your Resume</title>
      <description>Gerrit Hall is the CEO and co-founder of RezScore, a free web application that reads, analyzes and grades resumes instantly. Connect with Gerrit and RezScore on Facebook and Twitter. Many people think their LinkedIn profiles and their resumes are interchangeable, but you should not send your entire LinkedIn profile into a potential employer and expect to land an interview. While there is the LinkedIn Resume Builder, all that does is reformat your existing profile into a resume &#8212; it&#8217;s not tailored enough to show the value you could bring to the specific job you&#8217;re applying for. Sure, LinkedIn and your resume have a lot in common. They both include your professional summary, experience, skills, contact information, education and important links. But beyond that, there are plenty of things your LinkedIn profile has that need to stay clear of your resume. 1. All of Your Experience That job you held in high school is likely not applicable to your career path five years post-graduation, so don&#8217;t include it on your resume. The jobs you display on your resume should be relevant to the position you&#8217;re applying for, so show potential employers your pertinent accomplishments and results at each position in the bullet points. A resume should be much more focused towards a particular role than your profile. Think of your LinkedIn profile as your &#8220;master resume,&#8221; and then pull the most relevant information from it to build a resume for each position you apply for. For example, if you were applying for a job in social media, you&#8217;d want to include your internship at a local news station where you helped create a Facebook Page for the company. However, you don&#8217;t want to list your high school position where you worked at an after-school care facility. 2. Publications It&#8217;s true that a potential employer might want to see your work portfolio or samples, but including links to everything you&#8217;ve ever written on your resume is unnecessary. Keeping track of these on your LinkedIn profile can be helpful, though, particularly when the employer asks for links to your previous work or writing samples on the application. Instead of including links to everything you&#8217;ve done, simply provide a link to your LinkedIn profile or online portfolio on your resume (or in your email signature) to allow employers to check it out on their own time. 3. Recommendations Yes, you need to have references handy for moving forward in the hiring process, but it&#8217;s not necessary to take up space on your resume with phrases such as &#8220;References available upon request.&#8221; Employers expect this, so there is no need to say it &#8212; much less include any recommendations. It&#8217;s common for employers to ask for these further along in the hiring process anyway, though some may require it on the job application. 4. Interests While it&#8217;s great to let your networking connections see your interests on LinkedIn, a potential employer does not need to know that you enjoy playing basketball if you&#8217;re applying for a job in IT. The same goes for your love for cooking if your career path isn&#8217;t related to anything culinary. Leave out the talk about your interests in social media -&#8211; if the recruiter checks out your profiles, he&#8217;ll likely learn about your hobbies and favorite sports teams through the content you&#8217;ve shared. 5. Birthday Age discrimination is a worry among job seekers, whether they&#8217;re more &#8203;&#8203;experienced or fresh out of college. While it can be helpful for LinkedIn contacts to know when to send you a birthday wish, you do not need to include any personal information, such as your age or birthday, on your resume. Instead, you want to highlight your experience and skills to show the employer why you&#8217;re a good fit for the opening, regardless of how old you are &#8212; which means providing a compelling (yet concise) resume. 6. Marital Status Your personal life is your personal life. Whether you&#8217;re married or single should not affect your ability to do the job, so don&#8217;t give employers more insight into your personal business than necessary. Although job seekers who are used to creating a curriculum vitae (CV) might typically include personal information, such as marital status, place of birth or their spouse&#8217;s name, it is not appropriate to include this detailed information on your resume. What&#8217;s on your LinkedIn profile that&#8217;s not on your resume? Let us know in the comments below. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Sr. Brand Strategist at MSNBC in New York City Digital Senior Account Executive &#8211; PR at Edelman in Washington, D.C. Web Producer at Romney For President in Salt Lake City Image courtesy of Flickr, nanpalmero More About: contributor, features, job search series, jobs, linkedin, mashableFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/12/linkedin-profile-resume/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/12/linkedin-profile-resume/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage neon tote..have to have it #brimfield http://t.co/s0EQ8WDh</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Vintage neon tote..have to have it #brimfield http://t.co/s0EQ8WDh &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kh-EZZFgMS/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kh-EZZFgMS/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Hot Startups Using Tech for Good</title>
      <description>In our social entrepreneurship series, The World at Work, Mashable interviews the faces behind the startups and projects that are working to make a global impact. By harnessing the power of the web and digital technology, these companies have built a way for companies to commit to charity, made electric cars affordable and offered a new way for people to rally around political issues. While the companies are diverse, they are all on a mission to change our lives for the better and improve society. Here&#8217;s a roundup of featured projects from the last week, including exclusive video interviews with the founders of these innovative startups. To read more and watch the videos, click through to the full story, and follow the series to learn about more breakthrough companies. 1. Sparked Big Idea: Sparked is an online-only volunteer hub for people to donate their talents to non-profits, as well as an engagement tool for businesses to engage and incentivize employees to contribute to volunteer causes. Why It&#8217;s Working: Users can donate expertise and skills instead of money, and make time commitments according to availability and interest level. Read the full story here. 2. Holstee Big Idea: Holstee is an ecommerce marketplace for sustainable products that are &#8220;designed with a conscience.&#8221; Why It&#8217;s Working: Holstee is driven by its social values and not a race for profits. Yet, the revenue still pours in as consumers become emotionally attached to its vision and mission. The company gives back by investing in entrepreneurship abroad through microfinancing, helping others to scale their businesses. Read the full story and see the video here. 3. Coda Big Idea: Coda is offering potential owners (in California only, for now) the opportunity to design and reserve their own electric vehicle for only $99. Why It&#8217;s Working: Focused on reducing vehicle emissions while also providing a wallet-friendly and eco-friendly option for consumers, Coda aims to make a major splash in the consumer electric vehicle industry &#8212; and the automotive industry at large. Read the full story here. 4. Bamboo Bike Studio Big Idea: Bamboo Bike Studio holds bike-building workshops where students can craft their own bamboo bicycle &#8212; a sustainable form of transportation made in a sustainable way. Why It&#8217;s Working: Bamboo Bike Studio uses the money from stateside workshops to fund a bike factory in Africa, where bamboo can be harnessed into reliable, sustainable transport for very little money. Read the full story here. 5. Ruck.us Big Idea: Through Ruck.us, users are matched with politically active people that share their &#8220;political DNA,&#8221; then form groups around issues they&#8217;re passionate about and take action. Why It&#8217;s Working: Many Americans no longer define themselves as strictly Republican or Democrat &#8212; Ruck.us gives those independents an outlet for political expression outside the binary, two-party system. Read the full story here. What do you think of the efforts of these startups and foundations? Let us know in the comments below. More About: features, mashable, roundup, trending, World at WorkFor more Social Good coverage:Follow Mashable Social Good on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Good channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/12/startupsworld-at-work-7/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/12/startupsworld-at-work-7/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google+ Hangouts On Air for Everyone: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Google+ Hangouts On Air Now Available Worldwide: Google+ Hangouts On Air was launched last September to a limited number of broadcasters and is now rolling out to the rest of the world. This means &#8220;you can now go live in front of a global audience.&#8221; Here&#8217;s a reminder of what you can do:http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3pmSWh2BQcoFacebook Announces The App Center: The App Center is a new place for people to find social apps. &#8220;For the over 900 million people that use Facebook, the App Center will become the new, central place to find great apps&#8221;"Everything has an app detail page, which helps people see what makes an app unique and lets them install it before going to an app."What You Need To Know About Facebook&#8217;s IPO: Facebook&#8217;s initial public offering is expected to take place on May 18.Discussion from our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:Do you think of your blog as a social network?What are your favorite productivity apps?What&#8217;s your experience with Facebook Offers?Google+ Notifications in Gmail Get More Interactive: You can now view, comment on and +1 Google+ notifications from your Gmail inbox. These updates will appear in your Google+ stream in real time and responses from others will appear in Gmail.You can adjust which Google+ notifications you want emailed to your Gmail account via Google+ settings.Google Offers Get Closer to Your Business: Android users in the U.S. can now find Google Offers from nearby businesses using the latest release of Google Maps. You will be able to &#8220;see all the Google Offers near you in list or map form, making it easy to get great deals from local businesses on the go.&#8221;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yBrbIQ-1g80Twitter Tweaks the Tweet Design: &#8220;Now, when you hover over the newly redesigned tweet, you&#8217;ll always see options to reply, favorite or retweet in the lower-left corner against a grey background.&#8221;This design modification makes it easier to interact with others on Twitter.com.Tumblr Introduces Storyboard: Storyboard is Tumblr&#8217;s &#8220;new hub for in-depth conversations with Tumblr&#8217;s creative community.&#8221; Foursquare Adds a History Page: With the &#8220;new, fully searchable history page, you can easily jump to all your past check-ins from any month or year, and even filter them by who you were with, what type of place you were at, or which neighborhood, city, or country you were in.&#8221;Foursquare will be "adding more features like filtering by venue and adding tips or creating lists right from this history page."Groupon Rewards Launches Nationwide in the U.S.: &#8220;When you visit a participating Groupon Rewards merchant and use the credit card saved in your Groupon account, Rewards are unlocked after you&#8217;ve spent a certain amount predetermined by the business.&#8221;"Eliminating the hassles of check-ins, extra apps or punch cards, with Groupon Rewards you can automatically get benefits for things you already do."Here are a few useful social media tools worth noting:WP Pinner: A WordPress plugin that lets you manage your Pinterest account. &#8220;With this plugin you can easily auto-pin WordPress posts, schedule your pins throughout the day, auto-follow users to get noted and keep track of your account (CTR, clicks, likes, repins, reach, etc.).&#8221;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vx10ctSCLoMLujure: An easy tool for businesses to customize Facebook fan pages.Lujure is a simple, quick tool you can use, with no technology expertise at all, to customize your own Facebook page.Curate Me: A tool to help you stay current, find good things to share and get content ideas.Curate Me finds the best stories from your friends and the brilliant people you follow and delivers them straight to your inbox.And don&#8217;t miss this:Social Media Examiner&#8217;s Social Media Success Summit 2012 (online conference) just started. It&#8217;s not too late to join!Join 27 social media experts at Social Media Examiner&#8217;s big online conference! Go here to learn more.What social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-hangouts-on-air-for-everyone-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-hangouts-on-air-for-everyone-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google May Be Close to Acquiring Meebo for $100 Million [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Google is in discussions to acquire Meebo for as much as $100 million, sources have told the often-reliable AllThingsD. Meebo was founded in 2005 as a messaging app for the browser, a product that still exists as Meebo Messenger. The Mountain</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/12/google-acquiring-meebo/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/12/google-acquiring-meebo/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yummy catering :) http://t.co/vYGJlLSz</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Yummy catering :) http://t.co/vYGJlLSz &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KcoPEElgMR/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KcoPEElgMR/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erik reliving his youth at @thelandofnod space #fallpreview http://t.co/KfiY43zp</title>
      <description>Crate and Barrel: Erik reliving his youth at @thelandofnod space #fallpreview http://t.co/KfiY43zp &#9733; Retweeted by The Land of Nod Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KdN4Ytsvy4/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KdN4Ytsvy4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Are the Top Retailers on Social Media? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s become practically mandatory that brands incorporate social media into their business strategy, causing retailers to compete for popularity in stores and on the Internet, too. Campalyst has provided this infographic, which covers the largest Internet retailers in the U.S., and their presence on the five key social networks: Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Google+ and Pinterest. Victoria&#8217;s Secret is the top retailer on Facebook, with nearly 18.5 million fans, followed by Walmart with about 15 million fans. According to Campalyst, 97% of the Top 250 Internet Retailers are on Facebook, and average number of fans there is close to 1 million. On Twitter, Major League Baseball is the leading Internet retailer account with 1.9 followers. The brand also has the most on Google+, boasting more than 600,000 followers. Retail channels on YouTube do not show numbers as large as the other social platforms. Nike has the most subscribers with more than 200,000. Pinterest is still relatively new to the social media game, which explains why its numbers are the lowest. It may also suggest that the platform is better for user-generated content, rather than retail. Nordstrom leads on Pinterest with more than 14,000 followers. SEE ALSO: 8 Strategies for Launching a Brand Presence on Pinterest The infographic also breaks down what retail industries are leading on each platform. For example, apparel/accessories average 100,000 followers on Twitter, while computers and electronics only average about 62,000 &#8212; yet computers and electronics is the top industry with subscribers on YouTube. Take a look at the stats below and let us know what you think. Do any of the retail brands or industries surprise you? Is retail suitable for all of these platforms? Share your thoughts in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, pressureUSA More About: brands, Facebook, features, Google, infographic, pinterest, retail, Social Media, trending, Twitter, YouTubeFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/retailers-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/retailers-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
