<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Asking Twitter To Commit Suicide With A Google+ Dagger</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it&amp;#8217;s easy for power users to get drunk on that power.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m as guilty of this as anyone. When I constantly bitch that my Gmail account is SO DAMN SLOW, I forget that I also have a full 20 GB of email &#8212; something which Google PR always kindly reminds me. (And I came up with my own solution &#8212; &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/06/i-wouldnt-say-ive-been-missing-it/"&gt;quitting email entirely&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/robert-scoble"&gt;Robert Scoble&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps the&amp;nbsp;consummate&amp;nbsp;power user. Every time a new service launches, he quickly friends or follows as many people as he can, testing the limits. Then he inevitably bitches when limits are hit, or the service doesn&amp;#8217;t work well with that many connections. Because, you know, most people don&amp;#8217;t have 30,000 friends. (Nor does Scoble &#8212; but that&amp;#8217;s another matter.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyway, Scoble is the king of power using a product to its breaking point and then complaining about it. One recent example: Scoble &lt;a href="http://scobleizer.com/2011/01/30/why-i-was-wrong-about-quora-as-a-blogging-service/"&gt;complaining&lt;/a&gt; that Quora isn&amp;#8217;t really any good as a blogging&amp;nbsp;platform&amp;nbsp;&#8212; &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/31/quora-quora-quora-quora-quora-quora-quora/"&gt;a straw man argument that he himself set up&lt;/a&gt;, no less. This weekend, he was back at it. And the victim of his rage this time was a &lt;a href="http://scobleizer.com/2008/05/30/twitter-blames-its-users/"&gt;familiar one&lt;/a&gt;: Twitter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a post entitled, &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://scobleizer.com/2011/07/17/google-has-made-twitter-boring-heres-what-twitter-should-do-about-that/"&gt;Google+ has made Twitter boring, here&#8217;s what Twitter should do about that&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, Scoble goes on a long-ish rant about what features Twitter needs to add immediately to compete with the just-launched Google+. Missing in this rant is one very critical thing:&amp;nbsp;introspection. Scoble fails to recognize that he is a power user to the Nth degree.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Put more bluntly: if Twitter is batshit crazy enough to implement even half of the things that Scoble lays out, they will effectively kill their own product.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, we can rest-assured knowing that Twitter is very likely are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; this foolish. After being in business for &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/15/twitter-is-interesting/"&gt;a full five years&lt;/a&gt;, they must know by now that their strength is not to mimic every just-launched and hot-right-now new social network (in this case, Google+). Their strength is to remain true to &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/06/all-the-presidents-tweets/"&gt;what got them to where they are now&lt;/a&gt;: simplicity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s not to say Twitter should not add new functionality or improve upon their service. Of course they should. But if they added some of the things Scoble suggests like adding&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.twylah.com/"&gt;Twylah&lt;/a&gt; information (really?), removing the pushing of links from other services, and re-creating Google+ Circles for Twitter, a product that many people already don&amp;#8217;t use after signing up would become completely unusable for most people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter is not Google+. Nor does it need to be. If they tried to make it into Google+ on the fly, the millions of current users would rightfully throw a shit-fit. I have a feeling that Scoble would too.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/17/is-social-in-googles-dna/"&gt;In a guest post this weekend&lt;/a&gt;, Tom Anderson (more affectionately known as &amp;#8220;MySpace Tom&amp;#8221;) made the key point that many people often overlook &#8212; most services aren&amp;#8217;t killed by competitors, they kill themselves. Facebook didn&amp;#8217;t kill MySpace, MySpace killed itself (through mismanagement). MySpace didn&amp;#8217;t kill Friendster, Friendster killed itself (through scaling issues).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The truth is that Twitter &lt;em&gt;almost did&lt;/em&gt; kill itself a few years ago also due to scaling issues. But for whatever reason, none of their competitors were able to capitalize and Twitter emerged, stronger.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But Twitter trying to become Google+ would lead to their death. It would be them killing themselves. And while you could argue that them doing nothing in the face of Google+ could also lead to them killing themselves, I think that&amp;#8217;s way too early to call. And it assumes Twitter is not doing anything to improve their product &#8212; which is ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s look at Scoble&amp;#8217;s ideas, step by step.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;First Experience&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Scoble says that when a user first looks at Google+ versus Twitter, Twitter seems boring. That might be true for some, but the opposite is true for others. I&amp;#8217;ve talked to many people who take one look at Google+ and think it looks like a nightmare of content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He&amp;#8217;s right in that Twitter needs to do something more to get users engaged when they first sign up. But they know this. It&amp;#8217;s probably their biggest problem (well, perhaps beyond monetization). The solution is not to fundamentally change your product though.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Implementing&amp;nbsp;Twylah would be way too confusing for most users and&amp;nbsp;unnecessary. Revamping Twitter Lists would also not work for most users (more on that in a bit). Getting rid of spam is constantly a problem, there&amp;#8217;s no arguing there. Scoble suggests they filter results by Klout score, I suspect Twitter will eventually do something like this (though I think they have their own internal scores of that nature).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Pictures &amp;amp; Videos&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Um, Twitter did just launch a major entry in the photos space. If it&amp;#8217;s deemed important enough, I&amp;#8217;m sure the same will be true of videos. Scoble seems upset that images and videos aren&amp;#8217;t shown inline in your Tweet stream (instead, they&amp;#8217;re one click away in the right column on twitter.com). Again, I suspect that there are at least as many people who would hate that feature, as would like it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter&amp;#8217;s current&amp;nbsp;scan-ability&amp;nbsp;(the ability to quickly scan over content) is great because it&amp;#8217;s streamlined. Google+, by comparison, is horrible. This was effectively &lt;a href="http://weblog.muledesign.com/2011/07/density_and_difference.php"&gt;illustrated by Mike Monteiro&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a preference. And maybe Twitter will offer this option eventually. But by default, this would make a lot of current users want to vomit. Like me, for example.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Controls Over Content Distribution&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What Scoble wants here is the equivalent of Google+ Circles. He wants to be able to message just a few Twitter users at a time, and groups of them. But this is not what Twitter is about. Twitter (for the most part) is a public broadcast system. This has served them well &#8212; while others, like Facebook, have moved more in this direction.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ is taking a different approach with Circles (though it still has a Public channel which basically everyone I know seems to be using). Scoble wants Twitter to revamp the little-used Lists product to be more like Circles. But I&amp;#8217;d argue that would not work. &lt;a href="http://parislemon.com/post/7769030399/can-we-ever-digitally-organize-our-friends"&gt;I&amp;#8217;m still not sold&lt;/a&gt; that the Circles concept will work the way Google hopes it does long term. Right now, people are enjoying the ease of setting up these groups, but maintaining them will be hard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further, as Twitter&amp;#8217;s own &lt;a href="http://kevnull.com/2011/07/can-we-ever-digitally-organize-our-friends.html"&gt;Kevin Cheng argued this weekend on his personal blog&lt;/a&gt; (and well before Scoble&amp;#8217;s post), it&amp;#8217;s not clear that organizing your friends in a digital way will ever fully work. Social groups often have too much of a gray line (which Cheng calls a &amp;#8220;soft line&amp;#8221;). &lt;a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2011/07/explicit-groups-vs-implicit-groups.html"&gt;Fred Wilson takes this a step further&lt;/a&gt;, saying that beyond family and co-workers, which are well-defined groups, all groups change over time, and without automation far beyond what we see now, grouping largely will not work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google may have solved the &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/08/26/facebook-friend-lists/"&gt;no one wants to make lists&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; problem, but it very much remains to be seen if they&amp;#8217;ve solved the larger fundamental issue. I&amp;#8217;m skeptical. And while I love Twitter lists (for populating Flipboard, in particular), I know that most users simply do not take the time to make them. Nor am I sure they ever would/should, even if the right interface is there.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This. Is. A. Pure. Power. User. Problem. &#8212; At least for Twitter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;No Auto-Pushing Of Content&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Scoble is&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/Scobleizer"&gt;following&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;32,297 people on Twitter. That&amp;#8217;s 31,600 more people than me, and I&amp;#8217;m also a power user. When he complains that &amp;#8220;I look at Twitter and a lot of it has turned into a boring RSS feed.&amp;#8221; Why doesn&amp;#8217;t he, you know, unfollow a few hundred of those accounts that are just pumping in RSS content &#8212; like the TechCrunch account, for example? Because that would be an easy solution, and he doesn&amp;#8217;t think he should have to change his completely outrageous use-cases.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fact is that many people use Twitter for just this purpose. I increasingly use Twitter to replace my RSS reader, for example. If I don&amp;#8217;t want to see content pushed in, I unfollow that account. Simple.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further, the thought that if Google+ continues to gain popularity, the same users won&amp;#8217;t happen is laughable. Several of our competitors are already blanketing G+ with auto-pushed links. We haven&amp;#8217;t been doing that yet just because Google keeps saying they&amp;#8217;d prefer we wait until they have their proper business accounts set up (any day now, Google). This is going to happen. A lot. Welcome to the world of&amp;nbsp;distribution&amp;nbsp;tools.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;You Can See Who You Excited And Who You Pissed Off&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Okay, I don&amp;#8217;t even know where to start here, so I&amp;#8217;ll keep it short and sweet. This is mainly about ego, but it&amp;#8217;s also another power user feature that would just piss off a bunch of regular users.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;The Posts Autoflow&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Scoble, you use a Mac, download Twitter for Mac. Boom. Done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Seriously though, Twitter used to have this as a feature back in the day. They turned it off as scaling became an issue. They certainly could turn it on again, but they&amp;#8217;ve deliberately made the call not to. Certainly, they have a reason for this. They also just bought TweetDeck, which also does this. So maybe they view it (like TweetDeck itself) as, surprise, surprise, a power user feature.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also, while Google+ does auto-flow, I find the functionality to be extremely buggy right now. Sometimes my stream auto-updates, sometimes it does not. Often, I have to refresh to see the latest comments, +1s, etc. This actually pisses me off more than I find it useful. I&amp;#8217;m sure Google will figure it out &#8212; FriendFeed had this nailed back in the day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter Is Not Google+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let me just wrap this up by stating the obvious: Twitter is not Google+. If it tried to be, it would be the suicide of a massively popular product &#8212; one the freaking President of the United States uses. In my opinion, Twitter&amp;#8217;s rise can be directly attributable to attributed to something which is the opposite of everything Scoble is asking for: simplicity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter&amp;#8217;s core concept is the extension of simple messages throughout the past many decade. The postcard begat the SMS message begat the IM status message &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2009/07/04/short-is-sweet-postcards-begat-sms-begat-twitter/"&gt;begat Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes the simplest ideas resonate the most for the very reason that they are simple.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter has had a few moments in their history where they had to add a feature that would make the service more complicated &#8212; &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2009/11/11/simple-is-as-simple-does-the-risk-of-retweet/"&gt;like the new-style retweets, for example&lt;/a&gt; &#8212; and they were able to pull it off, but it was rough-going transition for a little bit. Imagine if they tried to tack-on some of these other things Scoble is suggesting? Actually, don&amp;#8217;t bother. Because Twitter is not going to commit suicide any time soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/393292/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&amp;amp;blog=24588526&amp;amp;post=393292&amp;amp;subd=tctechcrunch2011&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fJUfIRbtJsnXvxY703rQ8CViCIY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fJUfIRbtJsnXvxY703rQ8CViCIY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fJUfIRbtJsnXvxY703rQ8CViCIY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fJUfIRbtJsnXvxY703rQ8CViCIY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=SvTVK3nwcFw:Z63CFYwH8dw:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/SvTVK3nwcFw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/18/dont-drink-and-power-use/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/18/dont-drink-and-power-use/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News of the World phone hacking whistleblower found dead</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.22.2/3056?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=News+of+the+World+phone+hacking+whistleblower+found+dead%3AArticle%3A1608708&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Phone+hacking+%28Media%29%2CMedia%2CNews+of+the+World%2CAndy+Coulson+%28Media%29%2CUK+news%2CNews+International%2CPress+and+publishing%2CNational+newspapers+UK+%28media%29%2CNewspapers&amp;c5=Press+Media%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly&amp;c6=Amelia+Hill%2CJames+Robinson%2CCaroline+Davies&amp;c7=11-Jul-18&amp;c8=1608708&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c11=Media&amp;c13=&amp;c25=&amp;c30=content&amp;h2=GU%2FMedia%2FPhone+hacking" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Death of Sean Hoare &#8211; who was first named journalist to allege Andy Coulson knew of hacking &#8211; not being treated as suspicious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sean Hoare, the former News of the World showbiz reporter who was the first named journalist to allege Andy Coulson was aware of phone hacking by his staff, has been found dead, the Guardian has learned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare, who worked on the Sun and the News of the World with Coulson before being dismissed for drink and drugs problems, is said to have been found dead at his Watford home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hertfordshire police would not confirm his identity, but the force said in a statement: "At 10.40am today [Monday 18 July] police were called to Langley Road, Watford, following the concerns for welfare of a man who lives at an address on the street. Upon police and ambulance arrival at a property, the body of a man was found. The man was pronounced dead at the scene shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The death is currently being treated as unexplained, but not thought to be suspicious. Police investigations into this incident are ongoing."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare first made his claims in a New York Times investigation into the phone-hacking allegations at the News of the World.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told that newspaper that not only did Coulson know of the phone-hacking, but that he actively encouraged his staff to intercept the phone calls of celebrities in the pursuit of exclusives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a subsequent interview with the BBC he alleged that he was personally asked by his then-editor, Coulson, to tap into phones. In an interview with the PM programme he said Coulson's insistence that he didn't know about the practice was "a lie, it is simply a lie".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time a Downing Street spokeswoman said Coulson totally and utterly denied the allegations and said he had "never condoned the use of phone-hacking and nor do I have any recollection of incidences where phone-hacking took place".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sean Hoare, a one-time close friend of Coulson's, told the New York Times the two men first worked together at the Sun, where, Hoare said, he played tape recordings of hacked messages for Coulson. At the News of the World, Hoare said he continued to inform Coulson of his activities. Coulson "actively encouraged me to do it," Hoare said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September last year he was interviewed under caution by police over his claims that the former Tory communications chief asked him to hack into phones when he was editor of the paper, but declined to make any comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare emerged back into the spotlight last week, after he told the New York Times that reporters at the News of the World were able to use police technology to locate people using their mobile phone signals in exchange for payments to police officers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said journalists were able to use a technique called 'pinging' which measured the distance between mobile handsets and a number of phone masts to pinpoint its location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare gave further details about the use of 'pinging' to the Guardian last week. He described how reporters would ask a news desk executive to obtain the location of a target: "Within 15 to 30 minutes someone on the news desk would come back and say 'right that's where they are.'"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said: "You'd just go to the news desk and they'd just come back to you. You don't ask any questions. You'd consider it a job done. The chain of command is one of absolute discipline and what's why I never bought into, like with Andy saying he wasn't aware of it and all that. That's bollocks."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said he would stand by everything he had told the New York Times about 'pinging'. "I don't know how often it happened. That would be wrong of me. But if I had access as a humble reporter &#8230; ."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He admitted he had had problems with drink and drugs and had been in rehab. "But that's irrelevant," he said. "There's more to come. This is not going to go away."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare named a private investigator who he said had links with the News of the World, adding: "He may want to talk now because I think what you'll find now is a lot of people are going to want to cover their arse."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking to another Guardian journalist st last week, Hoare repeatedly expressed the hope that the hacking scandal would lead to journalism in general being cleaned up and said he had decided to blow the whistle on the activities of some of his former News of the World colleagues with that aim in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also said he has been injured at a party the previous weekend while taking down a marquee erected for a children's party. He said he had broken his nose and badly injured his foot when a relative accidentally struck him with a heavy pole from the marquee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare also emphasised that he was not making any money from telling his story. Hoare, who has been treated for drug and alcohol problems, reminisced about partying with former pop stars and said he missed the days when he was able to go out on the town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/phone-hacking"&gt;Phone hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsoftheworld"&gt;News of the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/andy-coulson"&gt;Andy Coulson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsinternational"&gt;News International&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pressandpublishing"&gt;Newspapers &amp; magazines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/national-newspapers"&gt;National newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newspapers"&gt;Newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/ameliahill"&gt;Amelia Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jamesrobinson"&gt;James Robinson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/carolinedavies"&gt;Caroline Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; Guardian News &amp; Media Limited 2011 | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://users.guardian.co.uk/help/article/0,,933909,00.html"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/news-of-the-world-sean-hoare</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/news-of-the-world-sean-hoare</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News of the World phone hacking whistleblower found dead</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.22.2/3056?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=News+of+the+World+phone+hacking+whistleblower+found+dead%3AArticle%3A1608708&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Phone+hacking+%28Media%29%2CMedia%2CNews+of+the+World%2CAndy+Coulson+%28Media%29%2CUK+news%2CNews+International%2CPress+and+publishing%2CNational+newspapers+UK+%28media%29%2CNewspapers&amp;c5=Press+Media%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly&amp;c6=Amelia+Hill%2CJames+Robinson%2CCaroline+Davies&amp;c7=11-Jul-18&amp;c8=1608708&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c11=Media&amp;c13=&amp;c25=&amp;c30=content&amp;h2=GU%2FMedia%2FPhone+hacking" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Death of Sean Hoare &#8211; who was first named journalist to allege Andy Coulson knew of hacking &#8211; not being treated as suspicious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sean Hoare, the former News of the World showbiz reporter who was the first named journalist to allege Andy Coulson was aware of phone hacking by his staff, has been found dead, the Guardian has learned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare, who worked on the Sun and the News of the World with Coulson before being dismissed for drink and drugs problems, is said to have been found dead at his Watford home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hertfordshire police would not confirm his identity, but the force said in a statement: "At 10.40am today [Monday 18 July] police were called to Langley Road, Watford, following the concerns for welfare of a man who lives at an address on the street. Upon police and ambulance arrival at a property, the body of a man was found. The man was pronounced dead at the scene shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The death is currently being treated as unexplained, but not thought to be suspicious. Police investigations into this incident are ongoing."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare first made his claims in a New York Times investigation into the phone-hacking allegations at the News of the World.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told that newspaper that not only did Coulson know of the phone-hacking, but that he actively encouraged his staff to intercept the phone calls of celebrities in the pursuit of exclusives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a subsequent interview with the BBC he alleged that he was personally asked by his then-editor, Coulson, to tap into phones. In an interview with the PM programme he said Coulson's insistence that he didn't know about the practice was "a lie, it is simply a lie".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time a Downing Street spokeswoman said Coulson totally and utterly denied the allegations and said he had "never condoned the use of phone-hacking and nor do I have any recollection of incidences where phone-hacking took place".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sean Hoare, a one-time close friend of Coulson's, told the New York Times the two men first worked together at the Sun, where, Hoare said, he played tape recordings of hacked messages for Coulson. At the News of the World, Hoare said he continued to inform Coulson of his activities. Coulson "actively encouraged me to do it," Hoare said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September last year he was interviewed under caution by police over his claims that the former Tory communications chief asked him to hack into phones when he was editor of the paper, but declined to make any comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare emerged back into the spotlight last week, after he told the New York Times that reporters at the News of the World were able to use police technology to locate people using their mobile phone signals in exchange for payments to police officers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said journalists were able to use a technique called 'pinging' which measured the distance between mobile handsets and a number of phone masts to pinpoint its location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare gave further details about the use of 'pinging' to the Guardian last week. He described how reporters would ask a news desk executive to obtain the location of a target: "Within 15 to 30 minutes someone on the news desk would come back and say 'right that's where they are.'"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said: "You'd just go to the news desk and they'd just come back to you. You don't ask any questions. You'd consider it a job done. The chain of command is one of absolute discipline and what's why I never bought into, like with Andy saying he wasn't aware of it and all that. That's bollocks."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said he would stand by everything he had told the New York Times about 'pinging'. "I don't know how often it happened. That would be wrong of me. But if I had access as a humble reporter &#8230; ."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He admitted he had had problems with drink and drugs and had been in rehab. "But that's irrelevant," he said. "There's more to come. This is not going to go away."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare named a private investigator who he said had links with the News of the World, adding: "He may want to talk now because I think what you'll find now is a lot of people are going to want to cover their arse."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking to another Guardian journalist st last week, Hoare repeatedly expressed the hope that the hacking scandal would lead to journalism in general being cleaned up and said he had decided to blow the whistle on the activities of some of his former News of the World colleagues with that aim in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also said he has been injured at a party the previous weekend while taking down a marquee erected for a children's party. He said he had broken his nose and badly injured his foot when a relative accidentally struck him with a heavy pole from the marquee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoare also emphasised that he was not making any money from telling his story. Hoare, who has been treated for drug and alcohol problems, reminisced about partying with former pop stars and said he missed the days when he was able to go out on the town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/phone-hacking"&gt;Phone hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsoftheworld"&gt;News of the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/andy-coulson"&gt;Andy Coulson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsinternational"&gt;News International&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pressandpublishing"&gt;Newspapers &amp; magazines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/national-newspapers"&gt;National newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newspapers"&gt;Newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/ameliahill"&gt;Amelia Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jamesrobinson"&gt;James Robinson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/carolinedavies"&gt;Caroline Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; Guardian News &amp; Media Limited 2011 | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://users.guardian.co.uk/help/article/0,,933909,00.html"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xI9zu2oik2EMX3gp2yzz3cNCeY8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/news-of-the-world-sean-hoare</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/news-of-the-world-sean-hoare</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind scenes, meticulous preparations under way - Associated Press</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; LONDON (AP) -- Fifty days and counting down. Behind the scenes hundreds are hard at work to make sure the April 29 royal wedding is a day to remember - not just for Prince William and Kate Middleton, but for the country. As the date nears, the machinery that makes a British royal event look, smell</description>
      <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</link>
      <guid>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police examine bag found in bin near Rebekah Brooks's home</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.22.2/71323?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Police+examine+bag+found+in+bin+near+Rebekah+Brooks%27s+home%3AArticle%3A1608793&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Rebekah+Brooks+%28Media%29%2CPhone+hacking+%28Media%29%2CPress+and+publishing%2CNational+newspapers+UK+%28media%29%2CNewspapers%2CMedia%2CUK+news%2CNews+of+the+World%2CPolice+and+policing&amp;c5=Press+Media%2CSociety+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly&amp;c6=Amelia+Hill&amp;c7=11-Jul-18&amp;c8=1608793&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c11=Media&amp;c13=&amp;c25=&amp;c30=content&amp;h2=GU%2FMedia%2FRebekah+Brooks" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Former NI chief executive's husband denies bag &#8211; containing computer, paperwork and phone &#8211; belonged to his wife&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detectives are examining a computer, paperwork and a phone found in a bin near the riverside London home of Rebekah Brooks, the former chief executive of News International.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guardian has learned that a bag containing the items was found in an underground car park in the Design Centre at the exclusive Chelsea Harbour development on Monday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The car park, under a shopping centre, is yards from the gated apartment block where Brooks lives with her husband, a former racehorse trainer and close friend of the prime minister David Cameron.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is understood the bag was handed into security at around 3pm and that shortly afterwards, Brooks's husband, Charlie, arrived and tried to reclaim it. He was unable to prove the bag was his and the security guard refused to release it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it is understood that the security guard called the police. In less than half an hour, two marked police cars and an unmarked forensics car are said to have arrived at the scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police are now examining CCTV footage taken in the car park to uncover who dropped the bag. Initial suspicions that there had been a break in at the Brooks' flat have been dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Wilson, Charlie Brooks's official spokesman, told the Guardian that Charlie Brooks denies that the bag belonged to his wife. "Charlie has a bag which contains a laptop and papers which were private to him," said Wilson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"They were nothing to do with Rebekah or the [phone-hacking] case."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wilson said Charlie Brooks had left the bag with a friend who was returning it, but dropped it in the wrong part of the garage. When asked how the bag ended up in a bin he replied: "The suggestion is that a cleaner thought it was rubbish and put it in the bin." Wilson added: "Charlie was looking for it together with a couple of the building staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Charlie was told it had gone to security, by which stage they [security] had already called the police to say they had found something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The police took it away. Charlie's lawyers got in touch with the police to say they could take a look at the computer but they'd see there was nothing relevant to them on it. He's expecting the stuff back forthwith."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Brooks was arrested on Sunday under suspicion of conspiring to intercept communications, and of corrupting police officers. She is due to appear before the Commons culture, media and sport select committee today on Tuesday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/rebekahwade"&gt;Rebekah Brooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/phone-hacking"&gt;Phone hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pressandpublishing"&gt;Newspapers &amp; magazines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/national-newspapers"&gt;National newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newspapers"&gt;Newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsoftheworld"&gt;News of the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/police"&gt;Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/ameliahill"&gt;Amelia Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; Guardian News &amp; Media Limited 2011 | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://users.guardian.co.uk/help/article/0,,933909,00.html"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/mystery-bag-bin-rebekah-brooks</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/mystery-bag-bin-rebekah-brooks</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police examine bag found in bin near Rebekah Brooks's home</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.22.2/71323?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Police+examine+bag+found+in+bin+near+Rebekah+Brooks%27s+home%3AArticle%3A1608793&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Rebekah+Brooks+%28Media%29%2CPhone+hacking+%28Media%29%2CPress+and+publishing%2CNational+newspapers+UK+%28media%29%2CNewspapers%2CMedia%2CUK+news%2CNews+of+the+World%2CPolice+and+policing&amp;c5=Press+Media%2CSociety+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly&amp;c6=Amelia+Hill&amp;c7=11-Jul-18&amp;c8=1608793&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c11=Media&amp;c13=&amp;c25=&amp;c30=content&amp;h2=GU%2FMedia%2FRebekah+Brooks" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Former NI chief executive's husband denies bag &#8211; containing computer, paperwork and phone &#8211; belonged to his wife&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detectives are examining a computer, paperwork and a phone found in a bin near the riverside London home of Rebekah Brooks, the former chief executive of News International.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guardian has learned that a bag containing the items was found in an underground car park in the Design Centre at the exclusive Chelsea Harbour development on Monday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The car park, under a shopping centre, is yards from the gated apartment block where Brooks lives with her husband, a former racehorse trainer and close friend of the prime minister David Cameron.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is understood the bag was handed into security at around 3pm and that shortly afterwards, Brooks's husband, Charlie, arrived and tried to reclaim it. He was unable to prove the bag was his and the security guard refused to release it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it is understood that the security guard called the police. In less than half an hour, two marked police cars and an unmarked forensics car are said to have arrived at the scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police are now examining CCTV footage taken in the car park to uncover who dropped the bag. Initial suspicions that there had been a break in at the Brooks' flat have been dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Wilson, Charlie Brooks's official spokesman, told the Guardian that Charlie Brooks denies that the bag belonged to his wife. "Charlie has a bag which contains a laptop and papers which were private to him," said Wilson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"They were nothing to do with Rebekah or the [phone-hacking] case."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wilson said Charlie Brooks had left the bag with a friend who was returning it, but dropped it in the wrong part of the garage. When asked how the bag ended up in a bin he replied: "The suggestion is that a cleaner thought it was rubbish and put it in the bin." Wilson added: "Charlie was looking for it together with a couple of the building staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Charlie was told it had gone to security, by which stage they [security] had already called the police to say they had found something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The police took it away. Charlie's lawyers got in touch with the police to say they could take a look at the computer but they'd see there was nothing relevant to them on it. He's expecting the stuff back forthwith."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebekah Brooks was arrested on Sunday under suspicion of conspiring to intercept communications, and of corrupting police officers. She is due to appear before the Commons culture, media and sport select committee today on Tuesday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/rebekahwade"&gt;Rebekah Brooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/phone-hacking"&gt;Phone hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/pressandpublishing"&gt;Newspapers &amp; magazines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/national-newspapers"&gt;National newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newspapers"&gt;Newspapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/newsoftheworld"&gt;News of the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/police"&gt;Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/ameliahill"&gt;Amelia Hill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; Guardian News &amp; Media Limited 2011 | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://users.guardian.co.uk/help/article/0,,933909,00.html"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zPVt17WO7RSGu-WDiPKBKz6P15I/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/mystery-bag-bin-rebekah-brooks</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/jul/18/mystery-bag-bin-rebekah-brooks</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google+: The Complete Guide</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/mashgoog" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/&amp;title=Google+: The Complete Guide&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/googleplus1.jpg" alt="" title="googleplus" width="50" height="50" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-669481" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Already using Google+? Follow &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/mashgoog" target="_blank"&gt;Mashable News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the latest about the platform&amp;#8217;s new features, tips and tricks as well as our top social media and technology updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/google-plus-icons-360.jpg" class="alignright" width="225px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/google-plus"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;: It&amp;#8217;s the hot social network on the block. In just three weeks, Google&amp;#8217;s competitor to Facebook and Twitter has amassed more than &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/google-10-million/"&gt;10 million users&lt;/a&gt;, and its users are sharing &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/14/larry-page-google-plus/"&gt;more than 1 billion pieces of content daily&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s become a hotbed for early adopters, tech luminaries, marketers and businesses around the world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ isn&amp;#8217;t the easiest thing to understand, though. It has a lot of features that can confuse beginners. Even advanced users can miss a lot of the little gems and nuances that define Google+. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s why we decided to dig into every aspect of Google+, from Hangouts to Circles, from Google+ for businesses to what&amp;#8217;s next for Google&amp;#8217;s social network. The result is an extensive guide on all of Google+&amp;#8217;s key features, as well as an introduction to the service and the important things you need to know about it. We&amp;#8217;ve included commentary, videos, photos and more in our in-depth guide. In addition, we will update this guide regularly with the newest information on Google&amp;#8217;s Facebook competitor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, here is &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8216;s complete guide to Google+:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;What Is Google+?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ is the search giant&amp;#8217;s latest attempt to create a social network that rivals Facebook. Google &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus/"&gt;launched Google+&lt;/a&gt; on June 28, 2011 with a private beta. The project was led by &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/107117483540235115863" target="_blank"&gt;Vic Gundotra&lt;/a&gt;, Google&amp;#8217;s SVP of social.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The social network is a collection of different social products. These features include Stream (a newsfeed), Sparks (a recommendation engine), Hangouts (a video chat service), Huddle (a group texting service), Circles (a friend management service) and Photos. We explain all of these features later in this guide. More features such as Games and Questions are expected to launch in the near future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google chose the name Google+ because it wants Google+ to be &amp;#8220;an extension of Google itself,&amp;#8221; Gundotra explained to &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; days before the launch. It&amp;#8217;s designed to be an improvement to all of Google, which is why the company also decided to change the iconic Google navigation bar to include a link to a user&amp;#8217;s Google+ profile, as well as a new icon that displays how many notifications a user has received, much like how Facebook handles notifications.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t Google&amp;#8217;s first shot at dominating the social space. It has &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/07/09/google-social-media-attempts/"&gt;a long history&lt;/a&gt; in social media, including Orkut and its biggest success in social, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. However, it&amp;#8217;s had &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/12/28/tech-win-flop-surprise-2010/"&gt;two very big flops&lt;/a&gt; in social: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/04/rip-google-wave/"&gt;Google Wave&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/02/09/google-buzz/"&gt;Google Buzz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Screenshots: What Google+ Looks Like&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This gallery will provide you with a quick overview of what Google+ looks like. Keep reading this guide to learn more about how to use all of Google+&amp;#8217;s features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Logo&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18171Google-Logo"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Logo" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/google-plus-logo-640.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the Google+ logo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Icons&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18169Google-Icons"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Icons" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/google-plus-icons-640.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Google+ icons. Starting top left and circling to the right: Circles, Hangouts, Home, Sparks, Profile, Photos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;New Google+ Navigation Bar&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18161New-Google-Navigation-Bar"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="New Google+ Navigation Bar" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/sandbar_one.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;All Google sites will sport the new Google+ navigation bar. It includes notifications, profile information and content sharing options.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Stream&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18159Google-Stream"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Stream" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_stream.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the Google+ Stream, where users share content and see what their friends are sharing. It is similar to the Facebook News Feed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18163Google-Circles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Circles" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_circles.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Circles is Google's version of the Facebook friend list or the Twitter List. Users can select multiple friends and drag-and-drop them into groups. This makes it easier to send stuff to friends, family or the entire world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Circles Editor&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18165Google-Circles-Editor"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Circles Editor" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_circleeditor.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the Google+ Circles editor in action. Google has created unique animations for adding and removing friends through HTML5.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Sparks&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#18167Google-Sparks"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Sparks" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_sparks.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Sparks is Google's content recommendation and discovery engine. Users can search different topics and find relevant articles, videos and photos. Users can then share that content with their friends.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Hangouts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20543Google-Hangouts"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Hangouts" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/plus-guide-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ has a unique video chat feature called Hangouts, which lets you chat with up to 10 people at the ame time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Photos&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20545Google-Photos"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Photos" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/plus-guide-19.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ allows you to upload and share photos with your friends. It includes photo tagging and a simple browser-based image editor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Profile&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20547Google-Profile"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Profile" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/plus-guide-17.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Profiles are like most profile pages -- it includes basic information about the user like interests, occupation and profile photos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Why Should Someone Use Google+?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Great, Google made a social network. Now you&amp;#8217;re probably asking yourself: Why the heck should I use Google+?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We aren&amp;#8217;t here to pitch Google+. Instead, &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101849747879612982297/posts/Nott5LCiDKr" target="_blank"&gt;we asked our Google+ followers&lt;/a&gt; a simple question: &lt;strong&gt;Why should someone use Google+?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The response was overwhelming. We got more than 500 responses on the &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; News account and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117691391504351341685/posts" target="_blank"&gt;my Google+ account&lt;/a&gt;. Since we can&amp;#8217;t post everybody&amp;#8217;s responses, we&amp;#8217;ve chosen six we believe encompass why so many people are excited by Google&amp;#8217;s new social initiative:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;#8220;Google+ is a much cleaner way to selectively share data with others. As Google integrates more of their other cloud products, like Documents, Calendar, and Reader, you&amp;#8217;re going to see it become one of the primary means of absorbing the data streaming from the Internet and sharing it with others.&amp;#8221; ~ &lt;A HREF="https://plus.google.com/109688307111271329945" target="_blank"&gt;Jason Poggioli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s the combination of being able to share based on (hopefully!) mutual interests with the ability to get exposure to interesting people and ideas. The relationship doesn&amp;#8217;t really have to be two way, but it doesn&amp;#8217;t all have to be public.&amp;#8221; ~ &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/111688710840393224386" target="_blank"&gt;Holly Henry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;For some reason, the level of engagement is higher. Commenting and resharing seems to happen at a higher rate here (so far.)&amp;#8221; ~ &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/100967353076892687633" target="_blank"&gt;Bill Shander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ve had a Facebook account since 2003. It&amp;#8217;s time for something more grown up that gives me more control and has a more organic user experience.&amp;#8221; ~ &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116413323316530767376" target="_blank"&gt;Sean Cooper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The clean user interface of Google+, combined with the lack of distracting elements, or so-called features (such as all of the add-on games and apps on FB that clutter up your stream), that I never use, attract me to Google+. This, combined with the Circles feature, choosing who you share with, are the primary draws.&amp;#8221; ~ &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/115534026950561786876" target="_blank"&gt;Scott Davis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;If Facebook and Twitter had a baby, they&amp;#8217;d call it Google+.&amp;#8221; ~ &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/111781659610540933304" target="_blank"&gt;Olaf Wempe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/plus-guide-1.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the moment, you need to be sent an invite by a friend to join Google+. While this restriction will eventually be lifted, it&amp;#8217;s best if you ask a friend to send an invite to your Gmail account. You must use a Gmail account to sign up for Google+. Google Apps accounts are currently not supported, though the search giant plans to add support for Google Apps email accounts in the near future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you accept your invite, you are taken to a page where you are asked to create your public Google Profile. Fill in information like your name and your birthday, and you are taken to Google+. If you have already filled out a Google+ Profile in the past, you skip this step and are taken to Google+.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While we go through every single one of Google+&amp;#8217;s features step-by-step in this guide, it&amp;#8217;s always smart to know the basic commands and syntax of Google+. To that end, we have included a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/the-google-cheat-sheet-pic/"&gt;Google+ cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt; that explains how to mention friends in your posts (like you can already do on Facebook or Twitter), how to bold your text and more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/google-plus-cheat-sheet.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;A Video Explanation of Google+&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The following videos, produced by Google, provide a quick introduction to Google+. Check these videos out, then keep reading our guide to learn more about each of Google+&amp;#8217;s key features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: A quick look&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/xwnJ5Bl4kLI&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/xwnJ5Bl4kLI&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google provides an overview of the entire Google+ project.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Explore Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/ocPeAdpe_A8&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/ocPeAdpe_A8&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Circles is Google's take on the friend list or the Twitter list.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Explore Settings&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/vnv1Mbj1jKw&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/vnv1Mbj1jKw&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this video, Google explores the different settings available on Google+.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Explore Mobile&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/N8gvHaX1cwY&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/N8gvHaX1cwY&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ will launch with an Android app. In this video, Google explores the app's features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Explore Hangouts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/QN38vHZjWXw&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/QN38vHZjWXw&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ comes with a group video chat feature called Hangouts. This video explains how it works.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Explore Sparks&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/0DoAl4JXhQo&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/0DoAl4JXhQo&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;In an attempt to get users to share more content, Google+ includes a feature called Sparks. It provides recommended content based on keywords or topics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/BeMZP-oyOII&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/BeMZP-oyOII&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this video, Google talks about the impact of friends and social groups.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Hangouts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/Tku1vJeuzH4&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/Tku1vJeuzH4&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google talks about spontaneous hangouts in this video.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Huddle&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/iA22daAstNg&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/iA22daAstNg&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google introduces Huddle, the company's group-texting feature.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Instant Upload&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/6y_xKVSRAy8&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/6y_xKVSRAy8&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ for mobile includes an instant upload feature for photos and videos. They're uploaded to a private album where they can then be shared from the desktop.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;The Google+ project: Sparks&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="642" height="408"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/MRkAdTflltc&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;embed width="642" height="408" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/MRkAdTflltc&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google talks about exploring interests through Sparks in this video.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Profile&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you have your Google+ account set up, the first thing you should do is fill in your user profile. If you&amp;#8217;ve already created a Google Profile before, that data will automatically be imported to your Google+ Profile &amp;#8212; in fact, your Google+ Profile replaces it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you first join Google+, it will ask you to enter a few key details, such as your tagline (a brief description of yourself), your employment and your education. It will also ask you to choose a profile photo. Once you set these details, you will have the opportunity to populate your profile with a myriad of other profile details. These include &amp;#8220;Introduction,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Bragging rights,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Occupation,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Places lived,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Relationship,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Looking for,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Other names,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Nickname&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Search visibility.&amp;#8221; On the right-hand side, you have the opportunity to add links that relate to yourself. Most users add a personal website or blog, as well as their Twitter, Facebook and LinkedIn accounts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While you&amp;#8217;re on your profile page, you also have the opportunity to change some of your privacy settings. You can allow people to email you from a link on your profile, and you can set this to be public, private or somewhere between using Google+ Circles (explained below). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Your profile also displays who is in your circles, and who has added you to their circles. You can change the privacy settings on the left-hand side of your profile to make this data public or private.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Profiles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20517Google-Profiles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Profiles" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-profiles/plus-guide-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you arrive at this screen, click on the "Complete your profile" button at the bottom fo the page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Filling in Your Google+ Profile&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20519Filling-in-Your-Google-Profile"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Filling in Your Google+ Profile" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-profiles/plus-guide-3.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Quickly fill in information such as your tagline, your employment and upload your profile photo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Profile Options&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20521Google-Profile-Options"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Profile Options" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-profiles/plus-guide-4.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different fields you can fill out on your Google+ Profile, but you don't have to fill them all out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;A Completed Google+ Profile&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20523A-Completed-Google-Profile"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="A Completed Google+ Profile" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-profiles/plus-guide-17.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is what a completed Google+ Profile looks like (I used &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117691391504351341685/about" target="_blank"&gt;my profile&lt;/a&gt; as an example.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Circles&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Understanding Circles is essential to mastering Google+. The search giant has opted not to let you simply &amp;#8220;friend&amp;#8221; your friends, like you do on Facebook, or &amp;#8220;follow&amp;#8221; different people as you would on Twitter. Instead, Google+ gives you more control over who sees your content. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Circles allows users to drag-and-drop their friends into different friend groups, which categorizes them. This allows you to put your mom in your &amp;#8220;Family&amp;#8221; circle, your boss in your &amp;#8220;Business&amp;#8221; circle and your best friend from college in your &amp;#8220;Friends&amp;#8221; circle. You can create as many circles as you&amp;#8217;d like, though making too many becomes cumbersome and diminishes the usefulness of Circles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To add friends to a circle, all you have to do is drag-and-drop them into the appropriate circle. You can add friends into as many circles as you want. You can also select multiple friends and drag them into a circle. It initially suggests friends based on who&amp;#8217;s in your Google Contacts, but it also lets you find friends by importing your address book from Yahoo!, Hotmail or your desktop. Removing friends from a circle is simple as well: just drag-and-drop from in the circle to outside the circle. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clicking on a circle gives you more granular control over adding and removing people. You can also rename your circle, write a short description about it, view the stream for your circle, open your circle in a tab and delete your circle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So why should you create circles in the first place? The answer is simple: You want to share different things with different friends. You may want to share a risqu&#233; photo with your close friends, but share a link about your company&amp;#8217;s newest hire with just your business network. Google+ Circles gives you the ability to have this kind of control over both what you share and what content pops up in your stream.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20525Google-Circles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Circles" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-circles/plus-guide-5.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Google+ Circles screen allows you to drag-and-drop your friends into different friend categories.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Drag-and-Drop Friends&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20527DragandDrop-Friends"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Drag-and-Drop Friends" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-circles/plus-guide-6.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you drag a friend over a circle, the circle expands.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google Explains Google+ Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20529Google-Explains-Google-Circles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google Explains Google+ Circles" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-circles/plus-guide-7.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the message you'll receive the first time you add somebody to a circle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Inside a Google+ Circle&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20531Inside-a-Google-Circle"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Inside a Google+ Circle" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-circles/plus-guide-8.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clicking on a circle lets you look at all the members of that group, as well as change things such as the membership and the name of the circle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Playing with Google+ Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20533Playing-with-Google-Circles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Playing with Google+ Circles" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-circles/plus-guide-18.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here's what Google+ Circles might look like after a few minutes of work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Stream &amp;#038; Sharing Content&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Facebook users will instantly get the hang of Google+ Stream &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s just a newsfeed of the latest content shared by your circles. This content can be anything from a status update to a photo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a few differences between the Google+ Stream and the Facebook News Feed. Posts by your friends move back to the top based on which post has the most recent comment, though eventually older posts are eventually buried in the stream. Instead of &amp;#8220;liking&amp;#8221; a post, you can &amp;#8220;+1&amp;#8243; a post &amp;#8212; this is part of Google&amp;#8217;s push for the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/03/30/everything-about-google-plus-1/"&gt;+1 Button&lt;/a&gt;. You can also share posts with your circles or mute a post if it&amp;#8217;s clogging up your stream.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Updating your status is a snap &amp;#8212; all you need to do is type some content in the &amp;#8220;Share&amp;#8221; box at the top of your stream and choose who to share it with. You can share it with the public (all of your followers) or just share it with certain circles. In addition to text, you can share photos, videos, links and your location. Like Facebook, Google+ automatically detects the content of the links you share and allows you to choose a thumbnail from that link.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/plus-guide-10.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The left-hand navigation includes a Stream option where you can filter your Google+ Stream. If you want to see posts only from your business network, you just have to click on that circle under the stream. Under the Stream option is a link to Google+ Sparks, which we explain later in this guide. There&amp;#8217;s also an option to activate Google Chat for your Google+ account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The right-hand navigation includes a link to manage your circles and a Suggestions section, where Google suggests people to add to your circles, based on who is in your Google Contacts and who your friends are following. Google also lets you start a Google+ Hangout video chat from the right-hand menu (we explain this feature in another section). You can also invite your friends to join you on Google+ from the right-hand nav.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Sparks&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/plus-guide-12.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stumped about what to share first on Google+? Want to find more stuff about your favorite animal or band? Google has you covered with Sparks, a content recommendation engine that finds the most relevant and interesting articles and videos on almost any subject you can imagine. The &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/sparks/interests/Android" target="_blank"&gt;Spark for Android&lt;/a&gt;, for example, contains links and thumbnails from articles about recent Android news. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google doesn&amp;#8217;t publish how it determines which content is the most relevant, but we imagine it uses signals from search, Google News, Google+ and others to determine which content is the most relevant algorithmically. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google provides a list of suggested topics, but you can type in almost any topic that suits your fancy. Some sparks have more content than others, though. You can also &amp;#8220;pin&amp;#8221; your favorite sparks to your left-hand navigation for easy access at any time. Sparks also lets you directly share the content you find with your circles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Hangouts&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;In our opinion, Google+ Hangouts may be the social network&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/01/google-the-pros-cons/"&gt;killer feature&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a novel twist on the traditional group video chat, and it&amp;#8217;s definitely received a positive reaction from the Google+ community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how it works: You click on the &amp;#8220;Start a hangout&amp;#8221; button on the right-hand menu of the Stream. Clicking it opens up a chat window where you can check your mic and choose who will be able to join the hangout (either by inviting individuals or sharing it with your circles). Once the hangout is live, your friends will see the hangout prompt in their stream. They can then join the hangout until a maximum of ten people have joined.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/hangouts-640.png" width="640px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve never used Google Talk before, you will have to install a small piece of software before Hangouts works properly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google SVP of Social Vic Gundotra compares Hangouts to friends sitting on the porch vs. knocking on a neighbor&amp;#8217;s door. Few people are willing to knock on a neighbor&amp;#8217;s door just to start a conversation, but if you see friends sitting on a porch and you walk by, it&amp;#8217;s almost rude not to drop in and say hi. Gundotra thinks one-on-one video chats are much like knocking on a neighbor&amp;#8217;s door, while a Google+ Hangout is like friends sitting on a porch.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;re in a hangout, you will notice a couple of things. First, you will notice that the video switches from person to person. This is based on who is talking into the microphone. You can hover over a person&amp;#8217;s video feed and either report them for abuse or &amp;#8220;mute&amp;#8221; them. Muting someone will mute them for everybody in the hangout, at least until he or she unmutes his or her mic. Users can also mute their video if they wish.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Hangouts also comes with a group text chat feature (similar to Google Talk). Another cool feature of Hangouts is that users can jointly watch a YouTube video. Settings lets you adjust the mic, camera and other video settings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ comes with a fully-built photo albums product, powered by the technology behind Picasa (also owned by Google). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clicking on the Photos tab on the top of your Google+ page will display recent photos uploaded by your friends, as well as how many comments each photo has received. Clicking on any of these photos brings up a photo slideshow with the most recent comments on the right-hand side and photos from your other friends on the bottom.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The slideshow is simple to navigate &amp;#8212; click on a picture to bring it up, or click and drag your mouse from side to side to scroll through other pictures. In this slideshow view, you can also tag yourself or a friend in a photo, or check out photo details such as what type of camera was used to capture the photo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another section of Photos lets you check out photos in which you&amp;#8217;ve been tagged. This is also the area where you can approve or reject photo tags. No photo will be tagged with your name until you approve it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most important feature of Photos, though, is the ability to upload photos and create albums. By clicking the giant &amp;#8220;Upload New Photos&amp;#8221; button at the top right, you can create a photo album by simply dragging and dropping photos into your browser. Once created, you can share that album with your circles, with individual friends or with the public. Albums remain private until you share them. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once uploaded, you have the ability to edit your photos right from Google+. The browser-based editor includes simple features such as cross processing, auto contrast and black-and-white effects. You can also rotate the image or delete it entirely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One more thing: Any photos you upload via the Stream will be added to an album called &amp;#8220;Photos from posts,&amp;#8221; available in the &amp;#8220;Your albums&amp;#8221; section of the Photos app.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Photos&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20535Google-Photos"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Photos" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-photos/plus-guide-15.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the home screen for Google+ Photos. Notice the icon with the number indicating how many comments each photo has received.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;An Individual Photo&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20539An-Individual-Photo"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="An Individual Photo" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-photos/plus-guide-19.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clicking on a photo takes you to this full-sized screen, where you can view the photo, see comments, make a comment and check out other photos from your circles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Uploading Photos to Google+&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20537Uploading-Photos-to-Google"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Uploading Photos to Google+" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-photos/plus-guide-16.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Adding photos to Google+ is as simple as drag-and-drop. You can also upload photos from your Android phone, and soon your iPhone.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Editing Photos&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/#20541Editing-Photos"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Editing Photos" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/google-photos/plus-guide-20.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ comes with a simple image editor for color-based effects. We hope Google will add more Instagram-style effects in the future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The last time Google treated privacy as a secondary feature, it got &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/09/03/google-buzz-lawsuit-settlement/"&gt;burned with a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;. This time around, Google isn&amp;#8217;t playing games with Google+ and privacy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the Google+ settings page (available if you click on the gear icon on the top right of the black bar), you can change all of your privacy settings. From the &amp;#8220;Account overview&amp;#8221; tab, you can change your password, activate multiple account sign-in (an advanced feature for users with lots of Google accounts) and delete your profile and/or Google account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;Profile and privacy&amp;#8221; tab is where you can really dig deep into your privacy settings. From here, you can edit the visibility of every part of your profile, manage your circles, change your network visibility, adjust your photo settings, or visit the Google Privacy Center. Google+ also has a feature where you can view your profile as your mom or your friend would see it. This is a useful feature that lets you know for sure if the content you want private is indeed private.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The settings page also has options for editing your email and mobile phone notifications, as well as options for changing the default language and connecting other social accounts to your Google+ profile. The latter feature is designed to improve Google Search more than your Google+ profile.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, Google is walking the walk when it comes to data liberation. As Google data liberation lead Brian Fitzpatrick explained to &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt;, the company believes that if it&amp;#8217;s to be trusted with more of your social data, it needs to provide users an option for taking that data out hassle-free. That&amp;#8217;s why you can download your Google+ data, including stream posts, profile data and photos. The export feature is powered by &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/29/google-takeout/"&gt;Google Takeout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Mobile&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/google-plus-android.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google owns one of the world&amp;#8217;s most popular mobile operating systems (Android), so it&amp;#8217;s no surprise that Google+ prominently features its mobile apps. As of July 16, Google+ only has an Android app, although it has a mobile web version and the iOS app is &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/04/google-plus-ios/"&gt;awaiting Apple App Store approval&lt;/a&gt;. The iOS app is almost identical to the Android app.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Google+ mobile apps are relatively straightforward. It comes with five different icons and a notifications bar. The mobile app allows you to access your stream, take and upload photos, view and update your profile and manage your circles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Two features stand out about the Google+ mobile apps. The first is a feature called &amp;#8220;Huddle,&amp;#8221; which is essentially a group texting feature not unlike &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/groupme"&gt;GroupMe&lt;/a&gt; or Beluga. It allows you to put a group of your friends together so you can send and receive group texts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The second unique feature of Google+&amp;#8217;s mobile apps is something called &amp;#8220;Instant Upload.&amp;#8221; The Instant Upload feature automatically takes the pictures you take and syncs them with your desktop. This makes it dead-simple for you to share photos you upload when you get home. These photos are uploaded into a private album you can manage and share at your convenience. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, Google+ also has a mobile interface that allows you to post updates, check what your circles are posting, comment and +1 your friends&amp;#8217; posts, and update your location. We expect Google to add more to Google+&amp;#8217;s mobile apps as it improves the service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Google+ For Businesses&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/at_azOmh69A?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ already has a lot of users, so it makes sense that businesses would want to get in on some of the action. Several businesses are already on Google+, including &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101849747879612982297" target="_blank"&gt;Mashable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/114277687548103339609/posts" target="_blank"&gt;Ford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117480638145249659856/posts" target="_blank"&gt;CBS News&lt;/a&gt; and others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But hold on! Before you start making your company&amp;#8217;s Google+ account, there are a few things you should know. The most important thing is this: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/06/google-plus-businesses/"&gt;Google doesn&amp;#8217;t want businesses creating Google+ profiles yet&lt;/a&gt;. The search giant announced on July 6 that it would be creating a platform for businesses, but that it would take some time to build.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The result is that the future of businesses and brands on Google+ has yet to be determined. Google could choose to delete all business entities, or it may transfer the followers of existing businesses to brand new business accounts. The search giant is &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/14/google-accelerates-google-plus-for-businesses/"&gt;accelerating the development&lt;/a&gt; of Google+ for businesses and will begin beta testing in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We will update this guide as we learn more about Google+ for businesses.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;What&amp;#8217;s Next for Google+?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google refers to Google+ as a project because it believes it&amp;#8217;s far from finished. The product is only a few weeks old and it has a lot of bugs that still need to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We do expect two Google+ features to launch in the near future, though. The first one is a Questions feature that will let users poll their friends, much like Quora or Facebook Questions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The second and more interesting product is &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/30/google-plus-games/"&gt;Google+ Games&lt;/a&gt;, a product rumored to be in development ever since &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/07/10/google-games-zynga/"&gt;Google invested $100+ million in Zynga&lt;/a&gt;, the creators of &lt;em&gt;FarmVille&lt;/em&gt; and other social games. Google+&amp;#8217;s code has multiple references to Google+ Games, so we expect it&amp;#8217;s only a matter of time until &lt;em&gt;Empires &amp;#038; Allies&lt;/em&gt; makes its Google debut. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most of all, expect Google&amp;#8217;s social network to evolve as it tries to meet user requests and sets its sights on Facebook, Twitter and the rest of the social media universe.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Follow Team Mashable on Google+&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/MashableCircle.jpg" class="alignright" width="225px"&gt;To help you get started on your Google+ journey, we&amp;#8217;ve included a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/15/mashable-google-plus/"&gt;full list of Mashable staff members that are actively using Google+&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, you can follow &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/mashgoog" target="_blank"&gt;Mashable News&lt;/a&gt; for the latest social media, technology and digital news from around the world. We look forward to engaging with you!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/105707669582831172745/posts"&gt;Ada Ospina&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; NYC Office Manager&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/107469895927414342167"&gt;Adam Hirsch&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; COO&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117818363829980497205"&gt;Adam Ostrow&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Editor in Chief&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101703900497034523246"&gt;Amy-Mae Elliott&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Features Writer&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/103619291449636349904"&gt;Andrew Reedman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; U.S. Director of Sales&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117691391504351341685"&gt;Ben Parr&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Editor at Large&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116269625715795017464"&gt;Brenna Ehrlich&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Associate Editor of Media &amp;amp; Entertainment&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/105714039375338797059"&gt;Brian Anthony Hernandez&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Copy Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117429013107995808644"&gt;Brian Dresher&lt;/a&gt; Director of Business Development&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116954239581842718603"&gt;Brie Manakul&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Ad Ops Manager&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/105545068944703206621"&gt;Charlie White&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Senior Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/115228314040424982574/posts"&gt;Chelsea Stark&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Community Intern&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/114274687956791581923"&gt;Christina Warren&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Mobile and Development &amp;amp; Design Reporter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/110349110664408276955/posts"&gt;Connie Preti&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Community Intern&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117711114332630815860"&gt;Emily Banks&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Assistant News Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/114199219545463600767"&gt;Erica Swallow&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Partner Content Associate Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/106009620651385224281"&gt;Frederick Townes&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; CTO&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/100834378485895409468"&gt;Jennifer Van Grove&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Startups Reporter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/110321775511217120259"&gt;Josh Catone&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Features Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116164820045631548037"&gt;Karen Hartline&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Events Director&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/113914722685746607679"&gt;Kate Hayden&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Events Assistant&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117519241832080569049"&gt;Lauren Drell&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Partner Content Assistant Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/111181389036901378787"&gt;Lauren Indvik&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Marketing &amp;amp; Media Associate Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/105818879899761203336"&gt;Louis Dorman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Art Director&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117000174975734429056"&gt;Matt Silverman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Associate Features Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/115723497250720724489"&gt;Meghan Peters&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Community Manager&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/112844561713780016118"&gt;Pete Cashmore&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Founder and CEO&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/107054398730220626019"&gt;Robyn Peterson&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Senior VP of Product&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117740874882168016435/posts"&gt;Sana Ahmed&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Executive Assistant&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/118079454568288767927"&gt;Sarah Kessler&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Startups Reporter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116946125317611044339"&gt;Sharon Feder&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Publisher&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117203199552198261635"&gt;Stacy Green&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Communications Director&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117365976800624936798"&gt;Stefanie Rennert&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; HR Manager&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/100655691978877752465"&gt;Stephanie Buck &lt;/a&gt;- Editorial Intern&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/115115679739187400203"&gt;Stephanie Haberman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Community Assistant&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/118122556596388698587"&gt;Tamar Weinberg&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Community and Global Advertising&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116657988252926468304"&gt;Tanya Salah&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; West Coast Sales Director&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/102940125102204708996"&gt;Todd Olmstead&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Community Intern&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/116771592604091695757"&gt;Todd Wasserman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Business and Marketing Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/108808857392620254086"&gt;Zachary Sniderman&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Social Good Assistant Editor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;+&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/113464984178845745585"&gt;Zoe Fox&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Social Good Intern &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;More Helpful Google+ Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The following is a collection of &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8216;s top resources on Google+. We will update this list on a regular basis:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 1) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus/"&gt;Google Launches Google+ To Battle Facebook [PICS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;2) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus-review/"&gt;Google+: First Impressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;3) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/the-google-cheat-sheet-pic/"&gt;The Google+ Cheat Sheet [PIC]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;4) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/01/google-the-pros-cons/"&gt;Google+: The Pros &amp;#038; Cons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;5) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/14/google-plus-chrome-extension/"&gt;5 Chrome Extensions That Improve Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;6) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/09/google-plus-plus-one/"&gt;What&#8217;s In a Name: Google+ Is Your Plus One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;7) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus-videos/"&gt;A Closer Look at Google&#8217;s Facebook Competitor [VIDEOS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;8) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/10/iphone-pics-to-google-plus/"&gt;HOW TO: Upload iPhone Photos to Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;9) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/07/top-google-plus-users/"&gt;10 Top Google+ Users Weigh In on the Web&#8217;s Newest Social Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;10) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/06/zuckerberg-on-google-plus/"&gt;Zuckerberg on Google+: It&#8217;s a Validation of Facebook&#8217;s Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;11) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/14/google-plus-growth-early-adopters/"&gt;Can Google+ Sustain Growth Beyond Early Adopters?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;12) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/create-google-plus-desktop-app/"&gt;HOW TO: Make a Google+ Desktop App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;13) &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/google-plus-parodies/"&gt;5 Hilarious Google+ Parodies [VIDEOS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/feature/"&gt;Feature&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google-plus/"&gt;Google Plus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/guide/"&gt;Guide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-networking/"&gt;social networking&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/trending/"&gt;trending&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EkicBV3oIwSzuFQtckT8sVLAJfU/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EkicBV3oIwSzuFQtckT8sVLAJfU/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EkicBV3oIwSzuFQtckT8sVLAJfU/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/EkicBV3oIwSzuFQtckT8sVLAJfU/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tYCKbUQcRO4:CviNJtZVCyQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/tYCKbUQcRO4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Essential Google+ Resources</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/mashgoog" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/&amp;title=19 Essential Google+ Resources&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/googleplus1.jpg" alt="" title="googleplus" width="50" height="50" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-669481" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Already using &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/google-plus"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;? Follow &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/mashgoog" target="_blank"&gt;Mashable News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for the latest about the platform&amp;#8217;s new features, tips and tricks as well as our top social media and technology updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/google-plus-green-3601.jpg" alt="" title="Google Plus" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-678719" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/google-plus/page/1/"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; hit the news feeds like very strategic and popular ton of bricks. But we haven&amp;#8217;t stopped there. In addition to breaking news, &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt; has provided how-tos and tools for maximizing your Google+ experience. We&amp;#8217;ve sourced reviews from some of the network&amp;#8217;s early adopters, and we&amp;#8217;ve also welcomed your input as you navigate one of the most buzzworthy social outlets of the year. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Read on for &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt;&amp;#8216;s roundup of all resources Google+. Gather tips, analyze reviews, participate in polls and, as always, voice your thoughts in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Google+ Tips, Tools and Talk&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/01/google-the-pros-cons/"&gt;Google+: The Pros &amp;#038; Cons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Here are some pros and cons of Google+, from the social network&amp;#8217;s early users.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus-review/#18169Google-Icons"&gt;Google+: First Impressions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Mashable&amp;#8217;s Ben Parr takes Google&amp;#8217;s new social network, Google+, for a spin. Check out his review.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/the-google-cheat-sheet-pic/"&gt;The Google+ Cheat Sheet [PIC]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; This Google+ cheat sheet includes most of the common syntax, hotkeys and tips you need to know to use Google+ like a pro. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/14/google-plus-chrome-extension/"&gt;5 Chrome Extensions That Improve Google+ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Whether you want to get better notifications, enjoy improved sharing options, or scroll through your stream faster, there&amp;#8217;s a free Chrome Extension to help.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/01/googleplus-facebook-userscript/"&gt;Make Google+ Look More Like Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A new userscript turns Google+ into a Facebook clone.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/create-google-plus-desktop-app/"&gt;HOW TO: Make a Google+ Desktop App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Want an easy way to access Google+ while using Google Apps accounts? Here&amp;#8217;s how to create a Google+ desktop app. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/10/iphone-pics-to-google-plus/"&gt;HOW TO: Upload iPhone Photos to Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Who says Android phone users get to have all the fun uploading photos to Google+? Here&amp;#8217;s how to do that with an iPhone, too.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/06/gplus-to-google-plus/"&gt;HOW TO: Get Your Own Google+ Vanity URL &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Gplus.to lets you create a vanity URL for your Google+ Profile.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/04/google-plus-contacts/"&gt;HOW TO: Import Your Facebook Contacts on Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A new Google Chrome extension makes extracting Facebook contacts a lot easier, helping new Google+ users more easily reconstruct their respective social graphs.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/07/top-google-plus-users/"&gt;10 Top Google+ Users Weigh In on the Web&amp;#8217;s Newest Social Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We&amp;#8217;ve scoured the profiles, Twitter feeds and blogs of the top Google+ users. You might be surprised to hear their reviews of the recent social networking phenomenon.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/02/myspace-tom-google/"&gt;What MySpace&amp;#8217;s Tom Anderson Thinks of Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Google+, the search giant&amp;#8217;s social network, has just received a strong endorsement from MySpace co-founder Tom Anderson.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/14/google-plus-growth-early-adopters/"&gt;Can Google+ Sustain Growth Beyond Early Adopters?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Google+ is getting rave reviews in the tech press and from early adopters, but we&amp;#8217;ve seen that with social networks before. Does Plus have what it takes to succeed long term?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/09/google-plus-plus-one/"&gt;What&amp;#8217;s In a Name: Google+ Is Your Plus One&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Ever wonder why Google picked a search-unfriendly and clumsy name for its ambitious new social network? The answer may be right in front of you.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/30/google-plus-games/"&gt;Get Ready for Google+ Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; It looks like Google has some big features planned for Google+, including a much rumored Google Games product.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/12/google-plus-parodies/"&gt;5 Hilarious Google+ Parodies [VIDEOS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We&amp;#8217;ve found five funny videos that offer a comedic look at the new service, including some classic memes updated for the occasion and some spoof walkthroughs that will make you smile.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/06/video-chat-faceoff/"&gt;Video Chat Faceoff: Google+ Hangouts vs. Facebook [POLL]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Now that Facebook has unveiled its video chat service, we have to ask: how does it compare to Google+ Hangouts?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus-poll/"&gt;What Do You Think of Google+? [POLL]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Will Google+ give Facebook a run for its money, or will it fall flat like some of Google&amp;#8217;s previous attempts at social?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/13/google-plus-features/"&gt;What Features Do You Want Google to Add to Google+? [OPEN THREAD]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We&#8217;d like to open this question to our readers: what features do you think Google should add to Google+ next?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Screenshots: Inside Google+&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Logo&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18171Google-Logo"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Logo" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/google-plus-logo-640.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the Google+ logo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Icons&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18169Google-Icons"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Icons" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/google-plus-icons-640.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Google+ icons. Starting top left and circling to the right: Circles, Hangouts, Home, Sparks, Profile, Photos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;New Google+ Navigation Bar&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18161New-Google-Navigation-Bar"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="New Google+ Navigation Bar" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/sandbar_one.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;All Google sites will sport the new Google+ navigation bar. It includes notifications, profile information and content sharing options.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Stream&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18159Google-Stream"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Stream" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_stream.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the Google+ Stream, where users share content and see what their friends are sharing. It is similar to the Facebook News Feed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Circles&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18163Google-Circles"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Circles" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_circles.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Circles is Google's version of the Facebook friend list or the Twitter List. Users can select multiple friends and drag-and-drop them into groups. This makes it easier to send stuff to friends, family or the entire world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Circles Editor&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18165Google-Circles-Editor"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Circles Editor" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_circleeditor.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is the Google+ Circles editor in action. Google has created unique animations for adding and removing friends through HTML5.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Sparks&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#18167Google-Sparks"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Sparks" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/gplus_sparks.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Sparks is Google's content recommendation and discovery engine. Users can search different topics and find relevant articles, videos and photos. Users can then share that content with their friends.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Hangouts&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#20543Google-Hangouts"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Hangouts" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/plus-guide-14.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ has a unique video chat feature called Hangouts, which lets you chat with up to 10 people at the ame time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Photos&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#20545Google-Photos"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Photos" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/plus-guide-19.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ allows you to upload and share photos with your friends. It includes photo tagging and a simple browser-based image editor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Google+ Profile&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/#20547Google-Profile"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Google+ Profile" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/introducing-google/plus-guide-17.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ Profiles are like most profile pages -- it includes basic information about the user like interests, occupation and profile photos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google-plus/"&gt;Google Plus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/list/"&gt;List&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/lists/"&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/resources/"&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/roundup/"&gt;roundup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/tips/"&gt;tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PrDZUkntYr85aOf7TBjJxz7PaFY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PrDZUkntYr85aOf7TBjJxz7PaFY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PrDZUkntYr85aOf7TBjJxz7PaFY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PrDZUkntYr85aOf7TBjJxz7PaFY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=e--7D3SrocI:AmjW8Qtr1kU:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/e--7D3SrocI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/07/16/google-plus-resources/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Track Tweets, Facebook Likes and More with Google Analytics</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Fhow-to-track-tweets-facebook-likes-and-more-with-google-analytics%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-track-tweets-facebook-likes-and-more-with-google-analytics/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="How to Track Tweets, Facebook Likes and More with Google Analytics &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/how-to/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="social media how to" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/how-to-pose.png" alt="social media how to" width="190" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t you wish you could track the traffic impact of Twitter, Facebook and Google+ using Google Analytics? Well now you can. Keep reading to learn how.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google&amp;#8217;s getting social in a big way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google has been quite busy lately, rolling out &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-get-started-with-google-plus-your-complete-guide/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Google&amp;#8217;s social network) to a limited audience, the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/+1/button/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google +1 button&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (a feature similar to Facebook&amp;#8217;s Like button), a new Google Analytics interface and Google Analytics Social Interaction Tracking.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Google Analytics Social Interaction Tracking&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This new Analytics feature allows you to &lt;strong&gt;track social interactions on your website, your blog or on your Facebook fan page&lt;/strong&gt;. These actions include the Twitter button and the Facebook Like, Unlike and Send actions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this article, I will &lt;strong&gt;guide you step-by-step in adding this powerful new tracking feature to your Facebook tabs or web pages&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;span id="more-10644"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Adding Google Analytics Social Tracking requires access to and modification of your web page files. It&amp;#8217;s pretty basic, but you should be somewhat comfortable working with HTML files.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;What is currently supported by Google&amp;#8217;s Social Tracking&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;As of this writing, my testing shows that the following social buttons are supported:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Facebook Like, Unlike, Send&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Twitter (only via the &amp;#8220;official&amp;#8221; Tweet button, not Tweetmeme or other third-party buttons)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Google+&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve not yet found a way to track the &lt;a title="LinkedIn Share button" href="http://www.linkedin.com/publishers" target="_blank"&gt;LinkedIn Share button&lt;/a&gt;. If anyone has had success tracking this button with the new Google Analytics, let me know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As for &lt;em&gt;WordPress plugins&lt;/em&gt;, you&amp;#8217;ll have to wait for plugin developers to integrate social tracking into their plugins. The &lt;a title="WordPress Plugin for GA Social Tracking" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/social-media-tracking/" target="_blank"&gt;one WordPress plugin for adding Google Analytics social tracking&lt;/a&gt; only supports the buttons listed above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Google&amp;#8217;s New Google Analytics Interface and Tracking Code&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to implement Social Interaction Tracking, you will have to &lt;strong&gt;update your current Google Analytics code to the latest version&lt;/strong&gt;, and then &lt;strong&gt;add a few snippets of code to your HTML file&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to view the Social Interaction Tracking metrics, you will need to use the &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; Google Analytics interface, which is available as an option at the top of the page when you&amp;#8217;re logged in to your Analytics account:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="new-analytics" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-new-analytics.gif" alt="New Google Analytics Interface" width="415" height="78" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;How to Get Your Updated Analytics Code&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;To get your updated Google Analytics code:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/analytics/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to your Google Analytics account.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View the new Google Analytics interface&lt;/strong&gt; by clicking &amp;#8220;New Version&amp;#8221; at the top right of the screen (see above image).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click on the domain account&lt;/strong&gt; you wish to access.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click the &amp;#8220;gear&amp;#8221; icon&lt;/strong&gt;, in the orange bar at the top right of your screen:&lt;/li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="GA-edit-gear" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-ga-edit-gear-1.gif" alt="GA Gear Edit Icon" width="250" height="96" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click on the &amp;#8220;Tracking Code&amp;#8221; tab:&lt;/strong&gt; Under &amp;#8220;Standard&amp;#8221; tab and below &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;1. What are you tracking?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; select either &amp;#8220;A single domain&amp;#8221; (if you&amp;#8217;re tracking a website or blog) or &amp;#8220;Multiple top-level domains&amp;#8221; (if you&amp;#8217;re tracking a Facebook fan page).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="GA-Tracking-Code2" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-ga-tracking-code-2.gif" alt="GA Tracking Code Tab" width="324" height="124" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy the code under &amp;#8220;2. Paste this code on your site&amp;#8221;.&lt;/strong&gt; It should look like this, but with your &amp;#8220;&lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UA-xxxxxx-x&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; account number:&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; var _gaq = _gaq || [];&lt;br /&gt; _gaq.push(['_setAccount', 'UA-xxxxxx-x']);&lt;br /&gt; _gaq.push(['_trackPageview']);&lt;br /&gt; (function() {&lt;br /&gt; var ga = document.createElement('script'); ga.type = 'text/javascript'; ga.async = true;&lt;br /&gt; ga.src = ('https:' == document.location.protocol ? 'https://ssl' : 'http://www') + '.google-analytics.com/ga.js';&lt;br /&gt; var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(ga, s);&lt;br /&gt; })();&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;You now have your updated Google Analytics code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Putting the code in all the right places&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The new version of your Google Analytics code should be placed before the closing &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tag of your HTML file. (Yes, this is different. The old version was usually placed before the closing &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, but that was then&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Between your Analytics code and the closing &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tag, insert this bit of code that calls the JavaScript that enables the social tracking:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!-- Google Analytics Social Button Tracking --&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://app.tabpress.com/_js/ga_social_tracking.js"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;The end result will be:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; var _gaq = _gaq || [];&lt;br /&gt; _gaq.push(['_setAccount', 'UA-xxxxxx-x']);&lt;br /&gt; _gaq.push(['_trackPageview']);&lt;br /&gt; (function() {&lt;br /&gt; var ga = document.createElement('script'); ga.type = 'text/javascript'; ga.async = true;&lt;br /&gt; ga.src = ('https:' == document.location.protocol ? 'https://ssl' : 'http://www') + '.google-analytics.com/ga.js';&lt;br /&gt; var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(ga, s);&lt;br /&gt; })();&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;!-- Google Analytics Social Button Tracking --&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://app.tabpress.com/js/ga_social_tracking.js"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;&lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UA-xxxxxx-x&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; will be replaced with your unique Analytics ID for this domain.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Now let&amp;#8217;s add the Like/Send button code&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in &lt;a href="../3-great-social-plugins-for-your-custom-iframe-tabs/"&gt;my Social Media Examiner post on Social Plugins for fan pages&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Facebook generates the Like/Send button code for you&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/" target="_blank"&gt;its Social Plugins page&lt;/a&gt;. For the &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/docs/reference/plugins/like/" target="_blank"&gt;Like/Send button&lt;/a&gt;, you just need to enter the URL you want people to &amp;#8220;like&amp;#8221;, select whether you want to include a Send button and a couple of other options, then copy the code in the popup dialog, which will look like this:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id="fb-root"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script src="http://connect.facebook.net/en_US/all.js#appId=201748293206869&amp;amp;xfbml=1"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;lt;fb:like href="www.hyperarts.com" send="true" width="450" show_faces="false" font=""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/fb:like&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;&lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#appId=xxxxxxxxxxxxxxx&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; is a random app ID that Facebook generates that allows you to access Insights for the button, but it&amp;#8217;s not necessary for the button to work. In my example, I omit the &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;appId&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; value from the code, which will work fine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT:&lt;/strong&gt; You must add the snippet of JavaScript (shown below) to the code that Facebook generates so that actions on that button trigger Google Analytics:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;_ga.trackFacebook();&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add the above code before the &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;fb:like /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tag:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id="fb-root"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script src="http://connect.facebook.net/en_US/all.js#xfbml=1"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript"&amp;gt;_ga.trackFacebook();&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;lt;fb:like href="www.besthawaiianvacationrentals.com" send="true" width="450" show_faces="false" font=""&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/fb:like&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Paste your Like button code anywhere between the &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Viewing your Google Analytics Social Tracking reports&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, the &lt;strong&gt;Social Tracking reports are only available in the &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; Google Analytics interface&lt;/strong&gt;. (See above for how to choose the new version option.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; It usually takes a few hours for Analytics to reflect activity on your web pages, but it can take up to 24 hours. See &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; &lt;a href="http://www.hyperarts.com/blog/?p=7109&amp;amp;preview=true&amp;amp;preview_id=7109&amp;amp;public=1&amp;amp;nonce=9ddc5e3ea5#troubleshooting"&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After logging in to your Analytics account, click into the domain for which you want to view reports, then in the left menu go to &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Visitors &amp;gt; Social&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8220;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="visitors-social" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-visitors-social.gif" alt="" width="245" height="387" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You have three options for viewing the social interactions:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engagement:&lt;/strong&gt; You see two metrics: 1) Not Socially Engaged and 2) Socially Engaged. This shows you how effectively each page is in motivating users to Like or Tweet your content:&lt;/li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="GA-engagement" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-ga-engagement.gif" alt="" width="402" height="144" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action:&lt;/strong&gt; This shows you the specific actions taken (Like, Unlike, Send), how many of each and percent of total actions:&lt;/li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="GA-actions" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-ga-actions.gif" alt="" width="500" height="198" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pages:&lt;/strong&gt; Details on which page&amp;#8217;s actions were taken and what those actions were.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Adding the Twitter button to the mix&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google&amp;#8217;s Social Tracking will also &lt;strong&gt;track tweets made with Twitter&amp;#8217;s Tweet button&lt;/strong&gt;. Interestingly, Tweetmeme &lt;a title="Tweetmeme" href="http://tweetmeme.com/about/retweet_button" target="_blank"&gt;now recommends&lt;/a&gt; using the Twitter Tweet button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After logging in to your Twitter account, go to &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/about/resources/tweetbutton" target="_blank"&gt;the Twitter Tweet button page&lt;/a&gt;, where you can select one of the three available options:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="twitter-count" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-twitter-count.gif" alt="Twitter Tweet Button" width="413" height="102" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve made your selection, just copy the code that is generated for you and paste it somewhere between the &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tags of your web page. Your code should look like this:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-count="horizontal" data-via="hyperarts"&amp;gt;Tweet&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add a bit of JavaScript to activate Twitter Social Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before the closing &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tag, place this bit of JavaScript to &lt;strong&gt;activate the Google Analytics tracking&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;the social tracking won&amp;#8217;t work without this tag!&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="border: 2px solid #c9c299; margin: 0pt 0pt 20px; padding: 15px; width: 500px; background-color: #ece5b6;"&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;!-- Load Twitter JS-API asynchronously --&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt; (function(){&lt;br /&gt; var twitterWidgets = document.createElement('script');&lt;br /&gt; twitterWidgets.type = 'text/javascript';&lt;br /&gt; twitterWidgets.async = true;&lt;br /&gt; twitterWidgets.src = 'http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';&lt;br /&gt; // Setup a callback to track once the script loads.&lt;br /&gt; twitterWidgets.onload = _ga.trackTwitter;&lt;br /&gt; document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0].appendChild(twitterWidgets);&lt;br /&gt; })();&lt;br /&gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think it matters where you put the above Twitter-tracking code, as long as it&amp;#8217;s inside the &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tags. I put it right before the closing &lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tag, after the Google Analytics tracking code and the call to the &amp;#8220;&lt;span style="color: #808000;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ga_social_tracking.js&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;A word about Google +1 tracking&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;As Google states on its page about Social Interaction Tracking,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, Google Analytics provides integrated tracking with &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/+1/button/"&gt;the Google +1 button&lt;/a&gt;. This means if you have set up both Google +1 and the latest version of Google Analytics on the same page, all +1 social interactions will be tracked automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, the +1 button is Google&amp;#8217;s version of the Facebook Like button. I&amp;#8217;ve added it to the HyperArts website and blog, but I haven&amp;#8217;t seen much traction with it yet. However, adding it can&amp;#8217;t hurt, and as it grows in popularity it will help your content reach a larger audience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you implement the above instructions accurately, you should see tracking results within several hours of initiating tracking, although &lt;a title="Google Analytics Update Data" href="http://www.google.com/support/analytics/bin/answer.py?answer=55541" target="_blank"&gt;Google says&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;it can take up to 24 hours to display results&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If, after 24 hours, you don&amp;#8217;t see any social tracking results (and I&amp;#8217;m assuming you will have done some testing of the buttons to ensure they work and to provide some data to Analytics):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double-check your code.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you have placed the code as instructed above, and make sure your URL values are correct.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the Google Analytics date range.&lt;/strong&gt; By default, Google Analytics displays the past month of data up to the previous day. You can manually change that range to include the current day by clicking the arrow next to the date range and changing the end date to the current day:&lt;/li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="GA-date-range" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0711tw-ga-date-range.gif" alt="GA Date Range" width="500" height="149" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding Social Tracking to your WordPress self-hosted blog:&lt;/strong&gt; There is already &lt;a title="WordPress Plugin for GA Social Tracking" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/social-media-tracking/" target="_blank"&gt;a plugin&lt;/a&gt; for this feature.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracking Facebook tabs:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you select the &amp;#8220;Multiple top-level domains&amp;#8221; option when getting your Analytics code. This is specifically for Facebook fan pages.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although this may look a bit, um, complicated, it should be pretty easy for those who are comfortable working with web files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your thoughts? Do you have questions?&lt;/strong&gt; Please leave your comments in the box below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-track-tweets-facebook-likes-and-more-with-google-analytics/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-track-tweets-facebook-likes-and-more-with-google-analytics/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cisco: 50 Billion Things on the Internet by 2020 [Infographic]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://rww.readwriteweb.netdna-cdn.com/images/data_explosion.jpg" /&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/internet-of-things/"&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;, when real world objects are connected to the Internet, is a trend that we've been actively tracking since early 2009. So far a lot of big technology infrastructure and solutions companies have gotten behind the trend, for the simple reason that they see a huge market opportunity. As more and more 'things' go on the Net, it creates more demand for network infrastructure like sensors and routers. Enter the likes of Cisco and &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/m2m_world_of_verizon_wireless.php"&gt;Verizon Wireless&lt;/a&gt;. Likewise, more technology solutions will be developed to upload and manage data from real world objects. Enter the likes of &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/ibm_ceo_lessons_opportunities_internet_of_things.php"&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/sensors_next_big_wave_of_computing.php"&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cisco has designed an infographic that offers a simple example of how Internet of Things will affect you in your everyday life. It also states that by 2020, there will be 50 billion 'things' connected to the Internet - everything from your body, car, alarm clock and even cows. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="ad" align="right"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sponsor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://d.ads.readwriteweb.com/ck.php?n=27781&amp;amp;cb=27781' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='http://d.ads.readwriteweb.com/avw.php?zoneid=14&amp;amp;cb=27781&amp;amp;n=27781' border='0' alt='' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There has been some contention about the &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; of connected things and by when. Cisco's prediction of 50 billion devices by 2020 matches &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/how_50_billion_connected_devices_could_transform_brand_marketing_everyday_life.php"&gt;Ericsson CEO Hans Vestberg's prediction&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year within a similar time period. However IBM recently put it at &lt;a href="http://readwriteweb.com/enterprise/2010/06/ibm-a-world-with-1-trillion-co.php"&gt;1 trillion connected devices&lt;/a&gt; by 2015. Indeed in April 2010, &lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/verizon_att_cisco_internet_of_things.php"&gt;Cisco's own CTO Padmasree Warrior&lt;/a&gt; said that by 2013 the number of devices connected to the Internet will reach 1 trillion. So even Cisco doesn't seem to have a consistent prediction. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Regardless, as the infographic below shows, the number of things connected to the Internet has already exceeded the number of people on earth. So this is a big trend - and big business for Cisco and other technology companies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/ciscoinfographic_iot.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infographic &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20110714/cisco-reminds-us-once-again-how-big-the-internet-is-and-how-big-its-getting/"&gt;via All Things D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/cisco_50_billion_things_on_the_internet_by_2020.php#comments-open"&gt;Discuss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5FyWvNaF_pcawyDZZrQuDAnltgA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5FyWvNaF_pcawyDZZrQuDAnltgA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5FyWvNaF_pcawyDZZrQuDAnltgA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5FyWvNaF_pcawyDZZrQuDAnltgA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:FFnlKYwJmN0"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?d=FFnlKYwJmN0" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:Ij26kaj3iuU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?d=Ij26kaj3iuU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:C2pbw5bZMiI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?d=C2pbw5bZMiI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?i=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?i=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?i=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?a=XbilKf_VdbQ:E_uRxAhzEA4:OqabYuBsmOY"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/readwriteweb?d=OqabYuBsmOY" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/XbilKf_VdbQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/cisco_50_billion_things_on_the_internet_by_2020.php?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+readwriteweb+%28ReadWriteWeb%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/cisco_50_billion_things_on_the_internet_by_2020.php?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+readwriteweb+%28ReadWriteWeb%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External Link: Meet the iPad 2 Book by Jeff Carlson Available</title>
      <description>Our own Jeff Carlson scored the impossible: his 48-page introduction to the latest Apple iOS device, "Meet the iPad 2" ($1.99), is available instantly on the iBookstore. It's an introduction to the device, and a long excerpt from his upcoming Pocket Guide to iPad 2.&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://db.tidbits.com/article/12029#comments"&gt;Read and post comments&lt;/a&gt; about this article | &lt;a href="http://db.tidbits.com/t/12029"&gt;Tweet this article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="sponsorbox"&gt; &lt;div class="sponsortext"&gt;&lt;A HREF="http://www.tidbits.com/about/support/contributors.html"&gt;&lt;IMG SRC="http://db.tidbits.com/images/badges/donors_normal.gif" ALT="" HEIGHT="50" WIDTH="50" BORDER="0" ALIGN="left"&gt;&lt;/A&gt;READERS LIKE YOU! Support TidBITS with a contribution today!&lt;BR /&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;a href="http://www.tidbits.com/about/support/contributors.html"&gt;http://www.tidbits.com/about/support/contributors.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;BR /&gt;Special thanks this week to Roger Yarbro, James Gower,&lt;BR /&gt;Michael Babcock, and Mike Millard for their kind contributions!&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="sponsorbox_bottom"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt; Copyright &amp;copy; 2011 Glenn Fleishman. TidBITS is copyright &amp;copy; 2011 TidBITS Publishing Inc. If you're reading this article on a Web site other than TidBITS.com, please &lt;a href="http://db.tidbits.com/contact.html"&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;, because if it was republished without attribution, by a commercial site, or in modified form, it violates &lt;a href="http://www.tidbits.com/terms/"&gt;our Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://itunes.apple.com/us/book/meet-the-ipad-2/id425671338%3Fmt%3D11</link>
      <guid>http://itunes.apple.com/us/book/meet-the-ipad-2/id425671338%3Fmt%3D11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotify launches in the US</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2762634"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.spotify.com/us/hello-america/</link>
      <guid>http://www.spotify.com/us/hello-america/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
