<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Turn Social Customers Into Brand Ambassadors</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/&amp;title=5 Ways to Turn Social Customers Into Brand Ambassadors&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Customer-service-LEGOS.jpg" alt="" title="Customer Service LEGOS" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-781185" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Duke Chung co-founded &lt;a href="http://www.parature.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Parature&lt;/a&gt; in 2000, with a vision to provide superior customer support software accessible via the Internet. Today, Parature&#8217;s Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) product suite supports millions of end users worldwide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the advent of social media channels, customer service has forever changed. Consumers are no longer willing to sit and listen to classical music on hold. In today&#8217;s age of hyper-responsiveness, customers expect instant responses from support reps on very public online platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead of shying away from social media, smart businesses will leverage their social channels to spread a positive brand reputation, to connect happy customers and to step up their customer support efforts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Consumers aren&#8217;t eager to blast negative messages about your company &#8211; unless your brand is unresponsive. I recently learned at an IBM conference that customers are five times more likely to post something positive than negative, and that companies usually have at least 10 warnings before someone posts a negative comment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Happy customers who get their issues resolved tell an average of four to six people about their positive experiences, &lt;a href="http://returnonbehavior.com/2010/10/50-facts-about-customer-experience-for-2011/" target="_blank"&gt;according&lt;/a&gt; to the White House Office of Consumer Affairs. It pays to treat your customers well, not only for the repeat business, but also to gain the positive word-of-mouth consumers now broadcast across social media. Satisfied customers can become your most influential brand ambassadors. They&#8217;ll help to answer customer service questions posted online and also tout their own positive experiences with your business. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are the five best ways to turn customers into brand ambassadors through customer service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Be Fast&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;When a customer turns to social media for a support issue, he expects a brand to generate the fastest response possible. According to a recent UK &lt;a href="http://www.informationweek.com/news/smb/ebusiness/229000566" target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;, 25% of social media users expect a response within one hour, and 6% expect a response within 10 minutes. If you allow a support issue to dangle for too long, you risk being perceived as a company that either doesn&#8217;t know the answer or doesn&#8217;t care enough to reply promptly. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remember, most people on social networks aren&amp;#8217;t itching to post negative comments. They only do so after a bad experience. Therefore, don&#8217;t give them enough time to have a bad experience. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Be Visible&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Private and direct messaging on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; is all well and good, but when it comes to customer service, it&#8217;s best to be totally transparent and visible. The answer you give to one customer could, in turn, help thousands more. Think of each post and interaction as a resource that future customers can reference. Not to mention, customers will be more apt to direct friends to your page with their own questions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Social media sites foster an online community around your brand. Watch how customers discuss and respond to your products so you can join the conversation and better understand the community that supports your brand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Be Consistent&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s vital that you ensure all customer support answers remain consistent across the web and across all social channels. If a common question is posted on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/linkedin/"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, then each response should communicate the same solution. Conflicting answers create confused, unhappy customers. Just as people expect consistent experiences with your products, they also expect consistent service across all of your channels. Brand accuracy drives confidence and credibility, and helps build brand loyalty among your customers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. Be Organized&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;If consistency creates brand ambassadors, then being organized is equally paramount. Admittedly, the cross-company integration and management of social media continues to be challenging. Maintaining a successful social media presence on just one network is a full-time job. Trying to do it over multiple networks is impossible if your support staff isn&#8217;t properly organized. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Customers can spot disorganization a mile away, especially online. However, if you demonstrate that your company support knows what it&#8217;s doing, you&#8217;ll earn the respect and trust of brand loyalists. Organization goes beyond knowing who does what on the support team; it&#8217;s also vital that everyone on the team is on the same page. Each team member must know where to seek reliable answers, and each must source information from the same place. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Be Human&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;As cool as Siri is, she still hasn&#8217;t crossed from digital assistant to human entity. Until then, your social media customer support should remain as human as possible. On the bright side, social networks already take the formalities out of conversation. It&#8217;s one of their biggest draws. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Therefore, a customer&#8217;s name isn&#8217;t &#8220;Inquiry #83kd4z.&#8221; She&#8217;s Christie from Denver. People respond best when they feel like they&#8217;re talking to other people. Your customer support should make customers feel as if they&amp;#8217;re posting a normal question on a friend&#8217;s wall. Creating that kind of relationship with your customer should be the priority of any company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Using customer service to create brand ambassadors isn&#8217;t the Herculean task it once was. Social media is presenting countless opportunities to turn your company&#8217;s support system into an open, interactive community, where customers can share their positive experiences with one another and spread the good word about your products and services &#8211; all on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaptainkobold/5181464194/in/photostream/" target="_blank"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kaptainkobold/" target="_blank"&gt;Kaptain Kobold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/brand-management/"&gt;brand management&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/customer-service/"&gt;customer service&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/marketing/"&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/6-NnImwBnlK1mebezHGiuX0dr-c/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/6-NnImwBnlK1mebezHGiuX0dr-c/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/6-NnImwBnlK1mebezHGiuX0dr-c/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/6-NnImwBnlK1mebezHGiuX0dr-c/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=S8SRg20tyts:gncVnqLBrvQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/business/~4/S8SRg20tyts" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/social-media-customers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Official Dropbox Guide To Getting More Space!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We get asked a lot how to get more space in your Dropbox, and we realized that we&#8217;ve never put an official guide together. So here it is! When people start using Dropbox, they start small but often need more and more space over time. We&#8217;ve created a bunch of free ways to get more space, but also make it simple to get loads of space really fast.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/gs"&gt;Take A Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; For people new to Dropbox, there are a few things you should try out first &amp;#8212; we want you to install Dropbox on a bunch of computers, use our sharing features, and more. We&#8217;ve put together &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/gs"&gt;a list of tasks to get started&lt;/a&gt;; and when you finish this quest, you&#8217;ll get an extra 250MB free.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/referrals"&gt;Tell Your Friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A while back, we noticed that most of our growth was from word of mouth: people that love Dropbox tell their friends. We&#8217;ve built a way to invite your friends to Dropbox that gives you both extra space (250MB for free)! We&#8217;ve made it really easy to email your friends from your address book and post to Twitter or Facebook. We&#8217;ve also given you a link to put anywhere on the web. The more people you invite, the more space you get!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/edu"&gt;Be A Student&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Dropbox was started back when our cofounder Drew Houston was still in school and forgot his USB key on a bus ride. To commemorate our victory over USB keys, and to make the lives of students even easier, students with a valid school email address get a whopping 500MB for each person they invite to Dropbox. All you need to do is &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/edu"&gt;confirm that you&amp;#8217;re a student&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have Fun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We&#8217;ve done a bunch of fun challenges and quests where the prize was more space. In January, we had our first DropQuest, which was a scavenger hunt across our site. It was a race to the finish to get some really special prizes, and every person that finished also got a bonus. Last October, Reddit stole our logo, so to say thanks we made a post where the top commenter got a 100GB boost to their Dropbox. We&#8217;ve made a fun little quest to make your Dropbox a little more social. A while back when we made an announcement on twitter, we gave a random re-tweeter 100GB to get the word out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We do this stuff all the time! The best way to keep up with the games is to &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/dropbox"&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/dropbox"&gt;like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/pricing"&gt;One More Thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If you ever need even more space, you can always subscribe to Dropbox Pro, available in 50GB or 100GB. Furthermore, referrals double to 500MB (1GB for students) per person you invite! But if you need even more than 100GB, or if you run your own business; you should check out &lt;a href="http://www.dropbox.com/teams"&gt;Dropbox for Teams&lt;/a&gt;, which is designed specifically for educators, non-profits, and businesses. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hopefully this gave you a good idea of how to get even more space for your Dropbox! Happy Dropboxing! Ohh, and just for good measure, we&#8217;ll pick someone who retweets our tweet about this post and give them a 100GB bonus!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://blog.dropbox.com/?p=938&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dropbox+%28The+Dropbox+Blog%29</link>
      <guid>http://blog.dropbox.com/?p=938&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dropbox+%28The+Dropbox+Blog%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blow Up Instagram Photos Into 20&#8243; x 20&#8243; Paintings With CanvasPop</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/canvaspop.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="CanvasPop" title="CanvasPop" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over 10 million people have created artful iPhonography with Instagram, but they&amp;#8217;ve never seen their masterpieces any bigger than a Postagram postcard. But now, thanks to a peculiar synergy between the mediums and a secret algorithm, &lt;a href="http://www.canvaspop.com/instagram"&gt;CanvasPop has found a way to blow up Instagrams&lt;/a&gt; and print them as beautiful canvas paintings. See, Instagram&amp;#8217;s filters reduce graininess and so does the texture of canvas. This means that even at 20&amp;#8243; by 20&amp;#8243;, almost 10x their size on the iPhone, $60 CanvasPop prints look wall-worthy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;CanvasPop is an expert at image upsizing, having been spun out of &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/10/12/dna-11-labs-diversifies-its-dna-based-art-offerings-adds-crowdsourcing-for-new-ideas/"&gt;DNA 11&lt;/a&gt; which printed blowups of DNA strands. CanvasPop launched 2 years ago to help emancipate low-resolution photos from mobile devices and social network. It excepts even the tiniest, noisiest images including old Facebook photos and those taken with the iPhone 3G. These are run through its algorithm that smooths pixelated edges, and the canvas they&amp;#8217;re printed on further obscures any imperfections. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Co-founder Adrian Salamunovic tells me CanvasPop saw Postagram and Prinstagram developing an Instagram ecosystem, and thought it could contribute something unique. Since those companies don&amp;#8217;t have its technology and they print on paper, they&amp;#8217;re restricted to producing stickers, small photo books, and posters tiled with little images.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Built on the Instagram API, users can visit the CanvasPop website and authenticate with their Instagram account. They then choose their images, select print sizes ($30 for 12&amp;#8243; by 12&amp;#8243; or $60 for 20&amp;#8243; by 20&amp;#8242;), and soon their prints are delivered to their door. The print CanvasPop sent me looked sharp from any farther than a few inches away. My only complaint was that it was packaged so securely to prevent damage in transit that it took me a few minutes to pull it free.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instagram has unlocked a generation of artists, helping people discover and capture the subtle beauty of the world around them. It seems tragic that once posted, Instagrams disappear down our social media streams and are rarely appreciated again. CanvasPop gives these works of art enduring life, and lets us express ourselves offline as vividly as we can on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456426/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gkOpWWtYoGVUJFEYAaHNoIFVcs/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gkOpWWtYoGVUJFEYAaHNoIFVcs/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gkOpWWtYoGVUJFEYAaHNoIFVcs/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gkOpWWtYoGVUJFEYAaHNoIFVcs/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=yqbiuXNv_t4:2-Zc2u7tRKI:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/yqbiuXNv_t4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/22/canvaspop/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/22/canvaspop/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Essential Tools for the Tech-Savvy Traveler</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/&amp;title=11 Essential Tools for the Tech-Savvy Traveler&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-767277" title="Smart_Logo 100" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Smart_Logo-100.jpg" alt="" width="100" height="65" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/trendsetter-tech-series"&gt;Trendsetter Tech Series&lt;/a&gt; is supported by &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;smart&lt;/a&gt;. Test drive the space saving, eco-friendly, totally unique, smart. Visit &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;smartusa.com&lt;/a&gt; to find a new smart center near you. smart &amp;#8212; unbig. uncar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/travelshopping360.jpg" alt="" title="travelshopping360" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-786659" /&gt;The holiday season is upon us, and that means one thing: traveling. Whether you&amp;#8217;re hastily coordinating the logistics to actually &lt;i&gt;get&lt;/i&gt; to grandma&amp;#8217;s house or frantically securing those last minute business deals on the other side of the country before 2012, finding the right flight, hotel and rental car is no joke. And if you&amp;#8217;re pressed for time or on a budget, getting a great package is nothing short of a holiday miracle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Luckily, there is a veritable cornucopia of travel applications, available both online and via smartphone, that can ease those transit-induced tension headaches. These 11 tools will stick with you every step of the way, from flight procurement to a last-minute business dinner suggestion, to smooth over the turbulence and make sure you get to your destination safely and cheaply.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;a href="http://hipmunk.com" target="_blank"&gt;Hipmunk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/#325971-Hipmunk"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://hipmunk.com&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Hipmunk&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/11-tools-for-savvy-traveling/Hipmunkresize.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;This travel deal curator categorizes all the available deals from various travel websites (including Hotwire and Orbitz) into one, easy-to-decipher graphic that pushes the best flights to the top. The website also has the power to sort by &#8220;Agony,&#8221; ensuring your cross-country trek has the shortest layovers and highest reliability ratings. &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/hipmunk/"&gt;Hipmunk&lt;/a&gt; is also available for free via &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/au/app/hipmunk-flight-search/id419950680?mt=8&amp;ls=1" target="_blank"&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://market.android.com/details?id=com.hipmunk.android"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, convenient for making plans on the go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/#325971-Hipmunk'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Series supported by smart&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-767275" title="Smart_Logo 200" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Smart_Logo-200.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="51" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/trendsetter-tech-series"&gt;Trendsetter Tech Series&lt;/a&gt; is supported by &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;smart&lt;/a&gt;. Test drive the space saving, eco-friendly, totally unique, smart. Visit &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;smartusa.com&lt;/a&gt; to find a new smart center near you. smart &amp;#8212; unbig. uncar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href=http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=933189&gt;YinYang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/applications/"&gt;applications&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/deals/"&gt;deals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/travel/"&gt;travel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/trendsetter-tech-series/"&gt;Trendsetter Tech Series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/p-3Av3tVD6Cbm1B2jVqNCWYKwSQ/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/p-3Av3tVD6Cbm1B2jVqNCWYKwSQ/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/p-3Av3tVD6Cbm1B2jVqNCWYKwSQ/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/p-3Av3tVD6Cbm1B2jVqNCWYKwSQ/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=09KhPS-0Qag:6rHulhRSFNs:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/09KhPS-0Qag" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/travel-tools-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For When You Have Too Much to Say</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://tmi.me/hO5bJ</link>
      <guid>http://tmi.me/hO5bJ</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Steve Jobs brainstorm with the NeXT team in this fascinating video</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The creation of NeXT and the sequential pivoting of the company from hardware to software to acquisition is one of the most fascinating segments of the career of Steve Jobs. Unfortunately, it&amp;#8217;s also one of the least documented as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many of us had high hopes that the &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/apple/2011/10/30/tnw-review-two-lessons-from-the-biography-of-steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson/"&gt;biography of Jobs by Walter Isaacson&lt;/a&gt; would illuminate the period of his career that defined a lot of the skills and practices that have made Apple a success. Sadly, it didn&amp;#8217;t deliver in that department, aside from a detailed description of the NeXT factory.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This video is from a series called Entrepreneurs, that documents the creation of NeXT. The real gems here are the way that Steve interacts with the team, shooting down what he feels are silly ideas and encapsulating several minutes of brainstorming with explicit goals.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My favorite phrase comes in relation to a statement he makes about making the best software for higher education,&amp;#8221;If we can&amp;#8217;t do that, then we oughta go broke.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/sOlqqriBvUM?fs=1&amp;#038;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a bonus, here are a couple more must-watch videos from the NeXT era. The first two are Jobs explaining the goals of NeXT in an internal video, and the second is a demonstration video of the NeXTStep software by Jobs himself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/p9dmcRbuTMY?fs=1&amp;#038;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="500" height="375" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dn3Ex-5dPAo?fs=1&amp;#038;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;d like to see more cool NeXT stuff, be sure to check out YouTuber &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/slomacuser"&gt;Slomacuser&amp;#8217;s channel&lt;/a&gt; for some other great material.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?a=pEHLnmCe3nk:oRRePBjDDAY:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?i=pEHLnmCe3nk:oRRePBjDDAY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?a=pEHLnmCe3nk:oRRePBjDDAY:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?a=pEHLnmCe3nk:oRRePBjDDAY:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/TheNextWeb?i=pEHLnmCe3nk:oRRePBjDDAY:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/TheNextWeb/~4/pEHLnmCe3nk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/shareables/2011/11/20/watch-steve-jobs-brainstorm-with-the-next-team-in-this-fascinating-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/shareables/2011/11/20/watch-steve-jobs-brainstorm-with-the-next-team-in-this-fascinating-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Music Companies: If The Artists Are Starving, Look To The Labels</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/chuck_berry_-_new_juke-box_hits.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Chuck_Berry_-_New_Juke-Box_Hits" title="Chuck_Berry_-_New_Juke-Box_Hits" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The distributive potential of the internet has done its part in disrupting the music industry, most visibly via iTunes. But iTunes was always a sort of simulacrum of a record store. Its icon was even a CD. They were providing, like Amazon, a digital abstraction of a physical store.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Where would we be if computers were just digital abstractions of desks full of paper? They were, of course, for a short time, but since then the potential of the home PC has pushed it further and further from the simple desk analogy. Why shouldn&amp;#8217;t it be the same in music?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many readers of this site are already happily signing up for the new music-streaming services of the net, but much of the world, including the music industry, is lagging far behind and blaming the new services when monetization doesn&amp;#8217;t work how they expect. The streamers have responded: Hey, don&amp;#8217;t look at us.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are two simple misunderstandings, it seems. One is why the labels are getting any sympathy at all. They agreed to a licensing agreement, after all. And a proportionate amount of income is diverted to each label. That seems like a reasonable proposition, and it must have seemed so to the labels, which not only own part of the streaming companies but must have negotiated the terms. Why is it they get to cry about it now? Did they not understand the concept of streaming music?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s possible, actually, that the streaming music services are simply priced too low. $10, $15, $20 per month for unlimited music is a great deal. Should a service like this be a great deal, or should it be &amp;#8220;fair&amp;#8221;? After all, $0.99 per song wasn&amp;#8217;t that revolutionary. Albums cost $12-18 and pricing ended up comparable. The fact that you could buy things song by song changed a lot, but as far as pricing went, it wasn&amp;#8217;t actually a bargain. The improvement was in convenience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But the streamers can&amp;#8217;t just start jacking up prices. They&amp;#8217;ve set a precedent with this $10 level, and the market likes it. Why wouldn&amp;#8217;t they? But it doesn&amp;#8217;t strike me as price-equivalent to what we&amp;#8217;ve been paying, more or less, for years and years. Sure, prices change. But why they change is a complicated question with many moving parts, and I&amp;#8217;m not entirely convinced that $10 for unlimited streaming is a price point that can be maintained.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Relevant to this is the second misunderstanding, which is &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1796382/mog-ceo-on-artist-payments-its-like-a-black-hole"&gt;the value of non-unit sales&lt;/a&gt;. Comparisons between income from album sales and income from streaming just don&amp;#8217;t make sense. In a way, people are paying for nothing, because at the end of the month, if their subscription lapses, they have nothing to show for it. The labels and Spotify have something to show for it, though, and haven&amp;#8217;t in fact given anything away. And people pay again and again for the same content. If I listen to a song this month and then again next month, I&amp;#8217;ve paid twice, haven&amp;#8217;t I? Or have I? The economics and philosophy of providing streams needs to be settled at an open table so everybody knows what they&amp;#8217;re talking about, and things like Lady Gaga&amp;#8217;s ridiculous allegations of microscopic payouts can be avoided.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But at the same time, it&amp;#8217;s hard to deny that smaller bands, whose sales came largely from iTunes and low-overhead small-scale record sales, are going to be left out in the cold. Should they just tour more? Or should they be pushing for a different, more lucrative licensing agreement? Good luck without major-label clout.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The entire cost of producing music, in fact, needs to be reassessed honestly and openly. The basic price of goods has to do with the cost of producing those goods, and we&amp;#8217;re using old numbers. How much would bananas cost if you didn&amp;#8217;t have to pay for transport? A lot less, I&amp;#8217;m guessing. How much less should music cost now that the costs involved in production have gone down enormously, and the costs of manufacturing and distribution have been, theoretically, almost totally eliminated? Again, probably a lot less.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Getting an honest assessment isn&amp;#8217;t going to be easy. The RIAA isn&amp;#8217;t exactly forthright on these matters, and naturally has an interest in keeping the perceived value of their product high. In the end, progress always ends up being a net opportunity, which is a nice way of saying that losses in ability or value may occur. The improvement caused by the internet has put thousands of retail and factory employees in the music industry out of work. The RIAA isn&amp;#8217;t immune to the same action, the contraction of part of its market, and the sooner it acknowledges this and plans for the future, the better.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/456991/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PlnZXbrRGlIX2mVI6YgAeNoN8-8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PlnZXbrRGlIX2mVI6YgAeNoN8-8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PlnZXbrRGlIX2mVI6YgAeNoN8-8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PlnZXbrRGlIX2mVI6YgAeNoN8-8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CVVLjcQN4t4:sC499QO4m0g:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/CVVLjcQN4t4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/22/streaming-music-companies-if-the-artists-are-starving-look-to-the-labels/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/22/streaming-music-companies-if-the-artists-are-starving-look-to-the-labels/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Hold a Google+ Hangout and Why You Should</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/how-to/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="social media how to" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/how-to-pose.png" alt="social media how to" width="190" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As Google&amp;#8217;s latest foray into social media, &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/20-ways-to-master-google/"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; has brought some new tools to the digital table. My personal favorite is Hangouts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google describes Hangouts as a &amp;#8220;front porch.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyone can drop in and say &amp;#8220;hi&amp;#8221; just like anyone could drop by when you&amp;#8217;re on your porch.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="youtube"&gt; &lt;iframe title="YouTube video player" class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="480" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QN38vHZjWXw?color1=d6d6d6&amp;amp;color2=f0f0f0&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=3&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QN38vHZjWXw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/QN38vHZjWXw/default.jpg" width="130" height="97" border=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QN38vHZjWXw"&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=QN38vHZjWXw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;3 Reasons to Consider a Google Hangout&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your prospects are already here! &lt;/em&gt;Video conferencing has been available for a while, but Google+ Hangouts takes it to where people are.&lt;span id="more-12541"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are some &lt;strong&gt;ways you can use Hangouts&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1: Part of the sales process&lt;/strong&gt;: You could &lt;strong&gt;invite people who are already in your sales pipeline to hang out&lt;/strong&gt;. Not to put a high-pressure sales speech on them. Just to further the relationship.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To make it more intriguing for people to join, try naming the Hangout &amp;#8220;Overcoming _________,&amp;#8221; where the blank is filled in with a key problem you know your prospects tend to have.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2: Office hours: &lt;/strong&gt;College professors have standing office hours&#8212;times students can be sure to see them at their desk. Why don&amp;#8217;t you? You could &lt;strong&gt;set up a standing weekly or monthly Hangout&lt;/strong&gt; as a way to increase customer service or to keep in touch with your staff.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3: Fireside chats: &lt;/strong&gt;Everyone seems to want time with the CEO, so why not give it? &amp;#8220;Town hall&amp;#8221;&#8211;style conference calls have been popular in recent years, but they are conducted over the phone. What if you were to &lt;strong&gt;set up a standing quarterly time for people to actually hear from your CEO&lt;/strong&gt;? And more than hear, they&amp;#8217;ll be able to see and interact.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hangouts could be used by colleges to communicate with incoming students, or alumni, or even current students or their parents. Or you could use this as a way for your board and investors to interact with the CEO between meetings. If you have a circle of &amp;#8220;investors&amp;#8221; and only invite them, they should be the only ones who see the invitation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is an incredibly efficient use of your CEO&amp;#8217;s time: she doesn&amp;#8217;t have to leave her desk. No travel time means she can be doing work right up to the Hangout time and start back up when it&amp;#8217;s done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;3 Steps to Start a Hangout&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1: Push the &amp;#8220;Start a Hangout&amp;#8221; button: &lt;/strong&gt;Starting a Hangout is as easy as clicking on the &amp;#8220;Start a Hangout&amp;#8221; button on the right side of your &lt;a href="http://plus.google.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Google+ profile&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 203px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1111mp-start-a-hangout.png" alt="start a hangout" width="193" height="137" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Click on the button.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2: Check your hair: &lt;/strong&gt;The kind folks at Google even give you a virtual green room so you can &lt;strong&gt;check your hair before you go live&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1111mp-check-your-hair.jpg" alt="check your hair" width="480" height="367" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;That&amp;#39;s me looking into my web camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3: Invite cool people: &lt;/strong&gt;Hangouts are only as good as the people who join you on them! So even if you make your Hangout public (open to anyone), &lt;strong&gt;be sure to invite individual people too&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And then you&amp;#8217;re ready to &lt;strong&gt;go live with your Hangout! The Hangout shows up on your timeline&lt;/strong&gt;, and the timeline of those who have you in their Circles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 473px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1111mp-join-this-hangout.jpg" alt="join this hangout" width="463" height="142" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Google+ posts your Hangout on your live feed to everyone in the Circles you&amp;#39;ve invited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;In the Hangout&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a video showing you exactly &lt;strong&gt;how to start a Hangout and what to do when you&amp;#8217;re in there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="youtube"&gt; &lt;iframe title="YouTube video player" class="youtube-player" type="text/html" width="480" height="385" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/fSsO6hiozlY?color1=d6d6d6&amp;amp;color2=f0f0f0&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=3&amp;amp;showsearch=0&amp;amp;rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fSsO6hiozlY"&gt;&lt;img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/fSsO6hiozlY/default.jpg" width="130" height="97" border=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fSsO6hiozlY"&gt;www.youtube.com/watch?v=fSsO6hiozlY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve started the Hangout, &lt;strong&gt;you still have lots of controls. Along the bottom&lt;/strong&gt; you have a series of buttons.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1111mp-lots-of-controls.png" alt="lots of controls" width="480" height="45" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;You have lots of control in the Hangout: inviting new people, chatting, choosing videos on YouTube and controlling your sound and video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1: Invite: &lt;/strong&gt;While in a Hangout, you always have the option to&lt;strong&gt; invite new people&lt;/strong&gt;. Just click on the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Invite&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; button on the far left to include individual people or entire Circles.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2: Chat: &lt;/strong&gt;Have you ever tried to share a web URL over the phone? It can be pretty challenging. The Chat feature is a great way to &lt;strong&gt;share web links and other information during a Hangout&lt;/strong&gt;. Once you click on the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Chat&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; button, you&amp;#8217;ll see the chat window for the rest of your time in the Hangout.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3: YouTube:&lt;/strong&gt; Google has already integrated YouTube videos into Hangouts. So now you can use the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;YouTube&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; button to share a promotional video from your company or a video that illustrates a point. Find a cool video before you&amp;#8217;re in a Hangout? Google now lets you &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; a Hangout right from YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#4: Volume and Video Controls: &lt;/strong&gt;If you work at home or in a busy work space, the buttons on the right are very helpful! You can use &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;mute video&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; to turn your camera on and off whenever you want. Most people never use this but it is a nice feature.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Mute Mic&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; button allows you to turn off your mic. So if you get a call or someone pops into your office, you can still listen to the Hangout without him having to hear you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; button allows you even more control. If you have more than one mic or camera, you can choose which one you want to use in the Hangout. And you can choose the &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Echo Cancellation&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8221; option. That will allow you to &lt;strong&gt;use your computer&amp;#8217;s built-in mic and speakers&lt;/strong&gt; without bugging the rest of the Hangout participants!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1111mp-a-lot-going-on.jpg" alt="hangout" width="480" height="374" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;There is a lot going on in a Hangout!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;3 Things to Fine-Tune&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1: Your costume: &lt;/strong&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re using Google+ for business, you&amp;#8217;ll need to &lt;strong&gt;decide how you&amp;#8217;ll dress for a Hangout&lt;/strong&gt;. When I speak, I wear bowties. Bowties are all over my social media avatars. But I don&amp;#8217;t wear bowties 24/7.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I often work from a home office, so I have to consciously choose whether to don a bowtie or simply hang out in a t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 379px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1111mp-hangout-in-a-tshirt.png" alt="hangout" width="369" height="214" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;I chose to hangout in a t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2: Your background: What people see behind you is as important as the face they see.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you want your business logo to show behind you? Or do you like the clean look of a blank wall?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some people have found my office to be ideal: the books and degrees in the background speak of my commitment to lifelong learning. (I honestly hadn&amp;#8217;t even picked up on that!)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the picture someone took of a Hangout I was on, you&amp;#8217;ll see that I have a trade show banner with my company name on it. Since I wasn&amp;#8217;t in a bowtie, I wanted people to remember what I did.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#3: Your purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Are you just experimenting with a Hangout? Or are you holding a team meeting? Different purposes have different outcomes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ is still new enough that I&amp;#8217;ve found it more effective to let people know I&amp;#8217;ll be holding a Hangout so they can be on Google+ when I share the invitation. Starting a Hangout and having no-one show up is like having your tray of food in the high school cafeteria and wondering if anyone will let you sit next to them. It can feel a bit lonely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fortunately, Google has added a wonderful feature. Now,&lt;strong&gt; if no-one shows up for your Hangout, they remove the Hangout from your timeline&lt;/strong&gt;. So you don&amp;#8217;t have an embarrassing post saying you hung out with &amp;#8220;0 people.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Some Closing Thoughts on Google+ Hangouts&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We all know that people only purchase from us when they know, like and trust us. That used to mean we needed to go to a lot of conferences to meet people. But a tool like Google+ Hangouts can help you &lt;strong&gt;do the interacting right from your desk&lt;/strong&gt;. And as Google rolls out the ability to broadcast Hangouts, you&amp;#8217;ll be able to extend your reach beyond the 10 people in the Hangout.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And as you do more Hangouts, and capture more images from those Hangouts, your company will stand out. People will know you&amp;#8217;re approachable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I was writing this article, I popped in to a Hangout. A Google employee joined us as we were chatting, so we got to ask him lots of questions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Why wouldn&amp;#8217;t you take up this opportunity? The only thing it costs is time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think? How are you using Hangouts? &lt;/strong&gt;Leave your questions and comments in the box below. &lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Fhow-to-hold-your-own-google-hangout-and-why-you-should%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-hold-your-own-google-hangout-and-why-you-should/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="How to Hold a Google+ Hangout and Why You Should &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-hold-your-own-google-hangout-and-why-you-should/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-hold-your-own-google-hangout-and-why-you-should/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who&#8217;s Tweeting About Black Friday? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As retailers prepare for post-Thanksgiving holiday shopping, consumers increasingly turn online to search for the best deals. Last year, according to the National Retail Federation, 212 million individuals spent an estimated $45 billion total on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/black-friday/"&gt;Black Friday&lt;/a&gt;. This year, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/18/black-friday-deals-social-media/"&gt;social media has played a big role in Black Friday marketing&lt;/a&gt;, and buzz about when and where consumers are shopping is stronger than ever. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Black Friday is already trending on &lt;a href="http://www.mashable.com/follow/topics/Twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;#8217;s no surprise, especially since most companies are expanding sales from Thursday night all the way up to Cyber Monday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Social media analysts at &lt;a href="http:..www.mashwork.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Mashwork&lt;/a&gt; monitored more than 270,000 tweets between Sept. 26, 2011 and Nov. 17, 2011 and found out where shoppers will be spending their money this upcoming Black Friday (whether it&amp;#8217;s online or in line), and what products they&amp;#8217;re going after.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/18/black-friday-deals-social-media/"&gt;Top 10 Black Friday Deals on Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s interesting, is that according to the study, more people will be buying for &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt; during Black Friday this year than for others. However, the number of shoppers more likely to buy for others has increased from last year&amp;#8217;s 26%.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s no wonder why most people have their eye on computers and tablets this holiday shopping season, since so many new products in the tablet industry have just recently rolled out. What&amp;#8217;s noteworthy, however, is that because these products are so new &amp;#8212; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/kindle-fire"&gt;Amazon&amp;#8217;s Kindle Fire&lt;/a&gt;, for instance &amp;#8212; shoppers tend to discuss brands on social media that they are engaged and familiar with, such as the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ipad"&gt;iPad 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Regardless, it will be interesting to see the kind of buzz on the actual day of shopping. Has social media played a role in your Black Friday plans? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/&amp;title=Who&amp;#8217;s Tweeting About Black Friday? [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/twitter-black-friday-infographic-972.jpg" alt="" title="Mashwork Black Friday" width="972" height="5635" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-800025" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infographic provided by &lt;a href="http://mashwork.com/index.php" target="_blank"&gt;Mashwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/black-friday/"&gt;black friday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/holidays-2011/"&gt;Holidays 2011&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/online-shopping/"&gt;online shopping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/shopping/"&gt;shopping&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/BVuM_mBiKwsxknWHKSPlXExUWFo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/BVuM_mBiKwsxknWHKSPlXExUWFo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/BVuM_mBiKwsxknWHKSPlXExUWFo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/BVuM_mBiKwsxknWHKSPlXExUWFo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Rfp_rU0uiPc:3tFYn_xwdqg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/Rfp_rU0uiPc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/22/black-friday-twitter-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[GEEKS!] Quantum Levitation</title>
      <description>It's kind of like magic.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fazed.org/view/?id=19212#comments"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ws6AAhTw7RA</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ws6AAhTw7RA</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
