<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX</title>
      <description>Scary Mommy: I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best and Worst Times to Share on Facebook, Twitter</title>
      <description>Want your link to get the most traction on Twitter? Post it on a Monday between 1:00 p.m. and 3:00 p.m. ET. Link shortening and tracking service bit.ly has released new data on the best and worst times to share links on popular social networks, from Facebook and Twitter to blogging site Tumblr. The company revealed that posting links to Twitter between the hours of 1:00 p.m. and 3:00 p.m. ET will give you the highest click rank, especially on days earlier in the week. Meanwhile, sending a tweet with a link after 8:00 p.m. should be avoided &#8212; as should posting links after 3:00 p.m. on Fridays. The half-life of a link posted to Twitter is about 2.8 hours, according to bit.ly. However, Facebook&#8217;s optimal posting times are slightly different than Twitter. Links sent between 1:00 p.m. and 4:00 p.m. get the most traction, with Wednesday at 3:00 p.m. being the best time to post on Facebook all week. Links posted after 8:00 p.m. and before 8:00 a.m. on Facebook also don&#8217;t get the most clicks. Similar to Twitter, bit.ly recommends not posting the links you want to go viral during the weekend. &#8220;While traffic starts to increase around 9:00 a.m., one would be wise to wait to post until 11am,&#8221; bit.ly said in a blog post on its site. &#8220;Traffic from Facebook fades after 4:00 p.m.&#8221; Meanwhile, Tumblr has a much different usage pattern than Facebook and Twitter. It&#8217;s suggested to wait until at least 4:00 p.m. ET. to post important content, and posts that go up after 7:00 p.m. get the most clicks during a 24-hour period. It&#8217;s also suggested that Friday evenings are a key time to post on Tumblr &#8212; a time bit.ly recommends avoiding on Facebook and Twitter. Bit.ly traffic from Tumblr peaks between 7:00 p.m. and 10:00 p.m. on Monday and Tuesday, with similar traffic on Sunday, according to the study. &#8220;It&#8217;s easy to see that just like your neighborhood restaurants, each social network has its own culture and behavior patterns,&#8221; bit.ly noted in the blog post. &#8220;By understanding the simple characteristics of each social network, you can publish your content at exactly the right time for it to reach the maximum number of people.&#8221; Do you notice a difference in engagement when posting at different times? Let us know in the comments what works best for you. More About: bit.ly, Facebook, Social Media, trending, tumblr, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/09/best-time-to-post-on-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/09/best-time-to-post-on-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nikola Tesla was the greatest geek who ever lived - The Oatmeal</title>
      <description>An ode to the father of the electric age.View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GM to Stop Advertising on Facebook (Wall Street Journal)</title>
      <description>GM plans to stop advertising on Facebook after its marketing executives determined their paid ads had little impact on consumers, a disappointing development just days ahead of Facebook's IPO.</description>
      <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304192704577406394017764460.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</link>
      <guid>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304192704577406394017764460.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Knowledge Graph: things, not strings</title>
      <description>Cross-posted from the Inside Search BlogSearch is a lot about discovery&#8212;the basic human need to learn and broaden your horizons. But searching still requires a lot of hard work by you, the user. So today I&#8217;m really excited to launch the Knowledge Graph, which will help you discover new information quickly and easily. Take a query like [taj mahal]. For more than four decades, search has essentially been about matching keywords to queries. To a search engine the words [taj mahal] have been just that&#8212;two words.But we all know that [taj mahal] has a much richer meaning. You might think of one of the world&#8217;s most beautiful monuments, or a Grammy Award-winning musician, or possibly even a casino in Atlantic City, NJ. Or, depending on when you last ate, the nearest Indian restaurant. It&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve been working on an intelligent model&#8212;in geek-speak, a &#8220;graph&#8221;&#8212;that understands real-world entities and their relationships to one another: things, not strings. The Knowledge Graph enables you to search for things, people or places that Google knows about&#8212;landmarks, celebrities, cities, sports teams, buildings, geographical features, movies, celestial objects, works of art and more&#8212;and instantly get information that&#8217;s relevant to your query. This is a critical first step towards building the next generation of search, which taps into the collective intelligence of the web and understands the world a bit more like people do.Google&#8217;s Knowledge Graph isn&#8217;t just rooted in public sources such as Freebase, Wikipedia and the CIA World Factbook. It&#8217;s also augmented at a much larger scale&#8212;because we&#8217;re focused on comprehensive breadth and depth. It currently contains more than 500 million objects, as well as more than 3.5 billion facts about and relationships between these different objects. And it&#8217;s tuned based on what people search for, and what we find out on the web.The Knowledge Graph enhances Google Search in three main ways to start:1. Find the right thing Language can be ambiguous&#8212;do you mean Taj Mahal the monument, or Taj Mahal the musician? Now Google understands the difference, and can narrow your search results just to the one you mean&#8212;just click on one of the links to see that particular slice of results:This is one way the Knowledge Graph makes Google Search more intelligent&#8212;your results are more relevant because we understand these entities, and the nuances in their meaning, the way you do.2. Get the best summary With the Knowledge Graph, Google can better understand your query, so we can summarize relevant content around that topic, including key facts you&#8217;re likely to need for that particular thing. For example, if you&#8217;re looking for Marie Curie, you&#8217;ll see when she was born and died, but you&#8217;ll also get details on her education and scientific discoveries:How do we know which facts are most likely to be needed for each item? For that, we go back to our users and study in aggregate what they&#8217;ve been asking Google about each item. For example, people are interested in knowing what books Charles Dickens wrote, whereas they&#8217;re less interested in what books Frank Lloyd Wright wrote, and more in what buildings he designed.The Knowledge Graph also helps us understand the relationships between things. Marie Curie is a person in the Knowledge Graph, and she had two children, one of whom also won a Nobel Prize, as well as a husband, Pierre Curie, who claimed a third Nobel Prize for the family. All of these are linked in our graph. It&#8217;s not just a catalog of objects; it also models all these inter-relationships. It&#8217;s the intelligence between these different entities that&#8217;s the key.3. Go deeper and broader Finally, the part that&#8217;s the most fun of all&#8212;the Knowledge Graph can help you make some unexpected discoveries. You might learn a new fact or new connection that prompts a whole new line of inquiry. Do you know where Matt Groening, the creator of the Simpsons (one of my all-time favorite shows), got the idea for Homer, Marge and Lisa&#8217;s names? It&#8217;s a bit of a surprise:We&#8217;ve always believed that the perfect search engine should understand exactly what you mean and give you back exactly what you want. And we can now sometimes help answer your next question before you&#8217;ve asked it, because the facts we show are informed by what other people have searched for. For example, the information we show for Tom Cruise answers 37 percent of next queries that people ask about him. In fact, some of the most serendipitous discoveries I&#8217;ve made using the Knowledge Graph are through the magical &#8220;People also search for&#8221; feature. One my favorite books is The White Tiger, the debut novel by Aravind Adiga, which won the prestigious Man Booker Prize. Using the Knowledge Graph, I discovered three other books that had won the same prize and one that won the Pulitzer. I can tell you, this suggestion was spot on!We&#8217;ve begun to gradually roll out this view of the Knowledge Graph to U.S. English users. It&#8217;s also going to be available on smartphones and tablets&#8212;read more about how we&#8217;ve tailored this to mobile devices. And watch our video (also available on our site about the Knowledge Graph) that gives a deeper dive into the details and technology, in the words of people who've worked on this project:We hope this added intelligence will give you a more complete picture of your interest, provide smarter search results, and pique your curiosity on new topics. We&#8217;re proud of our first baby step&#8212;the Knowledge Graph&#8212;which will enable us to make search more intelligent, moving us closer to the "Star Trek computer" that I've always dreamt of building. Enjoy your lifelong journey of discovery, made easier by Google Search, so you can spend less time searching and more time doing what you love.Posted by Amit Singhal, SVP, Engineering</description>
      <link>http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/05/introducing-knowledge-graph-things-not.html</link>
      <guid>http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2012/05/introducing-knowledge-graph-things-not.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook IPO Gets a Boost: 84 Million More Shares For Sale</title>
      <description>Just days away from launch, Facebook is continuing to make last-minute changes in its IPO plans. On Wednesday, Facebook announced that an extra 84 million shares will be added to its stock pool for sale. The extra shares will come entirely from insiders and early investors, according to the Associated Press. Facebook and its current stockholders will offer more than 421 million shares in the IPO. The company has raised the price range of its stocks to $34 to $38, up from $28 to $35. If the shares trade on the higher end, Facebook could raise $16 billion when it goes public. Some of the early backers who are filing to sell more shares are PayPal co-founder Peter Thiel, Accel Partners and Tiger Global Management, according to a Reuters report. Thiel will sell 16.8 million shares instead of 7.7 million. Accel Partners has reported 11 million more shares will be sold &#8212; totaling 49 million shares from the company and its director James Breyor, according to The Wall Street Journal. Tiger Global will sell 23.4 million shares &#8212; a huge step up from the 3.4 million shares it initially reported. This could to be a solution to reports that the Facebook IPO has been oversubscribed. However, the huge spike in shares also comes despite reports of underwhelming demand for Facebook public shares. Potential investors have expressed concern and fear that Facebook will not be able to increase its yearly earnings by building a advertising system for its mobile app. Facebook will need to introduce solutions to better reach its 901 million users. Last year, Facebook reported $3.7 billion in earnings. SEE ALSO: Facebook IPO: The Complete Guide Not all is rosy in advance of the IPO. On Tuesday, General Motors dropped out of Facebook&#8217;s ad program. Facebook lost $10 million in ad revenue from the deal. The company&#8217;s acquisition of Instagram will also Nasdaq with the symbol &#8220;FB.&#8221; Has all the hype influenced your interest in the Facebook IPO? Let us know whether you&#8217;re planning to buy or sit this one out. 1. Yandex (YNDX) -20.8% from its IPO Price Yandex, a Russian search engine, raised $1.3 billion when it went public in May, making it the biggest social media IPO of the year. Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of Katrina.Tuliao and Crunchies2009 via Flickr. More About: Facebook, facebook ipoFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/facebook-ipo-shares/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/facebook-ipo-shares/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Educational Android Apps for Adults</title>
      <description>1. Speed Anatomy If someone asks to see your calcaneum, get your mind out of the gutter and show them your heel bone. The calcaneum is one of many bones you can learn about as you play the Speed Anatomy quiz app. You&#8217;ll earn points for every question you get right and graduate to more difficult biological systems. Soon you&#8217;ll be able to point to your mental protuberance without hesitation. Price: Free or $.99 without adsClick here to view this gallery.There are hundreds of Android apps to help kids learn shapes, numbers, letters, and colors. But what about adults that want to continue their education? Whether you need to brush up on a skill like a foreign language or dive head first into a new topic, there are plenty of great educational apps that can get you started. Here are six we like. Is there an educational adult app you really like? Share it in the comments below. More About: Android Market, contributor, features, Google Android, mobile apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/educational-android-apps-adults/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/educational-android-apps-adults/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NBA Star Uses Twitter &#8212; And a Platypus &#8212; to Prank Sports Media</title>
      <description>Around the sports media scene, Denver Nuggets center JaVale McGee has a certain reputation: Quirky, unique, a bit out there, something of a laughingstock at times. Reporters and fans love to chuckle at his on-court goofiness. Examples abound, but here&#8217;s the best one: a legendary GIF of McGee throwing up a wild shot and then earnestly running back on defense &#8212; except his team still has the ball. This week, however, McGee decided to turn the tables on those who love to poke fun at a young millionaire basketball player just trying to do his best. On Monday afternoon, he posted this tweet to his 57,000 Twitter followers: Just copped a pet platypus &#8230;. #swag &#8212; Pierre McGee (@JaValeMcGee34) May 14, 2012 He followed that up with this picture: twitter.com/JaValeMcGee34/&#8230; &#8212; Pierre McGee (@JaValeMcGee34) May 14, 2012 McGee&#8217;s NBA coworker Marreese Speights was duly intrigued. So McGee continued hyping his new pets: &#8220;@Mospeights16: @JaValeMcGee34 what is that bro ?&#8221;my pet platypus&#8217; on deck lmao &#8212; Pierre McGee (@JaValeMcGee34) May 14, 2012 Fans also took a lot of interest in McGee&#8217;s platypus, sending him congratulations, criticism and tweets of admiration. McGee continued to tweet about the trials and tribulations of a platypus owner. He named his pets Peter and Paul, he said. But apparently, the platypus is a dangerous and poisonous animal that turned his hand &#8220;Barney purple.&#8221; Sports media &#8212; including a Washington, D.C., Gannett affiliate &#8212; eventually picked up the story. Then McGee closed his trap with a Wednesday tweet reading, &#8220;Jokes up!!!!!!!&#8221; Next, he chastised the media with these tweets: I can believe I fooled fans into believing I bought some platypus&#8217; but reporters? &#8212; Pierre McGee (@JaValeMcGee34) May 15, 2012 Media: u guys didn&#8217;t check ur sources before writing the story? All u had to do is go to google images&#8230;Smh&#8230;Sbn&#8230;Some others n dc. SHAME &#8212; Pierre McGee (@JaValeMcGee34) May 15, 2012 Boom! Better luck next time, media. But Denver area sportscaster Vic Lombardi spoke for many when he replied to McGee&#8217;s Twitter scolding with this tweet: @JaValeMcGee34 You definitely had me. You just come across as the type of fella who would enjoy the company of a platypus. &#8212; Vic Lombardi (@VicLombardi) May 15, 2012 Do you think McGee&#8217;s prank was a good use of Twitter? Let us know in the comments. More About: NBA, platypus, sports, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/mcgee-twitter-platypus-prank/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/mcgee-twitter-platypus-prank/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Launch: A Promising, Yet Controversial Job Candidate</title>
      <description>Discuss the show on Twitter: #BehindTheLaunch In Mashable&#8216;s new video series, Behind the Launch, we&#8217;re taking cameras behind the scenes at Vungle, an in-app video advertising startup. Last week, we met the the founders and saw them bring on Colin Behr to head up business development. This week, they courted big-name startup investors, such as 500 Startups&#8216; Dave McClure, DFJ Esprit&#8216;s Krishna Visvanathan and AOL Ventures&#8216; Adam Smith. But Vungle needs to focus more on the core &#8212; developing the product instead of fleshing out press releases and a website update. The team is fielding resumes for iOS developers, and while there are some promising candidates, the Vungle guys quickly find out that there&#8217;s always a catch. When Zain is asked to sum up the week in one word, his response is &#8220;unpredictable.&#8221; Watch today&#8217;s episode to see what happens, and join the conversation on Twitter, #BehindTheLaunch. Missed earlier episodes? Watch them here! Ep. 1: Meet Vungle Ep. 2: Bringing in a Closer Ep. 3: How to Court Startup Investors About Vungle Vungle is a San Francisco-based company that purveys mobile video ads to promote apps. Just last week, Vungle announced that it had raised $2 million from big Silicon Valley and Alley names: Google Ventures, AOL Ventures, Crosslink Capital, Ron Conway&#8217;s SV Angel, Dave McClure&#8217;s 500 Startups, Charles Hudson&#8217;s SoftTechVC&#8217;s, Maynard Webb, Scott McNealy and Tim Draper. Vungle also has offices in the UK and Pakistan. Zain Jaffer, CEO and Co-Founder &#8212; A successful and zany entrepreneur since age 15, Zain launched his first Internet company and built-up an impressive list of clients, including Google, Mozilla Firefox, MTV and Hilary Duff, before his 18th birthday. British. Jack Smith, Co-Founder &#8212; Self-described lunatic marketer and hacker. Started his career as a freelance web designer at age 13, founded a video startup, MediaRoots, in college. Met Zain at King&#8217;s College London University in 2009. British. Bryant Chou, CTO &#8212; Full stack engineer and software architect with more than five years of experience developing mobile apps. He&#8217;s an enthusiastic traveler who&#8217;ll share his travel tales with you over a cold beer. American. Marta Bulaich, Chief Yoga Officer &#8212; Marta&#8217;s first job was with the masterminds behind the TV infomercial legends Chia Pet and Clapper. After a career of working with various startups and venture capital firm, she came to Vungle to do public relations and center their chi in full lotus. American. Ben Lindsey, Senior Software Engineer &#8212; A veteran of four Silicon Valley startups with experience in Internet advertising, large scale databases and agile programming. When not slinging code, you cam find him cooking organic food, listening to electronica, backpacking around the world or running marathons. Colin Behr, Director of Business Development &#8212; Previously founded an Internet company, CyberPlanet Ltd, with Zain in 2004, and then moved to San Francisco to start another venture. Colin eventually went to University but dropped out after speaking with Zain about his new venture, Vungle. Ray Myers, Software Engineer &#8212; 25-year-old Linux geek who loves robotics and has been programming since he was 7. Ray is a Shotokan karate third-degree Black Belt, but you can usually find him at his computer, trying to make robots bend to his will. American. Series presented by Internet Explorer Behind the Launch is presented by Internet Explorer. Learn how IE is building a more beautiful web through hardware accelerated graphics and modern web standards like HTML5. Get IE9 today or download the Windows 8 Consumer Preview, which features the new IE10 to see where we&#8217;re headed. More About: Behind the Launch Series, features, mashable, mashable video, Startups, Vungle</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/vungle-ios-developer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/vungle-ios-developer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Search Just Got 1,000 Times Smarter</title>
      <description>Search for 'Andromeda' in the New Google Knowledge Graph Click here to view this gallery.The Google Search of the future is here. Now. Today. The long-talked-about sematic web &#8212; Google prefers &#8220;Knowledge Graph&#8221; &#8212; is rolling out across all Google Search tools, and our most fundamental online task may never be the same again. Starting today, a vast portion of Google Search results will work with you to intuit what you really meant by that search entry. Type in an ambiguous query like &#8220;Kings&#8221; (which could mean royalty, a sports team or a now-cancelled TV show), and a new window will appear on the right side of your result literally asking you which entity you meant. Click on one of those options and your results will be filtered for that search entity. To understand the gravity of this change, you need to know about the fundamental changes going on behind the scenes at Google Search. As we outlined in our report earlier this year, Google is switching from simple keyword recognition to the identification of entities, nodes and relationships. In this world, &#8220;New York&#8221; is not simply the combination of two keywords that can be recognized. It&#8217;s understood by Google as a state in the U.S. surrounded by other states, the Atlantic Ocean and with a whole bunch of other, relevant attributes. As Ben Gomes, Google Fellow, put it, Google is essentially switching &#8220;from strings to things.&#8221; To build this world of things, Google is tapping a variety of knowledge databases, including Freebase, which it bought in 2010, Wikipedia, Google Local, Google Maps and Google Shopping. Currently, Google&#8217;s Knowledge Graph has over 500 million people, places and things and those things have at least 3.5 billion attributes. That&#8217;s a lot of things. According to Google, search users will see these new knowledge graph results at least as often as they see Google Maps in results. In fact, this update will have a greater initial impact than the updates that brought Google Images, videos, news and books, combined. It&#8217;s big and it&#8217;s probably going to be everywhere. Summaries of Good Stuff In addition to the window which will help users find the right &#8220;thing,&#8221; Google will also surface summaries for things, which, again, will try to be somewhat comprehensive by tapping into the various databases of knowledge. A search for Frank Lloyd Wright, for instance, will return a brief summary, photos of Wright, images of his famous projects and perhaps, most interestingly, related &#8220;things.&#8221; People who search for Wright are also looking for other notable architects. It&#8217;s a feature that may remind users of Amazon&#8217;s penchant for delivering &#8220;people who liked this book also bought or searched for this one&#8221; results. Gomes said that the search results are tailored to deliver information that best relates to the initial search result. So the details delivered about a female astronaut will likely outline her space travel record, because that&#8217;s what people who search for her are, according to Google, most interested in. How the Knowledge Graph Works. Click to see full graph exampleSince this is a knowledge graph (&#8220;Web&#8221; might be a better word), the results are designed to help you dig more deeply into related topics. Google showed us how someone might start by searching for a local amusement park, find an interesting rollercoaster as one of the &#8220;things&#8221; that relates to the park and end up digging in on details about that coaster and other similar rides. It&#8217;s a &#8220;skeleton of knowledge that allows you to explore information on the web,&#8221; said Gomes. There is the potential, Gomes added, of serendipitous discovery. The more you dig into things, the more things you learn about. Of course, not every &#8220;thing&#8221; is the right thing. Wikipedia is, for example, a community-sourced encyclopedia that is known for both its breadth and depth of information and the occasional whoppers of misinformation it stores. Google&#8217;s Knowledge Graph includes an error reporting system. When users find misinformation, Google will share it with the source and the knowledge graph will get just a little bit smarter For now, though, the Knowledge Graph is not getting any smarter about you. If you search for an ambiguous topic and then guide Google Search to the more defined set of results, the same query later will not go directly to that filtered information &#8212; at least not yet. &#8220;We don&#8217;t have anything to announce for personalization,&#8221; said Gomes. The Competition Google&#8217;s chief search competitor, Microsoft Bing, also has millions of entities, but it&#8217;s not aiming for the purely semantic model of search results. Instead, Bing execs told Mashable that it&#8217;s focusing, in part, on much smaller set of segments that its users typically search on (i.e.: restaurants, hotels, movies) and trying to surface relevant information regarding those segments. A search result for hotels, for example, might include reservation tools. And while Google search now blends in Google+ results, Bing&#8217;s latest instantiation has moved social information to the right side of its search results page It&#8217;s unclear for now how the Google Knowledge Graph, which pushes aside keyword results in favor of relationships and artificial intelligence, impacts all the Search Engine Optimization (SEO) many web sites have done to push their search rank ever higher. Also unknown is how, if at all, Google&#8217;s sea change will impact Google+. Gomes revealed that some Google+ changes were coming &#8220;independent of this&#8221; update and that Google will be talking about them separately. Eventually, Google&#8217;s search will get smarter and will stop asking for your help to understand your query and start answering complex questions like &#8220;What is the coldest lake in the world in July?&#8221; It doesn&#8217;t matter why you want to know that, just that, someday, the right answer will be a click away on Google Search. Google&#8217;s Knowledge Graph will roll out across the U.S. (and on all Google platforms: desktop, mobile, tablet) in the coming days. Eventually, it will go global. Give it a try and let us know what you think of the brand new Google Search in the comments. More About: bing, Google, Search, Top Stories, wikipediaFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/google-knowledge-graph/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/16/google-knowledge-graph/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Yahoo Killed Flickr and Lost the Internet [Exclusive]</title>
      <description>Web startups are made out of two things: people and code. The people make the code, and the code makes the people rich. Code is like a poem; it has to follow certain structural requirements, and yet out of that structure can come art. But code is art that does something. It is the assembly of something brand new from nothing but an idea. More &#187;</description>
      <link>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</link>
      <guid>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Child Abuse is not someone else's problem to solve. It is up to all of us to help. Donate a tweet http://t.co/SOGKuCmI #DT @helpspreadthis</title>
      <description>Brian B Baker: Child Abuse is not someone else's problem to solve. It is up to all of us to help. Donate a tweet http://t.co/SOGKuCmI #DT @helpspreadthis &#9733; Retweeted by Thomas Matlack Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://JustCoz.org/helpspreadthis</link>
      <guid>http://JustCoz.org/helpspreadthis</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
