<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Sparks Visions of a Radically Open Future</title>
      <description>TED Global is underway in Edinburgh, Scotland, with a lineup of more than 70 speakers set to offer their visions of &#8220;radical openness&#8221; (the theme of this year's conference) across disciplines as diverse as corporate governance, global security and education. The conference was kicked off by Dan Tapscott, who in 2003 authored &#8220;The Naked Corporation,&#8221; which called for new levels of corporate transparency and accountability -- a novel idea at the time, when you consider there was no Facebook, Twitter or YouTube. In his talk, Tapscott defined what he sees as the four key principles for an open world: transparency, collaboration, sharing and empowerment. Offering examples&#8230; Continue reading... More About: crowdsourcing, open source, TED, ted global</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/ted-global-radical-openness/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/ted-global-radical-openness/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build &#8212; and Keep &#8212; an Engaged Audience [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Every web publisher -- and especially content marketer -- yearns for an engaged and loyal audience. But with the sheer volume of noise, clutter and -- well, content -- online it can be hard to figure out how to reach people and keep them coming back for more. The content marketing agency BlueGlass knows a lot about how to do this well. They've run successful campaigns for clients including eBay, Conde Nast and Greatist. Now BlueGlass is ready to share some of its secrets with Mashable readers. The company produced this exclusive infographic to run down some of the ways you too can build an engaged audience online. Here are a few quick tips: Make sure you have a gripping headline, ke&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/how-to-build-an-engaged-audience-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/how-to-build-an-engaged-audience-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orbitz Shows Mac Users Pricier Hotel Rooms Than PC Users [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Mac users don't just pay more for their computer than their PC counterparts, they also pay more for hotel rooms when the shop on Orbitz, according to a report. Orbitz's data found that Mac users spend 30% more on hotel rooms, so the company is starting to show them more expensive rooms, according to The Wall Street Journal. Orbitz could not be reached for comment, but "Orbitz executives confirmed that the company is experimenting with showing different hotel offers to Mac and PC visitors," the WSJ reported. The company added that it isn't showing the same room to different users at different prices. Research showed that Mac users spent $20 to $30 more per night on hotel rooms than PC o&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, microsoft, orbitz, Windows</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/mac-users-orbitz/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/mac-users-orbitz/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorry, Marketers, You&#8217;re Doing Twitter Wrong [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Most marketers are tweeting too much on the wrong days, not using hashtags enough and almost never do the one thing that will dramatically boost their retweets -- ask for them -- according to a new study looking at how marketers use Twitter from Buddy Media. The social media marketing firm, which was recently acquired by Salesforce, looked at 320 Twitter handles from the world's biggest brands from Dec. 11, 2011 to Feb. 23, 2012. Among the findings: Twitter engagement rates for brands are 17% higher on Saturday and Sunday compared to weekdays. However, most brands aren't taking advantage of this phenomenon and, on average, only 19% of the brands' tweets were published on the weekend. If&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Buddy Media, Marketing, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/marketers-failing-twitter-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/marketers-failing-twitter-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorry, Marketers, You&#8217;re Doing Twitter Wrong [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Most marketers are tweeting too much on the wrong days, not using hashtags enough and almost never do the one thing that will dramatically boost their retweets -- ask for them -- according to a new study looking at how marketers use Twitter from Buddy Media. The social media marketing firm, which was recently acquired by Salesforce, looked at 320 Twitter handles from the world's biggest brands from Dec. 11, 2011 to Feb. 23, 2012. Among the findings: Twitter engagement rates for brands are 17% higher on Saturday and Sunday compared to weekdays. However, most brands aren't taking advantage of this phenomenon and, on average, only 19% of the brands' tweets were published on the weekend. If&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Buddy Media, Marketing, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/marketers-failing-twitter-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/marketers-failing-twitter-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Releases Dedicated iOS Podcasts App</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/podcasts/id525463029?mt=8</link>
      <guid>http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/podcasts/id525463029?mt=8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We know what you're doing... A social networking privacy experiment by Callum Haywood</title>
      <description>Disclaimer: All data is pulled directly from Facebook, it is not censored, and it is publicly accessible via the Graph API. I cannot be held responsible for any persons actions as a result of using this experiment. All attempts have been made to ensure the accuracy and reliability of the information provided on this website. However, the information is provided "as is" without warranty of any kind. Callum Haywood does not accept any responsibility or liability for the accuracy, content, completeness, legality, or reliability of the information contained on this website. No warranties, promises and/or representations of any kind, expressed or implied, are given as to the nature, standard, accuracy or otherwise of the information provided in this website nor to the suitability or otherwise of the information to your particular circumstances. We shall not be liable for any loss or damage of whatever nature (direct, indirect, consequential, or other) whether arising in contract, tort or otherwise, which may arise as a result of your use of (or inability to use) this website, or from your use of (or failure to use) the information on this site. This website provides links to other websites owned by third parties. The content of such third party sites is not within our control, and we cannot and will not take responsibility for the information or content thereon. Links to such third party sites are not to be taken as an endorsement by Callum Haywood of the third party site, or any products promoted, offered or sold on the third party site, nor that such sites are free from computer viruses or anything else that has destructive properties. We cannot and do not take responsibility for the collection or use of personal data from any third party site. In addition, we will not accept responsibility for the accuracy of third party advertisements. If you see any posts on here that are yours and you want them removing, delete them from Facebook first, then they will stop appearing here (may take up to an hour), or contact me to block any posts by you from appearing.</description>
      <link>http://WeKnowWhatYoureDoing.com</link>
      <guid>http://WeKnowWhatYoureDoing.com</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 2.0 Released</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/sublime-text-2-0-released</link>
      <guid>http://www.sublimetext.com/blog/articles/sublime-text-2-0-released</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Just Changed Your Email Without Asking&#8212;Here's How to Fix It [Facebook]</title>
      <description>Hey, here's something really stupid and annoying: Facebook abruptly switched everyone's default email address to the @facebook.com account you've never used. Here's how to switch back Facebook's obnoxious overreach right now. So people can actually, you know, contact you. Remember long, long ago, when Facebook launched a Facebook email system and then nobody used it? That's fine&#8212;it was always just an option you were more than welcome to completely ignore. And we did, because we already had Gmail and work inboxes, and didn't need yet another. If our friends wanted to email us, they could just head to our profiles and have options. Not today! If you go to your profile (or anyone else's), you'll see the @facebook.com email account listed, and none of your others. They've all been hidden in a ham-handed attempt to make the Facebook inbox relevant. Luckily, it's easy to fix this foolish move. Go to your Timeline. Click about, under your contact info. Scroll down to "Contact Info" and hit edit. Switch all of the crossed out circle symbols to a full circle for each inbox you want visible on your profile. If you don't want @facebook.com to show up, switch it from a full circle to crossed out. Hit save. Facebook: don't do this again. [Forbes]</description>
      <link>http://gizmodo.com/5921085/facebook-just-changed-your-email-without-asking++heres-how-to-fix-it</link>
      <guid>http://gizmodo.com/5921085/facebook-just-changed-your-email-without-asking++heres-how-to-fix-it</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catch Up on &#8216;Behind the Launch&#8217; With This Recap</title>
      <description>In Mashable's episodic video series, Behind the Launch, we took cameras behind the scenes at Vungle, an in-app video advertising startup. The finale airs on Wednesday, June 27, but we wanted to offer a quick recap of the season, in case you missed a few episodes. Check out the video above to see an abridged version of episodes 1-14, and then watch the full-length launch episode here: About Vungle Vungle is a San Francisco-based company that purveys mobile video ads to promote apps. In May, Vungle announced it had raised $2 million from big Silicon Valley and Alley names: Google Ventures, AOL Ventures, Cro&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Behind the Launch Series, features, mashable, Startups, Vungle</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/vungle-recap/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/26/vungle-recap/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Orbitz, Mac Users Steered to Pricier Hotels</title>
      <description>Orbitz has found that people who use Apple's Mac computers spend as much as 30% more a night on hotels, so the online travel agency is starting to show them different, and sometimes costlier, travel options than Windows visitors see.</description>
      <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304458604577488822667325882.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</link>
      <guid>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304458604577488822667325882.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
