<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Hey, Pass Me a Beer, Milwaukee Style [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Summer just arrived, and I don&#8217;t know about you, but we&#8217;re getting awfully thirsty for some brewskis around here. This video shows you how it&#8217;s done here in Milwaukee (home of your humble narrator). We don&#8217;t waste any time getting a cold one in our hands to start the weekend right. &#8220;Hey, Pass Me a Beer&#8221; is a YouTube masterpiece by MrMatthewVEVO, and I can tell you first-hand: It exemplifies the awesomeness that is Milwaukee and the cheesehead state. What about all that spilled beer when these two cool dudes open the severely jostled cans? As long as the Brewers win, we can patiently ignore any spillage. If the Brewers lose? Well, it&#8217;s time to get out the chainsaw to open those beers for even more wanton spillage. There&#8217;s plenty more where that came from &#8212; after all, we&#8217;re in Brew City!</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/pass-me-a-beer-video/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/pass-me-a-beer-video/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#8217;s Insanely Great 1986 Clothing Line [PICS]</title>
      <description>Back in 1986, Apple designers took their talents to the closet creating a catalog full of extra short-shorts and trucker hats with rainbow-shaded Apple logos. They called it "The Apple Collection." The idea is far from the modern, sleek, minimalist and timeless design that make Apple products the sensation they are today. It's hard to imagine the black-turtleneck-loving Steve Jobs sporting these neon tracksuits. What do you think of these Apple get-ups? Would you wear them? Tell us in the comments. Images courtesy of Imgur, rickh3255 More About: apple, gallery, steve jobs, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/apple-80s-clothing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/apple-80s-clothing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Sephora Is Betting Big on Digital Shopping</title>
      <description>It's no longer enough to be a social brand. In order to survive in today's business world, organizations must transform themselves into social businesses. One of the emergent trends we're tracking is the move from social to experiential, where social media plays one part in the greater production of everyday customer engagement. It's not just about technology -- it's about technology enabling experiences that provide real value to customers, and helping them share that value with their communities. Sephora is one of the brands that's leading the way in shaping digital experiences for its customers. The company recently invested in an entirely n&#8230; Continue reading... More About: brands, entrepreneurship, experience, revolutiontv, Social Media, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/19/revolution-sephora/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/19/revolution-sephora/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Big Brands Create Social Media Campaigns</title>
      <description>Ad execs who work for brands that regularly advertise during the Super Bowl often say they begin planning for the following year shortly after the winning team heads to the locker room. But for Fiat, it only took a mere five to six weeks to put together a social media campaign built around its Super Bowl ad. Coca-Cola's social campaign for Coke Zero, "Make It Possible," took about six months to create. Meanwhile, Ford's "Doug" spokespuppet campaign took about a year from inception to the bitter end. How did it happen? Fiat went to its social media agency, Ignite, asked it to come up with ideas and then picked the best one. Ford also relied on its agency, Team Detroit, for ideation. Bu&#8230; Continue reading... More About: coca cola, features, ford, mashable, social media for business leaders series, social media strategy</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Big Brands Create Social Media Campaigns</title>
      <description>Ad execs who work for brands that regularly advertise during the Super Bowl often say they begin planning for the following year shortly after the winning team heads to the locker room. But for Fiat, it only took a mere five to six weeks to put together a social media campaign built around its Super Bowl ad. Coca-Cola's social campaign for Coke Zero, "Make It Possible," took about six months to create. Meanwhile, Ford's "Doug" spokespuppet campaign took about a year from inception to the bitter end. How did it happen? Fiat went to its social media agency, Ignite, asked it to come up with ideas and then picked the best one. Ford also relied on its agency, Team Detroit, for ideation. Bu&#8230; Continue reading... More About: coca cola, features, ford, mashable, social media for business leaders series, social media strategy</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 GIFs of the Week</title>
      <description>1. Bath Time This little guy can't help monkeying around in the sink.Click here to view this gallery. This week we have quite the eclectic collection of top GIFs -- some are new to the animated image scene, while others have been around for a while but gained traction over the past few days. We've got the ever-popular selection of adorable animals, but also a GIF of Johnny Carson trolling an elderly potato chip collector. Here's a look at our favorite GIFs of the week. SEE ALSO: Top 10 GIFs of the Week, Ending June 8 Which GIF in the gallery above gets your pick for best of the week? Let us know your opinion in the comments below. More About: features, GIFs, humor, tumblr, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/top-gifs-6-22/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/top-gifs-6-22/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 GIFs of the Week</title>
      <description>1. Bath Time This little guy can't help monkeying around in the sink.Click here to view this gallery. This week we have quite the eclectic collection of top GIFs -- some are new to the animated image scene, while others have been around for a while but gained traction over the past few days. We've got the ever-popular selection of adorable animals, but also a GIF of Johnny Carson trolling an elderly potato chip collector. Here's a look at our favorite GIFs of the week. SEE ALSO: Top 10 GIFs of the Week, Ending June 8 Which GIF in the gallery above gets your pick for best of the week? Let us know your opinion in the comments below. More About: features, GIFs, humor, tumblr, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/top-gifs-6-22/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/top-gifs-6-22/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Bird Poop Does it Take to Total a SmartCar?</title>
      <description>This may be the funniest Twitter response from a brand yet. Clayton Hove, the creative director of ad agency KK Bold, commonly peppers his Twitter account with witty one liners. On June 17, he sent this: SmartCar USA saw the tweet and one-upped it. Couldn&#8217;t have been one bird, @adtothebone. Sounds more like 4.5 million. (Seriously, we did the math.) twitter.com/smartcarusa/st&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/bird-poop-smartcar/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/bird-poop-smartcar/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lets Give Karen -The bus monitor- H Klein A Vacation! -- Indiegogo</title>
      <description>I&#8217;m not sure if this has already been brought to everyone&#8217;s attention or not, but here is the deal:http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l93wAqnPQwk&amp;feature=player_embeddedAbove is a video of a 68-year-old bus monitor named Karen Klein being verbally harassed by a group of middle schoolers on their way home from Athena Middle School in Greece, New York. Throughout the ten minute video, you can hear the kids verbally berate the woman, calling her a bitch, fatass, poor, ugly, and various other words of the like. At one point in the video, you can hear one of the kids yell, &#8220;You&#8217;re so fuckin poor you fat ass,&#8221; in which Karen responds, &#8220;I try to live by some of these words, I try and it&#8217;s really hard,&#8221; referring to the words on her purse. Now, I don&#8217;t know about you, but that broke my fucking heart. There&#8217;s even a point in the video where one of the kids touches Karen&#8217;s arm in an attempt to make fun of her. I&#8217;m not sure why these kids would want to bully a senior citizen to tears, but I feel we should do something, or at least try.She doesn't earn nearly enough ($15,506) to deal with some of the trash she is surrounded by. Lets give her something she will never forget, a vacation of a lifetime!Link to the school&#8217;s website: http://www.greece.k12.ny.us/athena-middle.cfmBus number: #784School&#8217;s fax number: (585) 966-4039Principal of the school&#8217;s E-mail address: David.Richardson@greece.k12.ny.usStaff E-mails &amp; Other Links: http://www.greece.k12.ny.us/staff_directory.cfm http://www.greece.k12.ny.us/contact.cfm?school=7 https://maps.google.com/maps?q=Greeced=0CGoQ_AUoAg http://pastebin.com/mMvJ4ZP8Links to the videos: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oipwaZos58E&amp;feature=plcp http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l93wAqnPQwk&amp;feature=plcp http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SBedTlo7BDs&amp;feature=plcpKaren&#8217;s Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/kklein1944</description>
      <link>http://www.indiegogo.com/loveforkarenhklein</link>
      <guid>http://www.indiegogo.com/loveforkarenhklein</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Organizations That Produce Excellent Content</title>
      <description>Todd is the CMO of Alfresco, provider of powerful document collaboration tools enjoyed by small teams and Fortune 500 companies alike. Todd and Alfresco&#8217;s goal is to help the world create great content that captures the attention of the otherwise engaged. In a world of content farms and commodity news cycles, it looks like the pendulum is starting to swing back towards hi-fidelity content, with a focus on content created for niche audiences. The value of such content lies in the effect it can have on readers, but also specific groups. Here are five examples of companies that have been tremendously effective with content, and what they can teach others trying to do the same. Why It Matters: The New York Philharmonic has made their entire archive of sheet music available to anyone with a browser. In the next 10 years, the Philharmonic plans to digitize its entire collection of eight million pages of documents and 7,000 hours of audio visual material. When finished, the repository is expected to contain more than two petabytes of data and 160 years of archival information available for instant retrieval. Their goal is to create an environment that is conducive to research, so not only do you have access to sheet music from Leonard Bernstein&#8217;s debut, but also the program, the actual score from which he conducted on that night, as well as audio clips. The New York Philharmonic has the largest private score collection in the world and the project is truly ambitious. The Takeaway: It&#8217;s not always about new content. Sometimes you already have everything that matters, and it&#8217;s just modernizing the content and giving it a fresh face, as the Philharmonic has done. G.E.&#8217;s buzzed-about Tumblr is another great example. Why It Matters: Contently is a new and very interesting kind of middleman &#8212; a marketplace for freelance writers all over the world. It&#8217;s good because it has the ability to raise the overall content quality of a much broader set of blogs and newsletters. How does it work? Contently customers upload into their system an editorial calendar of content they want created. Then, fully employed Contently editors (highly reputable journalists formerly at The New York Times, New York Magazine, etc.) hone those assignments and distribute them to freelance journalists for whom they are a fit. Those journalists turn in their drafts by the appointed deadline and the editors work with them to make sure the quality of reporting is always there. Their clients &#8212; companies like Mint.com and the American Express OPEN Forum &#8212; get content of substance for their corporate use. The Takeaway: You don&#8217;t have to be a journalist or have a journalist on staff to create awesome content. There are a lot of very qualified writers and organizations out there that can help you get the kind of writing your firm needs. Why It Matters: 955 Dreams is a unique kind of tablet application development shop that is putting an entire new spin on the intersection of education and entertainment. Their acclaimed apps, such as &#8220;The History of Jazz,&#8221; &#8220;On the Way to Woodstock&#8221; and &#8220;Band of the Day&#8221; showcase what happens when you take content &#8212; text and photos from Wikipedia for example &#8212; and combine it with original art and commentary. The &#8220;On the Way to Woodstock&#8221; app features more 100 hours of audio clips, video, and written content that&#8217;s designed to appeal to both experts and beginners alike. Further, their user interface and design is uniformly groundbreaking, adding depth to subjects and topics that deserve to be reinvigorated in this new medium. The Takeaway: Mash-up culture has spanned a whole new breed of interactive experiences that aren&#8217;t just text, or video, or sound, but rather unique cocktails of all three. Don&#8217;t think of different media types in silos. Some of the most interesting content experiences today come from a novel blend. Why It Matters: This is certainly a surprising choice, right? After 9/11, the Fire Department of New York City was faced with many challenges, one of which was the health and safety of the officers that responded during the collapse. Since then the FDNY has turned their website into a content powerhouse. They have been recording and managing Firefighter Line of Duty Injuries and the FDNY World Trade Center Medical Monitoring Program. They have also been instrumental in the treatment of WTC Cough &#8212; which is common in those present on that day &#8212; by publishing medical content by Dr. David Prezant and his team who were the first to bring awareness to the illness. The bureaucratic navigation and cross-functional organization behind the FDNY&#8217;s efforts is lost on the casual visitor, and that&#8217;s intentional. Governments are famous for creating content that is hard to access and make use of. When it came to post-9/11 medical issues and the long-term health of New York City, cutting out steps and keeping the FDNY site very current was non-negotiable. The Takeaway: Sometimes the most effective content projects are just about getting everyone on the same page. Gathering the most up-to-date content in real time, reducing clicks and making content accessible across platforms and devices is key, especially when you&#8217;re dealing with large corporations or governments. Why It Matters: If you&#8217;re not already familiar, Grantland is a startup of sorts inside one of the world&#8217;s largest media companies, ESPN. Run by celebrity journalist Bill Simmons, Grantland makes long-form cool again. It brings together sports, entertainment, and pop cultural beats under one roof. Grantland even has a special collaboration with McSweeny&#8217;s, which produces a quarterly magazine. The Takeaway: Shorter and more numerous pieces are not always better. In other words, you don&#8217;t need a factory. Your content should be rare in the right ways &#8212; rare in its quality, length, and form. Longer posts and more art-filled content (see here for a few more examples) can give you non-linear returns on your investment. Audiences respect the time and effort that goes into some of the harder-to-create pieces.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/organizations-that-produce-content-worth-emulating/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/organizations-that-produce-content-worth-emulating/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Organizations That Produce Excellent Content</title>
      <description>Todd is the CMO of Alfresco, provider of powerful document collaboration tools enjoyed by small teams and Fortune 500 companies alike. Todd and Alfresco&#8217;s goal is to help the world create great content that captures the attention of the otherwise engaged. In a world of content farms and commodity news cycles, it looks like the pendulum is starting to swing back towards hi-fidelity content, with a focus on content created for niche audiences. The value of such content lies in the effect it can have on readers, but also specific groups. Here are five examples of companies that have been tremendously effective with content, and what they can teach others trying to do the same. Why It Matters: The New York Philharmonic has made their entire archive of sheet music available to anyone with a browser. In the next 10 years, the Philharmonic plans to digitize its entire collection of eight million pages of documents and 7,000 hours of audio visual material. When finished, the repository is expected to contain more than two petabytes of data and 160 years of archival information available for instant retrieval. Their goal is to create an environment that is conducive to research, so not only do you have access to sheet music from Leonard Bernstein&#8217;s debut, but also the program, the actual score from which he conducted on that night, as well as audio clips. The New York Philharmonic has the largest private score collection in the world and the project is truly ambitious. The Takeaway: It&#8217;s not always about new content. Sometimes you already have everything that matters, and it&#8217;s just modernizing the content and giving it a fresh face, as the Philharmonic has done. G.E.&#8217;s buzzed-about Tumblr is another great example. Why It Matters: Contently is a new and very interesting kind of middleman &#8212; a marketplace for freelance writers all over the world. It&#8217;s good because it has the ability to raise the overall content quality of a much broader set of blogs and newsletters. How does it work? Contently customers upload into their system an editorial calendar of content they want created. Then, fully employed Contently editors (highly reputable journalists formerly at The New York Times, New York Magazine, etc.) hone those assignments and distribute them to freelance journalists for whom they are a fit. Those journalists turn in their drafts by the appointed deadline and the editors work with them to make sure the quality of reporting is always there. Their clients &#8212; companies like Mint.com and the American Express OPEN Forum &#8212; get content of substance for their corporate use. The Takeaway: You don&#8217;t have to be a journalist or have a journalist on staff to create awesome content. There are a lot of very qualified writers and organizations out there that can help you get the kind of writing your firm needs. Why It Matters: 955 Dreams is a unique kind of tablet application development shop that is putting an entire new spin on the intersection of education and entertainment. Their acclaimed apps, such as &#8220;The History of Jazz,&#8221; &#8220;On the Way to Woodstock&#8221; and &#8220;Band of the Day&#8221; showcase what happens when you take content &#8212; text and photos from Wikipedia for example &#8212; and combine it with original art and commentary. The &#8220;On the Way to Woodstock&#8221; app features more 100 hours of audio clips, video, and written content that&#8217;s designed to appeal to both experts and beginners alike. Further, their user interface and design is uniformly groundbreaking, adding depth to subjects and topics that deserve to be reinvigorated in this new medium. The Takeaway: Mash-up culture has spanned a whole new breed of interactive experiences that aren&#8217;t just text, or video, or sound, but rather unique cocktails of all three. Don&#8217;t think of different media types in silos. Some of the most interesting content experiences today come from a novel blend. Why It Matters: This is certainly a surprising choice, right? After 9/11, the Fire Department of New York City was faced with many challenges, one of which was the health and safety of the officers that responded during the collapse. Since then the FDNY has turned their website into a content powerhouse. They have been recording and managing Firefighter Line of Duty Injuries and the FDNY World Trade Center Medical Monitoring Program. They have also been instrumental in the treatment of WTC Cough &#8212; which is common in those present on that day &#8212; by publishing medical content by Dr. David Prezant and his team who were the first to bring awareness to the illness. The bureaucratic navigation and cross-functional organization behind the FDNY&#8217;s efforts is lost on the casual visitor, and that&#8217;s intentional. Governments are famous for creating content that is hard to access and make use of. When it came to post-9/11 medical issues and the long-term health of New York City, cutting out steps and keeping the FDNY site very current was non-negotiable. The Takeaway: Sometimes the most effective content projects are just about getting everyone on the same page. Gathering the most up-to-date content in real time, reducing clicks and making content accessible across platforms and devices is key, especially when you&#8217;re dealing with large corporations or governments. Why It Matters: If you&#8217;re not already familiar, Grantland is a startup of sorts inside one of the world&#8217;s largest media companies, ESPN. Run by celebrity journalist Bill Simmons, Grantland makes long-form cool again. It brings together sports, entertainment, and pop cultural beats under one roof. Grantland even has a special collaboration with McSweeny&#8217;s, which produces a quarterly magazine. The Takeaway: Shorter and more numerous pieces are not always better. In other words, you don&#8217;t need a factory. Your content should be rare in the right ways &#8212; rare in its quality, length, and form. Longer posts and more art-filled content (see here for a few more examples) can give you non-linear returns on your investment. Audiences respect the time and effort that goes into some of the harder-to-create pieces.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/organizations-that-produce-content-worth-emulating/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/organizations-that-produce-content-worth-emulating/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
