<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matt Groening finally reveals the location of Springfield: http://t.co/l2EFt7SG</title>
      <description>Slate: Matt Groening finally reveals the location of Springfield: http://t.co/l2EFt7SG &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/Matt-Groening-Reveals-the-Location-of-the-Real-Springfield.html?utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_medium=socialmedia&amp;utm_campaign=20120410&amp;utm_content=retinamattgroeningthesimpsons</link>
      <guid>http://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/Matt-Groening-Reveals-the-Location-of-the-Real-Springfield.html?utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_medium=socialmedia&amp;utm_campaign=20120410&amp;utm_content=retinamattgroeningthesimpsons</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rufus Wainwright Wants You to Instagram His Video</title>
      <description>Singer-songwriter Rufus Wainwright wants fans to use Instagram to create a lyric mosaic for his new single, Out of the Game. Users and fans are tasked with taking Instagram photos that represent a word in the lyrics of the song, &#8220;Out of the Game.&#8221; Users add the hashtag #OutOfTheGame to the caption and a second hashtag with the word the image represents. Photos will automatically become part of the mosaic, which is visible at instagram.rufaswainwright.com. Rufus will select the best photos to be part of a special lyric music video for &#8220;Out of the Game.&#8221; Additionally, a limited-edition print book of the best photos is also available for pre-order now. Wainwright is the latest artist to embrace the Instagram community. In February, Jason Mraz held an Instagram contest around his song &#8220;I Won&#8217;t Give Up.&#8221; The winning entries were printed on canvas and showcased at a private exhibit in New York City. The creative agency The Uprising Creative was behind both campaigns, recognizing that the photo service is a powerful way for artists to engage with their fans. Jeff Nicholas, partner at The Uprising Creative, spoke to us about why Instagram was chosen for this project. &#8220;The repetitious nature of the lyrics in the song made it ripe for this kind of mosaic,&#8221; Nicholas told us. Moreover, Instagram is a platform and service that appeals to Wainwright&#8217;s strong fanbase. &#8220;Instagram doesn&#8217;t make sense for all artists but with Rufus, it&#8217;s the perfect fit.&#8221; The viral nature of Instagram also makes it attractive for these kinds of promotions. &#8220;Users see the hashtag and want to learn more about the contest or album,&#8221; Nicholas explains. For Wainwright, the timing of this contest couldn&#8217;t be more perfect. Instagram was already a popular social destination &#8212; especially with its Android launch last week. With Monday&#8217;s news that Facebook has acquired the company, the service and app are garnering even more attention. Out of the Game will be available in the US on May 1, 2012. Users can pre-order the album on Amazon.com and iTunes now. More About: instagram, out of the game, rufus wainwrightFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/rufus-wainwright-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/rufus-wainwright-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Lets You Make Money from Pay-Per-View Videos</title>
      <description>Next time you have guests at your home for a live TV event, you might be streaming it from YouTube. Just don&#8217;t expect it to be free. YouTube announced it would add the option for partners to monetize on YouTube Live, its year-old streaming service, with advertisements or other paid options. In a blog post, YouTube Partner Product Manager Varun Talwar joked they considered renting a bouncy castle or hiring a magician to celebrate YouTube Live&#8217;s first birthday. &#8220;Neither of these seemed just right to celebrate the millions of you who&#8217;ve seen live videos,&#8221; Talwar wrote, &#8220;so we went with our favorite gifts: new features from our tireless engineers.&#8221; YouTube Live lets viewers watch live events, while companies and brands grow their following &#8212; and now, make a profit. This means live content will be accessible through a pay-per-view option. &#8220;A live event can be claimed in the new video manager like any other video and monetized with in-stream ads or paid options where you can set price by country,&#8221; Talwar writes. You can also preview live events before they actually go live, and view real-time analytics that show at-the-moment viewers according to geography and format. New Wirecast software lets YouTube partners produce and stream professional-quality live events directly from a desktop. Add files, images and other overlays to enhance the program. For those who are livestreaming enabled, simply download Wirecase for YouTube. What do you think about this new feature? How much would you pay to watch a big, live television event on YouTube? Tell us in the comments. More About: Advertising, live, streaming, YouTubeFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/youtube-live-streaming-for-brands/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/youtube-live-streaming-for-brands/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These "Texts from Hillary Clinton" are hilarious http://t.co/evUtO0In (via @bostonmamas)</title>
      <description>phdinparenting: These "Texts from Hillary Clinton" are hilarious http://t.co/evUtO0In (via @bostonmamas) &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://textsfromhillaryclinton.tumblr.com/</link>
      <guid>http://textsfromhillaryclinton.tumblr.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: Watney 'settles the score' with Doral</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502#42063502"&gt;&lt;img align="left" border="0" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/NBCSports/Components/Video/_NEW/s_nbc_glf_wgccadillacwatneyintv_110313_4x3.thumb.jpg" alt="March 13: Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)" style="margin:0 5px 5px 0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;</description>
      <link>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</link>
      <guid>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racist Hunger Games Fans Are Very Disappointed [Hunger Games]</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="float: left; padding-right: 10px;"&gt; &lt;!-- div style="background-color: #B3B3B3; width: 190px; padding: 1px;"&gt;&lt;a title="Click here to read Racist &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Hunger Games&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; Fans Are Very Disappointed" href="http://jezebel.com/hunger-games/" style="background-color:#888888; color:#FFFFFF; font-size:12px;text-align:right; display:block; height:14px; padding:1px 2px; text-decoration:none; text-transform:uppercase; width:156px;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: white;" class="hash"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: white;"&gt;hungergames&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div --&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;a title="Click here to read Racist &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Hunger Games&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; Fans Are Very Disappointed" href="http://jezebel.com/5896408/racist-hunger-games-fans-dont-care-how-much-money-the-movie-made" class="pp_image"&gt; &lt;img style="border-color: #B3B3B3; border-width: 0 1px 1px; border-style: none solid solid;" height="120" width="190" title="Click here to read Racist &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Hunger Games&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; Fans Are Very Disappointed" alt="Click here to read Racist &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Hunger Games&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; Fans Are Very Disappointed" src="http://img.gawkerassets.com/img/17hmzxq0swlg2jpg/original.jpg"/&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; The good news? &lt;em&gt;The Hunger Games&lt;/em&gt; made $155 million at the box office its opening weekend, making it the third-best debut in North American box office history. &lt;a href="http://jezebel.com/5896408/racist-hunger-games-fans-dont-care-how-much-money-the-movie-made" title="Click here to read more about Racist Hunger Games Fans Are Very Disappointed [Hunger Games]"&gt;More&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br style="clear: both;" /&gt; &lt;br clear="both" style="clear: both;"/&gt; &lt;br clear="both" style="clear: both;"/&gt; &lt;a href="http://ads.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=9bb553dd24acf51ccc16997acb923ac3&amp;p=1"&gt;&lt;img alt="" style="border: 0;" border="0" src="http://ads.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=9bb553dd24acf51ccc16997acb923ac3&amp;p=1"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt="" height="0" width="0" border="0" style="display:none" src="http://tags.bluekai.com/site/5148"/&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="0" width="0" border="0" style="display:none" src="http://insight.adsrvr.org/track/evnt/?ct=0:eiagm7b&amp;adv=wouzn4v&amp;fmt=3"/&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.gawker.com/~ff/jezebel/full?a=qQ7SbPZ4TRA:6lJ8HdX2G40:H0mrP-F8Qgo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/jezebel/full?d=H0mrP-F8Qgo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.gawker.com/~ff/jezebel/full?a=qQ7SbPZ4TRA:6lJ8HdX2G40:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/jezebel/full?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.gawker.com/~ff/jezebel/full?a=qQ7SbPZ4TRA:6lJ8HdX2G40:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/jezebel/full?i=qQ7SbPZ4TRA:6lJ8HdX2G40:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.gawker.com/~ff/jezebel/full?a=qQ7SbPZ4TRA:6lJ8HdX2G40:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/jezebel/full?i=qQ7SbPZ4TRA:6lJ8HdX2G40:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/jezebel/full/~4/qQ7SbPZ4TRA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://jezebel.com/5896408/racist-hunger-games-fans-dont-care-how-much-money-the-movie-made</link>
      <guid>http://jezebel.com/5896408/racist-hunger-games-fans-dont-care-how-much-money-the-movie-made</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Is Ruining Your Brain [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Admit it: As you&#8217;re reading this, you have tunnel vision &#8212; that feeling that the world is closing in on you after surfing the Internet for eight straight hours. Web dead head (yes, I made that up) is a growing concern for today&#8217;s connected generation, which collectively spends 35 billion hours on the Internet every month. But we&#8217;re not just talking one online shopping experience at a time. Often, we have four tabs open, cycling between emails and shopping, tweeting and word processing. Such multi-tasking actually raises stress levels and lowers creative thinking overall, according to the research compiled by ForensicPsychology.net. SEE ALSO: Your Desk Job Makes You Fat, Sick and Dead [INFOGRAPHIC] Turns out, multi-tasking online doesn&#8217;t positively exercise our brains or mental state. Heavy Internet users are 2.5 times more likely to be depressed. And web addiction reduces the white matter in our brains, basically the transmitters responsible for our memory and sensory abilities. Scared? Tell us about it. Thumbnail courtesy of iStockphoto, Firstsignal More About: features, Google, health, infographic, Social Media, trending, web</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/brain-internet-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/brain-internet-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tim Cook to Give First Public Interview as Apple CEO</title>
      <description>The All Things D conference has a long history of wrangling an impressive speaker list, and this year's gala is no different. The outlet has just confirmed that Apple CEO Tim Cook will be the keynote speaker for D10's opening night, just two years after the late Steve Jobs last sat down on those very red chairs in a keynote interview of his own. In fact, Cook's sit-down will come three years after the historic Jobs + Gates discussion from D7, and we're told that this will be Cook's first onstage event that isn't run by Apple or for an investor group as the company's head honcho. As ever, we'll be on site liveblogging the back-and-forth, and we'll be hanging around to hear from NYC Mayor Mike Bloomberg, Oracle CEO Larry Ellison, FCC chairman Jon Leibowitz and a whole host of others. Cook's appearance will kick things off on the evening of May 29th from Rancho Palos Verdes, California.Apple CEO Tim Cook to open D10 conference: yes, we'll be liveblogging originally appeared on Engadget on Tue, 10 Apr 2012 12:45:00 EDT. Please see our terms for use of feeds.Permalink | All Things D | Email this | Comments</description>
      <link>http://www.engadget.com/2012/04/10/apple-ceo-tim-cook-d10-speaker/</link>
      <guid>http://www.engadget.com/2012/04/10/apple-ceo-tim-cook-d10-speaker/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Instagram Owe Kodak a Billion Dollar Thanks?</title>
      <description>A few days ago, I was walking around the George Eastman Mansion in Rochester, NY, blissfully unaware that Facebook was preparing to buy Instagram for $1 billon dollars. I loved the tour. Eastman and his company, Kodak, turned early photography, an incredibly a cumbersome and rarified process in the mid 1800s, into a portable, easy-to-repeat consumer obsession. Today, the obsession continues but largely without Kodak, which is now mired in bankruptcy. In its place is, I guess, Instagram, the $1 billion-dollar baby. I still haven&#8217;t decided if I&#8217;m happy that Facebook bought the digital photography app and social network. I am an Instagram user, although I was not an early adopter. I think I first noticed it when I saw some shared images on Twitter that reminded me of old Instamatic photos. That was clearly the appeal of Instagram: the ability to take everyday digital images from your iPhone&#8217;s camera (now Android, too!) or photo library and apply a filter that made the picture look like it was taken by a camera that Kodak (or Polaroid, for you Land Camera fans) made more than 50 years ago. Hipsters everywhere instantly adopted Instagram as their own. Every Instagramed photo was somehow more authentic, like the act of adding a filter made the image hand-made. That&#8217;s not what really happens, of course. Instagram&#8217;s filters, although there are a bunch of them, do not change from image to image. That jagged edge on the &#8220;Kelvin&#8221; filter will look the same on one photo after another. But the effect is still quite good. These pictures look like you developed them yourself. That&#8217;s particularly rich, of course, since most people using Instagram today probably don&#8217;t even know what I&#8217;m talking about. Certainly, most Instagram users have never developed their own negatives or printed their own pictures. (Yes, I have, but that&#8217;s another, very long story.) Still there&#8217;s a thread of connection between what Eastman did &#8212; delivering photography from the pros to the every man by inventing roll film and a camera that could shoot with it &#8212; and what Instagram has done: taken something that took time and expertise (photo filter application), and given average consumers the ability to make beautiful (some might say artistic) photos and share them to, potentially, millions with the press of a virtual button. On the other hand, there would be no Instagram without Eastman and Kodak. Even the Instagram logo is similar to a classic Kodak Instamatic camera&#8212;though I don&#8217;t know that Instagram has ever paid a dime to Kodak. The Eastman museum displayed a lot of Kodak&#8217;s early cameras and related photography equipment, but no Instamatic that I could find. Although the camera arrived nearly 30 years after Eastman&#8217;s death, it helped solidify Kodak&#8217;s position in the &#8220;photography-for-everyone&#8221; pantheon. Clearly, the easy-to-use, low cost, and very portable camera influenced the Instagram team. As I looked at the remarkable innovation and sometimes quirky (a camera gun?) applications of photographic technology at the Eastman House, I couldn&#8217;t help but be a little depressed. Eastman&#8217;s genius launched two industries: photography and movies. He had become one of the richest men in the world and believed money could move mountains &#8212; or at least homes. He once had his own mansion split in half and had the two sections moved apart by 10 feet so he could enlarge the conservatory. The work cost $775,000 in the early 1900s. Today&#8217;s Kodak would no doubt have other, more pressing needs for the that money. As Kodak works its way out of Chapter 11, it&#8217;s obvious that the company held onto traditional photography as the centerpiece of its business for, perhaps, a little too long. Yes, it was one of the first to introduce a digital camera, but Kodak and its customers seemed to believe traditional film photography would never die. Too bad Kodak couldn&#8217;t have seen as far ahead as Eastman once was. Maybe it could&#8217;ve come up with the idea of Instagram and today Facebook would be buying it, instead. That&#8217;s a fantasy. The reality, though, is that Facebook and Instagram probably do owe Kodak something &#8212; maybe a debt of gratitude. Without Kodak, there would be no Instagram and I bet Facebook would be a much duller place, too. What do you think? How important was Kodak&#8217;s role in the development of digital photography and applications like Instagram that use it? 1860 Folding Camera and George Eastman on right Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, instagram, Kodak, photography</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/what-does-instagram-owe-kodak/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/10/what-does-instagram-owe-kodak/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
