<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>biorhythmist: RT @petersagal: Yo Yo Ma on the floor of a bathroom, with a wombat. http://t.co/6iWGyOhR</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="float:left;padding-right:5px;padding-bottom:5px;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fpetersagal%2Fstatus%2F146752011155673088%2Fphoto%2F1"&gt;&lt;img src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Fpetersagal%2Fstatus%2F146752011155673088%2Fphoto%2F1" height="61" width="51" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;RT @petersagal: Yo Yo Ma on the floor of a bathroom, with a wombat. http://t.co/6iWGyOhR&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tweetmeme.com/story/7571996618/twitter-peter-sagal-yo-yo-ma-on-the-floor-of-a"&gt;0 comments&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://tweetmeme.com/story/7571996618/twitter-peter-sagal-yo-yo-ma-on-the-floor-of-a</link>
      <guid>http://tweetmeme.com/story/7571996618/twitter-peter-sagal-yo-yo-ma-on-the-floor-of-a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater</title>
      <description>&lt;a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://buy.louisck.net/"&gt;Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;p&gt;PayPal Louis CK $5, you get to watch his special. Easy. Do it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?a=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?a=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?i=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?a=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?i=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?a=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?a=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/AustinKleonBlogandTumblr?i=3jBZBAzCsCE:JyM3wYoYyEo:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://tumblr.austinkleon.com/post/14019094766?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+austinkleontumblr+%28TUMBLR+%7C+AUSTINKLEON.com%29</link>
      <guid>http://tumblr.austinkleon.com/post/14019094766?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+austinkleontumblr+%28TUMBLR+%7C+AUSTINKLEON.com%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like Louis CK, the comedian. I also like Louis CK, the chap trying to do something different, making his own stuff and &lt;a href="https://buy.louisck.net/"&gt;distributing it straight to the audience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, I especially like his message to people who might want to download his material illegally instead of paying the five dollars:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;To those who might wish to &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; this video: look, I don&amp;#8217;t really get the whole &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; thing. I don&amp;#8217;t know enough about it to judge either way. But I&amp;#8217;d just like you to consider this: I made this video extremely easy to use against well-informed advice. I was told that it would be easier to torrent the way I made it, but I chose to do it this way anyway, because I want it to be easy for people to watch and enjoy this video in any way they want without &amp;#8220;corporate&amp;#8221; restrictions. Please bear in mind that I am not a company or a corporation. I&amp;#8217;m just some guy. I paid for the production and posting of this video with my own money. I would like to be able to post more material to the fans in this way, which makes it cheaper for the buyer and more pleasant for me. So, please help me keep this being a good idea. I can&amp;#8217;t stop you from torrenting; all I can do is politely ask you to pay your five little dollars, enjoy the video, and let other people find it in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you like something, even if you can get it for free, do try and do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://writeforyourlife.net/louis-ck-live-at-the-beacon-theater" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent link to 'Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater'" class="glyph"&gt;Read this post on Write for Your Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WriteForYourLife/~4/xTjySALLr7Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://buy.louisck.net/</link>
      <guid>https://buy.louisck.net/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear Congress, It's No Longer OK To Not Know How The Internet Works http://t.co/18NGrjun</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a1.twimg.com/profile_images/608299691/hands_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/cshirky"&gt;Clay Shirky&lt;/a&gt;: Dear Congress, It's No Longer OK To Not Know How The Internet Works &lt;a href="http://t.co/18NGrjun" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/18NGrjun&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/cshirky/status/147776825727262720"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://motherboard.tv/2011/12/16/dear-congress-it-s-no-longer-ok-to-not-know-how-the-internet-works</link>
      <guid>http://motherboard.tv/2011/12/16/dear-congress-it-s-no-longer-ok-to-not-know-how-the-internet-works</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest: Behind the Design of an Addicting Visual Network</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;250203826;74788347;p" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/&amp;title=Pinterest: Behind the Design of an Addicting Visual Network&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Volvo-logo-1001.png" alt="" title="Volvo logo 100" width="85" height="" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-831777" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/Leaders-in-Design-Series/?http://705-view.c3tag.com/v.gif?id=1216&amp;#038;cid=705&amp;#038;t=72%n" target="_blank"&gt;Leaders in Design Series&lt;/a&gt; is supported by &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;250203826;74788351;k" target="_blank"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;img src="http://ad.doubleclick.net/ad/N884.150394.MASHABLE/B5732258.11;sz=1x1;ord=%n"&gt;&lt;img src="http://ad.doubleclick.net/ad/N884.150394.MASHABLE/B5732258.8;sz=1x1;ord=%n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/pinterest-360.jpg" alt="" title="pinterest 360" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-837775" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ever find yourself in the rabbit hole of the internet, bookmarking and screengrabbing things you want to buy or images that inspire you? Well, judging from Pinterest&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://siteanalytics.compete.com/pinterest.com/" target="_blank"&gt;hockey-stick growth&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;#8217;re not alone in your digital collecting and curating. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The invite-only social discovery platform launched in March 2010, the brainchild of Paul Sciarra, Evan Sharp and Ben Silbermann, with the mission to &amp;#8220;connect everyone in the world through the &amp;#8216;things&amp;#8217; they find interesting,&amp;#8221; opining that books, recipes and items can bridge the gap between strangers. In October, the site surpassed &lt;a href="http://breakingnewsworld.net/2011/11/pinterest-surpasses-421-million-pageviews/"&gt;421 million pageviews&lt;/a&gt;, which means that each of its &lt;a href="http://www.dailydot.com/culture/how-to-pinterest-tutorial/"&gt;3 million users&lt;/a&gt; are spending quite a bit of time there, pinning and organizing images to help them plan their weddings, decorate their (oftentimes, dream) homes, create bucket lists and manage an inventory of favorite images &amp;#8212; no small feat on the ever-growing web. Images are presented in a bulletin board format with links to the original URL of the item or the info of the user who first uploaded it, so you know where it came from if you want more detes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While Pinterest has been around for 20 months, it&amp;#8217;s only recently hit the tech blogosphere after catching on with a more DIY, Etsy-frequenting crowd of moms and designers. It&amp;#8217;s simple, it&amp;#8217;s intuitive and it&amp;#8217;s user-friendly, which explains its organic, grassroots growth. By now, of course, tech has taken notice, and the site has since received $37 million in funding.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pinterest&amp;#8217;s simplicity and browsability comes from the nimble fingers of designer Evan Sharp. &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; spoke with Sharp about the site&amp;#8217;s design, its growth and how his background in architecture comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;#038;A with Evan Sharp, Pinterest Designer and Co-Founder&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr &gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/sharp-98_o.jpeg" alt="" title="evan sharp pinterest" width="180" height="225" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-837759" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me about the backstory of Pinterest &amp;#8212; where did the idea come from?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Myself and two of my friends were all working on the site at the end of 2009, more as a fun project than as an aspirational startup &amp;#8212; two of us were really big collectors as children. I was always collecting images on the web in folders on the desktop of my computer, but it wasn&#8217;t a very good system for remembering where things came from or who made them. We wanted to create a place where you can go to upload or collect things on the web and simply organize it the way you want to [each with its associated metadata].&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide on the bulletin board-style aesthetic?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s funny, when I was first designing the website, the grid that&#8217;s the layout of the site &amp;#8212; what you call a bulletin board &amp;#8212; is the thing I spent &lt;em&gt;by far&lt;/em&gt; the most time working on. We did about 50 iterations. We were trying to find a way of displaying these collections that felt very personal but also felt like a collection more than just a few images. I&#8217;ve always felt that the linear, chronological feed that you see on a lot of big social services is really great &amp;#8212; and before the feed there was nothing, so it&#8217;s certainly a great advance on the web &amp;#8212; but it&#8217;s not always ideal, especially for a visual product, and that&#8217;s why we spent so much time working on that layout. And it&amp;#8217;s been great for us &amp;#8212; the grid is the visual hallmark of our site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/pinterest-bulletin-board.png" alt="" title="pinterest bulletin board" width="640" height="375" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-837767" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sites inspire you, and where do you look for design inspiration?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I do look at a lot of apps and websites, but most of the precedence for what we&#8217;re doing is actually in physical spaces of discovery. A lot of them are museums, libraries or retail spaces, like a grocery store. If you think about how things are presented and laid out, you start to realize that the entire space is organized to allow you to discover all the things the store is selling. And if you walk into a bookstore, you can be overwhelmed with thousands and thousands of books, but they&amp;#8217;re categorized, and all of them are actionable by you &amp;#8212; you can walk over and take them off the shelf and open them. There&#8217;s a lot more history to those ideas [than the web] &amp;#8212; people have been working out [display designs] for hundreds of years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pinterest is big with the ladies and is popular for wedding planning, fashion and interior decor &amp;#8212; what did you think Pinterest would catch on for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I was designing Pinterest, I was in grad school for architecture, so I was using it for architecture-related drawings and buildings, and I always assumed it would catch on with the design and architecture world. It has, but it&#8217;s caught on in so many other verticals, too. Home decorating is one of the big ones. I didn&#8217;t think as much about target audience as I was thinking about creating something that was really cool and that could have enormous potential as a platform if we ever wanted to invest all of our time in it [which has happened].&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of tech startups these days break through on a tech site and then trickle down to a mainstream audience, but your growth has trickled up &amp;#8212; why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="line-height: 26px; width: 290px; border-left-color: #888888; border-left-style: dotted; border-left-width: 1px; margin-bottom: 10px; float: right; color: #888888; margin-left: 15px; padding-left: 15px; font-size: 20px; padding-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&#8220;We didn&#8217;t build this company to build a really hot tech startup &amp;#8230; It came out of what we wanted to build more than the idea to build.&amp;#8221;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Part of it is that we didn&#8217;t spend a lot of time trying to get tech coverage. We didn&#8217;t build this company to build a really hot tech startup; what we wanted to do was build a product &amp;#8212; and also a company &amp;#8212; that we wanted to work on for the next five or ten years. And a lot of that is hiring the right people and building a really great team, but another part of it is building a product that people actually use and that enhances their lives. It&#8217;s part of our philosophy &amp;#8212; we want to build something that everybody finds useful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does your background in architecture help you when it comes to web design? What lessons carry over?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Architecture is really difficult, and it takes a long time to master the third dimension. Going through an extremely rigorous and work-intensive graduate program in architecture formed a process in me, the process of taking theoretical concepts and then executing and working those ideas out in design. A lot of [the process] is about technique and spending the time designing, but there&#8217;s such a rich history of architecture and a great body of theory and knowledge, and an enjoyable part of [moving to web design] was learning to take abstract ideas and concepts and then solve them tangibly. The history of the process of architecture is really amazing in and of itself, and it&#8217;s been really helpful to me as a designer. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You previously worked at Facebook &amp;#8212; what lessons you bring to Pinterest?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always seen the product design team at Facebook as &amp;#8220;owning&amp;#8221; the idea of product design in a very real way, even though there&#8217;s not a lot of visibility to what they&#8217;re doing every day. It was really helpful for me to go through the rigorous gantlet they have &amp;#8212; it&#8217;s a great example of how a really big company can value design in a way that doesn&#8217;t interfere with what all the teams are doing. Learning how the company operated was really valuable for me, and I think it&#8217;s been really important for Pinterest&#8217;s success as a design product.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/pinterest.png" alt="" title="evan&amp;#039;s pinterest" width="640" height="388" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-837777" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What things do you pin on your own boards?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve been doing it for so long now that it&#8217;s changed a bit, but I&amp;#8217;ve always pinned the design and architecture stuff that I find inspirational. A lot of the rest of the things I do came out of what I found interesting on the site. In the early days, I was pinning stuff from other places besides Pinterest, but now a lot of my things are repins &amp;#8212; the Star Wars board, the travel board. There was a lot of Star Wars on the site &amp;#8212; it&#8217;s interesting to see what patterns come out when millions of people are pinning things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Picture-10.png" alt="" title="pinterest addict" width="180" height="" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-838089" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judging from the userbase and the pageviews and anecdotal evidence, there is an obsession with Pinterest &amp;#8212; why do you think that is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think it&#8217;s twofold &amp;#8212; at a basic level, it&#8217;s just a great place to go to see things that are interesting to you. Every time you go, you should see 50 to 100 things that hopefully are relevant or interesting to you. But the flipside of that &amp;#8212; and something I didn&#8217;t expect when we built the product &amp;#8212; is that there are are tons of people using the pictures to find things that impact their everyday life. People doing crafts projects, planning birthday parties, designing a home on the cheap. There are all sorts of life tips that come out of Pinterest. So now, not only are you finding stuff that&#8217;s interesting, but you&#8217;re also getting off Pinterest to do the things you&#8217;re finding on the site. What that means is that, at the end of the day, Pinterest can really complement your life instead of being a timesuck. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/about/etiquette/" target="_blank"&gt;Pin Etiquette&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#8221; it says that Pinterest is not a place for self-promotion. How, then, can Pinterest best be used by brands as a marketing tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A lot of brands are using Pinterest to share more about their brand; a good example of that is &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/wholefoods/" target="_blank"&gt;Whole Foods&lt;/a&gt;. They&#8217;re not just sharing the produce available at Whole Foods, they&#8217;re sharing [images of] a healthy lifestyle. &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/westelm/" target="_blank"&gt;West Elm&lt;/a&gt; isn&#8217;t just sharing the furniture they sell, they&amp;#8217;re sharing interior design tips. And the &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/todayshow/" target="_blank"&gt;Today Show&lt;/a&gt; isn&#8217;t just pinning that day&#8217;s guests [to promote the episode]. For most consumer brands, the idea &lt;em&gt;behind&lt;/em&gt; your brand makes sense on Pinterest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/pinterests-real-wall.png" alt="" title="pinterest&amp;#039;s real wall" width="640" height="480" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-838107" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lastly, what&#8217;s the company culture like at Pinterest?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting things for me now that we have a product that people love, is building a team at a company that people want to work at. What&#8217;s cool at Pinterest is that we have people who love the product, but the common thread on our team is that all of them have real interests and passions outside of Pinterest. Building a team of people who are generally interested in the world is great because that&#8217;s what the product is about, but it also means we&#8217;re creating a place where it&#8217;s really exciting to work. We&#8217;re designing a company as much as we&#8217;re designing a product.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Series supported by Volvo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;250203826;74788350;j" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/volvo-logo-200.png" alt="" title="volvo logo 200" width="200" height="126" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-831887" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/Leaders-in-Design-Series/?http://705-view.c3tag.com/v.gif?id=1216&amp;#038;cid=705&amp;#038;t=72%n" target="_blank"&gt;Leaders in Design Series&lt;/a&gt; is supported by &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;250203826;74788349;r" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Volvo&lt;/a&gt;. Experience the newest Volvo for yourself. Step inside the 325hp 2011 Volvo S60 T6 R-Design at &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;250203826;74788349;r" target="_blank"&gt;volvocars.us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;img src="http://ad.doubleclick.net/ad/N884.150394.MASHABLE/B5732258.10;sz=1x1;ord=%n"&gt;&lt;img src="http://ad.doubleclick.net/ad/N884.150394.MASHABLE/B5732258.9;sz=1x1;ord=%n"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/leaders-in-design-series/"&gt;Leaders in Design Series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/pinterest/"&gt;pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/dev-design/"&gt;Dev &amp; Design&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashdevdesign" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.devdesign" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/dev-design" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4jnAK7KlfXH39COB_esYiwZRnoY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4jnAK7KlfXH39COB_esYiwZRnoY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4jnAK7KlfXH39COB_esYiwZRnoY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4jnAK7KlfXH39COB_esYiwZRnoY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VxjW1QMCN5E:OF--VUfp4fk:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/VxjW1QMCN5E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/pinterest-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Google+ Really a Social Media Game Changer?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/&amp;title=Is Google+ Really a Social Media Game Changer?&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/google-plus-world-360.jpg" class="alignright" width="275" height="" title="Google Plus World"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google-plus/"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; may be less than a year old, but &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; bestselling author Chris Brogan is ready to crown it a game changer. His latest book, which will publish next week, is called &lt;a href="http://www.quepublishing.com/store/product.aspx?isbn=0789749149" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Google+ for Business: How Google&amp;#8217;s Social Network Changes Everything&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;i&gt;Everything?&lt;/i&gt;,&amp;#8221; we asked &lt;a href="http://www.chrisbrogan.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Brogan&lt;/a&gt;. He assured us, rather indignantly, that he hasn&amp;#8217;t made a mistake with his book&amp;#8217;s title.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google+ has an obvious advantage in search results, presents unique opportunities for brands and is backed by deep pockets, he argues. And all of these factors make it a social media platform that will stick around in a big way. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt; asked Brogan about what makes Google+ a different kind of social network, what has worked best for brands on the platform so far, and for his advice on developing a Google+ presence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;#038;A With Author Chris Brogan&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google+ was &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/28/google-plus/" target="_blank"&gt;unveiled in June&lt;/a&gt; and introduced &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/07/google-launches-branded-pages/" target="_blank"&gt;brand pages&lt;/a&gt; just last month. How have you explained what the new social network changes or how it works best when it hasn&amp;#8217;t been around for very long?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="line-height: 26px; width: 290px; border-left-color: #888888; border-left-style: dotted; border-left-width: 1px; margin-bottom: 10px; float: right; color: #888888; margin-left: 15px; padding-left: 15px; font-size: 20px; padding-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&#8220;Google+ posts sent to &amp;#8220;public&amp;#8221; rank fairly well in Google search results. You can&amp;#8217;t get that with Facebook or Twitter these days.&amp;#8221;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s pretty easy to explain. Google+ posts sent to &amp;#8220;public&amp;#8221; rank fairly well in Google search results. You can&amp;#8217;t get that with Facebook or Twitter these days. If almost 70% of people start their online trek to your website via search, then that&amp;#8217;s fairly self-explanatory. Second, Facebook works on a &amp;#8220;closed&amp;#8221; and insular &amp;#8220;who you know&amp;#8221; model, whereas Google+ works on a &amp;#8220;what you&amp;#8217;re into&amp;#8221; model. It&amp;#8217;s much easier to prospect in B than A. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The title of your book says that &amp;#8220;Google&amp;#8217;s Social Network Changes Everything.&amp;#8221; Can you be more specific?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Absolutely. I wrote about 200 pages of more specific. But for you? I&amp;#8217;ll boil the ocean: Search is probably the biggest reason it changes everything. Second, a very wealthy company (Google) is pushing Plus to be a very powerful effort to change the way we share information on the web. They&amp;#8217;ve spent money on commercials during many mainstream events, and they&amp;#8217;ve changed up many of their disparate applications and processes to point harder toward Google+. They&amp;#8217;ve really quickly moved towards building a social backplane that is a lot more functional than any other social network. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What about the opportunities for brands on Google+ is different than those on Facebook or Twitter?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Brands can share better than on Twitter, because the visual appeal of Google+ pages encourages more clicking. Brands can host hangouts and have deeper interaction than on Twitter. Because Google&amp;#8217;s search features are far more robust than Facebook, the opportunity to prospect and find more potential community members is much better. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Should brands approach their presence on Google+ differently than how they approach it on other social networks? And if so, how?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="line-height: 26px; width: 290px; border-right-color: #888888; border-right-style: dotted; border-right-width: 1px; margin-bottom: 10px; float: left; color: #888888; margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 10px; padding-right: 15px; font-size: 20px; padding-bottom: 15px;"&gt;&#8220;Brands should strongly advocate the individual employees as well as the brands on Google+.&amp;#8221;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Brands should strongly advocate the individual employees as well as the brands on Google+. There are restrictions to what a brand page can do, so the opportunity is to have really strong personal brands do some of the heavy lifting in building community. &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/118216759969087724610/posts" target="_blank"&gt;Scott Monty&lt;/a&gt; at Ford and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/104930289762156468674/posts" target="blank"&gt;Jennifer Cisney&lt;/a&gt; at Kodak are great examples of this. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;How many different brand representatives did you interview for the book? What was most surprising to you about the way they are using Google+?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spoke to a handful of people representing brands, and did a lot of research on others. Probably the first and most interesting surprise I had was how often Michael Dell, Chairman of Dell Computers, uses Hangouts to communicate with people live and in real time on the site. Beyond that, I wrote the book in early days, so the case studies were still developing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What is the most creative or effective way that you&amp;#8217;ve seen a brand use Google+?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really impressed with how Intel has built specific sharing circles for the different types of content they intend to share, but if I could only choose one, I really like how The Corcoran Group showcases all kinds of interesting things around New York City. They make their page so interesting that you just have to check in quite often. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which brands do you consider to have the top Google+ pages?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I like Intel, Corcoran Group, Alure Home Improvement, Red Bull, Ford, and Kodak. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google+ has a fraction of the number of users that Facebook has and is dominated by users who work in the technology sector. Do you think Google+ will ever catch up to Facebook in terms of its reach?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="line-height: 26px; width: 290px; border-left-color: #888888; border-left-style: dotted; border-left-width: 1px; margin-bottom: 10px; float: right; color: #888888; margin-left: 15px; padding-left: 15px; font-size: 20px; padding-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&#8220;I&#8217;m not predicting that Google+ wipes out Facebook, but the comparison is silly.&amp;#8221;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is one of the silliest questions people ask me. Facebook has been around for years. When Facebook first became publicly available, MySpace had a gazillion users. When AOL was at the top of its game as a community platform, there was no such thing as MySpace. Don&amp;#8217;t worry about counting users. Google has far deeper pockets than Facebook and several dozen applications that are all useful to business. I&amp;#8217;m not predicting that Google+ wipes out Facebook, but the comparison is silly. A few months of Google+ compared to a handful of years of Facebook is not a decent comparison. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/brands/"&gt;brands&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/chris-brogan/"&gt;chris brogan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/interview/"&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media-marketing/"&gt;social media marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rnxTnEy7mTeeYkMg2WdKgyZ_pFA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rnxTnEy7mTeeYkMg2WdKgyZ_pFA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rnxTnEy7mTeeYkMg2WdKgyZ_pFA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rnxTnEy7mTeeYkMg2WdKgyZ_pFA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=tTwoxA7PuD4:cuP_dem45QY:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/tTwoxA7PuD4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/google-plus-changes-everything/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Teen Mobile Data Usage Triples [STUDY]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/&amp;title=U.S. Teen Mobile Data Usage Triples [STUDY]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/teens-texting.jpg" alt="" title="teens texting" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-796539" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We already knew that teens out-text the rest of us, but this year their mobile data consumption accelerated at an unprecedented rate as well. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Teens ages 13 to 17 used 256% more mobile data in the third quarter of 2011 than in the same time period of 2010. Teens took in 320 MB of data per month on average, with males using 382 MB and females using 266 MB. Adults between 25 and 34 still use the most mobile data, averaging 578 MB each month. The chart below shows a complete breakdown of mobile data usage by age. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For this &lt;a href="http://blog.nielsen.com/nielsenwire/online_mobile/new-mobile-obsession-u-s-teens-triple-data-usage/" target="_blank"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;, Nielson analyzed recent mobile data from more than 65,000 U.S. subscribers. The study finds that the number of smartphone owners using mobile Internet has increased 45% this year, accounting for the widespread increase of mobile data usage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When it comes to texting, teens&amp;#8217; famously beloved mobile activity, they send seven texts per waking hour on average, or 3,417 messages per month. In Q3 of 2010 that number was higher, averaging 3,729 per month. Teen girls reign as texting queens, sending 3,952 messages per month. Teen boys, in comparison, send 2,815 texts per month. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/07/02/texting-teens-infographic/"&gt;Texting Teens: Typing Replaces Talking [INFOGRAPHIC]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Monthly texts sent decreased in order of age group, though no group comes close to matching teens&amp;#8217; patterns. You can see each age group&amp;#8217;s monthly averages in the below chart. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Following texting, the most popular mobile activities for teens were all data heavy &amp;#8212; surfing the Internet, social networking, emailing, downloading apps and using apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Voice minute usage is on the decline, especially for teens. The group used 17% less voice minutes this year (down from 685 minutes to 572 minutes), preferring texting for its speed, ease and fun. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do your patterns mimic teens, using more data and less voice minutes? Let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/mobile-data-by-age.jpg" alt="" title="mobile data by age" width="570" height="294" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-841917" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/mobile-data-usage.jpg" alt="" title="mobile data usage" width="570" height="285" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-841923" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jpott/" target="_blank"&gt;JPott&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile-data/"&gt;mobile data&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/nielson/"&gt;nielson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/teens/"&gt;teens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xmI2BPGbzo4mV4sFGX98-hHQEVA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xmI2BPGbzo4mV4sFGX98-hHQEVA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xmI2BPGbzo4mV4sFGX98-hHQEVA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/xmI2BPGbzo4mV4sFGX98-hHQEVA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=AgDHke2ORbM:ZsUtFCtv8f0:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/AgDHke2ORbM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/teens-data-usage/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>House Delays Taking Action on SOPA Until Dec. 21</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/&amp;title=House Delays Taking Action on SOPA Until Dec. 21&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/Firefox_censored_thumb.jpg" alt="" title="" width="275" height="" class="alignright" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The House Judiciary Committee on Friday postponed debate on the contentious &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/sopa/" target="_blank"&gt;Stop Online Piracy Act&lt;/a&gt; until Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Initial reports indicated that voting on the measure &amp;#8212; which if passed would create a &#8220;blacklist&#8221; of websites that infringe on copyrights &amp;#8212; would be pushed back to 2012. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, Rep. Darrell Issa has since confirmed via a tweet (below) that talks regarding SOPA will continue Dec. 21, right before lawmakers&amp;#8217; holiday break starts. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet tw-align-center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;BREAKING: Judiciary has scheduled the rest of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%2523SOPA"&gt;#SOPA&lt;/a&gt; markup next Wednesday, Dec. 21 at 9 AM EST. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%2523stopsopa"&gt;#stopsopa&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%2523open"&gt;#open&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%2523dontbreaktheinternet"&gt;#dontbreaktheinternet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%2523ip"&gt;#ip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Darrell Issa (@DarrellIssa) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DarrellIssa/status/147795287732264960" data-datetime="2011-12-16T21:48:37+00:00"&gt;December 16, 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In its heated two-day debate about H.R.3261 so far, the House Judiciary Committee has been deciding whether to pass the provision to the House floor. The debate unsurprisingly has pitted copyright holders such as Disney, the Motion Picture Assoication of America and the Recording Industry Association of America against Internet freedom organizations as well as companies such as eBay, Facebook, Google, Twitter and Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/sopa-house-debate/" target=_"blank"&gt;Fight Against SOPA Intensifies Surrounding House Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rep. Lamar Smith introduced the bill on Oct. 26. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/house-of-representatives/"&gt;House of Representatives&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/internet/"&gt;internet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/public-policy/"&gt;public policy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/sopa/"&gt;SOPA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/iGxekzMrc9KtO2gLVBS3KfT1YGQ/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/iGxekzMrc9KtO2gLVBS3KfT1YGQ/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/iGxekzMrc9KtO2gLVBS3KfT1YGQ/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/iGxekzMrc9KtO2gLVBS3KfT1YGQ/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=V8LmISxvjZ8:L-e-7M88BCY:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/V8LmISxvjZ8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/16/stop-online-piracy-act-house-postponed-wednesday/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
