<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips for Women in the Tech Industry</title>
      <description>Being a female entrepreneur in the male-dominated tech industry is challenging, and comes with a distinct set of barriers. Thankfully, there are several female-led organizations that are working to bring more women into the tech fold. I asked a panel of successful young female entrepreneurs from the Young Entrepreneur Council (YEC), an invite-only nonprofit organization comprised of the world&#8217;s most promising young entrepreneurs, what challenges women in tech face, and what could help eliminate some of those barriers? Here&#8217;s what they shared. 1. Women&#8217;s Organizations Help While women tend to be more relationship-oriented in general, I&#8217;ve found that networking our way into the inner circle of the tech world is not as easy for us. There are probably a number of reasons for this, but I believe organizations like Women 2.0 and Women in Technology will be instrumental in bridging that gap in the coming years. - Lisa Nicole Bell, Inspired Life Media Group 2. Sharing is Key Whether a woman is contemplating launching her first startup or simply considering registering for a course that will teach her to code, it&#8217;s so important that she share this with friends and colleagues. When these conversations between women don&#8217;t take place, the circle of women in tech grows at a much slower rate. Outside the tech world, there&#8217;s this perception that &#8220;only men are doing it.&#8221; But if we all talked about it more, I think that would give more women permission to dive in. - Amanda Aitken, The Girl&#8217;s Guide to Web Design 3. See the Glass as Half Full Despite the fact that we tell girls and women that any path is possible, there are still strong gender roles that reinforce the idea that women aren&#8217;t as good at STEM skills. The most important step we can take is to integrate these skills in the classroom as early as possible by showcasing successful female tech entrepreneurs. We also need to quit treating women in tech as a rarity, when numbers have grown dramatically. We&#8217;re creating something of a self-fulfilling prophecy, and we need to step back from that. - Thursday Bram, Hyper Modern Consulting 4. Develop Access to Capital Women founders can find it more difficult to raise funding for their businesses. The statistics show that less than 20 percent of female-led ventures get funding, which is much lower than the statistics for men. That said, there are several great organizations trying to help women reach their funding goals, including Women 2.0, Astia, and others. We need to support such groups. - Doreen Bloch, Poshly Inc. 5. Be Yourself When I was starting TalentEgg, not only was I a woman in the tech industry, but I was also very young &#8212; a 24-year-old who looked like I was only 15. Thankfully, I learned early on that my biggest strength was my ability to be myself. I didn&#8217;t pretend to be older than I was, or have more experience than I had. I also didn&#8217;t try to emulate men in my industry. I was just me, and I never listened to any commentary regarding the barriers that I was supposedly facing by being a young woman in technology. - Lauren Friese, TalentEgg Inc. 6. Having Some Chutzpah When it comes to women in tech, we need more of them, and a little chutzpah, too. I say that because once women start getting their hands dirty in the tech world, there&#8217;s no stopping them. That&#8217;s what&#8217;s important to remember. Also, there&#8217;s a huge shift happening right now as more women show an interest in this space. Those actions needs to be rewarded at a much earlier age for girls. - Nathalie Lussier, Nathalie Lussier Media 7. Find Mentors I recently read that only one in five professional women have had a mentor. Yet, most women believe having a mentor is important for career advancement. Sheryl Sandberg, Facebook&#8217;s COO, often discusses how important mentors have been in her career. When looking for a mentor, I think it&#8217;s good to seek out males and females. Women are more likely to choose a female mentor, and while I think it&#8217;s critical for women to support other women, it&#8217;s also good to have a male perspective. Personally, my male and female mentors push me and challenge me in different ways, and I really appreciate that. - Natalie MacNeil, She Takes on the World Image courtesy of iStockphoto, courtneyk More About: contributor, entrepreneurs, features, ment, women in technology</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/women-entrepreneurs-barriers-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/women-entrepreneurs-barriers-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Giving Away $50 Million in Free Advertising to Promote Video AdWords</title>
      <description>Google officially opened up its AdWords for video product to all businesses on Monday with a new program offering $50 million in free advertising to small businesses. The company announced on Monday that it is offering $75 in free advertising for 500,000-plus businesses. (The original post on the offer set the number at 500,000, which would come out to $37.5 million in total. A YouTube rep says the 500,000 isn&#8217;t a set number.) Introduced in September, AdWords for video is based on the same technology as AdWords, but is applied to video on the Google-owned YouTube. While with AdWords you pay for clicks and set budgets via bids, with AdWords for video, you only pay when someone watches your ad. The program was actually opened up for all businesses in December, but Monday is the official launch, which Google is helping to publicize with the $75 offer. Those interested in taking Google up on the offer can click here. The AdWords for video program is Google&#8217;s latest attempt to monetize YouTube, which draws 800 million unique visitors a month. Google doesn&#8217;t disclose financial data about YouTube, but analysts have estimated that the site&#8217;s revenues were in the $1 billion range in 2011. Image courtesy of Flickr, tschein More About: Adwords, Google, Small Business, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/google-50mfree-advertising/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/google-50mfree-advertising/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Video Tips for Businesses on Pinterest</title>
      <description>Grant Crowell is a multimedia writer and marketing analyst who&#8217;s been covering the online video space since 2006. Connect with him on LinkedIn or follow him at @grantcrowell. Since Pinterest was founded in 2008, it&#8217;s proven one thing: People love their visuals. And it looks like the site is becoming a hot space for online video marketing opportunities as well, with its recent integration of the Vimeo platform. SEE ALSO: Need More YouTube Views? Try Pinterest The video platform addition makes sense, given how video continues to grow on the network. For example, despite Pinterest&#8217;s &#8220;no-follow&#8221; links rule to third-party sites, videos on the site are being indexed by Google at a rapid rate. In late March, Google had indexed 1,170 Pinterest videos. By mid-April, that figure jumped to 5,870 video results &#8212; an increase of more than 500% in just three weeks. What that should tell brands and marketers is that now is the time to start looking at Pinterest as a video marketing vertical. Here are ten tips on how to get the most out of using video on this site. 1. Customize the Thumbnail Images Video thumbnails that are nicely photographed and appear to be art directed will blend in much better on Pinterest, and typically draw more attention than a video still frame. However, if you&#8217;re not a YouTube Partner, the images you get won&#8217;t always look great. Vimeo offers a far better solution where you can upload your own custom thumbnail. This leaves quality control in your hands. When selecting a thumbnail, find or create an eye-catching image that properly represents your video. If it&#8217;s a company product, consider setting it against a white background. If it&#8217;s more of an idea, then find a visual that provides a unique way of showcasing your theme. Whatever you do, make sure that your primary visual can clearly be seen at thumbnail size, and is not obscured by the default &#8220;play&#8221; button. 2. Have Descriptive Video Pins and Pinboards Pinterest recommends you create at least a few boards that cover a broad range of interests, rather than maintaining a single board devoted to one topic. Yet, some brands make the mistake of placing all of their videos on a single pinboard and non-descriptively titling it, &#8220;videos.&#8221; Don&#8217;t do that. You wouldn&#8217;t think of titling a pinboard, &#8220;images.&#8221; Instead, look for ways to combine your originally-produced videos with curated videos into pinboards around keyword-rich themes, and place them next to related static images you&#8217;ve pinned. For example, a product pin can be strategically placed next to an interesting video showing a lifestyle experience or demo of that product. Merchandising images and video together can prove to be more influential with viewers. 3. Keep Your Videos Short, When Possible Pinterest is designed for quick browsing and pinning, so you don&#8217;t want to make people feel like they&#8217;re going to be stuck watching a long video. Naturally, there will be exceptions, as some video themes, like DIYs or demos, may require more time. In either case, make sure to list the length of the video right in the description since viewers are becoming conditioned to seeing that in YouTube and search engine results. 4. Clearly Describe Video Content Don&#8217;t ever leave your description field blank. Describe to people what they can expect to see before they click on the video. Even with an eye-catching thumbnail image, and a relevant subject, people still read the description field of a video to make sure it&#8217;s worth their time. 5. Curate Fresh Videos with Fresh Descriptions Always consider taking the most popular and freshest videos that relate to whatever product, solution, lifestyle, or event you are a part of, and curating them. I recommend creating your own unique title and description instead of duplicating what appears on the original video page, so as not to appear &#8220;spammy.&#8221; 6. Include &#8220;Pin This&#8221; Annotations When you are using your own YouTube videos, Brian Honigman, the digital marketing manager at Marc Ecko Enterprises, suggests including annotations with a call-to-action for your audience. Basically, tell your visitors to &#8220;pin this video to Pinterest&#8221; or provide a link to your Pinterest profile as a way to connect. 7. Add &#8220;Pin Me&#8221; Notices in Video Outtros Of course, you can always feature your own call-to-action in the video content you create. Simply include something like &#8220;Follow me at pinterest.com/[pinterest name]&#8221; in your video outtros, like the example above. It makes for a great reminder for users to engage with you in another way and in a different community. 8. Put a &#8220;Pin It&#8221; Button Next to Your Video Player You likely already know that you can add the Pinterest follow button to your website or blog. You should also have it embedded right under the embedded video player on your website and blog pages. It&#8217;s just one more way your visitors can get to key content. 9. Create a Pinterest-Specific Video Campaign Some brands are now developing video campaigns to encourage users to follow them on Pinterest and pin their items. Take this Pinterest video campaign from a U.K. insurance comparison website. Their Driving in Heels video was part of a contest where users submitted the craziest shoes they have ever worn while operating a car. This turned out to be an effective cross-marketing strategy. It created awareness about a public safety issue (unsafe driving habits), while also generating increased brand awareness through theme-based pinning. 10. Repin Videos by Others Pinterest&#8217;s best brand practices page says &#8220;repinning is one of the most social activities on Pinterest and it&#8217;s how any user really builds his/her network of followers.&#8221; One way to do this with videos is to find influencers in your industry who already have Pinterest profiles, follow them, and include their videos on your own pinboard. Make sure to notify them about it on the comments section of their original pins. Better yet, you can create a custom video that comments on some of the more interesting &#8220;Pin-fluencers&#8221; in your community. Both of these are acceptable ways of reaching out to thought leaders and brand leaders. What other online video marketing opportunities are you seeing with Pinterest? Have you used video on Pinterest with a business strategy or an interesting business outcome? Let us know in the comments. 1. Perfect Palette 244,163 Followers 113 Boards 6,925 Pins Looking for a color theme for your upcoming wedding? Well, you've come to the right place. Click here to view this gallery. More About: contributor, features, ONLINE VIDEO, pinterest, social media marketing, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/pinterest-video-marketing-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/pinterest-video-marketing-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Now Has 901 Million Users</title>
      <description>Facebook disclosed on Monday that it has 901 million users, making it likely that it will pass the 1 billion mark well before the end of the year. The company, which dropped the stat in its amended S-1 filing, also notes that its network receives 3.2 billion comments per day and 300 million new photos daily. The site also claims 125 billion friendships. Of the 901 million figure, 526 million were described as daily active users in March. Some 488 million people also used Facebook mobile products that month, according to the filing. When Facebook filed its IPO paperwork with the SEC in February, the network tallied 845 million users. Back in January, Gregory Lyons, a senior analyst at iCrossing, estimated that Facebook would hit 1 billion users by August, a rate of growth that appears plausible based on the latest numbers. Even before Monday&#8217;s latest numbers dropped, Facebook was by far the largest social network in the world. Twitter, which passed 500 million users in February, is number two on the list &#8212; although Twitter says that only 140 million of those accounts are active. How big will Facebook get, and how fast? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Facebook, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/facebook-now-has-901-million-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/facebook-now-has-901-million-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Buys $550 Million in Patents from Microsoft</title>
      <description>Facebook has signed an agreement to acquire $550 million in patents from Microsoft, the companies announced jointly Monday. The patents were part of the $1.065 billion in patents Microsoft purchased from AOL earlier this month. In the initial agreement, Microsoft took ownership of approximately 925 U.S. patents and patent applications, in addition to a license to AOL&#8217;s remaining patent portfolio of about 300 patents. Facebook has now taken possession of 650 of those patents, &#8220;plus a license to the AOL patents and applications that Microsoft will purchase and own,&#8221; Facebook said in a release. That leaves Microsoft with 275 of the original patents and applications it purchased from AOL. Microsoft will also retain a license to 650 of the patents and applications now owned by Facebook, in addition to the ~300 AOL patents it gained a license to earlier. &#8220;Today&#8217;s agreement with Facebook enables us to recoup over half of our costs while achieving our goals from the AOL auction,&#8221; Brad Smith, executive vice president and general counsel of Microsoft, said in the release. More About: aol, Facebook, microsoft, patentsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/facebook-buys-microsoft-aol-patents/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/facebook-buys-microsoft-aol-patents/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Smartphone Users Taking Pictures, Updating Statuses at Restaurants [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Playing on your phone might be taboo while out to dinner, but more people are pulling out their mobile devices to snap and share pictures of meals and update their Facebook statuses, a new study suggests. According to an infographic by market research firm Lab42, about 19% of those that use their smartphone while at a restaurant update their status on Facebook. Meanwhile, about 24% said they take pictures of their entrees and 18% check-in to the restaurant on services such as Foursquare. Not surprisingly, smartphone users (20%) are also communicating with others to make dinner plans and 19% use mobile devices to find nearby restaurants. Meanwhile, about one in five people who use their smartphones during their dining out experience do so to view a menu online and find directions. Does it bother your when someone uses a phone while at a restaurant or is it now socially acceptable? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, robynmac More About: Mobile, smartphonesFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/smartphone-pics-restaurants-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/smartphone-pics-restaurants-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracky: The Most Useful Online Tool You&#8217;ll Use At Work Today</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Tracky Quick Pitch: Tracky is an application that boosts productivity by cutting Internet clutter. The web and mobile app brings email, chat, task collaboration and file sharing to one place. Genius Idea: Tracky is an application for planning, collaborating and getting tasks done. From the platform, share goals, news and finished tasks onto Twitter, Facebook and Pinterest. To the Tracky team, the Internet is an over-saturated place where people at work are bombarded with applications and tabs. The Tracky solution is simple &#8212; cut out the number of inboxes, social networks and applications people use to complete giant to-do lists. By using this social collaboration platform, busy bees can reduce jumping from project management tools such as Basecamp to Google Docs, email, instant messaging and calendars. Users can connect to Twitter, Facebook and Pinterest and share out information from within the app. &#8220;It really allows you to take a bunch of apps you are using to manage professional and social onto one platform,&#8221; Jennifer Gosse, chief marketing officer of Tracky told Mashable. &#8220;It&#8217;s an all-in-one tool. Tracky lets you have private presence or work with a team. You can also push out information.&#8221; The task-management platform lets users sign up and work publicly or privately. Users can invite team members to private chats or procure public feedback. Tracky lets people create and organize tasks &#8212; called tracks. Tracks look like tweets within the interface and show up in real time. Tasks may be organized by date created, time updated or by due date, and tagged with priority. Bare bones, Tracky is a virtual to-do list. There&#8217;s also the gratification of checking something off when completed. Each task can be assigned a due date in the calendar and can be uploaded with attachments. Share events with friends or families and include pictures, Microsoft Excel sheets or Word documents. Companies may use Tracky to get feedback from employees or customers. Simply ask a question to start off a conversation thread. Tracky&#8217;s main appeal is as an online task manager. Individuals can assign tasks, giving the reigns of a project to one or more people. It keeps documents together and organized as efficiently as popular project management tool Basecamp does. Tracky works as a social network as a platform built on the ease of social discovery. Users can connect with people in the same industry or seek out nearby groups with the app&#8217;s geo-location feature. Local startups can get in touch with each other. Companies looking for a developer, for example, can search within Tracky&#8217;s network of users to find relevant talent. The network&#8217;s public profiles cut out the need for an About.me profile. Professionals can list their business affiliations, company title and a few sentences about themselves. They can also connect all their social network accounts onto their Tracky page for easy access. The work-efficient platform is free for now in the private beta stage, and cost $5 per user a month for an unlimited account. The free plan will cover up to five projects and up to 100 MB of file storage. The unlimited plan will cover unlimited projects and up to 1 GB of file storage per person. There are corporate plans that are offered on &#8220;Tracky scales.&#8221; The current mobile application is only available on iOS, but will be available on Android markets in the next few weeks. Would this app make your job easier? Are you using similar applications to better manage your work day? Which ones? Sound off in the comments. Image courtesy of Flickr, ClickFlashPhotos Series Supported by Microsoft BizSpark The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark, a startup program that gives you three-year access to the latest Microsoft development tools, as well as connecting you to a nationwide network of investors and incubators. There are no upfront costs, so if your business is privately owned, less than three years old, and generates less than U.S.$1 million in annual revenue, you can sign up today. More About: bizspark, Business, Social Media, social networking</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/tracky-web-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/tracky-web-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Business and Content Guidance from Bell Labs</title>
      <description>Posted by Kate Morris I've been reading The Idea Factory, the history of the innovation that came out of Bell Labs around WWII. Innovation, invention and ideas are things that we don't get to talk much about in SEO. It's all about keywords, links, and content, but I want you to take some time today to think about ideas, inventions and innovations. Why? Because we all want to be millionaires (oh hush, yes you do), and while that might not happen to all of us, idea generation is central to our jobs in search marketing. Bell Labs was born out of a technology being invented (the telephone) and the problems AT&amp;T faced building a communications infrastructure in the United States (and how to connect overseas). We are talking serious problems like wood decay, birds and wires, distance and signal strength. Things we take for granted today. The men and women at Bell Labs strove to find the best materials, to make products and services better. We can learn from the team at Bell Labs. Use the ideals of hard work, research and development, invention, and innovation to drive us to make our websites, products, and services better. That's how you win on the internet. Be better than everyone else. Innovation is a Lengthy Process The term "innovation" dated back to sixteenth-century England. Originally it described the introduction into society of a novelty or new idea, usually relating to philosophy or religion an innovation defined the lengthy and wholesale transformation of an idea into a technological product or process meant for widespread practical use. This portion of the book really hit home with me. Innovation is a lengthy process of taking an idea to a product or process for widespread practical use. There are no overnight successes, just people that worked really hard behind the scenes pouring their blood, sweat and tears into an idea. The same should be true with your business and website. Innovation in your space is not just putting up a website and knowing the right keywords to target. It's about waking up at 5:30 in the morning to be at a networking breakfast at 8am a few times a month for a few years. Success is about determination, dedication and hard work. The time you take to discuss your idea, how you plan to be different with members of your target market, will pay back not only in the refining of that idea, but also in friends and allies when your business or website launch. Choosing the connected people is a strategic process; if they are there at 8am, they are dedicated too and have met others that are of the same breed. Now does that mean that everyone needs to go to 8am networking breakfasts? No. I hate them. But you get the idea. Want your website to be a success? Then spend the time in the following areas: Business Idea - don't copy someone else's idea unless you can be better than them and everyone else in the space doing the same Website Copy - Develop the copy for your site, and if you have products what you'll let others use. Write into affiliate contracts that your product descriptions are not to be used elsewhere. Treat website content like a white paper, protect it, don't allow others to copy it. Promotion - I am not talking online promotion, I'm talking the whole marketing umbrella. This is not something you buy/outsource and leave alone. It's your baby, own it! Make Goals, Not Hard Timelines Inventions are a valuable part, but invention is not to be scheduled or coerced. Harold Arnold, Bell Labs Need $10k by next year? Don't build a website, add products, pay someone in another country to write copy and do SEO and think you can do that. Good ideas don't fit in timelines. You cannot rely on keyword research tools to tell you what product area has low competition and can make you millions. What you can do is find an area, a business idea that you really love: something that you can get lost talking about for hours and not mind. Your first goal should be to find that idea. Once you have that (and most of you do as you have clients or work in-house for someone that has that idea already), then you need to set goals for what you want to accomplish. The goals should be: Lofty but attainable (one viral infographic a month is not an attainable goal, an increase in sales from organic search by 20% is attainable) Developed around making the customer happy (the happier they are, the more you sell, simple) Tied to your boss's goals (even if your boss is your wife) Once you know what you want to do, the end result, that drives how to get there. Now you have a purpose, but you can't rush it. You will fail, content will flop sometimes, there will be a keyword that you just have a hard time ranking for. Things will go wrong but things will also go amazingly right if you focus on a good goal. Do Something When you don't know what to do, do something!" Jim Fisk, Bell Labs This is my new favorite motto. Do something. As Will Critchlow says all the time, fail faster. Come up with as many ideas as you can to meet your goal, no matter how far out of the park they are. Execute. Try things, be risky, and fail (sometimes). I can almost guarantee you that even if you fail; you'll learn something you can apply to your next attempt. Studying Sharks Jim Fisk proposed a $50,000 study of sharks to help naval warfare. It made it to the top and the lead of Bell Labs finally killed it. How cool a story would that have made? I would have linked to it, what about you? Dare You Don't know what to do? Here are some ideas for every SEO out there. I dare you to try one. Data Mining. Take a half-day, look into the data you have in your company about clients, about the industry. If you were to clean it all up, could you show trends about your industry? Get creative and find a way to share that information in a resource, a white paper, blog post or infographic. And then do a marketing campaign around it. If it works well, make it an annual update about the industry. Content Revisit. Find your top 10 products or services pages. Revisit the content, when was it last written? Update it! Add resources; make it the page to go to for that product or service. Think from the perspective of a potential customer, what would make that page better than all of your competitor's pages? Consider new images, a video, new resources, reviews. Page 2 Revamp. Take 5 pages that rank on page 2. Revisit the title tag and meta description of those pages. Is the title tag over optimized? Does the meta description really pull you to the page? Rewrite them to be real, accurate and descriptive! $5000 Challenge. Ask for a budget that is normal for a project in your company or for a client and do something that is way out in left field. You in finance? Pay off someone's car loan. Don't give away a iPad, donate 100 to a school that teaches computer science to under-privileged kids. So would you do with $5000 to help your site? What is your shark bait? Shark Stock Photo from Shutterstock Sign up for The Moz Top 10, a semimonthly mailer updating you on the top ten hottest pieces of SEO news, tips, and rad links uncovered by the Moz team. Think of it as your exclusive digest of stuff you don't have time to hunt down but want to read!</description>
      <link>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/modern-business-and-content-guidance-from-bell-labs?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/modern-business-and-content-guidance-from-bell-labs?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Slick Analytics Dashboards to Monitor Your Business Website</title>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the American Express OPEN Forum, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business. If you&#8217;re running a company website without an analytics dashboard, you may as well be stumbling around in the dark. Building a viable and sustainable web presence in any industry is all about understanding the needs of your users and tailoring your service to fit their needs &#8212; how can you do that if you don&#8217;t even know what your users are looking at or how they got to your website? The good news is that analytics dashboards simple to implement, and they also come in a variety of shapes and sizes to suit the needs and goals of your small business. While some people swear by Google Analytics or the tracking plug-ins found organically within their specific web hosting or content managing service (think WordPress analytics), there&#8217;s a lot of information you may not be getting from these sources. For example, while Google Analytics does a great job tracking individual page vies, it doesn&#8217;t necessarily break down any meaningful social sharing or referrals. You may want to know why a specific webpage on your site garners major traffic, but Google Analytics will only note that it comes from Facebook. If you&#8217;d like to obtain a more tailored or granular look into your website, it&#8217;s best to make an investment in a third-party analytics dashboard that offers exactly the data that you need. You may find that you&#8217;ll not only be able to target the audience interested in your website, but you&#8217;ll also be able to optimize the content and structure to bring in more potential consumers in the long run. Do you have an analytics dashboard you swear by? Let us know in the comments. 1. Analytics Catch-All: Chartbeat Do you maintain a website that has only a few pages of static content or delivers periodic (but not super-frequent) content updates? Then you may benefit from Chartbeat, a pumped-up analytics dashboard that offered real-time analytics before Google did. The service&#8217;s dashboard is really simple &#8212; log in at any time and get a bird&#8217;s-eye view of every user on your site, including what page they&#8217;re on and where they came from. In addition to marking key traffic flow, Chartbeat also keeps tabs on the &#8220;engagement level&#8221; of each user. Specifically, anyone controlling the dashboard can check the level of users who are reading or writing on or about a particular page, as well as how many users are considered &#8220;idle.&#8221; The combination of this data can give you the best idea of when, where and how users are reaching your site, allowing you to adjust your content or SEO accordingly. Interested in how it works? Chartbeat actually offers a free 30-day trial of its services, and from there pricing plans begin at $9.95 per month. If you have a small budget to spend on analytics, this tool could serve you well and help you grow your online business. And If you&#8217;re in ecommerce, be sure to keep an eye out for Chartbeat&#8217;s savvy, up-and-coming cousin, Shopbeat. 2. Social Savvy: HootSuite HootSuite is an oldie, but a goodie &#8212; it&#8217;s still the premier dashboard for companies looking to get analysis of their social media efforts. If your company spends more time on Facebook and Twitter than a website or blog, HootSuite doubles as both a social media manager and analytics tabulator. In many ways, your never need to leave the HootSuite dashboard to manage your day-to-day engagement. The platform allows you to write and schedule posts on nearly every social media website in existence (the company recently added Digg, InboxQ and Trendspottr to its ever-growing list of served platforms) and then track the resulting conversations and referrals. The dashboard also pulls in data from Google Analytics and Facebook Insights to provide data of how campaigns are directly affecting home websites and Facebook Brand Pages. Another reason HootSuite remains popular is its low cost. The Pro Plan price for the dashboard is a paltry $5.99 a month, and it offers all of the above features. One downside, however, is that if you&#8217;re looking for a whole team to be simultaneously locked in to the system, you&#8217;re going to have to pony up an extra $15 for each additional admin. But if you&#8217;re looking for a way to deftly manage social media in a way that will drive potential companies or your website &#8212; and to a sale &#8212; then HootSuite is a dashboard worth paying for. 3. High Roller: Parse.ly Dash Is yours an up-and-coming company with high content output and striving for major visibility in the web space? Well, it&#8217;s time to make investment in Parse.ly Dash, the &#8220;predictive dashboard&#8221; that pays special attention to what&#8217;s trending right now and how to capitalize on what everyone is talking about on the Internet in real-time. If you&#8217;re looking for analytics that drill down, separate and categorize every page on your website, Parse.ly Dash will be more than happy to serve you. You can sort your content by author, topic, page and referral to get a good idea of not only where everyone is looking, but what sort of content to produce further down the road. Parse.ly Dash will actually suggest what topics your website should write about, and what trends are just breaking on the surface. The analytics dashboard offers multilateral control to the user in a more comprehensive way than most products do &#8212; you can essentially use it to plan for your website&#8217;s future content based on what your users respond to best. All of this control comes at a hefty price. The basic plan starts at $500 a month, well out of the price range of most startups and average businesses. But, if you&#8217;re looking to produce a content-heavy and highly engaging website, Parse.ly Dash will help take your website to the next level. More Small Business Resources From OPEN Forum: - Should Small Businesses Follow Everyone Back on Twitter? - Are You Falling into the Pricing Trap? - How to Take Your PR Pitches to the Next Level Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Jirsack More About: chartbeat, features, google analytics, hootsuite, mashable, open forum, social analytics, Web analytics</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/website-analytics-dashboard-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/website-analytics-dashboard-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Olympic Moms Video Will Make You Cry</title>
      <description>As athletes get ready to take the global stage during the London 2012 Olympic Games less than 100 days away, Procter &amp; Gamble has released a new ad praising mothers worldwide. Press play and cue the waterworks. In three days, the video has received over 700,000+ views on YouTube. P&amp;G, the personal care and cleaning products giant and Olympic partner, released the &#8220;Best Job&#8221; video in anticipation of the summer games. The video, directed by Alejandro Gonz&#225;lez I&#241;&#225;rritu, features mothers on four continents in London, Rio de Janeiro, Los Angeles and Beijing. These inspirational women raising their young Olympians are the true champs. SEE ALSO: Olympics Unveil Social Media Hub to Connect Athletes and Fans The &#8220;Thank You, Mom&#8221; campaign is the largest in the company&#8217;s 174-year history, according to a P&amp;G press release. It ties in social media and print elements. On the official &#8220;Thank You, Mom&#8221; Facebook Page &#8212; with over 510,000 likes &#8212; the company connects its consumers with posts about its products, Olympics news and athlete updates. There&#8217;s also an app within the page where sons and daughters can thank the maternal figures in their lives with a video, pictures or a simple message. Tell us in the comments if this video made you weep. Thumbnail image courtesy of P&amp;G More About: Business, Facebook, Marketing, proctor &amp; gamble, Social Media, social networking, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/olympic-moms-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/olympic-moms-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Digital Customer Service Guide</title>
      <description>In our recent Customer Experience Series, Mashable dove deep into the mysterious alchemy of customer service. Those who own their own business will tell you: Getting (and keeping) customers is not easy. There are so many different factors that must work together perfectly within a company to ensure that fans of your brand stay happy. Whether its making sure that your ecommerce platform doesn&#8217;t drive your users crazy or organizing your social media to build your community, forethought is key to a premium customer experience. These articles will give you comprehensive knowledge of many facets of digital customer service, with expert advice from community managers, CEOs and web designers. Here&#8217;s a roundup of all of our articles, brought together into this handy guide. To read more, click through to the full article, and you can access the entire series here. 1. 7 Ways to Lower Your Website&#8217;s Bounce Rate Businesses need to make sure their first impressions reel in the visitor to keep the person on your website and engaged with your brand. To help you combat pesky bounce rates, we&#8217;ve put together a list of usability considerations that can be used to lower your site&#8217;s bounce rate and improve visitor retention. From optimized page layouts to faster loading, there are a number of ways to keep web surfers hooked. Read the full story here. 2. 10 Essential Features of Every Good Business Website So your business has a website &#8212; or you&#8217;re in need of one for your brand new venture. Web design can be an overwhelming process, so we&#8217;ve spoken to a few web designers who told us what you need to have on your site &#8230; and what you can probably do without (like crazy Flash animation). We&#8217;ve gathered 10 website must-haves that will ensure your customers have a positive experience on the site, improve your company&#8217;s digital footprint and increase engagement with your brand. Read the full story here. 3. 8 Killer Web Form Builders for Your Site So you have your website set up with all the necessary features, but what about customer feedback? You have to be prepared to field the questions and concerns of your users, and nothing really does that better than a form. However, not all form builders are created equal. While they all seem to have some basic parts, there are special details and customizable options that make each builder unique. Here are eight great form-building options to choose from &#8212; find the one that fits you and your company&#8217;s needs. Read the full story here. 4. What You Need to Know About Building a Mobile App for Your Brand In case you haven&#8217;t noticed, most of your potential customers have gone mobile. Last June, consumers began spending more time on mobile apps than on the web, according to researcher Flurry. While creating a mobile website seems like an easy, cheap way to maintain visibility in this environment, another option is to create your own app. A few years ago, that wouldn&#8217;t have made any sense. But now prices have come down, the audience has grown and there&#8217;s a good chance that if you don&#8217;t have a mobile app, your competition will offer one. Read the full story here. 5. 10 Ways to Optimize Your Ecommerce Site for Google Search Ecommerce websites have several inherent qualities &#8212; shallow copy, duplicate content and a large product catalog &#8212; that make it challenging to achieve a high Google ranking. But there are some best practices you can employ, in addition to traditional SEO techniques, to help your ecommerce site gain traction on Google. Read the full story here. 6. 4 Ways To Make Your Ecommerce Site More Visually Appealing These days, every thriving retail business needs an ecommerce platform. While consumers flock to major online outlets like Amazon and eBay to get their share of products, smaller stores can benefit from the draw an online storefront can give them. Ecommerce is definitely the future of sales, but there&#8217;s one thing that could send your ecommerce storefront to an early demise: an ugly layout. It&#8217;s plain and simple &#8212; no one wants to shop at an unattractive, dated or unintuitive online storefront. Just as a front window display encourages customers to come into your store and take a peek at your wares, the way that your ecommerce landing and merchandise pages look either will entice users to click the check-out button or drive them to other websites. Read the full story here. 7. 12 Top Community Managers Share Their Tips for Better Engagement Engagement is one of the most talked about metrics for ROI. Some argue that the raw number of Likes, comments and retweets don&#8217;t mean anything. Instead, they point to a fans&#8217; level of investment, loyalty and engagement to determine whether social media is &#8220;paying off.&#8221; Mashable gathered tips from a dozen top community managers to help you boost activity on your social platforms. Read the full story here. 8. 14 Community-Driven Tips for Better Customer Relationships Like any other relationship, the foundation you establish with your client or customer is crucial to how the business relationship will develop over time. It requires taking the time at the start, going the extra mile and paying attention to detail. Customers are more likely to give you their loyalty when they experience consistency and transparency from the initial pitch. They appreciate you being genuine and upfront about your policies &#8212; no one likes a half-hearted response or to feel like they&#8217;ve been tricked. The following are some tips and tricks on how to build relationships with your customers from leaders in communications, PR and social media. Read the full story here. 9. 6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media We all know social media is an important tool for brand awareness and customer acquisition &#8212; but how exactly are you supposed to convert random Twitter and Facebook users into real-life customers? Well, that depends. Whether you&#8217;re a clothing shop, a restaurant or a subscription service, you must tailor your strategy so that it makes sense for your brand. That said, there are a few universal ways to help your company attract new faces on the social web. Read the full story here. 10. 2 Ways to Fix Customer Loyalty Programs Consumers aren&#8217;t as loyal to loyalty programs as they used to be. Why the dissatisfaction? Let&#8217;s call it the Groupon factor. Since 2008, there have been a flood of daily deal merchants, like Groupon and LivingSocial, that have filled customers inboxes with irrelevant offers. (Groupon itself has recently employed a Pandora-like &#8220;thumbs up, thumbs down&#8221; rating system to tackle this problem, which is best illustrated by the example of middle-aged men getting offers for bikini waxes.) Read the full story here. 11. 7 Mistakes to Avoid on Your Ecommerce Site We&#8217;ve all been there. You&#8217;re all set to buy something, credit card in hand, but for one reason or another you never close the deal. Maybe the third time you were asked to enter your credit card number you gave in. Perhaps it was the exorbitant shipping costs. Maybe the site crashed. If you actually want people to stick around and buy stuff from your site, you may want to take note of and avoid these common pitfalls. Read the full story here. Do you have a great customer service story? Tell us in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, ewg3D More About: Customer Experience Series, features, mashable, roundupFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/customer-service-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/22/customer-service-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
