<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>WWDC 2012 Keynote now available</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/126pihbedvcoihbefvbhjkbvsefbg/event/index.html</link>
      <guid>http://events.apple.com.edgesuite.net/126pihbedvcoihbefvbhjkbvsefbg/event/index.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS 6: Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <description>If you were looking for new mobile features, then iOS 6, which Apple unveiled on Monday at WWDC, does not disappoint. At WWDC 2012, Scott Forstall took the stage to unveil iOS 6 to developers. iOS 6 features more than 200 updates and improvements when compared to iOS 5. iOS 5 already boasts more than 80% adoption rate across devices and Apple boasted figures about iMessage, Twitter stats, Game Center and push notifications. So what's new in iOS 6? Siri Siri can now launch apps Siri can now Tweet (no hacks required!) Siri is smart about sports. It can pull in scores, game summaries and player stats. Siri integrates with Yelp and OpenTable for restaurant reviews an&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, apple maps, Facebook, iOS 6, siri, trending, wwdc, WWDC 2012</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/ios-6-revaled/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/ios-6-revaled/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook App Center: What Does It Actually Do?</title>
      <description>Facebook announced its App Center Thursday night -- but it wasn't immediately clear how users would benefit, or whether it simply added another layer between you and apps you download to your smartphone. More than 600 apps are featured in the App Center. These apps are not new, and are already able to sync with your Facebook account, should you let them. What has changed: now you can go to Facebook.com/appcenter, and choose apps you want to download on your Android or iOS device. Those apps then show up as notifications in your Facebook mobile app. Click the notification and it will take you to the regular app store on your phone so you can download the app in question. But you still&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apps, Facebook, facebook apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/facebook-app-center-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/facebook-app-center-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Social Media Day With Mashable in the Bay Area</title>
      <description>Mashable launched Social Media Day in 2010 as a way to recognize the digital revolution happening around the world. This is a global celebration of the technological advancements that have given rise to the connected generation. Come celebrate with Mashable and Motorola Mobility, our exclusive global sponsor, for our 3rd annual Social Media Day on June 30, 2012 at The Box SF. This event is free, but due to limited capacity, please make sure to register and arrive promptly. The event will feature networking, music, hors d'oeuvres, drinks and gadgets. For updates and to find out what others are up to for Social Media Day, follow our @mashsmday Twitter account and like our Soci&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Events, mashable, Social Media, social media day</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/social-media-day-2012-san-francisco/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/social-media-day-2012-san-francisco/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Lion Price Set at $19.99, Ships Next Month</title>
      <description>Apple announced on Monday during its 23rd annual Worldwide Developers Conference that its Mac operating system OS X Mountain Lion will be priced at $19.99 when it ships in July. Apple exec Craig Federrichi told conferences attendees that those who buy a new Mac will receive a free Mountain Lion upgrade. "This is for upgrades from Lion and all the way from Snow Leopard, and it will upgrade all of your personal Macs," Federrichi said. The exact date in July was not noted. In February, Apple released a developer preview of OS X Mountain Lion, which is the ninth major release of Mac's operating system. The update brings a slew of apps and popular features from the iPad and iPhon&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, Mountain Lion, Snow Leopard, wwdc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/mountain-lion-price-release-date/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/mountain-lion-price-release-date/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silencing the bell doesn't put out the fire</title>
      <description>Many big organizations have full-time employees who scan the social media, looking for people with a complaint. They swoop in and grease the squeaky wheel, solving the problem of the person who spoke up. The theory is that these loud complainers are a problem, and the easiest solution is to give them something to make them happy. Of course, that doesn't do anything for the 95% of the population that has the very same problem but isn't speaking up, right? When Jeff Jarvis blogged about Dell Hell, he hurt the company very badly. Mollifying Jeff (and those like him) did the company no good in the long run, though, because they didn't deal with the underlying cause, they merely gave the loud ones an excuse to be quiet. The purpose of the bell is to point to a fire somewhere else. Worry about that instead.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/silencing-the-bell-doesnt-put-out-the-fire.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/silencing-the-bell-doesnt-put-out-the-fire.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mashable Weekend Recap: 54 Stories You Might Have Missed</title>
      <description>The weekend went by quickly here at Mashable, where we had a merry team of driven journalists searching far and wide for the best tech, social media and business stories in the world. What do we find? We found a hilarious comic featuring our own Pete Cashmore. And look over there, it's an easy way to make your site ready for mobile. And what's this? Way-cool apps for iPhones? Count us in. And don't forget the boatload of rumors and speculation swirling around the upcoming WWDC. And that's just the beginning of it. Don't feel bad if you missed it, because we've placed every story published over the weekend right here in one convenient location. So sit back and savor the Mashable Weeken&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Weekend recap</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/weekend-recap-58/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/weekend-recap-58/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Dominates Global Social Network Traffic</title>
      <description>Facebook has a strong hold on traffic to various social networks across the globe, according to a new infographic map. Italian-based social media strategist Vincenzo Cosenza has looked at the most popular social networks used worldwide, according to traffic monitoring sites such as Alexa and Google Trends, and put together a map to highlight the leading platforms. He posted his findings on his blog, Vincos.it Facebook -- which boasts more than 845 million active users -- is the top-used social networking site in 126 out of 137 countries analyzed, including the U.S., Australia, Japan, the U.K., Canada, Brazil and India. Although Facebook has its roots in the U.S. (with 222 mi&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, international, Social Media, social networking, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/international-social-networks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/international-social-networks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Ways to Measure Your Brand&#8217;s Social Media Health</title>
      <description>Thanks to the variety of social media marketing tools available today, there is a nearly endless stream of data available to marketers. That could make it tough to determine what metrics actually matter for your campaign or brand and why. Here are nine key performance indicators and explanations for why they might matter to your brand. 1. Share of Voice: The number of mentions of your brand versus competing brands on the social web. Why You Should Care: Your Share of Voice can be a good indicator of the consumer awareness of your brand as compared to your competitive set. It essentially shows how much of the social conversation your brand has earned or is currently earning.&#8230; Continue reading... More About: brands, contributor, features, Marketing, online media, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/social-media-brand-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/social-media-brand-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Hotmail Getting a New Name Along With Its Redesign? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Microsoft is said to be working on a redesign of its Hotmail email platform, and leaked images of the new look have made its way onto the web. Liveside.net has released screenshots of Hotmail's new homepage design. Not only does it look a lot like Metro -- the company's new highly-visual interface associated with its Windows 8 software -- it appears to have a new name: Newmail. However, it's unknown whether &#8220;Newmail" is a placeholder name or if Hotmail will transition to that name soon. SEE ALSO: Windows 8 Release Preview Unleashes the Power of Metro [HANDS ON] The Window&#8217;s 8 Metro design upgrade aims to be viewable across devices and w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: email, hotmail, Metro, microsoft, Windows 8</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/hotmail-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/hotmail-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Hotmail Getting a New Name Along With Its Redesign? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Microsoft is said to be working on a redesign of its Hotmail email platform, and leaked images of the new look have made its way onto the web. Liveside.net has released screenshots of Hotmail's new homepage design. Not only does it look a lot like Metro -- the company's new highly-visual interface associated with its Windows 8 software -- it appears to have a new name: Newmail. However, it's unknown whether &#8220;Newmail" is a placeholder name or if Hotmail will transition to that name soon. SEE ALSO: Windows 8 Release Preview Unleashes the Power of Metro [HANDS ON] The Window&#8217;s 8 Metro design upgrade aims to be viewable across devices and w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: email, hotmail, Metro, microsoft, Windows 8</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/hotmail-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/hotmail-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The big challenge for apps making the leap to TV: Turning &#8220;me&#8221; into &#8220;we&#8221;</title>
      <description>There&#8217;s a big difference between a smartphone and a TV. As developers increasingly look to the opportunities of TV, they will have to shift their focus from thinking about a personal experience to a communal one &#8211; and I can&#8217;t wait to see what they come up with. The transition to a more &#8216;app-centric&#8217; approach to TV seems inevitable - Google is courting TV-focused developers, Apple is said to be launching a TV SDK at WWDC next week, Opera and Samsung have TV app stores, and there are bound to be many more opportunities to get apps onto our TVs in the future. While startups well versed in desktop, mobile or Web app development may be tempted to make that leap to the largest screen in the house, developing for TV presents unique challenges that will require some serious thought. Unlike your smartphone, tablet or laptop, a TV is first and foremost a communal device. We like to huddle around it in groups of family or friends after a hard day&#8217;s work. That means that the apps we&#8217;re used to using on our other devices won&#8217;t necessarily translate to TV particularly easily. I have a certain discomfort, for example, with the idea of my personal iCloud Photo Stream feeding into my Apple TV where anyone who&#8217;s watching can see it &#8211; the screenshots of apps and photos of speakers at conferences that populate it are intended for me (and perhaps you, dear reader), not for a communal audience to scroll through on a big screen in my house. Likewise, the idea of viewing the latest tweets from the people you follow on Twitter while watching a movie with your family seems unappealing. It seems logical that the big boys of the app world, from Twitter and Facebook to Evernote and Spotify will want to get onto our TVs, but while they&#8217;ve until now focused on offering personal experiences (your interests, your friends, your notes, your music), the challenge will be to rework their offerings into something that works on a big screen, in front of an audience. After all, you probably wouldn&#8217;t want to send Facebook messages to your friends in front of your family, and they&#8217;d probably find it a pretty dull experience, too. Can we make the personal communal? There are ways some of our favorite apps could be reworked for TV. A Twitter app that displays tweets from other people watching the same show as you could be fun, although arguably better served by a &#8216;second screen&#8217; app like Zeebox, or simply your favorite mobile Twitter client. A &#8216;social TV guide&#8217; that uses your Facebook friends&#8217; tastes to recommend what you should watch (in the mould of iPad app Tweek) is an excellent app for use on a TV, especially if it can combine multiple people&#8217;s Facebook accounts to recommend something that everyone in the room will like. The exciting thing is that there is a big opportunity for completely new apps and services the likes of which we&#8217;ve never seen before to conquer our TVs, designed from the ground up for communal use. What will they be? I&#8217;m not 100% sure, but it will be these apps that will sell the idea of apps on TV to the masses. Whatever happens, a TV shouldn&#8217;t be just another computer &#8211; it&#8217;s primarily a communal device, and the most successful developers will be those who treat it as such. Image credit: Pond 5</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/media/2012/06/10/the-big-challenge-for-apps-making-the-leap-to-tv-turning-me-into-we/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/media/2012/06/10/the-big-challenge-for-apps-making-the-leap-to-tv-turning-me-into-we/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
