<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>DC Earthquake Devastation - jmckinley's posterous</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a1.twimg.com/profile_images/1498883736/Jeremy_W._Peters_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jwpetersNYT"&gt;Jeremy W. Peters&lt;/a&gt;: First images coming in of DC earthquake devastation: &lt;a href="http://t.co/pHJCOen" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/pHJCOen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jwpetersNYT/status/163598915"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Retweeted by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/juliarothman"&gt;Julia Rothman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://jmckinley.posterous.com/dc-earthquake-devastation</link>
      <guid>http://jmckinley.posterous.com/dc-earthquake-devastation</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TMI.me: when you have too much to say...</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://tmi.me/dyEMy</link>
      <guid>http://tmi.me/dyEMy</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why there are so many engineers in India</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="520" height="245" src="http://cdn.thenextweb.com/in/files/2011/05/Picture_3-520x245.jpg" alt="Picture_3" title="Picture_3" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Why are there so many engineers in India?&amp;#8221; is one of the first questions someone tech savvy and vaguely familiar with India, would ask an Indian. In a lighter vein, but not very far from the truth, the answer is: &amp;#8220;Because there are so many people in India.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To truly understand modern engineering culture and mentality in India, which has been in the making for a few decades, we must go back to when India was liberated from the British rule in 1947. It is an oft-forgotten fact that &lt;em&gt;independent &lt;/em&gt;India is just &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indian_independence_movement" &gt;over sixty years old&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the fifties and the sixties when the hacker revolution was underway in MIT; India was just picking itself up from the devastation caused by being colonized for over two centuries. The Indian leaders had to make sure India could autonomously feed over 350 million people &amp;#8211; that was a gargantuan agricultural and engineering challenge in itself. Many developed nations were quick to dismiss India, saying it had missed the all-important Industrial revolution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sino-Indian_War" &gt;Sino-Indian war&lt;/a&gt; in 1962, in which India suffered a tactical defeat to China, led to swift changes in India&#8217;s military policy. The efforts would prove fruitful, when in 1965, the world witnessed the largest tank battle in military history since World War II, when India and Pakistan had their &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indo-Pakistani_War_of_1965" &gt;second major war&lt;/a&gt; over Kashmir. Six years later, India would be busy again, liberating Bangladesh (then East Pakistan) from Pakistan&#8217;s colonialism. To appreciate the role of engineering in these wars, one must ask, how did India manage to fight (and win) two major wars just a couple of decades after independence? Surely, India&#8217;s (and the Soviets&#8217;, with whom India enjoyed a healthy military relationship) military and engineers were in the right place. They would not realize it at that time, but they were building an almost bullet-proof military and industrial infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Not that these wars were any deterrents to India&#8217;s fledgling but rapidly growing agriculture, commerce and industry. India was a bit late to acquire nuclear power (some people attribute that to Mahatma Gandhi&#8217;s peace policies), and it snapped up partnerships with many Western countries. India&#8217;s agricultural revolution was operating at a whole new level after the government set in motion the Green Revolution, which led to phenomenal growths in agricultural output. In 1958, the Defense Research and Development Organization (DRDO) was set up, and it&#8217;s efforts would help India beat Pakistan twice in (aforementioned) separate wars within a span of six years. 1969 saw the coming of India&#8217;s very own NASA &amp;#8211; the Indian Space and Research Organization (ISRO) &amp;#8211; which was quick to launch it&#8217;s first satellite &lt;em&gt;Aryabhatta&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8211; in 1975 from the Soviet Union. In 1974 India performed it&#8217;s first nuclear test explosions &amp;#8211; ironically named &lt;em&gt;Smiling Buddha&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 1951, the first &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indian_Institutes_of_Technology" &gt;Indian Institute of Technology&lt;/a&gt; (IIT) was established at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.iitkgp.ernet.in/" &gt;Kharagpur&lt;/a&gt;. It would be the first autonomous university, and would operate free from Indian politics. This would prove a pivotal moment in the history of engineering in India. The standard had been set &amp;#8211; the best engineers in India would study at the IITs. By 1961, there were four more IITs. The high level of competition automatically ensured high-quality engineers flooding out to ensure India caught up with the world with respect to establishing an industrial framework for the future. People would repeatedly tell their children- study engineering, get a job and help build India.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Evidently, a lot was going on within India, but nobody else took notice. All this would change in 1991, when economic liberalization and globalisation were adopted by then Finance Minister, and current Prime Minister of India, Dr. Manmohan Singh. This, along with later reforms, paid huge dividends when India recorded it&#8217;s highest Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth rate in 2007 &amp;#8211; of 9%. By 2009, 300 million people had been saved from extreme poverty. Thanks to globalization, in 2006, international trade would form almost a quarter of India&#8217;s GDP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Along with globalisation came the now infamous brain-drain. India&#8217;s engineers found a new impetus to get into engineering colleges in India. After graduation, they could attend some of the most prestigious universities abroad &amp;#8211; Stanford, MIT, Harvard, Cambridge, Oxford &amp;#8211; all expenses paid, because these universities recognized the Indian engineers as hardworking, intelligent and massively competitive. It was nothing new &amp;#8211; Indian students had been visiting these universities since the early sixties &amp;#8211; though the volume of Indian students going abroad shot up in the nineties. For those who didn&#8217;t want to study further, developed nations offered jobs &amp;#8211; hundreds of thousands of them &amp;#8211; at mind-boggling salaries, and it was literally a human capital flight to the West, especially the USA.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The word spread, and the choice was clear. You could study for an engineering entrance exam, get through four years of engineering and then emigrate to USA. Else, you could study for a medical entrance examination, slog through med-school, do a post-doc specialization, an internship, become an assistant, and finally 15 years later, in-debt, start your own medical practise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The engineering path was way cooler &amp;#8211; engineering schools were way cooler. Booze, sex and casual use of narcotics infiltrated Indian engineering colleges in the 1970s, and they were &amp;#8220;the place to be&amp;#8221;. You could have the time of your life for four years, and then live the Great American Dream &amp;#8211; a term that is still used today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s difficult to pinpoint why other occupations like art, design, architecture failed to catch the whims of Indian students. An oft-cited reason is that they did it to save money- their school seniors would be studying for engineering, and the seniors would give their entrance-examination books to the juniors, often for free, and this would make a huge difference to the family&#8217;s expenditure. Another major contributing factor was that engineering colleges were less expensive than medical colleges, and only the rich kids could afford to go to medical school.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The hierarchy of an Indian classroom became clear &amp;#8211; the bright kids would become engineers, the rich kids would become doctors, and the dumb kids would go into arts. Why? Because it wasn&#8217;t difficult to get into arts school. It was always looked down upon if you came across someone with a B.A, even though he might be exceptionally bright and pursued arts for the love of it. The caste system, being abolished in Indian culture, had found it&#8217;s way into the Indian classroom in another form altogether &amp;#8211; engineers, doctors and arts majors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today, the calibre and quality of Indian engineers is under scrutiny, and the engineers of the 70s and the 80s can vouch for that fact. Students wrote anything and everything &amp;#8211; chemical equations, mathematical formulae, algorithms, sesquipedalian words for essays, and even complete text-books. The examination pattern fulfills their expectations &amp;#8211; asking questions straight from the book which require no application-level knowledge at all. The Indian educational system today is just as &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman" &gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/a&gt; noted about the education system in Brazil in his book &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Surely-Youre-Joking-Feynman-Adventures/dp/009917331X" &gt;Surely You&#8217;re Joking, Mr. Feynman!&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;It was a kind of one-upmanship, where nobody knows what&#8217;s going on, and they&#8217;d put the other one down as if they did know. They all fake that they know, and if one student admits for a moment that something is confusing by asking a question, the others take a high-handed attitude, acting as if it&#8217;s not confusing at all, telling him that he&#8217;s wasting their time.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The MIT hackers of the 60s did their best to make sure that the hacker revolution in America did not die out, and it looks like they succeeded. Hackers have revolutionized computers with the Free and Open Source Software (FOSS) movement , but something similar is yet to be seen in the Indian engineering ecosystem. One must ask though, has engineering been overdone? Becoming an engineer in India virtually guarantees financial security for life, and this blinds parents into forcing their children to choose engineering. It is a romanticized notion, but I often wonder how many David Beckhams, Quentin Tarantinos and Carlos Santanas are currently pulling off 9-5 shifts for IT firms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/in/2011/05/08/why-there-so-many-engineers-in-india/</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/in/2011/05/08/why-there-so-many-engineers-in-india/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Year Later, Facebook Killing Off Places &#8230;To Put Location Everywhere</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/7vp3ccias2w.jpeg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="7vp3ccIas2w" title="7vp3ccIas2w" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was almost exactly one year ago that Facebook &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/08/18/facebook-location/"&gt;launched Places&lt;/a&gt;, their location-based offering. Reading the press at the time, you would have thought it was going to be the Foursquare-killer, the Gowalla-strangler, the Loopt-beheader, etc. Nevermind that Facebook &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/08/18/facebook-places-gowalla/"&gt;partnered&lt;/a&gt; with all of them for the launch &#8212; those guys were done. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today: Foursquare recently raised a large round of funding valuing them &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/24/foursquare-closes-50m-at-a-600m-valuation/"&gt;at $600 million&lt;/a&gt;. And Facebook is killing off Places.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To be clear, Facebook is not ducking out of the location game itself. In fact, you could say that they&amp;#8217;re doubling-down on it. But they are moving away from the game that the &amp;#8220;check-in&amp;#8221; services have been playing. And a result of that is Places being killed off and being replaced by new &amp;#8220;Nearby&amp;#8221; area, &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/23/facebooks-massive-kitchen-sink-update-photo-tag-approvals-and-so-much-more/"&gt;as Jason outlined&lt;/a&gt; along with the bigger privacy changes today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Reading over Facebook&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="https://blog.facebook.com/blog.php?post=10150251867797131"&gt;own post&lt;/a&gt; on the location changes, it wasn&amp;#8217;t entirely clear what these changes meant for the concept of the check-in itself. When I asked Jason, he said Facebook tried to explain it to him for ten minutes, but it still wasn&amp;#8217;t clear. But &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/about/location"&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; appears to make it a little more clear. As I read it, check-ins will remain as a part of the product, but they&amp;#8217;ll no longer be emphasized. It seems that the hope is that people will move away from thinking of location in terms of &amp;#8220;checking in&amp;#8221; and instead think about it in terms of tagging your location to what ever it is you&amp;#8217;re doing &#8212; sharing a thought, posting a picture, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the new location page makes clear, Facebook now views location usage in three main ways:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Share where you&amp;#8217;ve been&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Share where you are now&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Share where you&amp;#8217;re going&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Past. Present. Future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is smart, as it&amp;#8217;s something none of the other location services have really nailed yet. And now that location is being emphasized on every Facebook action (though it can easily be turned off) &#8212; and not just on mobile &#8212; a lot of people are going to use it. Location as a layer of context is about to get a big upgrade.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All of this is also smart from a location-based advertising strategy. It&amp;#8217;s more data and more strong signals. What I&amp;#8217;m not yet clear on is what this means for Facebook&amp;#8217;s location-based deals service. Launched alongside Places last year, it would seem that this never really took off. And Facebook doesn&amp;#8217;t mention it today. I&amp;#8217;ve reached out to them to clarify.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The video on the location info page details how location tagging will work. The default on facebook.com appears to be city-level, and there&amp;#8217;s a secondary location button to add an actual venue (which is then inserted into your status message). You can also add location to photos you&amp;#8217;ve already posted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The video also points out that on mobile devices there will still be a check-in button, but the functionality will be different. It apparently will only exist as a part of a status update and there will be no more big blue &amp;#8220;Check In&amp;#8221; button that inserts your check-in into a stream of other check-ins (and again, no more Places area itself). Instead, once you select a place, it will simply be tacked on to the end of your status message.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Location sharing will also be tied to the more direct and simplified privacy changes Facebook outlined today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;div class="module-crunchbase"&gt; &lt;div class="configuration-neighbor"&gt; &lt;h2 class="global-module-header-black"&gt; &lt;span class="line-2"&gt; &lt;div class="cb-home-header cb-stack-home-header"&gt; &lt;a href="http://crunchbase.com"&gt;Crunchbase&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="cb-entity-header"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/facebook" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;FACEBOOK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class="container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel-container"&gt; &lt;div class="panel current"&gt; &lt;div class="leftgreen"&gt; &lt;div class="info-container info-container-stack-view"&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Company:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;FACEBOOK&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://facebook.com" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;http://facebook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Launch Date:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;1/2/2004&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="left-align"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;$2.34B&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="body-copy"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Facebook is the world&amp;#8217;s largest social network, with over 500 million users. Facebook was founded by Mark Zuckerberg in February 2004, initially as an exclusive network for Harvard students. It...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="profile-image"&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/facebook"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;a class="learn-more" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/facebook" onclick="s_objectID='post_widget_crunchbase';"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style="clear: both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/410375/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;div class="sharedaddy"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZppC4tB1pvT-woggcWUl5RqkREA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZppC4tB1pvT-woggcWUl5RqkREA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZppC4tB1pvT-woggcWUl5RqkREA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ZppC4tB1pvT-woggcWUl5RqkREA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Znbn7ZoLSGk:FxgrlhSTTpU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Znbn7ZoLSGk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/23/facebook-location-tagging/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/23/facebook-location-tagging/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flickr: alextoul's stuff tagged with allinone</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://www.flickr.com/photos/magnifyk/</link>
      <guid>http://www.flickr.com/photos/magnifyk/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greg Kot Tweets from SXSW | Follow Kot on his blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/#!/gregkot</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/#!/gregkot</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Adds Friend Annotations to the +1 Button</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/&amp;title=Google Adds Friend Annotations to the +1 Button&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/plus-one-button-640.png"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google is making the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/06/01/google-plus-one-button-2/"&gt;+1 Button&lt;/a&gt; more social with the addition of friend annotations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;You may have already noticed faces and names when you hover over a +1 button,&amp;#8221; Google Developer Advocate Timothy Jordan said in a post on the Google+ Platform preview. &amp;#8220;This change rolled out late last week. Now, you can make these recommendations even more visible to your users. Simply update the +1 button code, and an inline annotation will show next to the button.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The new annotations appear when a user hovers over the +1 button. Hovering over it will display a list of friends and contacts that have already clicked the +1 button for that page. Google has also unveiled new code for the +1 button that will display the faces and names of friends that have used the +1 button. This feature works much like how the Facebook Like Button appears for &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; stories, displaying how many people have +1&amp;#8242;d the page and which friends have +1ed it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The changes are small, but they will likely make the +1 button even more sticky. The search giant will need to do more though to compete with Facebook&amp;#8217;s button, which has become standard on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/04/21/facebook-like-button-one/"&gt;millions of websites&lt;/a&gt; across the world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Picture-7.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/centeR&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google-1/"&gt;Google +1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google-1-button/"&gt;Google +1 Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/pRlaGpiU6LvwvgFRAVB3Ic34Sq4/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/pRlaGpiU6LvwvgFRAVB3Ic34Sq4/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/pRlaGpiU6LvwvgFRAVB3Ic34Sq4/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/pRlaGpiU6LvwvgFRAVB3Ic34Sq4/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Pz6f4SuUM8E:soclvoiUBCU:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/Pz6f4SuUM8E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/23/google-button-friend-annotations/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's the earthquake map, east-coasters: http://t.co/hGVa7Eb</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a0.twimg.com/profile_images/393816089/tweet_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lisa_beebe"&gt;Lisa Beebe&lt;/a&gt;: Here's the earthquake map, east-coasters: &lt;a href="http://t.co/hGVa7Eb" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/hGVa7Eb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/lisa_beebe/status/69399531"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Retweeted by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/NickelodeonTV"&gt;Nickelodeon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/recenteqsww/Quakes/usc0005ild.html</link>
      <guid>http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/recenteqsww/Quakes/usc0005ild.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Software Is Eating the World</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Far from a bubble, we're watching a new generation of tech start-ups realize the Web's original potential, says Marc Andreessen.</description>
      <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460.html?mod=WSJ_GoogleNews</link>
      <guid>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460.html?mod=WSJ_GoogleNews</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind scenes, meticulous preparations under way - Associated Press</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; LONDON (AP) -- Fifty days and counting down. Behind the scenes hundreds are hard at work to make sure the April 29 royal wedding is a day to remember - not just for Prince William and Kate Middleton, but for the country. As the date nears, the machinery that makes a British royal event look, smell</description>
      <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</link>
      <guid>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>xkcd I love you #earthquake #Philly http://t.co/dh7Ezbr</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/712960374/monkey_normal.JPG" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/monkeycageblog"&gt;The Monkey Cage&lt;/a&gt;: USGS link: &lt;a href="http://t.co/y9jmFYi" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/y9jmFYi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/monkeycageblog/status/116630713"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Retweeted by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/tracilawson"&gt;Traci Lawson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/recenteqsus/Maps/US10/32.42.-85.-75_eqs.php</link>
      <guid>http://earthquake.usgs.gov/earthquakes/recenteqsus/Maps/US10/32.42.-85.-75_eqs.php</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
