<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Is No Joke at This Year&#8217;s Comedy Awards</title>
      <description>The Comedy Awards is the baby of the awards show ceremonies &#8212; only two years old. But the show&#8217;s huge digital and social presence keeps pace with the big boys. The event airs Sunday night at 9 p.m. ET/PT on Comedy Central, but it was taped last Saturday. Mashable had the opportunity to attend. Among traditional categories like &#8220;Best Comedy Film,&#8221; &#8220;Best Performance&#8221; and &#8220;Club Comic,&#8221; there are a number of digital categories: &#8220;Funniest Person on Twitter,&#8221; &#8220;Best Remix, Mash-Up or Supercut,&#8221; &#8220;Best Comedy App&#8221; and &#8220;Best Comedy Podcast.&#8221; The digital categories are viewers&#8217; choice, and voters can select their favorite nominee online. (The &#8220;Best Viral Original&#8221; was part of last year&#8217;s categories, and also viewers&#8217; choice.) There are also tinges of the web scattered throughout the show &#8212; most of presenter Andy Richter&#8217;s jokes are about social media montioring, and there&#8217;s a pretty hilarious moment when the &#8220;honey badger guy&#8221; documents Richter eating a sandwich. Zach Galifianakis&#8217; comedy web series Between Two Ferns will make an appearance on television for the first time, serving as a precursor to the awards show. Social media was a big topic of the evening. Nearly every comedian who entered the press room was asked about their presence (or lack thereof) on Twitter. The response was mostly supportive of the tool, or that they were so high profile they didn&#8217;t need social media. &#8220;Twitter seems like a nightmare to me,&#8221; Amy Poehler told the press backstage. &#8220;That just seems like a mistake waiting to happen.&#8221; Robin Williams, who was honored with the Stand-Up Icon Award, admitted to giving up on Twitter after sending one tweet. He compared seeing comedy live in a small venue to &#8220;seeing jazz,&#8221; claiming that those moments are not documentable, and that we need to live it when it happens. On the other hand, comedians like Key and Peele rely heavily on social media. Their show has an engaged audience online, and they admitted to using that feedback for future episodes. &#8220;In this day and age, it&#8217;s OK to have that dialogue,&#8221; says Peele. &#8220;It&#8217;s all evolving &#8212; we all know this is the way it&#8217;s going to be, and it&#8217;s moving so fast.&#8221; The awards show, which is hosted by Comedy Central, is one of the most socially engaged pushes from the network. By partnering with GetGlue and Viggle, viewers tuning in with their mobile device in hand will get exclusive stickers and extra points for checking in to the show. Make sure to check in to the #ComedyAwards tonight on @GetGlue and earn the exclusive sticker: ow.ly/aI7lg &#8212; The Comedy Awards (@TheComedyAwards) May 6, 2012 Social and digital technology have become an integral part of programming, and it&#8217;s no wonder the big winner at the Comedy Awards this year was FX. Louie won for &#8220;Best Sketch/Alternative Comedy Series&#8221; and &#8220;Best Comedy Directing &#8212; TV,&#8221; and Archer took home &#8220;Best Animated Comedy Series,&#8221; beating out The Simpsons, Family Guy and South Park. FX has made a significant push for social TV with its programming &#8212; including Archer, in which they partnered with GetGlue on an app that gives fans stickers for playing a spy-themed game and checking in. There&#8217;s also a second-screen app for the show, built in HTML5. Louis CK won &#8220;Best Stand-Up Tour&#8221; and &#8220;Best Comedy Special.&#8221; After the success of his digitally distributed special, he&#8217;ll bring it to television for the first time on FX. The 42-minute televised version will also run commercials for the website. &#8220;I love FX, I&#8217;m very grateful to them &#8212; so I thought they&#8217;ve never had a comedy special on, and it might be kind of cool to let them get a crack at it,&#8221; says CK. Were you surprised by the winners this year? Do you think social and digital media play a role in their success? Let us know in the comments. More About: Between Two Ferns, comedy, comedy awards, Comedy Central, Entertainment, features, louis ck, zach galifianakisFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/comedy-awards-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/comedy-awards-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollande 'wins French presidency'</title>
      <description>Socialist Francois Hollande has been elected as France's new president, early estimates say, in a vote that has wide implications for the eurozone.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-17975660</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-17975660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Tech Is Changing College Life [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>College students today are more tech savvy than ever before. Just how important is technology to their academic lives? More than 90% use email to communicate with professors and 73% say they cannot study without technology. Seven in 10 take notes on keyboards instead of paper, virtually all students who own an ereader and most use digital tools when preparing a presentation. All that tech has caused something of a dependency too &#8212; 38% of students can&#8217;t go more than 10 minutes without checking their smartphone or other device. All told, students spent $13 billion on electronics in 2009. Community college students are less digitally connected than students at four-year schools, but more and more people are making the Internet their education gateway. Twelve million students take at least one class online today &#8212; in five years, that number is projected to exceed 22 million. By 2014, analysts say, more than 3.5 million students will take all of their classes online. This is all according to research compiled by Presta Electronics. Presta used material from the Pew Research Center, Chronicle of Higher Education, Mashable and other sources to put together the infographic below. Check it out for the full picture of how technology is changing college students&#8217; lives. Do you think technology is changing college for the better &#8212; or are there downsides? More About: education, infographics, Social Media, TechFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/tech-college-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/tech-college-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FBI Wants Wiretap-Ready Social Networks Soon [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>The Federal Bureau of Investigation wants to make Facebook and other social networks easier to use for spying on suspected criminals &#8212; and it wants access ASAP. High-ranking FBI officials and other government representatives have been meeting with Internet industry leaders to ask them not to oppose a proposed law that would give federal agencies backdoor access to social networking sites, CNET reports. The FBI&#8217;s argument? As communication has shifted more and more online, previous laws allowing wiretaps on phone lines are becoming less and less useful. FBI lawyers have reportedly drafted a proposal that if passed into law would require social networking sites to rework their code for easier surveillance. It would also apply to instant messaging, VoIP and email providers that exceed a certain number of users. The proposal would update the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (CALEA) of 1994. That legislation originally applied to telecommunications providers, requiring them to provide back-end loopholes enabling easier access for law enforcement to spy on suspected criminals. In 2004, CALEA was expanded to include broadband networks as well. Expanding CALEA again to apply to services such as Gmail, Skype and Facebook would help the FBI address a worry that senior bureau officials dubbed as far back as 2008 as &#8220;Going Dark.&#8221; The name encapsulates a theory that as communication technologies continue to advance FBI surveillance capability will struggle to keep pace. Do you think social networks and other digital communication services should be required to code with FBI surveillance concerns in mind? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of Flickr, jaxxon More About: Facebook, FBI, privacy, security, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/fbi-wiretap-social-networks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/fbi-wiretap-social-networks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREAKING: Joe Biden Endorses Same-Sex Marriage</title>
      <description>Vice President Joe Biden has endorsed same-sex marriage, becoming the highest ranking American official to back marriage for gay and lesbian people. His comments signify a split within the Obama administration and may pave the way for President Obama &#8212; who says he supports civil unions and is still evolving on the matter &#8212; to also embrace equality. Biden made his remarks during an appearance on Meet the Press, telling host David Gregory that he is &#8220;absolute comfortable with the fact that men marrying men, women marrying women.&#8221; He added, however, that &#8220;the President sets the policy.&#8221; Biden has backed equal rights for the LGBT community throughout his career, but this is the first time he has publicly acknowledged his support of full marriage rights. In December of 2010, Biden predicted, &#8220;I think the country&#8217;s evolving and I think there&#8217;s an inevitability for a national consensus on gay marriage.&#8221; But when asked if he supports gay marriage during the 2008 Vice Presidential debate Biden was far more circumspect, saying, &#8220;No. Barack Obama nor I support redefining from a civil side what constitutes marriage. We do not support that.&#8221; He even sought common ground with Sarah Palin on the issue and noted that both believe that &#8220;there should be no civil rights distinction, none whastsoever between a committed gay couple and a committed heterosexual couple.&#8221; Since that performance, the administration has touted its accomplishments on behalf of the LGBT community &#8212; from the repeal of Don&#8217;t Ask, Don&#8217;t Tell to its refusal to defend the 1996 Defense of Marriage Act. Yet Biden&#8217;s support for marriage could solidify the support of the LGBT community &#8212; many of whom have recently expressed outrage over Obama&#8217;s unwillingness to issue an executive order prohibiting employment discrimination in federal contracting &#8212; just ahead of the 2012 election. Obama first told blogger Joe Sudbay that &#8220;attitudes evolve [on marriage equality] including mine&#8221; in October of 2010 and the administration last commented on his position during a press gaggle on March 30, 2012. &#8220;I don&#8217;t anticipate that the President would make news on [marriage equality],&#8221; Press Deputy Josh Earnest told a reporter en route to Burlington, Vermont when asked about Obama&#8217;s &#8220;evolving position.&#8221; Gay and lesbian couples can wed in six states and the District of Columbia. Washington and Maryland both passed same-sex marriage laws in 2012, but they are currently being challenged by voter referenda.</description>
      <link>http://thinkprogress.org/lgbt/2012/05/06/478786/biden-marriage/?mobile=nc</link>
      <guid>http://thinkprogress.org/lgbt/2012/05/06/478786/biden-marriage/?mobile=nc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is This Censorship? Facebook Stops You From Posting &#226;&#8364;&#732;Irrelevant Or Inappropriate&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Comments</title>
      <description>Colleen Taylor / TechCrunch:Is This Censorship? Facebook Stops You From Posting &#8216;Irrelevant Or Inappropriate&#8217; Comments &#8212; Today was just another Saturday morning in blog land when Robert Scoble, the well-known tech startup enthusiast, went to post a comment on a Facebook post written by Carnegie Mellon student &#8230;</description>
      <link>http://www.techmeme.com/120505/p10</link>
      <guid>http://www.techmeme.com/120505/p10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pair vs. Pair: Pair The App Is Getting Sued By Pair Networks, The Hosting Company</title>
      <description>It was less than a week ago that Tenthbit, the developers of the buzzy, new social-networking-app-for-couples (or other partners) Pair, picked up a $4.2 million seed round, money the founders said would be used to expand its mobile development and design teams. Now it looks like some of those funds might also need to go to legal bills. Tenthbit is getting sued by pair Networks, a hosting and domain registration company based in Pittsburgh, for trademark infringement. Tenthbit, meanwhile, has also sued pair Networks, to prevent the other suit from going ahead. Pair Networks is asking for an injunction on Pair the app, as well as &#8220;other relief as this Court deems appropriate.&#8221; Tenthbit argues the two do not compete directly, and would therefore not result in any brand confusion. While trademark cases can be a dime a dozen &#8212; and there is no guarantee of how this one will fall &#8212; this one is interesting for a few reasons: One is that it pits a startup working at the forefront of mobile social networking, against the kind of Internet company that has been around for years and is not so much about disruption as it is about making the internet work like it&#8217;s supposed to. Another is that this old-school Internet company has apparently taken others to court for the same reason &#8212; and won. And there a couple of other twists to this story, as you&#8217;ll see below. Tenthbit&#8217;s case against pair Networks was filed first, in a U.S. District Court in the District of Northern California, San Jose, on April 6 in an apparent attempt to stop pair Networks from filing its own case. That didn&#8217;t seem to work, and pair Networks filed its own case against Tenthbit in a Federal court in Pennsylvania on April 27. Both suits are embedded below. Pair Networks alleges in its suit that Tenthbit &#8220;doubly infringes&#8221; on pair Network&#8217;s trademark through both the use of the brand &#8220;Pair&#8221; as well as its URL, www.trypair.com. Pair Networks says that it has spent &#8220;substantial amounts of time, effort, and money&#8221; to ensure that the public associates the Pair family of marks (these include pair.com, pair.net, and pair.org, among others) with its own company. Pair Networks, founded in 1998, offers its services both in the U.S. as well as internationally and claims to be one of the world&#8217;s biggest privately-held hosting companies. It says it delivers more than one billion Web hits per day via its servers. Pair the app, meanwhile, has seen over 220,000 downloads since it went live in the app store a month ago. Pair Networks says that it has been policing for the use of its name by Internet-related companies for years now, and cites three different examples in its complaint where courts have ruled in its favor in other trademark infringement cases. For its part, Tenthbit maintains that it is not in the same business as pair Networks &#8212; with a consumer mobile app being on the opposite end of the Internet spectrum from offering hosting and domain registration services to websites. &#8220;It is axiomatic and commonplace that the same word may be used as a trademark by different parties provided that such use does not create a likelihood of confusion on the part of relevant consumers,&#8221; the app makers&#8217; lawyers, Orrick, Herrington and Sutcliffe, write in response to the infringement claims. There are a few other eyebrow-raising points in pair Networks&#8217; complaint against Tenthbit: Pair Networks claims that its reputation is being damaged because Pair the app is associated with &#8220;explicit adult activity&#8221; like &#8220;sexting.&#8221; (The suit doesn&#8217;t mention the spinoffs that Pair has spawned, such as PairMixer, which helps you find someone to pair with on the app if you are unattached.) Weird coincidence: Pair Networks claims that Tenthbit possibly already knew about pair Networks when it had registered its own domain as trypair.com because it turns out that among the companies hosted by pair Networks is Y Combinator, the incubator where Tenthbit created and launched Pair. Y Combinator used pair Networks for hosting for at least six years. Pair Networks is asking to get all the profits that Tenthbit will have made from Pair the app. (It&#8217;s a free app, with no revenue-generating services incorporated into it at this point.) The cases are due to be heard later this year. We have reached out to Pair, pair Networks and their legal teams for further comment. Pair&#8217;s $4.2-million seed funding round, announced on May 1, came from an A-list of angels that included Ashton Kutcher&#8217;s A-Grade Ventures, Dave Morin, Paul Buchheit, Founder Collective, SV Angel, Lerer Ventures, Michael Birch, Sam Altman, CrunchFund, Tencent, Yuri Milner,Betaworks, Alexis Ohanian, Garry Tan, Harjeet Taggar, Gary Vaynerchuk, Brandee Barker, Brian Pokorny, Elad Gil, and Susan Wu. View this document on Scribd View this document on Scribd</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/05/pair-vs-pair-pair-the-app-is-getting-sued-by-pair-networks-the-hosting-company/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/05/pair-vs-pair-pair-the-app-is-getting-sued-by-pair-networks-the-hosting-company/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Post by Sex Offender Scares Away Star Football Prospect</title>
      <description>Players tweeting irresponsibly. Embarrassing photos. Unwanted news leaks. Now you can add a new item to the list of ways social media can be a headache for sports teams &#8212; unsavory characters scaring away potential stars. That&#8217;s what happened at Ohio State University, where a lauded high school football recruit de-committed from the school after a convicted sex offender posted photos he took with him on Twitter. Alex Anzalone of Wyomissing, Pa., is one of the mostly highly rated high school linebackers in the country and had pledged to play in college at Ohio State. During a campus visit last month, according to the Associated Press, Anzalone posed for a photograph with an apparent fan named Charles Eric Waugh. Waugh later posted the photo to Twitter and used the network to contact other Ohio State players, recruits and coaches. Hardcore college sports fans frequently use Twitter and Facebook to tell hotshot recruits how great they&#8217;d look in their school&#8217;s colors. The problem here? Waugh, who is 31 years old and reportedly lives in Ashland, Kentucky, pleaded guilty in 2008 to five counts of possession of underage sexual content. &#8220;You don&#8217;t want your son to go to a place where there&#8217;s a potential issue,&#8221; Anzalone&#8217;s father told the Reading Eagle on Saturday. &#8220;You expect the staff to have some sort of control on how things are handled with recruits when they visit. This is ridiculous.&#8221; Ohio State released a statement in which it said the episode was symptomatic of social media&#8217;s power to enable wide-ranging and unexpected connections, and sent a cautionary email message out to more than 1,000 student athletes. &#8220;The email message also reminded them of the negative implications that can be realized through simple associations on social networking sites,&#8221; the school&#8217;s statement read. &#8220;This individual is not associated with Ohio State. He is not a booster. He has not engaged in any activities on behalf of the University. The Department of Athletics will continue to monitor this issue and it will remain proactive in its efforts with regard to precautions for its student-athletes.&#8221; Is it fair to blame a school if creepy fans contact athletes via social media? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy Scallop Holden, Flickr. More About: Social Media, sports, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/twitter-ohio-state-football-prospect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/twitter-ohio-state-football-prospect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Post by Sex Offender Scares Away Star Football Prospect</title>
      <description>Players tweeting irresponsibly. Embarrassing photos. Unwanted news leaks. Now you can add a new item to the list of ways social media can be a headache for sports teams &#8212; unsavory characters scaring away potential stars. That&#8217;s what happened at Ohio State University, where a lauded high school football recruit de-committed from the school after a convicted sex offender posted photos he took with him on Twitter. Alex Anzalone of Wyomissing, Pa., is one of the mostly highly rated high school linebackers in the country and had pledged to play in college at Ohio State. During a campus visit last month, according to the Associated Press, Anzalone posed for a photograph with an apparent fan named Charles Eric Waugh. Waugh later posted the photo to Twitter and used the network to contact other Ohio State players, recruits and coaches. Hardcore college sports fans frequently use Twitter and Facebook to tell hotshot recruits how great they&#8217;d look in their school&#8217;s colors. The problem here? Waugh, who is 31 years old and reportedly lives in Ashland, Kentucky, pleaded guilty in 2008 to five counts of possession of underage sexual content. &#8220;You don&#8217;t want your son to go to a place where there&#8217;s a potential issue,&#8221; Anzalone&#8217;s father told the Reading Eagle on Saturday. &#8220;You expect the staff to have some sort of control on how things are handled with recruits when they visit. This is ridiculous.&#8221; Ohio State released a statement in which it said the episode was symptomatic of social media&#8217;s power to enable wide-ranging and unexpected connections, and sent a cautionary email message out to more than 1,000 student athletes. &#8220;The email message also reminded them of the negative implications that can be realized through simple associations on social networking sites,&#8221; the school&#8217;s statement read. &#8220;This individual is not associated with Ohio State. He is not a booster. He has not engaged in any activities on behalf of the University. The Department of Athletics will continue to monitor this issue and it will remain proactive in its efforts with regard to precautions for its student-athletes.&#8221; Is it fair to blame a school if creepy fans contact athletes via social media? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy Scallop Holden, Flickr. More About: Social Media, sports, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/twitter-ohio-state-football-prospect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/06/twitter-ohio-state-football-prospect/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
