<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Tech This Week [PICS]</title>
      <description>1. Brydge to Somewhere This is not the first iPad keyboard case I've seen, but Brydge for iPad comes the closest to simulating a laptop when you partially surround your beloved tablet with its aerospace-grade aluminum. Its keyboard is just about close enough to get Apple's lawsuit lawyers fired up, and once you place the iPad into its hinge-like maw, you can tilt the screen back just like a laptop.Click here to view this gallery. We found a boatload of spectacular tech from which to choose this week, and strangely enough, futuristic and fascinating devices seemed to be coming at us in pairs. What do we mean by that? We found a pair of bridges, one for an iPad and one for computers, a pair of inventions that involve passive cooling, a couple of items that involve vapor in mysterious ways, a pair of high-tech pins, and then two speedy conveyances that both relate in some way to Ferrari. SEE ALSO: Previous editions of Top 10 Tech This Week Confused? Don&#8217;t be &#8212; you&#8217;ll love what we&#8217;ve discovered this week, finding only the coolest and most worthy technological advances, designs and products for your perusal, right here on Top 10 Tech This Week. Here&#8217;s last week&#8217;s Top 10 Tech. More About: green tech, Ivy Bridge, kickstarter, Top 10 Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/top-10-tech-this-week-27/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/top-10-tech-this-week-27/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Startups Using Tech To Do Good</title>
      <description>In our social entrepreneurship series, The World at Work, Mashable interviews the faces behind the startups and projects that are working to make a global impact. By harnessing the power of digital technology, these five companies have altered commonplace models such as crowdfunding and toy development to change the world for the better. While the companies are diverse, they share a common thread: A passionate leader who&#8217;s devoted to improving lives. Here&#8217;s a roundup of featured projects from the last week, including exclusive video interviews with the founders of these innovative startups. To read more and watch the videos, click through to the full story, and follow the series to learn about more breakthrough companies. 1. Skillshare Big Idea: Skillshare provides an online hub for people to sign up to teach or attend offline classes. Why It&#8217;s Working: Skillshare allows anyone to teach a class &#8212; and make money while doing so. Users choose to learn topics in five main categories at very little cost: creative arts, culinary arts, entrepreneurship, lifestyle and technology. Read the full story here. 2. Indiegogo Big Idea: Indiegogo is a crowdfunding platform that also helps users amplify their project through a special &#8220;gogofactor.&#8221; The more traction a campaign gains, the more eyes will see it. Why It&#8217;s Working: Indiegogo relies on &#8220;user democracy&#8221; &#8212; anybody can raise money for anything, and the power of the funders help dictate what catches fire and ends up on the website&#8217;s homepage. The result is that those looking for funding can reach new audiences to help get their work realized. Read the full story and see the video here. 3. Love With Food Big Idea: Love With Food is asubscription-based online food gourmet delivery service that sends tasty morsels directly to your door. For every box of treats it delivers, Love With Food donates an equivalent amount of money to a local food bank. Why It&#8217;s Working: Smaller food producers often have trouble affording marketing and distribution services, and one in every five American children are going hungry. Love With Food is helping to solve both of those problems in one fell swoop. Read the full story here. 4. Zaarly Big Idea: Zaarly is a marketplace for anything &#8212; whether you want to send your wife flowers, have someone bring you dinner or need someone to mow your lawn. Sellers are hiring locally and keeping money within the community, while providers are putting money in their pockets. Why It&#8217;s Working: Zaarly enables anyone to become an entrepreneur &#8212; whether you want to pick up some extra cash or be a full-time Zaarly user, the platform empowers people in Zaarly markets to get things done. And if you&#8217;re a small business that needs a little bit of help doing errands or filing paperwork, there&#8217;s an eager person waiting for you on Zaarly. Read the full story and see the video here. 5. Jerry the Bear Big Idea: Jerry the Bear is a robotic teddy bear that &#8220;has&#8221; diabetes. Children are able to take care of Jerry by checking his blood glucose levels, giving him &#8220;insulin shots&#8221; and &#8220;feeding&#8221; him a variety of foods. Why It&#8217;s Working: Targeted specifically to children living with type 1 diabetes, Jerry helps sick kids not only learn about the procedures that are performed on them daily but also empowers them to understand the importance of symptom-checking and self-care. Read the full story here. What do you think of the efforts of these startups and foundations? Let us know in the comments below. More About: features, mashable, World at WorkFor more Social Good coverage:Follow Mashable Social Good on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Good channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/world-at-work-5/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/world-at-work-5/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 specialist (and super smart) search engines</title>
      <description>Google is widely (and rightly) recognised as the mother of all search engines. But, if you need to drill down your searches by more specific details, do you trust Google to give you what you need every single time? Here&#8217;s a collection of 3o vertical search engines which you should have up your sleeve when you need some specialist power. Flights / Travel 1. SkyScanner.net &#8211; The leading flights search engine, providing information about all carriers to help you find the best deal. 2. Momondo.com &#8211; Very similar to SkyScanner and with an added &#8216;current searches&#8217; widget to see what flights other people are searching for. (Particularly handy in Europe!) 3. Hipmunk - The San Francisco-based startup that&#8217;s swiftly revolutionizing trip-planning for savvy travelers with flights, trains and hotel search. Blogs 4. IceRocket.com &#8211; Searches for content from blogs, Twitter, Facebook and more. 5. BlogPulse.com &#8211; Blog-specific search engine searching through more than 170 million blogs. 6. eBuzzing Labs - The top blogs section is a great place to start a topic-specific blogs and content. Images 7. TinEye.com &#8211; a reverse image search engine &#8211; this finds out where an image came from, how it&#8217;s being used and where you can find the best resolution version. 8. PicSearch.com &#8211; Searches through more than 3 billion online photos. People 9. Pipl.com &#8211; Search for people all over the world from a simple interface. 10. 123people.com &#8211; Aggregates public information from a number of sources to give a spread of person-specific information. Forums 11. BoardReader.com &#8211; The best free discussion board and forum search tool out there. Music 12. MixTurtle.com &#8211; Basic music search engine by artist and / or song title. 13. SongBoxx.com &#8211; Search over 7,000,000 tracks from the one location. 14. Music-Map.com &#8211; Type in your favourite artist and then a map of similar artists will be returned (very cool). 15. AudioGalaxy.com &#8211; Search for and save your playlists in the cloud from this very slick site. Audio and Video 16. PodScope.com &#8211; The web&#8217;s leading podcast search directory. 17. Blinkx.com &#8211; Search over 35 million hours of video. Resources 18. SlideFinder.net -Instead of starting a new presentation slide from scratch, see if the one you need is here. 19. FileDigg.com &#8211; Search for files by type e.g. .ppt and .pdf etc. Domain names 20. Panabee.com &#8211; A great way to search for website domain names and generate names if you are struggling for ideas. [Also, read this before naming your startup.] 21. NameNinja.com &#8211; Another brainstorming tool to discover domain names. Icons 22. Iconfinder.com &#8211; Great for finding different file versions e.g. .png and .ico. 23. Iconseeker.com &#8211; A standard icon search engine. 24. IconArchive.com &#8211; One of the most comprehensive icon search engines on the web, includes really useful sub-category search. Private search 25. DuckDuckGo.com &#8211; This engine allows you to search for sites without bring tracked at the other end. Similar websites 26. SimilarSites.com &#8211; Search for sites similar to the ones you love in a simple way. All-rounders 27. Blekko.com &#8211; Uses &#8216;slashtagging&#8217; to narrow down your results. 28. KeoTag.com &#8211; Tag search multiple search engines for the latest content. 29. Scour.com &#8211; A social search community. 30. Greplin.com &#8211; Another social search engine with desktop capability. While some of these are better alternatives to Google and the other major engines, for the most part, the big boys do it incredibly (incredibly, incredibly) well. olly via shutterstock</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/lifehacks/2012/04/29/30-specialist-and-super-smart-search-engines/</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/lifehacks/2012/04/29/30-specialist-and-super-smart-search-engines/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Funniest &#8216;Animals Being Dicks&#8217; [GIFS]</title>
      <description>Here at Mashable we sometimes get a brain itch that can only be scratched by watching copious amounts of hilarious animal GIFs. If you suffer from the same ailment, let us point you in the direction of Animals Being Dicks, a place on the Internet where it&#8217;s okay to laugh at our furry friends. The premise is simple: Animals are perfectly capable of cretinous behavior, and celebrating their wretchedness is a truly funny pastime. We asked creator and curator John Williams why he thought his Tumblr blog hit the nail on the humor head. &#8220;People like to imagine human traits in animals, and I think this idea that animals have the capacity to be petty assholes on purpose is hilarious,&#8221; he says. &#8220;That&#8217;s why most of the animals have people names like Rick or Janice. Also, my dad used to name all his pets distinctly human names. We had a dog named Dan.&#8221; SEE ALSO: First World Problems: 14 Cringe-Worthy Complaints We asked Williams to curate his top 12 Animals Being Dicks GIFs. You can see his selections &#8212; along with his commentary &#8212; in the gallery below. Let us know in the comments below your go-to place online for animal-themed chortles. 1. Purrkour "It's the toes on this one that do it for me." Click here to view this gallery. Thumbnail image courtesy of Flickr, Ryan M. More About: features, gallery, humor, trending, tumblrFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/best-animals-being-dicks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/best-animals-being-dicks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Science</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: This guest post was written by Richard Price, founder and CEO of Academia.edu &#8212; a site that serves as a platform for academics to share their research papers and to interact with each other. Almost every technological and medical innovation in the world has its roots in a scientific paper. Science drives much of the world&#8217;s innovation. The faster science moves, the faster the world moves. Progress in science right now is being held back by two key inefficiencies: The time-lag problem: there is a time-lag of, on average, 12 months between finishing a paper, and it being published. The single mode of publication problem: scientists share their ideas only via one format, the scientific paper, and don&#8217;t take advantage of the full range of media that the web makes possible. The stakes are high. If these inefficiencies can be removed, science would accelerate tremendously. A faster science would lead to faster innovation in medicine and technology. Cancer could be cured 2-3 years sooner than it otherwise would be, which would save millions of lives. The time-lag problem The first major inefficiency is the time-lag problem for distributing scientific ideas. After you have written a scientific paper, it takes, on average, 12 months for the paper to be distributed to the global scientific community. During that time the paper is going through the peer review process, which takes an extremely long time. If you read a paper, and have some thoughts about it, and write up a response, it is going to take 12 months for your response to be seen by the global scientific community. Science is fundamentally a conversation between scientists around the world. Currently the intervals between iterations of that conversation are 12 months on average. This 12 month time-lag represents a huge amount of friction in the circulation of scientific ideas. Imagine the slowdown on the web if every blog post, and every tweet, and every photo, was made available on the web 12 months after it was originally posted. Imagine if all the stories in your Facebook News Feed were 12 months old. People would be storming the steps of Congress, demanding change. The time-lag in the distribution of scientific ideas is significantly holding back science. It&#8217;s critical for global progress that we work to remove this inefficiency. The single mode of publication problem Historically, if a scientist wants to make a contribution to the scientific body of knowledge, it has to be in the form of a scientific paper. Blogging hasn&#8217;t taken off in science, because scientists don&#8217;t get credit for writing blog posts. You often hear a scientist saying &#8216;I&#8217;m not going to put these ideas in a blog post, because they are good enough for me to incorporate into a paper, which I&#8217;ll publish in the next couple of years&#8217;. Everyone loses out because of that delay of a couple of years. Most people who share information on the web have taken advantage of the rich media that the web provides. People share information in all kinds of forms: videos, status updates, blog posts, blog comments, data sets, interactive graphs, and other forms. By contrast, if a scientist wants to share some information on a protein that they are working on, they have to write a paper with a set of two dimensional black and white images of that protein. The norms don&#8217;t encourage the sharing of an interactive, full-color, 3 dimensional model of the protein, even if that would be a more suitable media format for the kind of knowledge that is being shared. The future of science: instant distribution Tim Berners-Lee invented the web in order to make it easier for him and his colleagues to share their research papers. The web has impacted science, but over the next few years, the web is going to entirely re-invent the way that scientists interact. In 5-10 years&#8217; time, the way scientists will communicate will be unrecognizable from the way that they have been communicating for the last 400 years, when the first academic journal was founded. The first change will be instant distribution for all scientific ideas. Some sites, such as arXiv, Academia.edu, Mendeley, and ResearchGate have brought instant distribution to certain sub-fields of science recently, and this trend is going to continue to all fields of science. In a few years, scientists will look back and will struggle to believe that they used to exist in a world where it took 12 months to circulate a scientific idea around the world. Discussing the idea of 12 month distribution delays for ideas will produce the same confused look that it produces today, when one asks someone to conceive of 12 month distribution delays to tweets, blog posts, and general web content. Instant distribution means bringing the time-lag for distributing a scientific paper around the world down to 1 day, or less. This speed-up will have a transformative effect on the rate of scientific progress in the world. Discoveries will be made much more quickly. One of the reasons that technological progress in the 20th century was so much greater than growth in previous centuries is that there were so many powerful communication technologies invented in the 20th century that connected people around the globe: the telephone, the TV, the internet. Bringing instant distribution to science will have a similarly transformative effect on scientific progress. The future of science: rich media Historically scientists have written their papers as native desktop content. They have saved their papers as PDFs, and uploaded the files to the web. Over the next few years, scientific content will increasingly become native web content, and be written natively for the web. Scientific content will be created with the full interactivity, and richness, of the web in mind. Most papers are downloaded from the web, and printed out by scientists for reading. The content was written in such a way that it&#8217;s fully readable in print-out form. Most web content is inherently rich. No-one prints out their Twitter and Facebook News Feeds to read them, or blog posts. The idea of printing out content doesn&#8217;t make sense for much of the web&#8217;s content, such as YouTube videos, Facebook photos, interactive maps, and interactive graphs such as those on you find on Quantcast, or Yahoo Finance. The hyperlink itself is a piece of interactivity built into web content. One reason you don&#8217;t want to print out a Wikipedia article to read it is that the page is full of useful links, and you want to be adjacent to that interactivity when reading the article to take advantage of the full power of the article. Historically, scientific papers have cited other papers, but those citations are not hyper-linked. To citizens of the web, the idea of referring to some other page without linking to it seems an impossibly old-fashioned way of sharing content. Imagine reading a blog, or a Facebook News Feed, where there were no links, and everything was plain text. Instead, there was a set of references at the end of the page, and those references told you were to find certain other pages on the web, but the references weren&#8217;t themselves hyperlinked. A citation to a video would something like &#8220;YouTube.com, Comedy section, page 10, &#8220;Coke bottle exploding&#8221;, video id = 34883&#8221;. You would then have to go to YouTube and navigate to the right section to get the video that has that title. This experience would indeed be a nightmare. The difference between that, and how the web currently is, is the difference between where scientific communication is right now, and where it will be in a few years, when scientists fully adopt the rich media of the web. Scientists will share content in whatever format makes sense for the piece of content in question. They will share ideas in the form of data sets, videos, 3-d models, software programs, graphs, blog posts, status updates, and comments on all these rich media. The ways that these content formats will connect with each other will be via the hyperlink, and not via the citation. The citation will look like an ancient concept in a few years. Science is undergoing one of the most exciting changes in its history. It is in a transition period between a pre-web form of communication to a natively web form of communication. The full adoption of the web by scientists will transform science. Scientists will start to interact and communicate in wonderful new ways that will have an enormous effect on scientific progress. The future of science: peer review In a world of instant distribution, what happens to peer review? Will this be a world where junk gets published, and no-one will be able to tell whether a particular piece of content is good or bad? I wrote a post on TechCrunch a few weeks ago called &#8220;The Future of Peer Review&#8221;, arguing that the web has an instant distribution model, and has thrived. I argued that the web&#8217;s main discovery engines for content on the web, namely search engines, and social networks, are at their heart, evolved peer review systems. These web-scale peer review systems, search engines and social networks, already drive most discovery of scientific content. The future of science: academic credit Historically scientists have gained credit by publishing in prestigious journals. Hiring committees, and grant committees, historically have looked at the kinds of journals a scientist has managed to get published in as a measure of the quality of the scientist&#8217;s work. In the last few years, such committees have also started to look at citation counts too. As scientific content moves to become native web content, scientific content will increasingly be evaluated according to the kinds of metrics that reflect the success of a piece of content on the web. Web metrics vary, and evolve. Some are internet-wide metrics, such as unique visitors, page views, time on site. Others are specific to certain verticals, or sites, such as Twitter follower counts, StackOverflow score, Facebook likes, and YouTube video views. As these metrics are increasingly understood in the context of scientific content, scientists will increasingly share content that attracts this kind of credit. If you can share a data-set, and collect credit for it, you will. If you can comment on a paper, and collect credit for it, you will do that too. If sharing a video of a process is more compelling than having black and white images of the process, videos will take off. Directing Silicon Valley&#8217;s resources towards accelerating science Science is in the process of being re-built and transformed. It is going to be an exhilarating process. The positive impact to society will be significant. The next wave of science is not being built by scientific publishers. It is being built by engineering-focused, Silicon Valley tech companies. It is being built by talented and visionary engineering and product teams. Silicon Valley&#8217;s formidable resources are starting to turn in the direction of science, having been focused for the past 2-3 years on areas like optimizing strawberry credit flows on FarmVille. Venture capital, entrepreneurial talent, and engineering talent is starting to flow into the space, and the future of science is starting to be built. The ecosystem needs more resources. It needs more engineers, entrepreneurs, and venture capital. The prizes for success in transforming science go to everyone in the world. $1 trillion a year gets spent on R&amp;D, of which $200 billion is spent in the academic sector, and $800 billion in the private sector. There are vast new companies waiting to be built here. As the extraordinary Silicon Valley innovation engine increasingly directs itself at transforming science, you can expect to see acceleration on a scale that science has never seen. Science will change beyond recognition, and the positive impact on the rate of technology growth in the world will be enormous. The time to act is now. If you are a VC, invest in science startups. If you are an entrepreneur, hunt for an idea in the space and run with it. If you are an engineer or designer, there is a list of startups trying to accelerate science here.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/29/the-future-of-science/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/29/the-future-of-science/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web 2.0 Is Over, All Hail the Age of Mobile | PandoDaily</title>
      <description>Web 2.0 Is Over, All Hail the Age of Mobile Hamish McKenzie, pandodaily.com When they look back at this era, Inter&#173;net his&#173;to&#173;ri&#173;ans will mark Face&#173;book&#8217;s Insta&#173;gram acqui&#173;si&#173;tion as the sym&#173;bol&#173;ic moment when the Great Shift was con&#173;firmed. Sig&#173;nif&#173;i&#173;cant&#173;ly, it also came soon after Steve Jobs&#8217; death. The device that Job&#8230; &#8220;Where&#173;as Web 2.0 val&#173;ues &#8211; char&#173;ac&#173;ter&#173;ized by social shar&#173;ing and col&#173;lab&#173;o&#173;ra&#173;tion &#8211; drove the design and devel&#173;op&#173;ment of the likes of Face&#173;book and LinkedIn, the mobile age demands new para&#173;me&#173;ters. Now we need ser&#173;vices that require less typ&#173;ing, fewer but&#173;tons, sim&#173;ple swipe and pinch actions, brows&#173;ing that seam&#173;less&#173;ly inte&#173;grates ver&#173;ti&#173;cal and hor&#173;i&#173;zon&#173;tal move&#173;ment, larg&#173;er images, and fewer data hooks that clut&#173;ter up the user expe&#173;ri&#173;ence. Face&#173;book and Google&#8217;s cur&#173;rent mobile iter&#173;a&#173;tions don&#8217;t meet those stan&#173;dards.&#8221;</description>
      <link>http://www.digital-diva.co.uk/post/22037653983/web-2-0-is-over-all-hail-the-age-of-mobile</link>
      <guid>http://www.digital-diva.co.uk/post/22037653983/web-2-0-is-over-all-hail-the-age-of-mobile</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimize: How to Attract and Engage More Customers [Book Review]</title>
      <description>in "Optimize", Lee Odden contends that it takes many stakeholders in an organization - and not just on the marketing team - to contribute to an effective content marketing program and integrate it with search and social marketing.</description>
      <link>http://searchenginewatch.com/article/2171148/Optimize-How-to-Attract-and-Engage-More-Customers-Book-Review?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+sew+%28Search+Engine+Watch%29</link>
      <guid>http://searchenginewatch.com/article/2171148/Optimize-How-to-Attract-and-Engage-More-Customers-Book-Review?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+sew+%28Search+Engine+Watch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interest in Pinterest Reaches a Fever Pitch [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Could Pinterest be the silver bullet for retailers on social media? Pinterest is clearly resonating with online consumers in a big way. To put it simply, customers who find a product via Pinterest are more likely to purchase it than those who find the product via other social networks. SEE ALSO: 10 Video Tips for Businesses on Pinterest Pinterest is hot. In fact, in March 2012 the site served up 2.3 billion page impressions to over 4 million unique visitors a day. Who are these people? Why do Pinterest users respond so strongly to products that are pinned? This infographic from Tamba breaks down the stats, explaining why Pinterest is so powerful with its consumption-friendly audience. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto/Ultra Generic More About: online businesses, pinterest, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/pinterest-interest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/29/pinterest-interest/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Great Entrepreneurs Create Their Own Luck</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: This post is authored by guest contributor Thor Muller, a New York Times best selling author. His latest book, &#8220;Get Lucky: How to Put Planned Serendipity to Work for You and Your Business&#8221; is available now. This is the story of how a young British fine artist accidentally became a materials scientist, founding a high-growth company that created a whole new product category. It&#8217;s also a parable for how great entrepreneurs systematically create their own luck. Jane ni Dhulchaointigh is the founder and CEO of Sugru, a London-based startup that makes an amazing moldable adhesive for repairing any physical object. It&#8217;s a cross between silly putty and duct tape, a space age rubber that can be molded into any desired shape by hand, and that sticks to a vast array of surfaces. With customers in over 100 countries, and all seven continents, Sugru has taken the world by storm. What we see in Jane&#8217;s journey, so far from California&#8217;s tech startup scene, is the same thing we see in virtually all startups that work: the ability to harness serendipity, the unplanned discoveries, large or small, that end up being the turning points in careers and businesses. Hard work, training and process may be the foundation of success, but serendipity is where the magic happens. And even though serendipity is by definition unpredictable, its appearance is anything but random. Jane&#8217;s stunning rise is the result of her mastering what we call the skills of planned serendipity, a set of behaviors that have allowed her, over and over again, to generate the chance discoveries, recognize the good ones, and take action on those that matter most. Here&#8217;s how it happened, and what we can learn from her breakout success. Start With A &#8220;Geek Brain&#8221; Jane originally studied to be a sculptor, an interest that had possessed her for years. She returned to school in 2003 to study commercial product design at the Royal College of Art. It seemed a prudent career move given the high demand for designers (and the lack of jobs for sculptors), but it was a switch that proved difficult. Her impulse was to follow her own interests over solving the narrowly defined product problems discussed in class. Before long, her background in sculpture combined with her insatiable curiosity led her to begin experimenting with new materials. Jane was equipped with one of the great advantages in cultivating serendipity, a geek brain&#8211;what we define as an obsessive curiosity in an area of interest and the ability to notice anomalies, overcoming the conventional wisdom that constrains others. The geek brain gave Jane distance from the rote conventions of design school, allowing her to connect ideas from across domains in unusual ways. Find Space to Play Having a mindset geared for recognizing unexpected ideas is rarely enough on its own&#8212;Jane needed an environment that allowed her to explore and put this geek brain to good use. The workshop at her college served this purpose well: I was destroying things and putting them back together: chipping blocks of wood apart and putting them back together with other materials&#8230;One experiment I did was combining silicone caulk with very fine wood dust from the workshop. From that combination I made these fancy wooden balls. I found it fascinating that you could make something that looked like wood but had other properties&#8212;if you threw them on the floor they&#8217;d bounce. Jane&#8217;s early explorations with her strange rubbery material was driven by a fascination with the possibilities of what she could make, rather than any specific purpose to which it could be put. This is the hallmark of a true exploratory mode, as premature focus can kill good ideas before they ever emerge. Still, as her discovery started to take shape, she began to spend more and more time wondering what it might actually be good for. Be Opinionated Jane&#8217;s boyfriend noticed that she had been using her funny rubber to repair or customize things around the house&#8212;enlarging a sink plug that was too small, or making a more ergonomic knife handle. It had been so natural for her to use the rubber in this way because she personally believed in the value of repairing her things rather than running out and buying a replacement. The instinct was so natural, in fact, that she hadn&#8217;t even consciously registered what she was doing. It was only when her boyfriend drew her attention to it that she saw the opportunity in a flash. Jane had stumbled on a product idea that mapped perfectly to a deeply held conviction: she hated waste. She was fed up with it and knew she wasn&#8217;t alone. &#8220;In the past, some people would have thought that repairing something is a compromise because you couldn&#8217;t afford to buy it new again,&#8221; Jane says. &#8220;But now there are increasing numbers of people who would rather repair or reuse than throw something out and needlessly buy something new because of the waste involved.&#8221; Her insight was that this space-age rubber she&#8217;d invented could be an essential innovation in this cause. She saw the potential in her chance discovery only because she had an overriding purpose that gave her a unique perspective. &#8220;Every granny who finds it hard to open a jam jar can manipulate this material,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Anyone who has a stiff part on their bike can adapt it to be whatever the bike needs.&#8221; Project the Possibility The only problem was that the material didn&#8217;t actually exist yet. The makeshift rubber Jane had been playing with had all kinds of problems: it didn&#8217;t adhere to enough surfaces, it had a terribly short shelf-life, and it was too high maintenance to make a successful commercial product. This was the do-or-die moment. As an artist, there was every reason in the world to give up&#8212;she had no business thinking she could solve this incredibly technical problem. Instead, Jane pulled a Jujitsu serendipity move: employing only her faulty prototype and her storytelling skills, she projected her vision as broadly as she could, telling anyone who would listen about it. Early stage entrepreneurs like Jane don&#8217;t always know what exact outcomes to expect, but they are willing to publicly put their ideas into the world, allowing them to connect with the as yet unknown people and opportunities that make their products possible. It worked. Attention followed from the strength of her vision, attracting local press mentions, a set of science advisors, and a grant from the National Endowment for Science, Technology, and Arts. Follow Unplanned Paths The grant wasn&#8217;t huge, a mere &#163;35,000, but it was enough to start testing materials&#8212;as long as Jane did the testing herself. To do that, she realized, she would have to do something that was not only unexpected, but would have seemed absurd a few months before: she&#8217;d have to diverge from her career path and be trained as a lab technician and set up her own laboratory. She wasn&#8217;t waiting around to find a CTO who knew better. This former art student must learn to be a materials scientist. It took her two years of painstaking trial-and-error, but eventually she created a brand new, patented class of silicone that worked for her aims. Only Jane&#8217;s immovable sense of purpose kept her going through month after month of laborious formulation and failure, long before her work would bear fruit. This is a recurring paradox of serendipity: stick-to-itness&#8212;the ability to stay committed to a purpose&#8212;is often the very thing that allows new paths to be recognized and taken. Design Openness into the Product and Company Initially there was tremendous pressure to fit the new product into a well-worn category that the traditional business world would understand. Then it struck Jane that she could create a brand designed to activate the creative spark in people. She could leave the product&#8217;s purpose intentionally open&#8212;the tagline would become &#8220;Hack Things Better&#8221;&#8212;so that customers could use their own imagination. One of the first things she did after launching the product was create an online community for customers to share their ideas. Creating permeability at the edge of her company allowed new directions and opportunities to serendipitously emerge. As a result the company and its customers have developed a truly symbiotic relationship. That &#8220;perfect fit&#8221; Jane had been seeking for her unusual rubber years ago? Her customers are telling her what it is&#8212;or rather, all of the perfect fits they&#8217;ve found. Repairing computers, cables for laptop chargers, phones, and outdoor equipment have emerged as the leading uses for her one-of-a-kind product. Jane is finding the company being pulled by customers in directions she could never have imagined during those years of painstaking materials research, but in each case the path is perfectly aligned with the company&#8217;s purpose. The Kind of Luck That Matters Entrepreneurs often cite &#8220;luck&#8221; as a key ingredient of success, yet this means far more than just being in the right time, right place. The luck that builds careers and companies is the kind that unfolds gradually, choice by choice, as people recognize and seize surprise opportunities, attracting others to them long before it&#8217;s obvious that their business is the next big thing. These skills of planned serendipity are not vague, metaphysical concepts; they can be mastered by any of us, and can shape how we run our startups as they grow. We can learn how to make our businesses luckier.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/28/how-great-entrepreneurs-create-their-own-luck/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/28/how-great-entrepreneurs-create-their-own-luck/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>51 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>Have you spent the past week studying the nuts and bolts of the new Gmail interface? Or have you been preoccupied with the space shuttle Enterprise&#8216;s final flight to New York City (and the absurd memes that came along with it)? For whichever reasons you missed our latest digital media resources, use our weekly features roundup to catch up in a flash. This week, we&#8217;ve covered ways your business can use video on Pinterest, digital tools to help you reduce junk mail and tips on how to curate and share great content. We also have a list of the sassiest brands on social media, a rundown of essential tools for marketers and a gallery of iPhone cases that look good enough to eat. We even have video interviews with entrepreneurial trailblazers like Brian Solis and Mark Cuban. Go ahead and take advantage of these valuable resources! Editor&#8217;s Picks 4 Tips for Picking the Right Crowdfunding Platform Crowdfunding presents a great opportunity for startups. Here are four things companies should consider when picking a crowdfunding source. The Decline of KONY 2012: Where Did the Online Buzz Go? KONY 2012 couldn&#8217;t sustain its momentous social buzz following its March launch, despite April 20&#8242;s Cover the Night. How a Social Network Helps Families Coping With Autism MyAutismTeam connects parents of children with autism spectrum disorder to other parents, specialists and essential services. Bitchin&#8217; Kitchen: How a Web Chef Cooked Up a Hit TV Show Nadia G of &#8220;Bitchin&#8217; Kitchen&#8221; successfully turned her web series into a show on one of the most popular networks in the U.S. Learn how she did it. How to Dress Your Baby Like a Geek We&#8217;ve rounded up the best clothing options for baby gamers, sci-fi nerds and tech geeks alike. Etsy: A Beginner&#8217;s Guide to the Crafty Ecommerce Site Etsy has changed a lot since its launch in 2005. Whether you&#8217;re a veteran user or a newbie, take a look at our handy guide. 11 Tips for Getting the Most Out of Gmail&#8217;s New Interface We&#8217;ve highlighted 11 Gmail tips and options that will help you adjust to the new design. Social Media 10 Video Tips for Businesses on Pinterest Pinterest is a perfect way to share ideas in a visual form. Here are ten tips on how you can use video marketing on Pinterest. 20 TV Shows With the Most Social Media Buzz This Week [CHART] Which TV shows generate the most buzz on social networks? Find out each week from our social TV chart. 10 Must-Follow Tumblrs for Science Lovers Whether you like gazing at galaxies or exploring the microscopic world, these 10 Tumblrs will make your dashboard more sciency. 10 Tumblrs Serving Up the Best Animated GIFs Whether you like &#8217;90s nostalgia, movie clips, reality TV or animals, these 10 Tumblr sites will help you get your GIF fix. 10 Sassy Brands on Social Media Brands are showing more personality as the web becomes more social. Here are 10 hilarious brands killing it right now. 10 Funniest Sketch Comedy Channels on YouTube We&#8217;ve rounded up some of the best comedy channels on YouTube, each known for a different type of humor. 25 &#8216;Green&#8217; Photos From the Mashable Community In the spirit of Earth Day, we asked you to send us a photo that represented &#8220;green&#8221; for this week&#8217;s Mashable Photo Challenge. How Social Media Is Changing Sports [INFOGRAPHIC] This infographic shows many of the ways social media has had an impact on sports over the past few years. 5 Tips for Great Content Curation If you&#8217;re a curator looking for some boundaries in what feels like the wild West, here are five best practices to consider. For more social media news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s social media channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Business &amp; Marketing Should You Combine Your Personal and Business Social Media Identities? There are a lot of pros and cons to melding your personal brand with your company&#8217;s on social media. We analyze both sides. 3 Slick Analytics Dashboards to Monitor Your Business Website If you don&#8217;t have analytics on your site, you&#8217;re not getting the most out of your business. Check out these simple and helpful dashboards. How Skillshare Is Transforming Education as We Know It Online marketplace Skillshare lets anyone with specialized skills teach an offline class. Anyone with the desire to learn can attend. Crowdfunding: How Indiegogo Connects Concepts With Cash Looking to fund a project? Indiegogo can help you reach the vast corners of the Internet to make the most of crowdfunding. 3 Reasons the Call Center Is Far From Dead The rise of the smartphone has created many opportunities to interact with clients, but here&#8217;s why it isn&#8217;t killing the call center. How Digital Journalists Used Data to Report on Murdoch Scandal Innovative digital journalism played a starring role in the wake of a massive document release during an inquiry into British media ethics. How One App Uses Digital to Empower Education Three Ring allows teachers and students to digitize student work by snapping a picture or video with their mobile or tablet devices. 4 Tips for Keeping Your Gamified Community Motivated If you&#8217;ve found that gamification is right for your business, here are four steps to help keep your community in involved. How One Website Fights Hunger With Gourmet Goodies Love With Food is a food delivery service that donates a portion of every sale to local food banks across the country. Why Great Design Is the Future of Content Marketing The beautification of the web is upon us. How will this shift toward visual storytelling affect content marketing? We explore the trends. 5 Things You Didn&#8217;t Know About Mark Cuban [VIDEO] Internet and entertainment entrepreneur Mark Cuban shares his entrepreneurial experiences, love of sports and tells us what&#8217;s next. 60 Minutes to a More Efficient Social Business Strategy This 60-minute social media makeover will help companies create a more effective social media presence. 9 Things Businesses Need to Know About Web Security Small businesses are of particular interest to cyber criminals. At any given time there are more than 750,000 websites are being hacked or appearing on various hacker lists. Ditto&#8217;s 3D Virtual Fitting Tech Makes It Possible to Try on Glasses Online 3D virtual fitting technology lets you determine whether a pair of glasses flatters your face before making a purchase. Facebook Marketing: Why Less Is More Venture capitalist and social media consultant Peter Shankman shares the best tips and tricks for marketing your brand on Facebook. Could Zaarly Disrupt the Global Economy? [VIDEO] By optimizing the freelance economy, the startup might just change the way the world works. 12 Essential Tools for the Content Marketer There&#8217;s no single type of content marketing that works best for all companies. Diversification is key. Here are twelve types we recommend. Why No Brand Is Too Big to Fail, Too Small to Succeed Brian Solis talks about how companies should consider the consumer and community above all else when designing and presenting a product. How Mark Cuban Does Business [VIDEO] Internet mogul and Dallas Mavericks owner Mark Cuban sits down with Jesse Draper of The Valley Girl Show to discuss his business strategy. How to Maximize Your Facebook Engagement Data shows brands miss out on customer Facebook engagement more often then they realize. Here&#8217;s why. For more business news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s business channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Tech &amp; Mobile 20 Minimalist Backgrounds for a Simpler Desktop If you need a distraction-free background, these 20 minimalist designs are a breath of fresh air. 7 Tips for Women in the Tech Industry We asked successful female entrepreneurs what challenges women in tech face and what can help. Here&#8217;s what they shared. Is the Digital World Killing Creativity? [INFOGRAPHIC] The current age of digital disruption has opened a cornucopia of creative endeavors, but the ability to multitask may also hinder creativity. 14 Weird iPhone Cases You Won&#8217;t Believe If you&#8217;re itching to make a statement with your iPhone, have we got a selection of cases for you! DODOcase: How Bookbinding Inspired the Popular iPad Cover Patrick Buckley explains how his background in engineering and publishing led to one of the top iPad cases around. 10 Epic Movie Gadgets You Wish Were Real Technology has come a long way over the years, but there are still a ton of movie gadgets that we&#8217;re anxiously hoping will come to life. How Does Google Drive Compare to the Competition? Google Drive is an impressive product, but how does it compare to other cloud companies? 20 &#8216;Edible&#8217; iPhone Covers Are you a foodie at heart? Why not get an iPhone cover that celebrates your favorite foodstuff? The 15 Types of People Who Play Draw Something [VIDEO] This video details several type of Draw Something players, such as over detailed, terrible drawers and people who refuse to buy colors. 9 Digital Tools to Reduce Your Junk Mail Is your paper trail too massive to manage? Check out these tools to cut out your unwanted mail. 12 Mysterious Google Maps Sightings A look at some mysterious things found on Google Maps, from crop circles to capsized boats. How a Distasteful Meme Sparked a Web Culture War A family&#8217;s attempt to fight the Internet over a controversial meme involving its daughter has fueled more harm than good. 10 Kindle Cases That Look Like Books The Kindle offers you an entire digital library in the palm of your hand. We&#8217;ve found 10 book-themed Kindle cases to match. 10 Free WordPress Themes for Photo Lovers Organize all your favorite images with these 10 free WordPress themes made especially for shutter bugs. 8 Out-of-This-World Photos of the Space Shuttle Enterprise Check out these eight pictures of Space Shuttle Enterprise&#8217;s arrival at New York City&#8217;s John F. Kennedy Airport. For more tech news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s tech channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci. More About: Business, COMMUNICATIONS, Features Week In Review, Social Media, TechFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/digital-media-resources-36/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/digital-media-resources-36/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
