<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram is acquired by Facebook</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://blog.instagram.com/post/20785013897/instagram-facebook</link>
      <guid>http://blog.instagram.com/post/20785013897/instagram-facebook</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sephora Gives Its Shopping Experience a Makeover</title>
      <description>Sephora is getting a little more digital. Today the beauty chain rolled out an completely updated website with Pinterest and Instagram integration, an updated mobile site, and officially launched a program that will bring iPads to the store&#8217;s sales counters and put iPod touch point-of-sale devices in the hands of many of its sales associates. &#8220;Beauty has passionate shoppers, and Sephora is the mecca of beauty&#8221; Julie Bornstein, Senior Vice President of Sephora Direct told Mashable. She describes today&#8217;s updates as &#8220;Where beauty meets intelligence.&#8221; Pinterest integration is something that many brands have started to embrace, however, Sephora is taking that integration a step further. Every item on Sephora&#8217;s online store now has a &#8220;Pin It&#8221; button you can click to add the item to one of your boards on the site. Where Sephora takes its Pinterest integration to the next level, however, is in its own Pinterest account. Starting today shoppers will be able to browse the Pinterest boards of Sephora employees, and see what products are their favorites. &#8220;These are people who get to try ever product,&#8221; Bornstien says, which gives their opinions of what products are best a little more weight. The company has also added a new feed on Instagram where you can get a behind-the-scenes look at Sephora and its staff, as well as what trends are hot in the beauty world &#8211;we hear a color called Tangerine Tango is making headlines these days. In addition to the Pinterest integration, every product on the new website has been tagged with 25 different characteristics such as target age group, ingredients, and price so you can narrow down a particular search while you shop. The tagging process took a team of 50 employees 5,000 hours to fully index and tag. The result Sephora hopes is a incredibly targeted and personal experience when shopping on its site. Products on the site also now have color views, so if you&#8217;re looking for something like a purple eye shadow you can hover over the color and see what that product would really look like. Sephora.com also now offers store availability information, so you can find out if the eye shadow you need is in stock, and keeps track of your past purchases and samples you&#8217;ve received (including those in store) so you can keep track of your purchases and use that information to make future ones. For instance, if you purchased a lip gloss you loved while on vacation, you&#8217;ll be able to see exactly what it was on the site and be able to order it right then or find out whether it&#8217;s available at the Sephora near you. That information is also available in the mobile version of the site. While you&#8217;re at a Sephora store you can use your iPhone to scan products off the shelves and read reviews. The company has also added iPads to the Beauty Center in 20 of its stores that can be used to navigate the website, as well as view the menu of services available at the center. Store associates are now equip with iPod touch point-of-sale devices &#8211;something that has been in testing for the past 6 months&#8212; that can be used to make purchases or reference the store&#8217;s website while on the move. Digital is a huge part of Sephora&#8217;s business. The company has seen a 300% increase over the past year in mobile shopping on its website, with 70% of its mobile traffic coming from iOS devices. iPad traffic to Sephora.com is up 400% in Q1 of 2012 over the same period last year, and 20% of all of the traffic to the site comes from mobile devices. &#8220;Digital is a must for the future of retailing,&#8221; says Bornstein. &#8220;With social, digital, mobile and website updates, we&#8217;re giving our clients the most personalized experience ever seen in the beauty industry, and connecting clients with our experts in ways that are most relevant to them. We&#8217;re excited to makeover the future of shopping.&#8221; More About: beauty, iOS, ipad, iphone, SephoraFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/09/sephora-makeover/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/09/sephora-makeover/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Group Search: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?LinkedIn Rolls Out New Group Search: LinkedIn&#8217;s Group Search helps you search across all of the groups on LinkedIn to find the right one for you. You&#8217;ll find this search now gives you better results.New Group Search results show your connections who may be in a particular group.Tumblr Improves Facebook Integration: Tumblr users now have improved functions on Facebook&#8217;s Timeline, News Feed and Ticker.You now have more options when sharing Tumblr posts.Twitter for BlackBerry Introduces New Features: The improved Twitter for BlackBerry makes it easier to share links to web pages directly from the browser. When you tweet a link it will automatically be shortened. And you can upload photos to Twitter right from your BlackBerry&#8217;s camera.Twitter for BlackBerry makes it easier to connect to the people and things you care about.Buddy Media Deepens Integration With YouTube: The social media marketing platform Buddy Media now offers big-brand clients options to customize and brand their YouTube channels. Buddy Media is one of a few companies offering these capabilities.Notice the social media integration on this YouTube channel.Here are some social media tools worth noting:Forum For Pages: A Facebook app that allows you to add a discussion board to your Facebook page.Forum For Pages gives you a place for discussions on your Facebook page.CircleMe: A social tool to collect all of your likes and discover new ones. CircleMe makes it easy to showcase your favorite things.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-rxE9O4tnXsZoomSphere: This social media tool gives you insights into the most popular sources of content across the main social media platforms.ZoomSphere is a social media influence-tracking system for Facebook, Twitter, Google+, YouTube, LinkedIn and Pinterest.Check out our annual report:Social Media Marketing Industry Report 2012: Be sure to check out the results of Social Media Examiner&#8217;s fourth-annual social media study. Here&#8217;s a cool infographic based on key findings in this study.Check out these highlights from Social Media Examiner's latest Social Media Marketing Industry Report.And don&#8217;t miss this:Social Media Examiner presents Social Media Success Summit 2012! (online conference). The 50% off discount ends very soon!Join 27 social media experts at Social Media Examiner&#8217;s big online conference! Go here to learn more.What social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/linkedin-group-search-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/linkedin-group-search-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest is Now the No. 3 Social Network in the U.S. [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Pinterest is now the number three most-popular social network in the U.S., behind Facebook and Twitter, according to Experian Hitwise. A new report from the researcher shows Pinterest got 21.5 million visits during the week ending Jan. 28, a nearly 30-fold increase over a comparable week in July. Not surprisingly, the site skews female with a 60/40 ration of women to men visitors. Experian rep Matt Tatham says Pinterest beat its next-closest competitor, LinkedIn, in total visits in February. Tatham says the rankings by total visits for March is as follows: 1. Facebook: 7 billion 2. Twitter: 182 million 3. Pinterest: 104 million 4. LinkedIn: 86 million 5. Tagged: 72 million 6. Google+: 61 million The report, which tracks visits rather than unique visitors, is based on web traffic and doesn&#8217;t factor in visits from mobile sites. According to Experian&#8217;s reckoning, Foursquare only got 2.9 million visits in March and Instagram got 10.2 million. ComScore, which doesn&#8217;t measure mobile traffic either, but ranks sites by uniques rather than total visits, did not include Pinterest in its list of the top 50 web properties in February. However, LinkedIn made number 27 with 36 million visitors. ComScore listed Pinterest as its number three &#8220;top-gaining&#8221; properties, however, with 17.8 million total visitors that month. ComScore&#8217;s March figures were not available at press time. More About: Experian Hitwise, Facebook, Google, pinterest, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive Look Inside the New Facebook HQ: You&#8217;ll Like This [PICS]</title>
      <description>Facebook HQ. You Like This The company is now completely moved out of its Palo Alto pad, and into the much more spacious Menlo Park facility it broke ground on last year. Click here to view this gallery. It&#8217;s been a little more than a year since Facebook bought a 57-acre campus on the outskirts of Menlo Park in Silicon Valley, and started the slow process of turning it into its headquarters of the future. Well, the future is now. As of last week, every last Facebook staffer has been moved into the Menlo Park facility, which is almost unrecognizable compared to the way it looked a year ago. Mashable checked in on the new Facebook HQ in December, but there&#8217;s been a lot going on since then. The entire campus has a fresh coat of paint &#8212; not to mention fresh graffiti-style spray painted and stenciled artwork everywhere. (Employees are encouraged to &#8220;hack their space.&#8221;) We got an unprecedented behind-the-scenes look at what makes Facebook tick &#8212; the high-tech booking systems, amusingly-named conference rooms, and premium caffeination facilities. (What really makes Facebook so eager to constantly upgrade itself? Two words: Philz Coffee.) We saw plenty of things that make working at the social network so much fun &#8212; including a wall where Jeremy Lin had marked his height, towering above the rest of the staff. Take a look at the pics, and tell us in the comments whether you&#8217;d want to work here. More About: Facebook, Facebook HQ, mark zuckerberg, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/facebook-hq/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/07/facebook-hq/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Ways to Rethink the Press Release</title>
      <description>Jonathan Rick is a director at Levick Strategic Communications. He contributes to Levick&#8217;s Bulletproof Blog. Follow him @jrick. Every year, for the last ten years, someone has proclaimed that the press release is dying. While the rumors of its demise are exaggerated, they are not totally unfounded. That&#8217;s because the press release is, in fact, being eclipsed by digital alternatives that are more flexible, more interesting, and more relevant. In 2010, when Google made a major announcement not by press release but by blog post, we reached what seemed like a milestone. Five years earlier, a company of Google&#8217;s stature would have issued a statement on a newswire. Now, a Google executive was crafting a more thoughtful narrative that the company published on its official blog. This shift in medium and message represents a new era in corporate communications. News now needs to be conveyed in an empathetic tone and delivered in a user-friendly format. And Google isn&#8217;t the only company using this strategy. Dell breaks news on its blog all the time. When Netflix has something to say, it complements a traditional release with a first-person post. Southwest Airlines takes the prize for a blog that whips CNN-type announcements into HBO-like celebrations. What&#8217;s so encouraging about this trend is that it isn&#8217;t exclusive to corporate behemoths. To the contrary, smaller companies can leverage blog-centric communications with great success. Here are four examples of those that do it well. 1. Zillow Zillow, the real estate company, has a great blog where it bypasses the typical corporate press release. Instead, it opts for more conversational posts like: &#8220;Whether you&#8217;re driving around a neighborhood checking home values on your smartphone, using an iPad to draw a search around that dream neighborhood while waiting at the airport, or doing some serious house hunting on your computer at home, there are multiple ways to home search and shop with Zillow.&#8221; Similarly, new hires are introduced by their respective manager in a first-person post. The Lesson: Keep it human. Your stakeholders, and your customers, prefer it that way. 2. Patagonia Those searching Patagonia&#8217;s website for a press release will look in vain. Instead, media folks are invited to join the Patagonia PR Facebook group. This group is dedicated to keeping journalists, writers, editors, and other media informed about Patagonia and its outdoor clothing products. While a social network isn&#8217;t technically a blog, it works. In fact, Patagonia also operates a robust blog. The Lesson: Passion, even edginess, does not get in the way of your message. Passion actually shows personality, and that there&#8217;s a real person behind your press shop. 3. Innocent When the British smoothie-maker Innocent announced new juice blends earlier this year, it did so via press release and blog post. The difference between the two versions speaks volumes. Here&#8217;s the press release: &#8220;We&#8217;ve been so pleased with how popular the juice has been that we got back in to the kitchen and have made some delicious juice blends, which we think everyone will enjoy just as much.&#8221;Here&#8217;s the blog post: &#8220;You can choose from our delicious apple and raspberry recipe or totally tasty tropical (sorry), depending on whether you need to be transported to a dappled orchard or a desert island.&#8221;The formatting differences between the two are even more glaring. The press release lacks any social sharing buttons. Its claim to fame: it&#8217;s downloadable as a PDF. The blog post features the colorful new bottles and video created for the occasion. There&#8217;s also a promise to reward the most interesting comments with a free case of the new blends. The Lesson: Entertaining consumers is as important as informing them. 4. ServInt When ServInt, a web host, announced a new line of servers from their Flex brand, the press release followed the tried-and-trite formula. &#8220;ServInt, a pioneering provider of managed cloud hosting for enterprises worldwide, today introduced its new line of fully managed, dedicated servers under the Flex brand.&#8221; Then things got interesting on their blog, ServInt Source, which ran three posts about Flex. First, ServInt&#8217;s sales director touted the servers&#8217; &#8220;power and options.&#8221; A week later, its vice president of marketing connected the new machines to the company&#8217;s new brand identity. Finally, the COO placed these changes in the context of industry-wide developments. What&#8217;s significant about this approach is how it turns a single announcement into multiple opportunities. With press releases this continuity is difficult. A blog, however, is perfect for ongoing updates. The Lesson: Make it personal. Comments from soldiers in the trenches are more memorable than a few quotes from a chief executive. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, 12_Tribes More About: contributor, corporate blogs, features, Marketing, Social MediaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/press-release-blog-lessons-alternative/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/press-release-blog-lessons-alternative/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups, This Is How Design Works &#226;&#8364;&#8220; by Wells Riley</title>
      <description>A guide to understanding digital %26 physical product design for startups</description>
      <link>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</link>
      <guid>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Pinterest for B2B Marketing: 6 Practical Tips | CustomerThink</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://www.customerthink.com/blog/leveraging_pinterest_for_b2b_marketing_6_practical_tips</link>
      <guid>http://www.customerthink.com/blog/leveraging_pinterest_for_b2b_marketing_6_practical_tips</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Glass: One day... - YouTube</title>
      <description>We believe technology should work for you &#8212; to be there when you need it and get out of your way when you don't. A team within our Google[x] group started Pr...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowdfunding: What it Means for Investors</title>
      <description>Bill Clark is the CEO of Microventures, a securities broker/dealer that uses a process similar to crowdfunding which allows backers to invest $1,000 to $30,000 in startups online. You can follow him on Twitter @microventures.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/crowdfunding-means-investors-183126335.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/crowdfunding-means-investors-183126335.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Employers Are Paying in 2012 [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have been working hard for your companies under tight financial constraints during the last few years, a silver lining might be coming your way. Thanks to rosy outlooks of employers in companies of all sizes across the country, it looks as though 2012 is going to be the year of the raise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to the infographic below, which was researched and compiled by &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/" target="_blank"&gt;PayScale.com&lt;/a&gt;, more than 93% of employers surveyed plan to give compensation adjustments to their workforces. That&amp;#8217;s significantly more than the percentage of employers who actually gave their employees salary adjustments in 2011 (60%) and 2010 (about 30%). The good news isn&amp;#8217;t just for the already-employed, either: A large percentage of companies in the business support services, information/telecommunications and retail sectors expect financial growth in 2012 &amp;#8212; a sure sign of new jobs to come.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Check out the infographic, which also maps out employer performance in 2011 in areas such as recruiting, social media and overall growth. Do you think 2012 will be a boom year for employees? Let us know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;title=How Employers Are Paying in 2012 [INFOGRAPHIC]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/PayScale_Compensation_Infographic_972.jpg" alt="" title="Infographic Final RGB 2" width="972" height="6231" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-966053" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Social Media Job Listings&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every week we post a list of &lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/find-jobs"&gt;social media and web job opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&amp;#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661878" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Public Affairs Special Programs Coordinator, PPA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the British Embassy in New York City&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661959" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Marketing Sales Manager &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at TMG in Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/661877" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Director of Marketing &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Found Animals Foundation in Los Angeles&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infographic courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/" target="_blank"&gt;PayScale.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/infographic/"&gt;infographic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-search-series/"&gt;job search series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/salary/"&gt;salary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/rNhvygdoxeRLDAMVT_ixdtFYSMc/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=VEhsDCIC070:lWh1qCov_8I:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/VEhsDCIC070" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/03/salary-guide-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
