<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Is Hotmail Getting a New Name Along With Its Redesign? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Microsoft is said to be working on a redesign of its Hotmail email platform, and leaked images of the new look have made its way onto the web. Liveside.net has released screenshots of Hotmail's new homepage design. Not only does it look a lot like Metro -- the company's new highly-visual interface associated with its Windows 8 software -- it appears to have a new name: Newmail. However, it's unknown whether &#8220;Newmail" is a placeholder name or if Hotmail will transition to that name soon. SEE ALSO: Windows 8 Release Preview Unleashes the Power of Metro [HANDS ON] The Window&#8217;s 8 Metro design upgrade aims to be viewable across devices and w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: email, hotmail, Metro, microsoft, Windows 8</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/hotmail-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/hotmail-redesign/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Twitter&#8217;s First-Ever TV Commercial [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Twitter ran on Sunday its first-ever TV spot during the broadcast of the 2012 Pocono 400 NASCAR race. Omid Ashtari of Twitter sent a tweet informing the community to check out the social networking site's first commercial spot. The 16-second clip features NASCAR racer Brad Keselowski seated in his car and taking a picture of the scene with his iPhone. Keselowski, who came in 24th place during the race, is taking advantage of the iPhone's capability to upload pictures directly to Twitter. in case you missed, here is @Twitter's first ever TV spot during today's #NASCAR race youtube.com/watch?v=nYz76M&#8230;&#8212; Omid Ashtari (@omid) June 10, 2012 What's especially interesting&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Advertising, apple, commercials, iphone, Social Media, social networking, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/twitter-commercial/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/twitter-commercial/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compared to magical</title>
      <description>The easiest way to sell yourself short is to compare your work to the competition. To say that you are 5% cheaper or have one or two features that stand out--this is a formula for slightly better mediocrity. The goal ought to be to compare yourself not to the best your peers or the competition has managed to get through a committee or down on paper, but to an unattainable, magical unicorn. Compared to that, how are you doing?</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/compared-to-magical.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/compared-to-magical.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Can Track Disease &#8212; Can It Predict Outbreaks?</title>
      <description>After analyzing 17 million mentions of illness in Facebook posts and tweets (separating "Bieber fever" from actual fever) and plotting genuine ailment mentions on a map, founder of Sickweather, Graham Dodge, has noticed trends in how disease spreads throughout the United States. For one thing, disease spreads most quickly between Hartford, Conn. and Washington D.C., an area he has dubbed "contagion alley." And it is impacted by big events like the Super Bowl. When the New York Giants played the New England Patriots in Indianapolis this February, Twitter mentions of illness in Indianapolis spiked, more than doubling those in demographically similar city Dayton, Ohio. Several studies&#8230; Continue reading... More About: disease, features, health, lifestyle, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/social-media-disease-tracking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/social-media-disease-tracking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WWDC iOS 6 Rumors: What To Expect, Reject, and Wish For</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s WWDC time. Like, tomorrow. And we expect to see plenty of fun announcements, not least of which being a brand new mobile operating system, iOS 6. It&#8217;s the type of Apple product every iPhone owner can enjoy, and I&#8217;m more than pumped to bring you a full list of expected, rumored, and wishlist features that we&#8217;ll soon enjoy. So how does a silver user interface sound as opposed to blue? What about a departure from Google Maps and a brand new 3D map view brought to you direct from Apple? How about Facebook integration as deep as (if not deeper than) Apple&#8217;s beloved Twitter? All that and more after the break. iMaps?Rumor: Apple is ditching Google Maps data for its own in-house Maps system The app will have a 3D mode Argument: We&#8217;ve been hearing about it from multiple sources for weeks We&#8217;ve seen it, albeit in blurry form Apple acquired three mapping companies in the past few years Apple&#8217;s new iPhoto app isn&#8217;t even using Google Maps data Objection: In regards to iPhoto, it&#8217;s only fair to note that the app isn&#8217;t using Apple&#8217;s in-house system either. Instead, it uses OpenStreetMap data. Judgment: This one&#8217;s highly likely. There&#8217;s really no other reason for Apple&#8217;s map tech shopping spree last year. We&#8217;ve seen blurry images, heard it from various corners of the blogosphere for nearly a month, and it makes sense for Apple&#8217;s general trajectory as a company. Google is a major competitor, and piggybacking off of the search giant in an area where Apple can afford to keep in-house doesn&#8217;t make sense any longer. Plus, most of the top brass one of Apple&#8217;s recent map tech acquisitions, C3 Technologies, has left the company for other endeavors. This is usually the case when Apple builds out new features through acquisitions. Facebook integrationRumor: Facebook will be baked straight into iOS 6 the same way that Twitter is in iOS 5 This will allow for system-wide Facebook authentication services for apps, sharing to a limited extent (links, perhaps photos), and possibly check-ins. It would also be possible to integrate Facebook Events with the iOS calendar (iCal) Also possible, but even less likely: Integration of Facebook Chat with iMessages Argument: It comes rather confidently from MG Siegler Apple likes Facebook Apple wants to keep things as easy as possible for users, and baking in Facebook only makes sense for users of Apple products, Facebook, and developers Facebook sharing is already built into iTunes desktop When asked about future plans with Facebook, Tim Cook said &#8220;stay tuned.&#8221; Objection: Apple has baked in Facebook before and scrapped the idea Facebook is a far more complicated network than Twitter: Facebook privacy, Open Graph, etc. Concerning the deeper integration (iCal, iMessages, and even Photos), Apple usually takes its time with these big endeavors, like with Siri Judgment: Likely. As the LA Times points out, all signs point to a Facebook-laden iOS 6. Facebook is usually the most popular social app on the App Store, and Facebook is picking up some serious steam in the mobile realm. Partnering in this way only makes sense, and should only strengthen both companies. Color Scheme Change-UpRumor: The iOS 6 user interface will be silver, rather than blue Argument: Blue is used as a complimentary, not primary, color in most Apple products (like the background of File, Edit, etc. in the OS X menu bar when clicked). OS X and iPad have silver-based UI Apple likes to unify its products as much as possible Apple&#8217;s WWDC 2012 app has a silver row of buttons, instead of black and blue Objection: Apple&#8217;s really good at not trying to fix it if it ain&#8217;t broken For example, certain apps like Calendar, Contacts, and YouTube haven&#8217;t really changed at all since their debut in 2007 Judgment: This one seems pretty likely, as well. Not only has the WWDC app and iPad UI been silver since their inception, but the newly released iPhoto app has also been dipped in chrome. Everything about Apple is silver, from their hardware on the notebook line to the backside of the iPad to the Apple icon on most of the company&#8217;s brick-and-mortar stores. Why was iOS ever blue to begin with? Siri for iPadRumor: Siri support, not just voice dictation, will come to the iPad The personal assistant will be accessed through a hold tap to the home button (like on iPhone 4S), whether the iPad is locked or not Siri will take up only a small portion of the screen, popping up from the bottom of whatever app the user is currently in It may only come to new iPads Argument: It&#8217;s only a matter of time 9to5Mac &#8220;trusted sources&#8221; claim Siri is in testing on second and third-gen iPads Again, Apple wants to unify its products Siri is used in voice dictation on the iPad, it&#8217;s just not fully functional Objection: The iPad may be too far away to understand dictation, according to some skeptics Siri is still in beta. Why jump to a new device? &#8220;Users aren&#8217;t proving adventurous with their usage&#8221; It&#8217;s possible that Apple may not reveal Siri for iPad at WWDC Judgment: This one&#8217;s a maybe, but only because it may not show its face tomorrow, not because it won&#8217;t happen. Siri for iPad is only a natural progression. My guess is that it&#8217;s unveiled tomorrow and available only to third-generation iPads. Apple is scaling Siri to make sure that quality stays up to snuff with concerns for servers, etc., just like Siri was only available on the iPhone 4S. Siri APIsRumor: Apple will finally let developers integrate Siri at a command level Argument: John Gruber and MG Siegler are both betting on it Developers were given limited access to Siri in iOS 5.1 for dictation It would go over well with developers, and offer an interesting new assortment of applications to users There are at least three dozen sessions at WWDC marked TBA. Gotta fill &#8216;em up somehow. Objection: As with Siri for iPad (and earlier generation iThings), iPad is still in beta. Perhaps it should graduate before migrating to new territory. Tim Cook said on May 30 that we&#8217;d see some amazing stuff out of Siri &#8220;in the coming months.&#8221; Judgment: I&#8217;m entirely on the fence about this one. Gruber and Siegler count for something, especially combined, and it&#8217;s a developers&#8217; conference. It would kind of be like Christmas morning for a developer. At the same time, it goes against scaling Siri, and it feels rushed. Yet still, Tim Cook&#8217;s hints are ambiguous. The release of a Siri API at WWDC would be a month from his statement, which is discouraging. But amazing Siri-integrated apps would appear in the coming months. iCloud Updates Rumor: Apple is syncing new and current OS X features with iOS 6 through iCloud This includes iCloud Tabs, Do Not Disturb for Notifications, and Mail VIPs iCloud Tabs is said to offer a synchronized list of Safari tabs open across all Apple devices. Do Not Disturb would be a toggle under Airplane Mode in Settings that would disable notifications Argument: An iCloud beta site confirms that new iCloud features will affect iOS 6. Mail VIPs is already a feature in OS X Mountain Lion, and it&#8217;s much appreciated by users. It only makes sense to include it in iOS 6 Mail. iCloud Tabs have been integrated into OS X 10.8 Developer Preview 2 in March. Even with rumors of added display real-estate to the next-gen iPhone, horizontal resolution wouldn&#8217;t change. With most games played in landscape, the ability to disable not only badges but banners during play is even more needed. Objection: All three features come by way of anonymous &#8220;trusted sources&#8221; at 9to5Mac, with no real concrete evidence behind them. Judgment: It seems like these features only make sense in the new mobile OS. It&#8217;s all-but-announced that whatever&#8217;s happening with iCloud &#8212; and some new things are undoubtedly happening &#8212; will be a part of iOS 6. However, the specific features listed don&#8217;t have much solid proof to back them up. We could be entirely wrong. Perhaps the Notes and Reminders synchronization shown on the iCloud beta page are on the WWDC menu. We&#8217;re keeping you up to date on everything you should expect from the all-but-announced features to wishlist items. Check out Matt&#8217;s rumor round-up on Apple&#8217;s Notebook announcements, as well as a forthcoming post on possible OS X features to look forward to. WWDC 2012 is set to be the biggest developer&#8217;s conference yet.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/10/wwdc-ios-6-rumors-what-to-expect-reject-and-wish-for/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/10/wwdc-ios-6-rumors-what-to-expect-reject-and-wish-for/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WWDC iOS 6 Rumors: What To Expect, Reject, and Wish For</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s WWDC time. Like, tomorrow. And we expect to see plenty of fun announcements, not least of which being a brand new mobile operating system, iOS 6. It&#8217;s the type of Apple product every iPhone owner can enjoy, and I&#8217;m more than pumped to bring you a full list of expected, rumored, and wishlist features that we&#8217;ll soon enjoy. So how does a silver user interface sound as opposed to blue? What about a departure from Google Maps and a brand new 3D map view brought to you direct from Apple? How about Facebook integration as deep as (if not deeper than) Apple&#8217;s beloved Twitter? All that and more after the break. iMaps?Rumor: Apple is ditching Google Maps data for its own in-house Maps system The app will have a 3D mode Argument: We&#8217;ve been hearing about it from multiple sources for weeks We&#8217;ve seen it, albeit in blurry form Apple acquired three mapping companies in the past few years Apple&#8217;s new iPhoto app isn&#8217;t even using Google Maps data Objection: In regards to iPhoto, it&#8217;s only fair to note that the app isn&#8217;t using Apple&#8217;s in-house system either. Instead, it uses OpenStreetMap data. Judgment: This one&#8217;s highly likely. There&#8217;s really no other reason for Apple&#8217;s map tech shopping spree last year. We&#8217;ve seen blurry images, heard it from various corners of the blogosphere for nearly a month, and it makes sense for Apple&#8217;s general trajectory as a company. Google is a major competitor, and piggybacking off of the search giant in an area where Apple can afford to keep in-house doesn&#8217;t make sense any longer. Plus, most of the top brass one of Apple&#8217;s recent map tech acquisitions, C3 Technologies, has left the company for other endeavors. This is usually the case when Apple builds out new features through acquisitions. Facebook integrationRumor: Facebook will be baked straight into iOS 6 the same way that Twitter is in iOS 5 This will allow for system-wide Facebook authentication services for apps, sharing to a limited extent (links, perhaps photos), and possibly check-ins. It would also be possible to integrate Facebook Events with the iOS calendar (iCal) Also possible, but even less likely: Integration of Facebook Chat with iMessages Argument: It comes rather confidently from MG Siegler Apple likes Facebook Apple wants to keep things as easy as possible for users, and baking in Facebook only makes sense for users of Apple products, Facebook, and developers Facebook sharing is already built into iTunes desktop When asked about future plans with Facebook, Tim Cook said &#8220;stay tuned.&#8221; Objection: Apple has baked in Facebook before and scrapped the idea Facebook is a far more complicated network than Twitter: Facebook privacy, Open Graph, etc. Concerning the deeper integration (iCal, iMessages, and even Photos), Apple usually takes its time with these big endeavors, like with Siri Judgment: Likely. As the LA Times points out, all signs point to a Facebook-laden iOS 6. Facebook is usually the most popular social app on the App Store, and Facebook is picking up some serious steam in the mobile realm. Partnering in this way only makes sense, and should only strengthen both companies. Color Scheme Change-UpRumor: The iOS 6 user interface will be silver, rather than blue Argument: Blue is used as a complimentary, not primary, color in most Apple products (like the background of File, Edit, etc. in the OS X menu bar when clicked). OS X and iPad have silver-based UI Apple likes to unify its products as much as possible Apple&#8217;s WWDC 2012 app has a silver row of buttons, instead of black and blue Objection: Apple&#8217;s really good at not trying to fix it if it ain&#8217;t broken For example, certain apps like Calendar, Contacts, and YouTube haven&#8217;t really changed at all since their debut in 2007 Judgment: This one seems pretty likely, as well. Not only has the WWDC app and iPad UI been silver since their inception, but the newly released iPhoto app has also been dipped in chrome. Everything about Apple is silver, from their hardware on the notebook line to the backside of the iPad to the Apple icon on most of the company&#8217;s brick-and-mortar stores. Why was iOS ever blue to begin with? Siri for iPadRumor: Siri support, not just voice dictation, will come to the iPad The personal assistant will be accessed through a hold tap to the home button (like on iPhone 4S), whether the iPad is locked or not Siri will take up only a small portion of the screen, popping up from the bottom of whatever app the user is currently in It may only come to new iPads Argument: It&#8217;s only a matter of time 9to5Mac &#8220;trusted sources&#8221; claim Siri is in testing on second and third-gen iPads Again, Apple wants to unify its products Siri is used in voice dictation on the iPad, it&#8217;s just not fully functional Objection: The iPad may be too far away to understand dictation, according to some skeptics Siri is still in beta. Why jump to a new device? &#8220;Users aren&#8217;t proving adventurous with their usage&#8221; It&#8217;s possible that Apple may not reveal Siri for iPad at WWDC Judgment: This one&#8217;s a maybe, but only because it may not show its face tomorrow, not because it won&#8217;t happen. Siri for iPad is only a natural progression. My guess is that it&#8217;s unveiled tomorrow and available only to third-generation iPads. Apple is scaling Siri to make sure that quality stays up to snuff with concerns for servers, etc., just like Siri was only available on the iPhone 4S. Siri APIsRumor: Apple will finally let developers integrate Siri at a command level Argument: John Gruber and MG Siegler are both betting on it Developers were given limited access to Siri in iOS 5.1 for dictation It would go over well with developers, and offer an interesting new assortment of applications to users There are at least three dozen sessions at WWDC marked TBA. Gotta fill &#8216;em up somehow. Objection: As with Siri for iPad (and earlier generation iThings), iPad is still in beta. Perhaps it should graduate before migrating to new territory. Tim Cook said on May 30 that we&#8217;d see some amazing stuff out of Siri &#8220;in the coming months.&#8221; Judgment: I&#8217;m entirely on the fence about this one. Gruber and Siegler count for something, especially combined, and it&#8217;s a developers&#8217; conference. It would kind of be like Christmas morning for a developer. At the same time, it goes against scaling Siri, and it feels rushed. Yet still, Tim Cook&#8217;s hints are ambiguous. The release of a Siri API at WWDC would be a month from his statement, which is discouraging. But amazing Siri-integrated apps would appear in the coming months. iCloud Updates Rumor: Apple is syncing new and current OS X features with iOS 6 through iCloud This includes iCloud Tabs, Do Not Disturb for Notifications, and Mail VIPs iCloud Tabs is said to offer a synchronized list of Safari tabs open across all Apple devices. Do Not Disturb would be a toggle under Airplane Mode in Settings that would disable notifications Argument: An iCloud beta site confirms that new iCloud features will affect iOS 6. Mail VIPs is already a feature in OS X Mountain Lion, and it&#8217;s much appreciated by users. It only makes sense to include it in iOS 6 Mail. iCloud Tabs have been integrated into OS X 10.8 Developer Preview 2 in March. Even with rumors of added display real-estate to the next-gen iPhone, horizontal resolution wouldn&#8217;t change. With most games played in landscape, the ability to disable not only badges but banners during play is even more needed. Objection: All three features come by way of anonymous &#8220;trusted sources&#8221; at 9to5Mac, with no real concrete evidence behind them. Judgment: It seems like these features only make sense in the new mobile OS. It&#8217;s all-but-announced that whatever&#8217;s happening with iCloud &#8212; and some new things are undoubtedly happening &#8212; will be a part of iOS 6. However, the specific features listed don&#8217;t have much solid proof to back them up. We could be entirely wrong. Perhaps the Notes and Reminders synchronization shown on the iCloud beta page are on the WWDC menu. We&#8217;re keeping you up to date on everything you should expect from the all-but-announced features to wishlist items. Check out Matt&#8217;s rumor round-up on Apple&#8217;s Notebook announcements, as well as a forthcoming post on possible OS X features to look forward to. WWDC 2012 is set to be the biggest developer&#8217;s conference yet.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/10/wwdc-ios-6-rumors-what-to-expect-reject-and-wish-for/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/10/wwdc-ios-6-rumors-what-to-expect-reject-and-wish-for/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Need a Quick Opinion? There&#8217;s An App For That</title>
      <description>Does this shirt go with these pants? Is the Galaxy S III a great phone? If you're looking for a quick opinion on something, there's now an app for that. Appropriately named "Thumb," the app lets you ask yes or no questions and get a thumbs up or down from the community. The app has been around since July 2010 and just launched version 3.0, which revamps the experience and adds a number of new features into the mix. "Anything you can potentially ask for an opinion of people did it, and that kind of blew us away," Thumb CEO Dan Kurani told Mashable about the app's early days. "We thought we were building a utility and we found out when we launched it that it's very much a social tool th&#8230; Continue reading... More About: App, Thumb</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/thumb-version-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/thumb-version-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineer Creates Coolest Business Card Ever [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Here's an enterprising young electrical engineer who wanted to directly impress all those who received one of his business cards. What did he do? Well, he did some electrical engineering on the business card itself. Cody Shaw, a recent University of Waterloo engineering graduate who wanted to get himself a job in printed circuit board design and manufacture, decided to use a tiny circuit board as a business card. Rigging up LEDs with what's known as a 555 timer, the card's LEDs flashing patterns change when you interact with the timer using different light sources. But wait a second, isn't all this expensive? We asked Cody about that, and he say&#8230; Continue reading... More About: business card, jobs, mashable video, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/cool-business-card/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/cool-business-card/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineer Creates Coolest Business Card Ever [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Here's an enterprising young electrical engineer who wanted to directly impress all those who received one of his business cards. What did he do? Well, he did some electrical engineering on the business card itself. Cody Shaw, a recent University of Waterloo engineering graduate who wanted to get himself a job in printed circuit board design and manufacture, decided to use a tiny circuit board as a business card. Rigging up LEDs with what's known as a 555 timer, the card's LEDs flashing patterns change when you interact with the timer using different light sources. But wait a second, isn't all this expensive? We asked Cody about that, and he say&#8230; Continue reading... More About: business card, jobs, mashable video, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/cool-business-card/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/cool-business-card/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Your Site Mobile Ready in Just 30 Seconds</title>
      <description>Ready to convert an existing website into a mobile-friendly platform but not sure how to get started? New York-based startup bMobilized has released a new do-it-yourself tool that instantly converts a website into a full-featured HTML5-enabled mobile site in just a few clicks. Even better, it only costs $5 a month to keep the mobile [...] More About: apps, Mobile, Small Business, smartphones, Startups</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/make-site-mobile-ready/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/10/make-site-mobile-ready/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>55 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>Maybe you were too busy hunting down celebrities on the new video chat service, Airtime. Better yet, maybe you were using it to land a job. For whatever reason, you missed out on some of Mashable's features coverage this week, and that simply won't do. Thankfully, we've rounded up the top resources in social media, business and tech to catch you back up to speed. We've continued our series of beginners' guides with cheat sheets on Twitter and Reddit. And in a week of password-hacking mania, we've got tips for ensuring that your LinkedIn and eHarmony profiles stay safe and secure. Be sure to check out our Google search tips and keyboard shortcuts, the latest episodes of our web ser&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, COMMUNICATIONS, Features Week In Review, Social Media, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/digital-media-resources-43/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/digital-media-resources-43/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Re-Imagination Of Everything: I&#8217;m Pissed That The Future&#8217;s Not Here Fast Enough</title>
      <description>I&#8217;ve seen the future, and it consists of a 5 foot eleven-inch hologram of Tupac rapping onstage with an incredibly stoned Snoop Dogg and Dr. Dre at Coachella. Despite all the (consumer Internet) startups I interact with, with the possible exception of TaskRabbit, Dropbox and Uber, this pretty old-school hologram technology applied in this completely novel use case is the closest I&#8217;ve ever come to feeling like I live in the future. I&#8217;m not alone, HoloTupac actually impressed KPCB analyst Mary Meeker, of all people, so much she included it in a surprisingly overlooked 50 slide portion of her famed Internet Trends presentation: &#8221;The Re-Imagination Of Almost Everything&#8221; as the &#8220;Re-Imagination Of Concerts.&#8221; According to Meeker, society is currently going through a phase of innovation that will inevitably result in an evolution of almost all products and services, a phase which is being fueled by an explosion of new mobile devices, easier connectivity, a renewed focus on UI and design and a &#8220;what do I have to lose?&#8221; economic environment. According to Meeker, we&#8217;re currently in the first generation of this re-imagination of everything &#8212; and she backs this her argument with the fact that Encyclopedia Britannica JUST went out of print a couple months ago. To Meeker, taxi&#8217;s will eventually be Ubers, drawing with pen and paper will eventually be replaced by the app Paper, VCs will be eliminated by Kickstarter and notes will fall to the wayside as people warm up to Evernote. The sum total of this disruption of the way humans live will eventually result in an addressable market of over $36 trillion according to her calculations. So here&#8217;s why I&#8217;m pissed: Arguably as I write this from our offices in SOMA, I&#8217;m at Ground Zero of this re-imagination (and across the street from the Creamery) but every time I go to a store (even said Creamery), I&#8217;m handed a paper receipt, which I may or may not recycle or toss. Sure the paper receipt business is multi-million dollar industry that likely employs a multitude of well meaning people, but it&#8217;s a business that couldn&#8217;t be destroyed a moment too soon. I mean think about how many receipts you&#8217;ve thrown away over a lifetime, now multiply that by a billion and think about the effect that has on the environment, among other things. Inefficiency at its finest. And yet, it&#8217;s still happening, despite the existence of payments technologies like Square, just like I still use Post-it notes in addition to Evernote. Every time a taxi driver bitches at me for using a credit card, I wonder why the Re-Imagination Of Everything hasn&#8217;t engulfed everything its wake. Same deal with purchasing postage stamps and flying United (ugh). The sad part is that the isn&#8217;t here yet. So much so that using the more successful re-imagined products, like using Postmates to pick up anything from anywhere, feels like going back to the future in a sense. It&#8217;s almost if we live in some sort of hybrid dystopia, with innovation only accessible to a wealthy, fortunate few, who even then have to slog through piles and piles of receipts to complete an expense report. I guess the only recourse is to ask you guys (the entrepreneurs in the room) to hurry the fuck up. Please read through Meeker&#8217;s slides below, and leave your suggestions for other industries that desperately need re-imagination in the comments. View this document on Scribd</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/09/the-re-imagination-of-everything-im-pissed-that-the-futures-not-here-fast-enough/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/09/the-re-imagination-of-everything-im-pissed-that-the-futures-not-here-fast-enough/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
