<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Olympics Venues Hit Foursquare</title>
      <description>Foursquare users can now check-in to Olympics venues around the world &#8212; and potentially win a trip to the 2012 London Games by doing so. The International Olympic Committee (IOC) launched check-in locations around the world and an official Olympics badge on Tuesday. The IOC&#8217;s official Foursquare page has details on more than 40 historic sites from past games and venues for the upcoming edition in London. Fans who check-in to at least two venues and follow the IOC on Foursquare will unlock the &#8220;Get Fit for Olympic Day&#8221; badge pictured above. They&#8217;ll also be entered into a contest for a trip to this summer&#8217;s Olympics in London. &#8220;Our integration with Foursquare and the ability to leave location-based tips from the athletes is one more way to serve highly engaged fans of the Olympic Games and to integrate social media directly into the Olympic fan experience,&#8221; Alex Huot, the IOC&#8217;s social media director, said in a press release. &#8220;We wanted to do something fun and thank our fans who make an effort to stay fit by offering them a chance to win a trip to the Olympics.&#8221; The Olympic Day tie-in refers to a holiday taking place June 23 to promote fitness and health in countries around the world. The holiday was first celebrated in 1948. Foursquare check-ins are just one aspect of what are being hyped by some as &#8220;the first social Olympics.&#8221; The IOC is heavily promoting social media, and Twitter and other platforms are expected to play a prominent role with fans, athletes and media in London. Last month the IOC unveiled its Olympics Athletes&#8217; Hub, a digital portal to verified athlete Facebook and Twitter feeds as well as additional digital content. However, a series of stringent restrictions on what fans and athletes can post from where during the Games has some crying foul. The 2012 Summer Olympics take place from July 27 through August 12 in London. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, nkbimages More About: foursquare, olympics, sportsFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/olympics-foursquare/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/olympics-foursquare/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siri, Y U No Understand Me? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Siri is a loyal mistress, following you wherever you go &#8212; but is she a good listener? Since the iPhone 4S began coming standard with Siri last October, the voice activated personal assistant has become a cultural phenomenon. Samuel L. Jackson and Zooey Deschanel star in Siri-themed ads for the phone. A creepy iPhone case forces you to interact with Siri. A different project enables Siri to destroy your phone if it&#8217;s lost or stolen, and a viral video shows what happens when Siri goes psycho. But everyone&#8217;s not impressed. In March, a man filed suit against Apple, alleging that Siri &#8220;does not perform as advertised.&#8221; Anecdotally, many others have complained that Siri doesn&#8217;t respond to voice commands and questions as hyped. Given the controversy, Internet education portal OnlineDegrees.com rounded up a number of studies and statistics from sources including The Wall Street Journal, ABC News and others over the past several months to produce the infographic below. Among the findings: 87% of iPhone 4S owners use Siri at least once per month, with just over half describing themselves as &#8220;satisfied&#8221; with her performance. 9% say they&#8217;re not satisfied, while 36% say they&#8217;re somewhere between happy and unhappy. Only two-thirds of users, however, employ Siri for anything beyond searching the web, making a phone call or sending a text. At least 30% of users say they would never use Siri to schedule a metting, play music or even send an email, while just a quarter use Siri to send emails on a daily basis. Check out the infographic below for more on how iPhone owners do &#8212; and don&#8217;t &#8212; use Siri. Then let us know in the comments &#8212; do you think Siri really works? More About: apple, infographics, iphone, siri</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/siri-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/siri-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight: Morgan Stanley cut Facebook estimates just before IPO</title>
      <description>, May 22, 2012 (Reuters) -- In the run-up to Facebook's $16 billion IPO, Morgan Stanley, the lead underwriter on the deal, unexpectedly delivered some negative news to major clients: The bank's consumer Internet analyst, Scott Devitt, was reducing his revenue forecasts for the company. &gt; read full story</description>
      <link>http://www.newsdaily.com/stories/bre84l069-us-facebook-forecasts/</link>
      <guid>http://www.newsdaily.com/stories/bre84l069-us-facebook-forecasts/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marvel Comics Fans: Submit Your Questions for Stan Lee</title>
      <description>Stan Lee, titan of the comic book industry, will be interviewed by Mashable&#8216;s Sam Laird on Thursday. For those unfamiliar, Stan Lee is one of the creative forces behind Marvel Comics. He took part in the creation and development of some of the most famous superheroes and comic book series, such as the Fantastic Four, Spider-Man, Iron Man, the Hulk, and X-Men. Without the vision and talent of Lee, the Marvel Comics franchise would not have grown to become the great success it is today. The company has converted many of the original comic book franchises into movies, including most recently The Avengers movie, which set a record for the highest grossing film on opening weekend. Even at 89 years of age, Lee is taking full advantage of digital media. He is currently in the process of launching his own comic convention and plans to bring all sorts of social engagement for those attending and following online. Lee has a showcase of awards and honors for his achievements including a member of the Will Eisner Comic Book Hall of Fame as well as receiving a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame. We&#8217;re taking questions for Stan from you, our Mashable readers. We want to know: what would you like to be able to ask the comic book visionary? We&#8217;ll choose some of the most unique, poignant, or just plain interesting reader-submitted questions to ask him. Submit your question in the comments below by Wednesday, May 23 at 8:00 P.M. EDT, and be sure to check back to read our interview with Stan Lee. Image courtesy Gage Skidmore, Flickr. More About: comic books, interviews, Marvel, Stan LeeFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/stan-lee-interview/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/stan-lee-interview/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow the Kentucky and Arkansas Primaries on Social Media</title>
      <description>Mitt Romney still hasn&#8217;t crossed the threshold to have locked up the Republican nomination for president, even though he&#8217;s more than 800 delegates ahead of his nearest rival, Ron Paul. Thus, the primaries continue on. Tuesday night is election night in Kentucky and Arkansas &#8212; and social media will be ablaze with tweets, twitpics and video from the night&#8217;s voting action. Whichever Republican candidate comes out on top in Arkansas is likely to carry the state in November&#8217;s general election, too &#8211; it&#8217;s a solid-red state with little love for President Obama. There are whispers that a write-in Democratic candidate could put up a fight against the president in the state, although that would have no real political significance. Both states will also feature primaries for races in the House of Representatives, which should prove more interesting to watch than the pretty-much-settled national-level showdown. In all of Tuesday night&#8217;s contests, politicians will be using social media to garner support, voters will be talking about their candidate of choice and journalists will be covering the election night story. Follow Mashable to see the best examples of social media&#8217;s use throughout the night. [View the story "The Kentucky and Arkansas Primaries on Social Media" on Storify] Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, Henrick5000 More About: 2012 presidential campaign, Politics, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/kentucky-arkansas-primaries/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/kentucky-arkansas-primaries/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Tests New Timeline Design [PICS]</title>
      <description>Facebook is testing a series of cosmetic changes to the top of users&#8217; Timelines, the company has confirmed. Screenshots of the new design were posted on Talking Points Memo Tuesday morning. The images (below) show a condensed version of Timeline, in which a user&#8217;s details (name, occupation, education, location) appear in reverse type on top of &#8212; rather than below &#8212; the cover photo. The carousel of thumbnail images highlighting friends, photos, places, likes, etc. has also been compressed. Images are now replaced by thumbnails. Next to these, a new &#8220;Summary&#8221; section appears, presumably to highlight key events on a user&#8217;s Timeline. The new version: The old (current) version: It&#8217;s not clear if the new design will give users greater control over the appearance of their Timelines. We&#8217;re curious to know, for instance, whether users will be able to modify the color of the type that appears on top of their cover photos. What do you think of the new design? Do you like the reverse type? Would you miss the thumbnail images if they were removed? BONUS: The Evolution of the Facebook Profile 2005 - The Facebook Back in the days when The Facebook was only available to select networks, the News Feed didn't exist. Users hopped between profiles like this one.Click here to view this gallery.Top image courtesy of iStockphoto, -Oxford- More About: Facebook, facebook timeline, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/facebook-tests-new-timeline-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/facebook-tests-new-timeline-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Want to Chat With Your Car? Meet Siri-Like Control for Automobiles</title>
      <description>Meet Dragon Drive!, the latest in talking-car technology. Nuance Communications unveiled on Tuesday a new Siri-like voice platform designed specifically for the connected car. The platform allows you to send and receive texts and email via voice commands in five languages, including English, French, Italian German and Spanish. For example, you can tell the system the following: &#8220;Reply to Alex, &#8216;Sushi sounds great. See you at 7.&#8217;&#8221; Although hands-free voice recognition software in cars is nothing new, adoption has been slow due to the unnatural nature of some of its commands. Nuance aims to simplify the process by blending the vehicle&#8217;s internal computers with cloud technology that can access your email and text messages, so you don&#8217;t even need to use your phone during the process. The company is working with manufacturers to get the solution integrated into new cars, so unfortunately drivers won&#8217;t be able to add the system to existing vehicles. &#8220;The entire automotive ecosystem faces a critical challenge &#8212; keep consumers connected to the content they love without imposing dangerous distractions behind the wheel,&#8221; said Arnd Weil, vice president and general manager at Nuance Mobile, in a statement. &#8220;Dragon Drive! has been designed from the ground up with a focus on voice and natural language, bridging that gap to give consumers the ability to take full advantage of the broad range of services today&#8217;s connected car has to offer.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Do People Really Want Self-Driving Cars? [VIDEO] Although Dragon Drive! is focused on messaging right now, the company said it will allow users to download songs, locate nearby restaurants and get directions in the future. Dragon Drive! is the first application in a series of Nuance products expected to hit the market soon. The industry expects the demand for connected to cars to grow significantly in the future. In fact, according to a report by IMS Research, the category is expected to jump 650% by 2017, reaching 40.5 million unit sales. Meanwhile, a recent JD Power 2012 U.S. Automotive Emerging Technologies Study showed that drivers are interested in the trend &#8212; about 69% of study participants said they want natural language voice activation functionality and 68% want wireless connectivity. Do you want to talk to your car? Is this truly the future of the automobile industry? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, fotografstockholm BONUS: New York Auto Show: The Coolest Car Tech Terrafugia's Transition Flying Car Here's that flying car you've been dreaming of your whole life. From aircraft company Aircraft company Terrafugia comes the Transition car, which touts four wheels, two wings and the ability fly two people anywhere.Click here to view this gallery. More About: cars, siri</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/nuance-dragon-drive/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/nuance-dragon-drive/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Facebook Wreck Marriages?</title>
      <description>Real-Time Advice: Newlywed CEO Mark Zuckerberg may want to watch his status updates, divorce lawyers say. Facebook often gets blamed for breakups.</description>
      <link>http://blogs.smartmoney.com/advice/2012/05/21/does-facebook-wreck-marriages/?mod=1122</link>
      <guid>http://blogs.smartmoney.com/advice/2012/05/21/does-facebook-wreck-marriages/?mod=1122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Holds Its First Google+ Conference For Photographers</title>
      <description>There&#8217;s a good chance that last year around this time you didn&#8217;t know about Google+ &#8212; which wasn&#8217;t even in beta form yet &#8212; and &#8220;Hanging out&#8221; was something you only did in person. But the search engine giant has made big strides with its social network in the past 12 months, so much so that it&#8217;s hosting its first-ever Google+ conference in San Francisco this week for photographers. For the next two days Google is hosting what it calls a &#8220;HIRL&#8221; or &#8220;Hang Out in Real Life,&#8221; bringing together some of the biggest photographers with presences on Google+. The conference is designed to help photographers to refine their photography skills, grow their brand and get the most out of their Google+ experience. &#8220;We are photographers ourselves,&#8221; Bradley Horowitz, VP of product at Google, said during the opening keynote for the conference Tuesday. &#8220;We are geeks. Photography geeks are a sublayer of geek, and there are a lot of us on the Google+ team&#8221; While Google+ may be not be as popular on the social networking side as Facebook, the service is exceptionally popular for photographers, partly for how it handles content. &#8220;Photos are the lifeblood of our service,&#8221; says Horowitz. &#8220;We wanted to make the content the hero.&#8221; Photos on Google+ are typically displayed larger than they are on other services and offer several advantages for photographers, including the ability to carefully tailor which groups of people are able to see the photos uploaded to the service. If you&#8217;re not in San Francisco for the conference but love photography and Google+, you can still participate in the various sessions taking place over the next two days virtually via Google+ hangouts. Sessions are streamed live, and if you sign up for sessions via the Google+ Photographers conference app, you can ask questions during the talks and participate as if you were attending in person. What do you think about Google+ from a photography perspective? Will you attend the conference virtually? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Google, photography</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/google-holds-its-first-google-conference-for-photographers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/google-holds-its-first-google-conference-for-photographers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Holds Its First Google+ Conference For Photographers</title>
      <description>There&#8217;s a good chance that last year around this time you didn&#8217;t know about Google+ &#8212; which wasn&#8217;t even in beta form yet &#8212; and &#8220;Hanging out&#8221; was something you only did in person. But the search engine giant has made big strides with its social network in the past 12 months, so much so that it&#8217;s hosting its first-ever Google+ conference in San Francisco this week for photographers. For the next two days Google is hosting what it calls a &#8220;HIRL&#8221; or &#8220;Hang Out in Real Life,&#8221; bringing together some of the biggest photographers with presences on Google+. The conference is designed to help photographers to refine their photography skills, grow their brand and get the most out of their Google+ experience. &#8220;We are photographers ourselves,&#8221; Bradley Horowitz, VP of product at Google, said during the opening keynote for the conference Tuesday. &#8220;We are geeks. Photography geeks are a sublayer of geek, and there are a lot of us on the Google+ team&#8221; While Google+ may be not be as popular on the social networking side as Facebook, the service is exceptionally popular for photographers, partly for how it handles content. &#8220;Photos are the lifeblood of our service,&#8221; says Horowitz. &#8220;We wanted to make the content the hero.&#8221; Photos on Google+ are typically displayed larger than they are on other services and offer several advantages for photographers, including the ability to carefully tailor which groups of people are able to see the photos uploaded to the service. If you&#8217;re not in San Francisco for the conference but love photography and Google+, you can still participate in the various sessions taking place over the next two days virtually via Google+ hangouts. Sessions are streamed live, and if you sign up for sessions via the Google+ Photographers conference app, you can ask questions during the talks and participate as if you were attending in person. What do you think about Google+ from a photography perspective? Will you attend the conference virtually? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Google, photography</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/google-holds-its-first-google-conference-for-photographers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/google-holds-its-first-google-conference-for-photographers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Words that Simply Don't Exist in English</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://sobadsogood.com/2012/04/29/25-words-that-simply-dont-exist-in-english/</link>
      <guid>http://sobadsogood.com/2012/04/29/25-words-that-simply-dont-exist-in-english/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube</title>
      <description>Jeff Pidgeon: SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
