<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>FTC Issues First Internet Data Fine</title>
      <description>The Federal Trade Commission slapped data collection firm Spokeo with an $800,000 fine on Tuesday for collecting details about people's lives and selling them to would-be employers without protecting those individuals' privacy. It's the first FTC fine involving personal data collected online and sold to potential employers. The FTC argued in the case that Spokeo was running as a "consumer reporting agency" that violated the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FCRA) by not checking if the data it collected was accurate or would be used for legally permissible purposes. Spokeo also violated the FCRA by failing to notify people who were rejected from a potential job because of data it sold to&#8230; Continue reading... More About: data collection, Marketing, privacy, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/ftc-first-internet-data-fine/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/ftc-first-internet-data-fine/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On First Impressions of iOS 6</title>
      <description>iPad Siri The iPad has Sir.Click here to view this gallery. At WWDC 2012, Apple unveiled the next generation of iOS. iOS 6 sports more than 200 new features and upgrades -- including the new Apple Maps, deep Facebook integration and improvements to Siri. Although iOS 6 won't be available on compatible devices until sometime this fall, the first beta build is currently available to developers. We've gone ahead and installed iOS 6 on our new iPad (64GB Verizon LTE model) and poked around with the new features. While it is clear that this is a beta -- certain features aren't fully baked and there is some crashing and inconsistency with a few existing apps -- it's equally clear that this is a solid OS update. SEE ALSO: iOS 6: Everything You Need&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, apple maps, Facebook, features, iOS 6, ipad, iphone, siri</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/ios-6-beta-hands-on/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/ios-6-beta-hands-on/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Launches WordPress Tool, Makes Blogging More Social</title>
      <description>Facebook announced sweeping integrations for WordPress.org and WordPress.com VIP users on Tuesday morning -- allowing you to add your blog content to the social network in one click. The integrations are accessible through a Facebook for WordPress plugin (available here) and allow bloggers and administrators of WordPress-based sites to cross-publish content to WordPress, their own Facebook Timelines and the Facebook Pages they oversee. "The plugin was built by Facebook engineers in collaboration with open source partners, and makes it simple for anyone to make their WordPress site more social &#8211; no coding required," Facebook engineer Matt Kelly wrote in a blog post introducing t&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, WordPress</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/facebook-wordpress/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/facebook-wordpress/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Launches WordPress Tool, Makes Blogging More Social</title>
      <description>Facebook announced sweeping integrations for WordPress.org and WordPress.com VIP users on Tuesday morning -- allowing you to add your blog content to the social network in one click. The integrations are accessible through a Facebook for WordPress plugin (available here) and allow bloggers and administrators of WordPress-based sites to cross-publish content to WordPress, their own Facebook Timelines and the Facebook Pages they oversee. "The plugin was built by Facebook engineers in collaboration with open source partners, and makes it simple for anyone to make their WordPress site more social &#8211; no coding required," Facebook engineer Matt Kelly wrote in a blog post introducing t&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, WordPress</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/facebook-wordpress/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/facebook-wordpress/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Confirms Facebook Integration of Usernames, Hashtags, Photos</title>
      <description>Twitter has quietly tweaked the way usernames, hashtags, photos and more are cross-posted to Facebook. &#8220;The updated Twitter for Facebook integration now includes additional rich media experiences related to the first photo, URL, @mention or #hashtag in the cross-posted tweet,&#8221; Twitter spokesman Robert Weeks told Mashable on Thursday night. &#8220;This update is available for everyone.&#8221; Twitter&#8216;s Help Center also notes the changes, which Weeks says rolled out at the end of May: &#8220;We have fixed many issues with the Twitter for Facebook integration, including the ability to post to Facebook Pages, and added some new features!&#8221; Users who don&#8217;t see the integration working can disconnect their Twitter and Facebook accounts in their Twitter profile settings and then reconnect their accounts in their Twitter profile settings. SEE ALSO: Twitter Rewind &#8212; Big Highlights From 2012 to 2006 Facebook user Damien Basile tipped Mashable off to the changes (see examples above). BONUS: Twitter&#8217;s Top Tweets-Per-Second Moments 1. Castle in the Sky on TV Anime movie Laputa: Castle in the Sky was televised in Japan on Dec. 9, 2011. The movie was made in 1989 by famed director Hayou Miyazaki, who also directed Spirited Away and Princess Mononoke. During one point in televised broadcast in 2011, viewers joined forces, sending tweets at the same time to symbolically help the movie's characters cast a spell. Data compiled by Brian Anthony Hernandez; gallery created by Chelsea Stark. Image courtesy of che_fox, Flickr.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, hashtags, Social Media, TwitterFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/twitter-facebook-integration-usernames-hashtags/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/twitter-facebook-integration-usernames-hashtags/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Confirms Facebook Integration of Usernames, Hashtags, Photos</title>
      <description>Twitter has quietly tweaked the way usernames, hashtags, photos and more are cross-posted to Facebook. &#8220;The updated Twitter for Facebook integration now includes additional rich media experiences related to the first photo, URL, @mention or #hashtag in the cross-posted tweet,&#8221; Twitter spokesman Robert Weeks told Mashable on Thursday night. &#8220;This update is available for everyone.&#8221; Twitter&#8216;s Help Center also notes the changes, which Weeks says rolled out at the end of May: &#8220;We have fixed many issues with the Twitter for Facebook integration, including the ability to post to Facebook Pages, and added some new features!&#8221; Users who don&#8217;t see the integration working can disconnect their Twitter and Facebook accounts in their Twitter profile settings and then reconnect their accounts in their Twitter profile settings. SEE ALSO: Twitter Rewind &#8212; Big Highlights From 2012 to 2006 Facebook user Damien Basile tipped Mashable off to the changes (see examples above). BONUS: Twitter&#8217;s Top Tweets-Per-Second Moments 1. Castle in the Sky on TV Anime movie Laputa: Castle in the Sky was televised in Japan on Dec. 9, 2011. The movie was made in 1989 by famed director Hayou Miyazaki, who also directed Spirited Away and Princess Mononoke. During one point in televised broadcast in 2011, viewers joined forces, sending tweets at the same time to symbolically help the movie's characters cast a spell. Data compiled by Brian Anthony Hernandez; gallery created by Chelsea Stark. Image courtesy of che_fox, Flickr.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, hashtags, Social Media, TwitterFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/twitter-facebook-integration-usernames-hashtags/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/twitter-facebook-integration-usernames-hashtags/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TiVo + PayPal = Click-to-Buy TV Ads</title>
      <description>Removing a step or two between advertising and purchasing, TiVo on Tuesday announced it has teamed with PayPal so users can easily buy products they see in TV ads. The deal means that advertisers can now add a new dimension to their 30-second TV spots and interactive TiVo ad placements. Users who like an advertised product can do so with a few clicks of their remote after they set up their accounts. Such ads are not ones that typically run during broadcasts but instead pop up during various interactions such as when shows are paused. Ads sporting the feature will begin circulating during the fall 2012 TV season. The companies did not name advertisers that are using the platform. TiVo h&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Advertising, paypal, tivo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/tivo-paypal-click-to-buy-tv-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/tivo-paypal-click-to-buy-tv-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magazine Cover Saying Rachael Ray Cooks Dog Goes Viral &#8212; But It&#8217;s Fake</title>
      <description>A magazine cover suggesting that a popular television chef and talk show host enjoys cooking her family and dog is a fake, the publication's founder said. The image, which shows Rachael Ray and her dog on the cover of Tails magazine, includes a subheadline claiming the TV personality "finds inspiration in cooking her family and her dog." The photo has gone viral, cropping up in Facebook feeds for months as an example of poor punctuation changing the meaning of a phrase. But the problem is, the image was altered from the original, which claims Ray finds more conventional "inspiration in cooking, her family, and her dog." Tails founder Janice Brown told journalists that the doctored cover first appeared about two years ago on the site Funny Or Die and has circulated ever since, but she finally felt compelled to defend her publication last year. But the cover has swept across Facebook again in recent days, and she was contacted by media blogger Jim Romensko about the image. "We let it go for a bit -- it's funny and all that -- but when people started attacking our professionalism, saying we didn't do copy editing and proofing, we set the record straight," Brown said. Brown said Tails reaches 150,000 monthly subscribers and employs six staffers, including a copy editor. The "setting it straight" post will be placed in a more prominent location on the magazine's website, Brown said.</description>
      <link>http://www.wlwt.com/news/entertainment/Rachael-Ray-doesn-t-cook-her-dog-or-her-family/-/9837584/14788322/-/gnhw2b/-/index.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.wlwt.com/news/entertainment/Rachael-Ray-doesn-t-cook-her-dog-or-her-family/-/9837584/14788322/-/gnhw2b/-/index.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat vs. Thunder: The NBA Finals of Twitter [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>The 2012 NBA Finals tip off Tuesday night with a hugely intriguing matchup between LeBron James's Miami Heat and Kevin Durant's Oklahoma City Thunder. The series may go seven games before we know who deserves the Larry O'Brien Championship Trophy, but the pre-series results are already in as far as the Twittershere is concerned -- and the Heat win in a route. Over the course of the playoffs, the Heat have been mentioned about 750,000 times compared to about 285,000 mentions for the Thunder. Heat players, meanwhile, count about twice as many cumulative followers as the Thunder. The social media analytics company PeopleBrowsr recently pulled this data and more using its Kred influe&#8230; Continue reading... More About: NBA, sports, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/nba-finals-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/nba-finals-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Brands Are Becoming Publishers</title>
      <description>According to Deanna Brown, CEO of Federated Media Publishing, &#8220;Content, in the right context, is ultimately king.&#8221; The publishing industry is undergoing a massive disruption, in which storytelling, advertising, and technology are beginning to intersect. By having unhindered access to social and mobile media platforms, brands are experimenting with paid, owned, and earned media to reach connected consumers in their channels of relevance. As brands dabble in publishing, traditional marketing and advertising networks are also evolving. Federated Media is no stranger to the game. On this episode of Revolution, Deanna Brown explores the curre&#8230; Continue reading... More About: brands, content marketing, revoltiontv, storytelling, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/revolution-federated-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/revolution-federated-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden Twitter Experiment Goes Painfully Awry</title>
      <description>The Swedish government has been handing over the @sweden Twitter account to a different citizen each week, and this week's owner is steering the car right off a social media cliff. The project began in December, but an article in The New York Times brought the story to a new level of prominence Monday after a series of questionable tweets. Tuesday, the current Swede behind the account doubled down on the controversial tweeting, as seen below. When the project began as a means to promote Sweden as a tourist destination, Thomas Br&#252;hl, CEO of VisitSweden, told Mashable &#8220;No one owns the brand of Sweden more than its people. With this initiative we let them show their Sweden to th&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Marketing, Social Media, sweden, trending, Twitter, viral, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/sweden-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/sweden-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You Kill Someone, Don&#8217;t Google it First</title>
      <description>A Florida couple accused of strangling a 19-year-old girl reportedly searched Google for advice on murder methods and later discussed what to do with the body through text messages and Facebook. James Ayers, 32, and Nicole Okrzesik, 23, researched &#8220;chemicals to passout a person,&#8221; &#8220;making people faint,&#8221; &#8220;ways to kill people in their sleep,&#8221; &#8220;how to suffocate someone&#8221; and &#8220;how to poison someone&#8221; on Google just minutes before killing Juliana Mensch. According to police, Mensch slept on the floor while the couple trolled the Internet. The duo were friends with Mensch, even getting high with her in their Fort Lauderdale home, but dec&#8230; Continue reading... More About: crime, Florida, Google, murder</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/florida-couple-murder-google/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/florida-couple-murder-google/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
