<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>25 Words that Simply Don't Exist in English</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://sobadsogood.com/2012/04/29/25-words-that-simply-dont-exist-in-english/</link>
      <guid>http://sobadsogood.com/2012/04/29/25-words-that-simply-dont-exist-in-english/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where's the heat?</title>
      <description>Is that your goal? To find the next hot thing? Do you want to buy it, sell it, use it, eat it? In every industry where there's fashion (which is every industry), people spend an enormous amount of time looking for heat. It defines the cutting edge, determines what's in or out, what's hot or not. Two things worth considering: a. the hot thing isn't always the thing that's aligned with your goals. Sure, sometimes the most profitable item is also the hot item of the moment, but for many companies, market share or profitability or utility has not a lot to do with being on the cutting edge of fashion. And as a user, the hot item of the moment isn't necessarily the thing that will create value or even identify you as truly hip. b. The cycle of hot keeps getting shorter. You can chase this, but it's not free, and it might not get you where you want to go.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/wheres-the-heat.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/wheres-the-heat.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A true story</title>
      <description>Of course, that's impossible. There's no such thing as a true story. As soon as you start telling a story, making it relevant and interesting to me, hooking it into my worldviews and generating emotions and memories, it ceases to be true, at least if we define true as the whole truth, every possible fact, non-localized and regardless of culture. Since you're going to tell a story, you might as well get good at it, focus on it and tell it in a way that you're proud of.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/a-true-story.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/a-true-story.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Weekly Email Digests: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Twitter Brings Weekly Email Digest to Your Inbox: You can now &#8220;discover the best of Twitter in a weekly email digest delivered to your inbox. This summary features the most relevant tweets and stories shared by the people you&#8217;re connected to on Twitter.&#8221;"Stories feature a design similar to the recently updated Discover tab, emphasizing who shared each story beneath summaries to help you decide which ones matter most to you."Facebook Initial Public Offering Proves Social is Hot: &#8220;Facebook has priced its initial public offering at $38 per share, making it the third-largest IPO in U.S. history.&#8221;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiuX64iHrgMDiscussion from our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:The importance of social media monitoringHow to set up specific social media goalsHow to track your blog with Google AnalyticsFacebook Insights Has Two New Features for Apps: You can now check App Ratings and Negative Feedback for your apps on Facebook Insights. &#8220;App Ratings and Negative Feedback can inform not only how you design your app experience to increase engagement and satisfaction, but also how your app grows through the App Center.&#8221;The new App Ratings provide a variety of information including statistics by gender and age.Facebook Improves Mobile News Feed Design: The photos in your mobile Facebook news feed are now much bigger. Shares of single photos look a lot like Instagrams.Photos shared on Facebook are now larger on mobile news feeds.Facebook Slowly Launches Facebook Pages Manager iPhone App Outside of the U.S.: iPhone users in Australia, New Zealand and possibly a few other countries can currently download a free Facebook Pages Manager app to manage their Facebook pages.This new app helps Facebook page managers on the go.Google Adds More Google+ Integration Inside Gmail: &#8220;Today&#8217;s changes include quick access to contact details when viewing past conversations as well as improved integration with Google+ circles.&#8221; in the search box.&#8221;"]"Circles are also now supported in search and filters. Find messages from a specific circle by typing circle:[circle nameLinkedIn Today Redesign: LinkedIn Today has a new design. LinkedIn has &#8220;made changes across the product experience to offer further customization of news so that members can receive the most timely and relevant news impacting their peers and industry.&#8221;There's a &#8220;Customize your news&#8221; tab on the right side which enables you to control the news feed in LinkedIn Today.LinkedIn Introduces Windows Phone App: This is LinkedIn&#8217;s latest mobile application."You&#8217;ll find that in some cases (hint: companies and jobs), the Windows Phone app offers even more functionality than its iOS and Android siblings."Here&#8217;s a useful social media tool worth noting:Scan-to-gram: A tool to turn your Instagram profile into a QR code.Scan-to-gram provides a new fun way for companies to have a web presence and grow their following on Instagram.What social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/twitter-weekly-email-digests-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/twitter-weekly-email-digests-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalization Is Not A Feature</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: Scott Brave is the CTO and co-founder, Baynote. We&#8217;ve all watched from the sidelines as companies have come out in a burst of glory, and then, two years later, spent their venture capital, lost their user base, and failed to monetize. This begs the question &#8211; what are the factors that drive a company&#8217;s survival, differentiate it, and ultimately make it a winner? In today&#8217;s online world, personalization is increasingly making or breaking companies. The companies that win are the ones making personalization a key company value &#8211; not just a feature. In the early days of the web, consumers were happy just to gain access to information. However, as technology became more sophisticated, and as more consumers and companies came online, we quickly moved out of the access age and into a state of information overload, often leaving consumers frustrated and confused. Companies that helped consumers cut through the clutter to reveal relevant information had a critical and sustainable competitive advantage in their respective areas. The concept of relevance is critical to the success of Google, for example. Personalization is not new. Popularized by Amazon and Netflix more than a decade ago, personalization is the practice of tailoring information to people based on what they are looking for, what they have found interesting in the past, what their friends have engaged with, or based on explicit inputs like their interests. Personalization has gotten a lot of positive attention recently because it can be used to great effect to organize the web&#8217;s information overflow into relevant, meaningful experiences. Winning companies approach personalization as a core value of how they do business &#8211; a &#8220;customer-centric&#8221; philosophy &#8211; rather than an add-on &#8220;feature.&#8221; As proof, here are some examples of companies that have built their businesses around personalization and the competition that they left in their wake. News: Flipboard vs. Yahoo! News In 2001, Yahoo! launched Yahoo! News, providing a repository for news articles that became the first-ever most-emailed page on the web. However, Yahoo! News neglected to treat personalization as a core value &#8211; and in so doing missed out on the opportunity to tap into the social graph of personal information to personalize and curate content for users based on their interests. With Yahoo! treating personalization as a feature and not a core value, by 2010, consumers moved on to new, more personalized content curation services that were specifically designed for consuming media. One example of such a personalized news source is Flipboard, which works across Apple devices, and allows users to &#8220;flip&#8221; through their social networking feeds and feeds from partner websites to find the news articles that are most interesting to them. Within a year of its founding, Flipboard had amassed a $200 million valuation. Today, the company&#8217;s valuation and user base continues to skyrocket, while Yahoo!&#8217;s continues to hemorrhage. Flipboard won because it applied personalization to consumer choice for news articles that other news providers hadn&#8217;t accounted for, sparking the beginning of the content curation boom. Interestingly, Yahoo! recently announced plans to eliminate many of its online properties in order to focus on its most popular ones and make the content on those sites personalized to the user. It seems Yahoo! has finally caught on to the fact that users like personalized content and will engage with brands and services that provide content tailored to their interests. Music: Pandora vs. Internet radio This example seems counter-intuitive &#8211; wouldn&#8217;t people want to listen to their favorite radio station online? This just never took off. Why? Internet radio contained way too much content &#8211; it wasn&#8217;t focused or specific enough. Consumers had to work too hard to find the music they liked. Once consumers were introduced to a better way to curate and listen to music, they were never going back. When Pandora allowed users to input their music preferences through both explicit selections and implicit actions to help shape their content stream, it changed the listening experience. Pandora made listening to music online personal. After Pandora, just listening to the radio online seemed like a waste of time. Dining: Alfred (Google) vs. Opentable OpenTable provides a free service that lets users make reservations online. The company first came on the scene in 1998, and has steadily built up its business &#8211; today over 25,000 restaurants are signed up with the service. While OpenTable provides restaurant recommendations along the side of the screen based on location, it is a feature rather than being core to the experience. Alfred, on the other hand, is a mobile app developed by Clever Sense (purchased by Google in December) that delivers dining recommendations based exclusively on your inputs and your Facebook check-ins and profile. By offering recommendations for restaurants that are personalized to consumer&#8217;s inputs and behavior Google could become a leading provider of time-critical dining data, and a big player in the multi-billion dollar restaurant industry. These examples have all shown how companies that embrace personalization as a core value, and not just a feature can win. In today&#8217;s consumer-driven society companies that don&#8217;t pay attention to what people want most at any given moment risk losing significant market share to competitors that have built a culture around delighting customers with a highly personalized experience at every turn.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/18/personalization-is-not-a-feature/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/18/personalization-is-not-a-feature/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anonymous Hackers Claim to Take Down Chicago Police Website</title>
      <description>The Chicago Police Department website is down, and &#8220;hactivists&#8221; from the group Anonymous are taking credit. It&#8217;s part of a protest in Chicago against the NATO summit, where U.S. President Barack Obama is meeting with world leaders. Activists are protesting NATO&#8217;s policies, holding signs such as &#8220;War (equals) Debt,&#8221; and &#8220;NATO, Go Home.&#8221; Members of the hacker group Anonymous, calling themselves &#8220;AntiS3curityOPS,&#8221; posted a video on YouTube with an ominous message to the Chicago Police Department, but that video has since been made private. We added a full transcript of the video to the bottom of this post. In the bold video manifesto, the group responded to what it perceived as police brutality against the protesters on Saturday night, and vowed to take action: &#8220;We are actively engaged in actions against the Chicago Police Department, and encourage anyone to take up the cause and use the AntiS3curityOPS Anonymous banner. For those able, chicagopolice.org should be fired upon as much as possible. We are in your harbor Chicago, and you will not forget us.&#8221; Police are investigating the possible hacking of the city of Chicago&#8217;s website, according to the Chicago Sun-Times. Law enforcement officials told the AP late Saturday they planned to arrest people committing violent acts. Said police superintendent Garry McCarthy, &#8220;If anything else happens, the plan is to go in and get the people who create the violent acts, take them out of the crowd and arrest them. We&#8217;re not going to charge the crowd wholesale &#8212; that&#8217;s the bottom line.&#8221; At press time, the site, CityofChicago.org was still inaccessible. According to Cyber War News, the Anonymous group also claimed to have taken the NATO website offline, but it was accessible early Sunday afternoon. Here&#8217;s a transcript from the Anonymous video that has since been removed from YouTube: Greetings fellow citizens of the world. We are AntiS3curityOPS. While this has come to no surprise, the NATO protests are already reaching a boiling point. As tonight we have already witnessed the Chicago Police Dept sending out a request for two water cannons deployed on Michigan Avenue, which the protesters briefly were able to close off the street completely. Just a few moments ago we witnessed cops on horses seemingly all too content with the destiny that has turned their hearts cold, trampling over protesters trying to intimidate. And you know what we saw during this? Protesters locking arms and holding their ground. A few had Anonymous masks on, a few were girls who looked like they belonged safely off on the sidelines bravely charging cops with shields and on horse. All the while the protesters are chanting &#8220;Take those animals off those horses,&#8221; drowning out any attempts by the Chicago police to get a word in. Everyone of you are heros to us. What we saw tonight watching a bit of the protest was everyday, average people fighting back and finally refusing to stand down. The NATO Summit is being utilized in such a way, and we couldn&#8217;t have predicted it more accurately. On the video we saw mothers, teenagers, elderly, the anarchists, white, black, Hispanic &#8212; this movement sees no skin color. Every sort of person is well represented in these actions. This is not a time to have our differences divide us; this is a time we all need to come together and rally around our brothers and sisters bravely in the streets of Chicago risking their lives to make the one voice they have, heard. If every single one of us has a voice, one opinion, let us unite and show the violent Chicago police, and the government big brother tactics that we are not going to take this. We are actively engaged in actions against the Chicago Police Deptartment, and encourage anyone to take up the cause and use the AntiS3curityOPS Anonymous banner. For those able, chicagopolice.org should be fired upon as much as possible. We are in your harbor Chicago, and you will not forget us. So for those unable to engage in attacks online by ddos, share with everyone you know what&#8217;s presently going on in Chicago, Tweet celebrities on twitter with the #SolidarityWithChicago #FuckNATO #FTP hashtags and get it trending. Also keep watching the live feeds, and spreading the live feed links all relevant places. Together, we the people, are going to take the power back. We are AntiS3curityOPS. We are Anonymous. We are legion. We do not forget. We do not forgive. Chicago Police Department, expect us. Images courtesy of Flickr, gaelx More About: anonymous, hacking, protests</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/anonymous-hackers-police-website/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/anonymous-hackers-police-website/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecommerce in China: How the World&#8217;s Biggest Market Buys Online</title>
      <description>China is poised to become the biggest online marketplace in the world within the next few years, according to multiple estimates. Online retail generated $121 billion in sales in China last year, up 66% from 2010, according to Barclays Capital. The size of China&#8217;s ecommerce market is expected to more than triple over the next three years, with sales reaching $420 billion by 2015. That&#8217;s 20% more than what the U.S.&#8217;s ecommerce market is forecast to bring in that year. China has an estimated 193 million online shoppers, more than any other country. By 2015, those consumers will be spending $1,000 per year online &#8212; the same amount that U.S.&#8217;s 170 million online shoppers currently spend annually. By that time, ecommerce could account for more than 8% of all retail sales in China, Boston Consulting Group predicts. A number of factors are driving the growth. One is the increase of China&#8217;s middle class, which is expected to balloon from 200 million to 800 million people over the next 20 years, according to Acquity Group. The spread of government-subsidized, high-speed Internet access and Internet-connected cellphones have widened the pool of potential shoppers to 513 million &#8212; or about 40% of the population. Broadband Internet access costs around $10 per month, compared to $30 per month in India and $27 per month in Brazil. Shipping prices and reliability have also been improved, particularly in urban coastal cities: Shipping costs Chinese corporations about a sixth of what their American counterparts pay, according to BCG. Impressively, China&#8217;s major online marketplace, Alibaba-owned Taobao, is estimated to account for half of all packages shipped in China. People in China shop online for three main reasons, according to an Acquity Group survey conducted among 1,000 people across roughly 150 cities last year. One, greater product selection. (A separate survey by BCG found that a quarter of Chinese shoppers buy online because they can&#8217;t get the products they want at brick-and-mortar stores.) Two, the ability to compare prices across vendors: 65% of respondents said they compared retailers before making a purchase. Three, convenience. Still, ecommerce is a young industry in China. Although more people are shopping online in China as the U.S., penetration is much lower, relative to the population; only 14% of China&#8217;s 1.3 billion residents shop online, compared to about 54% in the U.S. Chinese shoppers are also gravitating towards lower-priced items. What&#8217;s holding them back? Trust appears to be the primary issue. As was the case with other markets, including the U.S., the early days of online shopping in China have been plagued by credit card fraud and counterfeit goods &#8212; some of which are swapped out for genuine articles during shipment. These two issues have been addressed, in part, by the introduction of PayPal-like payment services, including Alibaba-owned Alipay, which allows users to make purchases without sharing their credit card details with individual vendors. As an extra security measure, Alipay only transfers payments to vendors after clients have received and expressed satisfaction with their goods. Poor return policies are also thwarting growth. Fifty-nine percent of respondents in Acquity&#8217;s study complained that it wasn&#8217;t easy to return goods to online stores. And although shipping infrastructure is improving in China, it still has a long way to go, particularly outside major cities. &#8220;Literally thousands of Tier 3 and Tier 4 cities do not have the logistics or supply chains to make products easily available locally,&#8221; Simon Cousins, CEO of public relations firm Illuminant, told Fast Company. Apparel is the most popular buying category, making up roughly half of all online sales in China. (By comparison, apparel makes up about a fifth of online retail sales in the U.S.) And while sales of physical goods are increasing quickly, digital content is growing at a slower rate, making up about one-third of all online sales, says BCG. The Major Players The three big Internet companies in China are Alibaba, Baidu and Tencent, which dominate three different categories of the market: ecommerce, search and messaging, respectively. The vast majority of online transactions in China &#8212; 85% as of 2009 &#8212; take place between consumers, according to AK Kearney&#8217;s estimates. Approximately 90% of those transactions are executed on Alibaba-owned Taobao, frequently described as the &#8220;eBay of China.&#8221; Like eBay, users on Taobao can purchase and sell new and used goods at fixed or negotiated prices, as well as through auction-style listings. Unlike eBay, most goods are new, and there are no listing or transaction fees &#8212; the majority of Taobao&#8217;s revenue comes from advertising. Next year, the company will bring in $716 million in pre-tax earnings and will be worth $14.3 billion, according to estimates from Goldman Sachs. Business-to-consumer retail is quickly gaining steam online, however: AK Kearney estimates that B2C transactions will make up 40% of the market by 2015. About half of B2C transactions currently take place on Taobao Mall, or Tmall, another Alibaba property. There, 50,000 merchants and 200,000 brands, including major western brands like Nike and Gap, have already set up shop. Unlike Taobao, Tmall charges businesses fees for transactions. An estimated $16 billion in sales was generated on Tmall in 2011, a figure BCG expects will double this year. Together, Taobao and Tmall were responsible for 81% of online transactions by dollar amount in 2010. Forty-eight thousand products were sold per minute on Taobao that year, more than the number sold by China&#8217;s top five brick-and-mortar retailers combined. More than 60% of buyers on Taobao and Tmall pay for their transactions using Alipay, a payment system comparable to PayPal. Twenty percent of transactions on B2C sites are also paid for using Alipay. Other players in the space include 360buy.com, a multibrand retailer often described as the online, Chinese equivalent of Best Buy. It is the second largest B2C site in China, generating around $5 billion in sales in 2011. Individual brands are also setting up shop to sell directly to consumers. Social Media&#8217;s Role Because Chinese consumers distrust advertising and news sources, recommendations from online reviewers and peers on social networks have heightened roles. Ninety-five percent of Internet users living in Tier 1, 2 and 3 cities in China are registered on at least one social media site, according to a study released by McKinsey in April. They&#8217;re active, too: 91% of the survey&#8217;s 5,700 respondents said they had visited a social media site in the previous six months, compared to 67% in the U.S. and 30% in Japan. They spend 46 minutes per day on social media sites, compared to 37 minutes in the U.S. and seven minutes in Japan. More than 40% of online shoppers in China consume and post product reviews online &#8212; about double the percentage of online shoppers in the U.S., according to BCG. Why the distrust of advertising? &#8220;Advertising is associated with [government] propaganda,&#8221; Calvin Soh, a former chief creative officer of Publicis Asia, told me in a conversation at Asia&#8217;s Fashion Summit in Singapore this week. &#8220;Social media is the people.&#8221; In terms of volume of users, MySpace-like Qzone leads with 536 million, followed by microblogging platforms Tencent Weibo (310 million) and Sina Weibo (250 million), according to a November 2011 report from we are social. Renren, a Facebook-like site particularly popular among students, has 137 million users. Kaixin, another Facebook-like site popular especially among white collar office workers, has 116 million. Demographics vary among networks: Consumers who identify Sina Weibo as their favorite site tend to have higher incomes and are more likely to live in Tier 1 cities, McKinsey finds. McKinsey believes that social media has a greater influence on purchasing decisions for consumers in China than for anywhere else in the world. &#8220;People rely more on word-of-mouth from friends, family and key opinion leaders, many of whom share information on social media,&#8221; the study reads. But many companies in China have yet to leverage social media properly, McKinsey says. There&#8217;s a lack of familiarity with online social platforms at the executive level. Many companies are also failing to mine consumer insight data from these platforms &#8212; and many who are have yet to act on the information they&#8217;ve gathered. International Entry Given the growth projections for China&#8217;s retail market, it&#8217;s no surprise that foreign brands are increasingly upping their investments in the region. Investment began in earnest in the 1980s, when sports apparel brands like Nike and Adidas, luxury and accessory giants such as LVMH, and fast food franchises including Yum! Brands (and later, in 1990, McDonalds) began moving into the region. At the time, real estate in Tier 1 cities was comparatively cheap, and foreign brands established themselves through aggressive brick-and-mortar expansion, says Maureen Mullen, head of research and advisory services at L2. Nike, for instance, now has more than 6,000 stores in China. In a report on fashion and China, BCG describes China&#8217;s consumer markets in the &#8217;80s as &#8220;unsophisticated, yet eager,&#8221; one &#8220;hungry for highly recognizable brands.&#8221; Sportswear brands did particularly well because they complimented &#8220;the low-key wardrobe needs of consumers at a time when there were very few occasions that required more fashionable apparel.&#8221; By 2008, between 20% and 25% of the average Chinese consumer&#8217;s wardrobe was composed of sportswear by dollar amount. Foreign luxury brands have also fared well, particularly apparel, accessories, beauty and auto brands, as well as watchmakers. These categories are favored in China as channels for conspicuous consumption. &#8220;People don&#8217;t have homes to invest in in the China; homes are small, not spaces to invite your friends and display your wealth,&#8221; Julie Harris, global managing director of trend forecasting agency WGSN, tells Mashable. &#8220;As a result, conspicuous consumption manifests itself in what they wear.&#8221; Mid-range brands like Gap and Abercrombie &amp; Fitch have had a tougher time in China. The former, for instance, has only about 15 stores in the country. &#8220;There is not a clear ground for mid-range brands to stand,&#8221; says Angelia Teo, content director of WGSN&#8217;s Asia-Pacific region. &#8220;China understands luxury and heritage, it understands best-in-class product, it understands value,&#8221; she says. Brands that simply do a look well, like Abercrombie &amp; Fitch or Hollister, are not as appealing. You have to be cheap, or &#8220;you have to offer craft or technique or a unique point-of-view,&#8221; she explains. What&#8217;s Next Mullen says it&#8217;s increasingly important for Chinese companies to focus on ecommerce, whether they&#8217;re established international conglomerates or young retail startups. &#8220;If you look at wealth creation in China, 75% is expected to come from some 200 Tier 2 and Tier 3 cities. To build out an aggressive brick-and-mortar presence would be a huge challenge, at this point.&#8221; Those investments might not pay off in the short-term, says Mullen, but that will change as the online retail market grows. One thing&#8217;s for sure: China&#8217;s ecommerce market is certainly a very different beast than the U.S.&#8217;s. Images courtesy of Flickr, Kent Wang, Robert Ennals More About: Business, china, ecommerce, economy, fashion, features, luxury, retailFor more Startups coverage:Follow Mashable Startups on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Startups channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/ecommerce-china/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/ecommerce-china/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Marketing</title>
      <description>I have been asked this question a lot lately, &#8220;Where do you think marketing is headed?&#8221; and &#8220;What is the future of digital marketing?&#8221;. Given the changes affecting how consumers reach brands, how marketers reach consumers and how companies are approaching marketing I wanted to write about these questions that have surfaced recently.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/wenbryant/508467/future-marketing</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/wenbryant/508467/future-marketing</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Zuckerberg&#8217;s Bride, Priscilla Chan? [PICS]</title>
      <description>The Facebook founder married his girlfriend of nine years on Saturday, May 19, just one day after the the company&#8217;s stock went public. On Sunday, the interwebs were asking &#8220;who is the woman now married to the 28-year-old billionaire?&#8221; Her Facebook profile provides some details: Chan was born in Braintree, Massachusetts and graduated from Quincy High School in 2003. Chan graduated from Harvard in 2007 with a degree in biology. It was at Harvard where she met Mark. She worked as a fourth- and fifth-grade science teacher for about a year, from 2007-2008, until she left to pursue a graduate degree at University of California, San Francisco to become a doctor. She graduated last week, and that&#8217;s what the pleasantly surprised wedding guests thought they were celebrating. Take a look at the reactions to news of the wedding from those in the Twitterverse: Congratulations to Mark Zuckerberg on his wedding. The couple is registered at Morgan Stanley. All items are $38 &#8212; not a penny less. &#8212; Eddy Elfenbein (@EddyElfenbein) May 20, 2012 I hope MySpace Tom caught the bouquet at Mark Zuckerberg&#8217;s wedding reception. &#8212; Nick Stadler (@NickadooLA) May 20, 2012 Seems like Mark Zuckerberg&#8217;s wedding was the honeymoon to Facebook&#8217;s IPO &#8212; jhoney (@jhoney954) May 20, 2012 Congratulations, Mark Zuckerberg and Priscilla Chan! It&#8217;s a shame you didn&#8217;t invite all your 800 million friends. &#8212; Carl Jerome Velasco (@prattlechap) May 20, 2012 Mark and Priscilla Photo courtesy Facebook/Priscilla ChanClick here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, mark zuckerberg</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/priscilla-chan/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/priscilla-chan/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Branding: It All Began With A Picture</title>
      <description>Your photo speaks volumes about you: make sure those volumes are filled in with your hopes, aspirations, personality and talent and not the result of a haphazard occurrence that you have been too careless to display. Your quality picture will pay off big: and the more visible you are, the higher the return. So get ready to collect.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/danielschawbel/510460/it-all-began-picture</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/danielschawbel/510460/it-all-began-picture</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surprisingly entertained by http://t.co/FrO3KhwG, probably mostly because the random metrics it chose seemed to consider me quite pleasant.</title>
      <description>Tom Coates: Surprisingly entertained by http://t.co/FrO3KhwG, probably mostly because the random metrics it chose seemed to consider me quite pleasant. &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://Klouchebag.com</link>
      <guid>http://Klouchebag.com</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Fascinating Things We Learned From Reddit This Week</title>
      <description>1. What Your PC Is Doing During Shutdown This in-depth explanation of what the computer does when it shuts down is fascinating. For many in the tech world, this may seem like a no-brainer, but there are a lot of people who may believe the PC simply turns off and remains dead until the user turns the power back on. The discussion leads to why hard reboots and stopping software installations half-way are not good for your computer -- something basic users might not realize. Originally, the user posted his question on Google, but could only find information on viruses. Image courtesy of David MastersClick here to view this gallery.Reddit often gets a lot of flack. Under all of the chatter, upcoming memes and viral videos, there are tons of conversations that share at least one new, interesting fact every day. The web is moving past the stigma that crowdsourced sites like Wikipedia are unreliable. On Reddit, as it is with any source, users know that every fact must be carefully scrutinized. But Reddit is getting more credible every day. There are educated conversations happening with professionals in technology, fashion, medicine, science, history and pop culture &#8212; among other fields. Even celebrities and professionals are taking to the platform to hold casual interviews with its users, because let&#8217;s face it, these are some of the smartest people who see through the crap on the Internet. We&#8217;ve gathered five interesting facts you may, or may not, have already known that came from a discussion on Reddit. More About: computer, fact, fashion, features, reddit, Science, TED, water</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/reddit-learning/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/reddit-learning/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
