<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Sony Says PSN Services Will Resume Shortly, Offers Apology</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.crunchgear.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/PlayStation-Default-554x341.jpg" class="right"/&gt;As the initial hysteria (mostly justified) surrounding the &lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/tag/sony/"&gt;Sony&lt;/a&gt; PSN breach subsides, more measured estimates of the damage are appearing, but more serious questions are becoming relevant. It&amp;#8217;s still too early to be sure what the extent of the damage is, but the early and sensational estimates (propagated before Sony announced relevant numbers) seem to be giving way to a more complex, nuanced look at the damage. A few people have claimed suspicious activity on their accounts so far, but there doesn&amp;#8217;t seem to be any systematic fraud going on &amp;#8211; on the other hand, it isn&amp;#8217;t easy to immediately leverage 10-15 million credit cards.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sony &lt;a href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2011/04/30/press-release-some-playstation-network-and-qriocity-services-to-be-available-this-week/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it will be reestablishing access to &amp;#8220;some&amp;#8221; PSN and Qriocity services this week, with a focus on access to account details, online play, and access to purchased media. Other services should be online within a month. As far as restitution, Sony is offering a month of Playstation Plus and Qriocity Unlimited for free, plus a free PSN download, currently unspecified. Security is, of course, being &amp;#8220;enhanced.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That would likely be enough to compound for an ordinary extended outage, but this was more than a glitch. Sony will likely get rougher handling from an investigation of their security practices than from frustrated customers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An unofficial poll showed that a good number of gamers seemed to be resigned to sticking with PSN in some way &amp;mdash; giving up the platform would be too great of a sacrifice for the huge number of consumers who, while angry, were likely only put out rather than affected materially by the breach. Sony will be making various ways to re-secure and audit your account available, and has said they will pay any fees associated with, say, credit card cancellation and reissuing. They also implied they will provide a secure &amp;#8220;out&amp;#8221; for users who want to just cut and run.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.crunchgear.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/psn.jpg" class="center"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we noted on Friday, Sony has &lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2011/04/29/more-psn-developments-fbi-credit-card-databases-and-hard-questions-for-sony/"&gt;secured help from several parties&lt;/a&gt; who, let&amp;#8217;s hope, will lay their hands on the hackers responsible for the breach. But for every eye looking out for the hackers, there&amp;#8217;s one looking hard back at Sony, who may be partially liable. While the criminal acts perpetrated by the hackers certainly deserve investigation, the other side needs a look as well &amp;mdash; the primary question being not how did someone gain access, but why was so much data accessible via any method at all?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are allegations going around that Sony was running outdated Apache servers, and that employees with no clearance were allowed within the physical firewall. Who knows but these may be true? At any rate, it&amp;#8217;s clear that the databases containing personal information were &lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2011/04/27/psn-breach-credit-cards-encrypted-other-things-not-so-much/"&gt;insufficiently protected&lt;/a&gt;, and although Sony denies the credit card numbers were accessible, its careful wording seems to imply that the data was indeed taken. An official, independent investigation is almost certainly underway already (it being such a high-profile incident; indeed, the FBI is already involved), but it will take some time before any real results can be announced. Too little is known (or rather, too much of what is known is on questionable authority) for any kind of estimate of damages, and any criminal charges will have to wait as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2011/04/27/first-lawsuit-filed-against-sony-for-psn-debacle/"&gt;A lawsuit has already been filed&lt;/a&gt; in advance of the facts, as they so often are, but if it&amp;#8217;s done properly it will not rely on technical details, but rather Sony&amp;#8217;s responsibilities to its customers as custodians of privileged information. Even if Sony were to prove elsewhere that it met reasonable standards for security, the response to the the breach seems to have been sluggish, even if what they say is true and they were unaware of the extent of the damage until a week after the event.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The greatest damage may be less easily quantifiable, though no less serious. It&amp;#8217;s the damage to Sony&amp;#8217;s brand. Apple, Microsoft, Nintendo, and Google (among other competitors in Sony&amp;#8217;s many markets) have managed to go for years with no such catastrophic breaches &amp;mdash; there have been some, to be sure, but the PSN breach is nice and easy for everyone to understand and judge, and the scale really is remarkable. I don&amp;#8217;t want to say something like &amp;#8220;it&amp;#8217;s the beginning of the end for Qriocity,&amp;#8221; but it may be that this evolving service is too weak at this stage to survive such a serious blow. It won&amp;#8217;t help the launch of their tablets, that&amp;#8217;s for sure. And consumer trust, so difficult to measure, will only go down, at a time when a litigious and beleaguered Sony desperately needs good PR. Regardless of the actual material damage of this debacle, it looks likely to be an ugly year for Sony.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/SePJldPcE3eYhRooSvKyHbXKGHk/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/SePJldPcE3eYhRooSvKyHbXKGHk/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/SePJldPcE3eYhRooSvKyHbXKGHk/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/SePJldPcE3eYhRooSvKyHbXKGHk/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/crunchgear?a=ehNf2y1XjSw:cRC7dw8gRA8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/crunchgear?i=ehNf2y1XjSw:cRC7dw8gRA8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/crunchgear?a=ehNf2y1XjSw:cRC7dw8gRA8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/crunchgear?i=ehNf2y1XjSw:cRC7dw8gRA8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/crunchgear?a=ehNf2y1XjSw:cRC7dw8gRA8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/crunchgear?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.crunchgear.com/2011/05/01/sony-says-services-to-resume-shortly-offers-apology/</link>
      <guid>http://www.crunchgear.com/2011/05/01/sony-says-services-to-resume-shortly-offers-apology/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple's Chinese workers treated 'inhumanely, like machines'</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.22.2/5075?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=Apple%27s+Chinese+workers+treated+%27inhumanely%2C+like+machines%27%3AArticle%3A1552166&amp;ch=Technology&amp;c3=Obs&amp;c4=Apple+%28Technology%29%2CChina+%28News%29%2CiPad%2CiPhone%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CTechnology+Gadgets&amp;c6=Gethin+Chamberlain&amp;c7=11-Apr-30&amp;c8=1552166&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c11=Technology&amp;c13=&amp;c25=&amp;c30=content&amp;h2=GU%2FTechnology%2FApple" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Investigation finds evidence of draconian rules and excessive overtime to meet western demand for iPhones and iPads&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An investigation into the conditions of Chinese workers has revealed the shocking human cost of producing the must-have Apple iPhones and iPads that are now ubiquitous in the west.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The research, carried out by two NGOs, has revealed disturbing allegations of excessive working hours and draconian workplace rules at two major plants in southern China. It has also uncovered an "anti-suicide" pledge that workers at the two plants have been urged to sign, after a series of employee deaths last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investigation gives a detailed picture of life for the 500,000 workers at the Shenzhen and Chengdu factories owned by Foxconn, which produces millions of Apple products each year. The report accuses Foxconn of treating workers "inhumanely, like machines".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the allegations made by workers interviewed by the NGOs &#8211; the Centre for Research on Multinational Companies and Students &amp; Scholars Against Corporate Misbehaviour (Sacom) &#8211; are claims that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#9632; Excessive overtime is routine, despite a legal limit of 36 hours a month. One payslip, seen by the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt;, indicated that the worker had performed 98 hours of overtime in a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#9632; Workers attempting to meet the huge demand for the first iPad were sometimes pressured to take only one day off in 13.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#9632; In some factories badly performing workers are required to be publicly humiliated in front of colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#9632; Crowded workers' dormitories can sleep up to 24 and are subject to strict rules. One worker told the NGO investigators that he was forced to sign a "confession letter" after illicitly using a hairdryer. In the letter he wrote: "It is my fault. I will never blow my hair inside my room. I have done something wrong. I will never do it again."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#9632; In the wake of a spate of suicides at Foxconn factories last summer, workers were asked to sign a statement promising not to kill themselves and pledging to "treasure their lives".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxconn produced its first iPad at Chengdu last November and expects to produce 100m a year by 2013. Last year Apple sold more than 15m iPads worldwide and has already sold close to five million this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the allegations were put to Foxconn by the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt;, manager Louis Woo confirmed that workers sometimes worked more than the statutory overtime limit to meet demand from western consumers, but claimed that all the extra hours were voluntary. Workers claim that, if they turn down excessive demands for overtime, they will be forced to rely on their basic wage: workers in Chengdu are paid only 1,350 yuan (&#163;125) a month for a basic 48-hour week, equivalent to about 65p an hour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked about the suicides that have led to anti-suicide netting being fitted beneath the windows of workers' dormitories, Woo said: "Suicides were not connected to bad working conditions. There was a copy effect. If one commits suicide, then others will follow."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement, Apple said: "Apple is committed to ensuring the highest standards of social responsibility throughout our supply base. Apple requires suppliers to commit to our comprehensive supplier code of conduct as a condition of their contracts with us. We drive compliance with the code through a rigorous monitoring programme, including factory audits, corrective action plans and verification measures."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/apple"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/china"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/ipad"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/iphone"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/gethin-chamberlain"&gt;Gethin Chamberlain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; Guardian News &amp; Media Limited 2011 | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://users.guardian.co.uk/help/article/0,,933909,00.html"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/CZsBbHjGoQAzF4t9MPsk0IC7iGM/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/CZsBbHjGoQAzF4t9MPsk0IC7iGM/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/CZsBbHjGoQAzF4t9MPsk0IC7iGM/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/CZsBbHjGoQAzF4t9MPsk0IC7iGM/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2011/apr/30/apple-chinese-workers-treated-inhumanely</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2011/apr/30/apple-chinese-workers-treated-inhumanely</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The P2P Evolution</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://tctechcrunch.files.wordpress.com/2011/05/space-robot-handshake.jpg" class="snap_nopreview shot2" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many years ago, after graduating college, I came home before moving to NYC, wondering how I would scrounge together the money for the first month&#8217;s rent and security deposit so my friends and I could all live together in the Big Apple. I had one month to get the cash, and instead of going out for traditional, hourly-wage work, I decided to go through all of my old stuff and throw it on &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com/"&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt;. In those days, I got online through dial-up, would have to mail a hard copy of the pictures to interested buyers, and would ship items to auction winners only when their check arrived by mail and cleared into my bank account. In one month, I got rid of winter jackets, sports equipment, and baseball cards to the tune of $7,000, tax free, enough to buffer the move to NYC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A few years later, when I moved to San Francisco, it was &lt;a href="http://www.craigslist.com/"&gt;Craigslist&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue, helping with initial sublets, furniture, stereo equipment, and the odd jobs I did to soften the transition. Without knowing it, I was stumbling through life fueled mainly by a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_peer-to-peer_processes"&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;/a&gt; (P2P) network and economy that helped me connect supply and demand, as well as time and money. Instead of using consignment shops or hosting a garage sale, or instead of buying new items in a traditional store, I buffered my moves to NYC and SF primarily fueled by P2P networks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That was P2P 1.0, anchored by eBay and Craigslist, networks that have connected billions. And, while these companies continue their march, we are already into the next peer-to-peer evolution: P2P 2.0. Unknowingly at the time, I was exposed to the thought a few years ago in graduate school, when my classmate, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/jamesreinhart"&gt;James Reinhart&lt;/a&gt;, came up with the idea for a &#8220;Netflix for used clothes,&#8221; which has morphed into venture-backed &lt;a href="http://www.thredup.com/"&gt;thredUP&lt;/a&gt;, a P2P network connecting parents to trade gently-worn baby and kid clothes, goods that are very expensive to buy new. Another success is &lt;a href="http://www.lendingclub.com/home.action"&gt;Lending Club&lt;/a&gt;, a peer lending site connecting lenders with borrowers primarily for refinancing credit card debt or small business loans.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today, P2P 2.0 is in full-swing, and that&#8217;s putting things lightly. &lt;a href="blank"&gt;Y Combinator&lt;/a&gt; breakout &lt;a href="http://www.airbnb.com/"&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; began as an ad-hoc solution for the founders to earn a little extra scratch during a convention when tight hotel supply provided an &lt;a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/02/22/airbnb/"&gt;opportunity&lt;/a&gt; to rent out air mattresses in their apartment, with the added touch of breakfast. The result today is a rapidly growing company and brand that aims to connect those who seek space with those who need it&#8212;you can rent boats, treehouses, and even castles. Airbnb has been so successful that it&#8217;s spawned a handful of international copycats and motivated the likes of &lt;a href="http://www.getaround.com/"&gt;GetAround&lt;/a&gt;, a P2P car-sharing network.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The newest entrant into the P2P space is the concept I&#8217;m most excited about: &lt;a href="http://zaarly.com/"&gt;Zaarly&lt;/a&gt;. The founder, being taller than average, realized prior to boarding a flight in economy class that he would be willing to pay someone on the same flight to swap for an exit row seat. That moment gave &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/03/09/want-someone-to-bring-you-a-beer-get-that-and-anything-else-from-zaarly/"&gt;birth&lt;/a&gt; to Zaarly, a new service that will leverage a mobile device&#8217;s location to connect those who demand something to those who can provide it. Imagine busy New Yorkers with disposable cash demanding something immediately, delivered right now: &#8220;Zaarly it.&#8221; The Zaarly concept connects time and money in the P2P vector, just like eBay connects sellers and buyers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All of this activity in P2P 2.0 is now possible because of advancements in location sensors in mobile devices and social network platforms. The time is ripe for even much more advancement in P2P ideas, leveraging today&#8217;s technologies in new ways. Even as consumer-focused entrepreneurs work to build the next solutions, they are raising money on P2P services like &lt;a href="http://angel.co/"&gt;Angel List&lt;/a&gt;, which connects fundraising entrepreneurs with seed stage capital and has shaken up the early stage investing game. &lt;a href="http://www.taskrabbit.com/"&gt;Task Rabbit&lt;/a&gt; connects individuals and businesses with &#8220;task runners&#8221; that provide an outsourced task service, and &lt;a href="https://www.listia.com/"&gt;Listia&lt;/a&gt; is an eBay for trading free stuff, where site users earn and spend credits. (Many others are also emerging, please add them &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-peer-to-peer-consumer-startups?q=peer+to+"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;During all these P2P transactions, companies like &lt;a href="https://squareup.com/"&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.roamdata.com/"&gt;Roam&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.bu.mp/"&gt;Bump&lt;/a&gt; leverage mobile phones to help drive payments. For instance, buyers and sellers can trade data by bumping their phones together, where Bump technology &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/bump-technologies"&gt;measures&lt;/a&gt; the movement from the accelerometer and pairs two users together. Square connect buyers and sellers using a credit card and mobile device. A merchant can charge a customer for goods or services by using the Square reader attached through a device&#8217;s audio jack to read a buyer&#8217;s credit card (like a cassette tape) and transmit the signal to help complete the transaction. (Surprisingly, not many others have yet fully &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/What-other-products-similar-to-Square-use-the-iPhone-audio-port-to-transmit-data?q=square+audio"&gt;leveraged&lt;/a&gt; the phone&#8217;s audio jack or accelerometer, making Square, Roam, and Bump standout.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The driving force behind all of this P2P activity is the fact that today&#8217;s technologies make many more types of transaction possible between average consumers by finding an equilibrium between time and money, supply and demand. Transactions once locked up and never realized now create entirely new economies, free of established brands and fat middle-men.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a world where everyone is rushing to drive all commerce online, some P2P solutions sprinkle a dose of humanity into the transaction. Will P2P services keep bringing more of this human element, personalization, and discovery into the foreground? Will services like &lt;a href="http://www.housefed.com/"&gt;Housefed&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a personal meal service, create a welcome alternative to nuking frozen food for dinner? It will be fascinating to see what new types of businesses are built on top of these P2P engines, and what traditional businesses they will disrupt. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The U.S. economy, struggling its way slowly out of a major recession, will only benefit from a continuous flow of new ideas to help connect people and keep things going. And, the potential for these services overseas is just staggering, especially within cultures that already have strong informal economies baked into their DNA. So big, in fact, that the simple desire to swap airline seats or find a reasonably-priced place to crash during a convention could create, accelerate, and fortify new informal micro-economies in the far corners of earth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: Flickr/ &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nasarobonaut/4691143282/"&gt;NASA Robonaut&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="cbw snap_nopreview"&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_header"&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/javascripts/widget.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_header_text"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/"&gt;CrunchBase Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_content"&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subheader"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/airbnb-2"&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subcontent"&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/cbw/company/airbnb-2.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subheader"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/square"&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subcontent"&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/cbw/company/square.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subheader"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/zaarly"&gt;Zaarly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_subcontent"&gt;&lt;script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/cbw/company/zaarly.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cbw_footer"&gt;Information provided by &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/"&gt;CrunchBase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/tctechcrunch.wordpress.com/299064/" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=techcrunch.com&amp;amp;blog=11718616&amp;amp;post=299064&amp;amp;subd=tctechcrunch&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fz01H5tidrG0pKXe6Wmoem_VXFA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fz01H5tidrG0pKXe6Wmoem_VXFA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fz01H5tidrG0pKXe6Wmoem_VXFA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/fz01H5tidrG0pKXe6Wmoem_VXFA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=CR3iYOIgIYw:i8rAaD3-QDY:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/CR3iYOIgIYw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/01/p2p-evolution/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Techcrunch+%2528TechCrunch%2529</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/01/p2p-evolution/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Techcrunch+%2528TechCrunch%2529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Send Button: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="tweetmeme_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Ffacebook-send-button-this-week-in-social-media%2F"&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2Ffacebook-send-button-this-week-in-social-media%2F&amp;amp;source=smexaminer&amp;amp;style=normal&amp;amp;service=bit.ly&amp;amp;service_api=R_d59caa5bf89cd7663e205e72cb1d6cc1&amp;amp;b=2" height="61" width="50" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/research/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" title="social media research" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/research-pose.png" alt="social media research" width="110" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Welcome to our weekly edition of what&amp;#8217;s hot in &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/tag/social-media-news/" target="_blank"&gt;social media news&lt;/a&gt;. To help you &lt;strong&gt;stay up-to-date with social media&lt;/strong&gt;, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;What&amp;#8217;s New This Week?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/blog/post/494/" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Send Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: You now have the option of adding a &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/docs/reference/plugins/send/" target="_blank"&gt;Send button&lt;/a&gt; to your content, similar to the Facebook Link button. This new button allows your readers to choose people they want to share your content with.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 491px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0411ck-facebook-send-button.png" alt="facebook send button" width="481" height="292" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Readers can &amp;quot;send&amp;quot; links to Facebook Groups, Facebook friends and even to email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/04/26/facebook-deals-what-it-means-for-you_n_853883.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Deals Launches Test Programs in Atlanta, Austin, Dallas, San Diego and San Francisco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Similar to &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/tag/groupon/" target="_blank"&gt;Groupon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/?sk=deals&amp;amp;campaign_id=107175436034212&amp;amp;ap=1" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Deals&lt;/a&gt; allows local businesses to offer digital coupons on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 484px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0411ck-facebook-deals.png" alt="facebook deals" width="474" height="485" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Your Facebook friends will see your Deals unless you change your privacy settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://klout.com/blog/2011/04/introducing-the-new-klout-com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Klout Launches New Site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: This new version allows you to &amp;#8220;compare your Klout profile to others, gain new insight on your score, see the latest Klout Perks, and control which influencers are displayed on your profile.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 488px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0411ck-new-klout.png" alt="new klout" width="478" height="446" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The new Klout &amp;quot;shows more relevant topic and influencer data and a clearer view of how your Klout is changing over time.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.delicious.com/" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube Founders Acquire Delicious From Yaho&lt;span style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Delicious users will be happy to hear that this popular bookmarking platform has a new owner, &lt;a href="http://www.avos.com/delicious-press-release/" target="_blank"&gt;Avos&lt;/a&gt;, that plans to &amp;#8220;make the site even easier and more fun to save, share, and discover the web&#8217;s &amp;#8216;tastiest&amp;#8217; content.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0411ck-delicious-avos.png" alt="delicious avos" width="480" height="368" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;&amp;quot;Yahoo! will continue to operate Delicious until approximately July 2011.&amp;quot; When the transition period is complete, information will be moved over to Avos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are a couple of other social media tools worth a look.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pressjack.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PressJack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A desktop application that allows publishers to convert their web content into digital magazines instantly. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;A desktop version of the application &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;is currently &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt; in beta.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 492px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0411ck-pressjack.png" alt="pressjack" width="482" height="169" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;PressJack makes it easy to organize your content into a beautifully laid out digital magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10pt;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wp4fb.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WP4FB&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;A free WordPress template to create Facebook landing pages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 489px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/0411ck-wp4fb.png" alt="wp4fb" width="479" height="493" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Worth a try?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don&#8217;t miss this:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/socialmedia11/sme/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media Examiner&amp;#8217;s Social Media Success Summit 2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Check out the &lt;em&gt;largest&lt;/em&gt; online social media conference! Help your business grow with social media.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/socialmedia11/sme/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img title="456x250" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/456x250smss11.gif" alt="" width="456" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What social media news caught your interest this week?&lt;/strong&gt; Please share your comments below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-send-button-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-send-button-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How 3 Companies Took Content Marketing to the Next Level</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/&amp;title=How 3 Companies Took Content Marketing to the Next Level&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/hands-keyboard-360.jpg" alt="content image" title="content image" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-602117" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shane Snow is a Mashable contributor and cofounder of &lt;a href="http://contently.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Contently.com&lt;/a&gt;, an &#8220;agile publishing&#8221; platform for brands and professional bloggers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It goes by many names: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/04/01/branded-content/"&gt;branded content&lt;/a&gt;, custom publishing, content marketing. Cheap and ubiquitous web technology has become fuel for a rising trend of businesses becoming publishers and brands becoming media companies. Through content creation, brands can engage directly with an audience rather than relying on intermediary media channels. If you publish and spread great content, customers will come to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the Content Marketing Institute, an organization that provides research and education on content marketing, &#8220;93% of marketing professionals create, or plan to create content marketing as part of their overall programs in the next year.&#8221; Money is being slurped away from print advertising (44% of marketers have decreased their print ad budgets over the last three years) and put in large part toward social media and custom publishing (70% have increased their social media.publishing budgets over the last 3 years), &lt;a href="http://www.contentmarketinginstitute.com/content-marketing-stats/general-trends/" target="_blank"&gt;according to CMI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blogging, tweeting and posting not only generate brand awareness and buzz, they also build links, which are like gold to Google&#8217;s ranking algorithm. In short, content marketing is the new SEO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How should your business or brand think about its content marketing strategy? Take some tips from the following companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 1. &lt;a href="https://www.mint.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Mint.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/630mint.jpg" alt="mint image" title="mint image" width="630" height="271" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-602121" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When personal finance startup Mint launched in 2006, it was quickly thrown into competition with web startups like Wesabe, and established juggernauts like Quicken. Three years later, the company is a market leader in online personal finance and &lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17939_109-10351715-2.html" target="_blank"&gt;sold&lt;/a&gt; to Intuit for $170 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mint owes much of its user adoption and brand success to its aggressively intelligent content strategy. Unlike the half-hearted, months-between-updates blogs that most businesses keep, Mint&#8217;s blog &#8220;MintLife&#8221; was a core part of the company&#8217;s operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mint dedicated significant resources to its blog, including a full time editorial staff and a slew of freelance contributors. It invested time in social news sites like &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/reddit"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/digg"&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt;, and after months of seeing consistent, quality Mint content, readers in those communities began trusting Mint as high quality, reliable, and cool to share. Eventually, those users turned into Mint customers, even advocating Mint in their personal networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;News and tips posts, link roundups, slideshows, videos, and infographics were all key components in Mint&#8217;s content strategy, and they were held to a strict editorial standard. By establishing itself as a smart resource that was easy and accessible to the financially curious, Mint was able to leverage its content credibility to convert readers into buyers of its actual product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mint is consistently lauded as a pioneer in successful blog content marketing. Big takeaways for attaining Mint-like success include the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dedicate resources to content (whether paying outsourced/contributed writers or in-house editors).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enforce high quality editorial standards on all content types (writing, illustration, video).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Share content smartly through social channels.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remember consistency and patience in building up an audience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 2. &lt;a href="http://www.hubspot.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Hubspot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/630hubspot.jpg" alt="hubspot image" title="hubspot image" width="630" height="204" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-602125" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Makers of the marketing software platform Hubspot know the value of good content for inbound marketing. Hubspot cofounder Dharmesh Shah anecdotally told me that his customers who blog regularly average about six times more inbound leads than those who don&#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It makes sense that Hubspot itself does a lot of content marketing. They produce case studies, videos, podcasts, webinars, and ebooks for their audience, educating them about their industry. All of that education helps Hubspot customers use the platform more effectively, but it also scoops new users out of seemingly thin air with every piece of content it publishes to the blogosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hubspot has over 4,000 customers. Their primary customer acquisition method: inbound leads from content marketing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&#8217;s what the rest of us can take away from Hubspot&#8217;s content marketing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Produce content with the goal of being seen as a &#8220;thought leader&#8221; rather than simply for the sake of having large quantities of content.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Publish diverse types of content, and don&#8217;t confine yourself to a single effort.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&#8217;t just produce content about yourself; create content that&#8217;s helpful to your audience.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt; Hubspot is a Mashable sponsor.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 3. &lt;a href="http://www.openforum.com/" target="_blank"&gt;American Express&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/630amex.jpg" alt="amex image" title="amex image" width="630" height="227" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-602129" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When did credit card companies start turning into media companies? It&amp;#8217;s been happening for years, but American Express has done a bang-up job of turning its business and money expertise into actionable content for entrepreneurs &#8212; an influential subset of Amex&#8217;s total user market &#8212; with OpenForum.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open Forum offers tools for small businesses, many of which have tie-ins with Amex products, but the site is also dedicated to hosting insightful and engaging content about the many facets of running a business. Useful content is produced by publishers like &lt;em&gt;Inc. Magazine&lt;/em&gt; (as well as &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt;), and hosted on OpenForum.com, while other articles are created by in-house Open Forum writers. It&#8217;s a hybrid advertising/guest blogging/in-house editorial operation, and it&#8217;s fostering a community around the topic of running a business. All of the conversations and content in the community live under the American Express flag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lessons from Open Forum&#8217;s content marketing include the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get trusted contributors to publish guest content on your properties.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Develop a community of users around a topic (rather than around your brand), and let your brand be the host of the community.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&#8217;t neglect original content authored by you. (You want to be the host and an expert).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt; OpenForum is a Mashable content partner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Final Thought&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Omnipresent publishing tools and Internet culture have made branded content more than a possibility for web businesses; they&#8217;ve made it a necessity. Whereas five years ago your business needed to have a website in order to exist, soon your company&#8217;s survival may depend on your ability to be an effective publisher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from Mint, Hubspot, and American Express, many other companies have had great success in with content marketing. Whose branded content have you liked (or disliked)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/ford_logo_driveone.jpg" alt="" title="ford_logo_driveone" width="85" height="47" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-559843" /&gt;Interested in more Business resources? Check out &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/explore/"&gt;Mashable Explore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a new way to discover information on your favorite Mashable topics.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=519171"&gt;jgroup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/blog/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/blogging/"&gt;blogging&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/case-study/"&gt;case study&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/content/"&gt;content&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/marketing/"&gt;MARKETING&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/publishing/"&gt;publishing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/startups/"&gt;startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business &amp;amp; Marketing&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business &amp;amp; Marketing on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business &amp;amp; Marketing channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hPjPSljkz-lGNsS66ttrmq3KC84/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hPjPSljkz-lGNsS66ttrmq3KC84/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hPjPSljkz-lGNsS66ttrmq3KC84/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hPjPSljkz-lGNsS66ttrmq3KC84/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zz_Og_6SHU8:RhGn0IZ8ltg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/zz_Og_6SHU8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/content-marketing-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind scenes, meticulous preparations under way - Associated Press</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; LONDON (AP) -- Fifty days and counting down. Behind the scenes hundreds are hard at work to make sure the April 29 royal wedding is a day to remember - not just for Prince William and Kate Middleton, but for the country. As the date nears, the machinery that makes a British royal event look, smell</description>
      <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</link>
      <guid>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Confidence</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very few people succeed in business without a degree of confidence. Yet everyone, from young people in their first real jobs to seasoned leaders in the upper ranks of organizations, have moments &amp;#8212; or days, months, or even years &amp;#8212; when they are unsure of their ability to tackle challenges. No one is immune to these bouts of insecurity at work, but they don't have to hold you back. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the Experts Say&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; "Confidence equals security equals positive emotion equals better performance," says Tony Schwartz, the president and CEO of The Energy Project and the author of &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Be-Excellent-Anything-Four-Transforming/dp/1451610262/ref=sr_1_1"&gt;Be Excellent at Anything: The Four Keys to Transforming the Way We Work and Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. And yet he concedes that "insecurity plagues consciously or subconsciously every human being I've met." Overcoming this self-doubt starts with honestly assessing your abilities (and your shortcomings) and then getting comfortable enough to capitalize on (and correct) them, adds Deborah H. Gruenfeld, the Moghadam Family Professor of Leadership and Organizational Behavior and Co-Director of the Executive Program for Women Leaders at Stanford Graduate School of Business. Here's how to do that and get into the virtuous cycle that Schwartz describes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Your piano teacher was right: practice does make perfect. "The best way to build confidence in a given area is to invest energy in it and work hard at it," says Schwartz. Many people give up when they think they're not good at a particular job or task, assuming the exertion is fruitless. But Schwartz argues that deliberate practice will almost always trump natural aptitude. If you are unsure about your ability to do something &amp;#8212; speak in front of large audience, negotiate with a tough customer &amp;#8212; start by trying out the skills in a safe setting. "Practice can be very useful, and is highly recommended because in addition to building confidence, it also tends to improve quality. Actually deliver the big presentation more than once before the due date. Do a dry run before opening a new store," says Gruenfeld. Even people who are confident in their abilities can become more so with better preparation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get out of your own way&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Confident people aren't only willing to practice, they're also willing to acknowledge that they don't &amp;#8212; and can't &amp;#8212; know everything. "It's better to know when you need help, than not," says Gruenfeld. "A certain degree of confidence &amp;#8212; specifically, confidence in your ability to learn &amp;#8212; is required to be willing to admit that you need guidance or support." &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the flip side, don't let modesty hold you back. People often get too wrapped up in what others will think to focus on what they have to offer, says Katie Orenstein, founder and director of The OpEd Project, a non-profit that empowers women to influence public policy by submitting opinion pieces to newspapers. "When you realize your value to others, confidence is no longer about self-promotion," she explains. "In fact, confidence is no longer the right word. It's about purpose." Instead of agonizing about what others might think of you or your work, concentrate on the unique perspective you bring. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get feedback when you need it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; While you don't what to completely rely on others' opinions to boost your ego, validation can also be very effective in building confidence. Gruenfeld suggests asking someone who cares about your development as well as the quality of your performance to tell you what she thinks. Be sure to pick people whose feedback will be entirely truthful; Gruenfeld notes that when performance appraisals are only positive, we stop trusting them. And then use any genuinely positive commentary you get as a talisman. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also remember that some people need more support than others, so don't be shy about asking for it. "&lt;a href="http://www.thewhitehouseproject.org/"&gt;The White House Project&lt;/a&gt; finds, for example, that many women need to be told they should run for office before deciding to do so. Men do not show this pattern of needing others' validation or encouragement," says Gruenfeld. It's okay if you need praise. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take risks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Playing to your strengths is a smart tactic but not if it means you hesitate to take on new challenges. Many people don't know what they are capable of until they are truly tested "Try things you don't think you can do. Failure can be very useful for building confidence," says Gruenfeld. Of course, this is often easier said than done. "It feels bad to not be good at something. There's a leap of faith with getting better at anything," says Schwartz. But don't assume you should feel good all the time. In fact, stressing yourself is the only way to grow. Enlisting help from others can make this easier. Gruenfeld recommends asking supervisors to let you experiment with new initiatives or skills when the stakes are relatively low and then to support you as you tackle those challenges. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principles to Remember&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Be honest with yourself about what you know and what you still need to learn &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Practice doing the things you are unsure about&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Embrace new opportunities to prove you can do difficult things&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Don't:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Focus excessively on whether you or not you have the ability - think instead about the value you provide &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Hesitate to ask for external validation if you need it &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Worry about what others think &amp;#8212; focus on yourself, not a theoretical and judgmental audience&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Case Study #1: Get the knowledge and get out of your own way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; In 2010, Mark Angelo, was asked by the CEO of Hospital for Special Surgery in New York to create and implement a program to improve quality and efficiency. Mark was relatively new to the organization. He had worked as a business fellow for the previous year but had recently taken on the role of director of operations and service lines. Even though he had background in operations strategy from his days as a management consultant, he was not familiar with the Lean/Six Sigma principles he'd need to use for this project and didn't feel equipped to build the program from scratch. He was particularly concerned he wouldn't be able to gain the necessary support from the hospital's physicians and nurses. What would they think of a young administrator with no hospital experience telling them how to improve quality and increase efficiency?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For five months, Mark struggled to get the project on track and his confidence suffered. He knew that his apprehension was in part due to his lack of knowledge of Six Sigma. He read a number of books and articles on the subject, talked to consulting firms that specialized in it, and spoke with hospitals that had been successful in developing and implementing similar programs. This helped but he realized he still didn't know if he would be able to get the necessary people on board. "I was anxious and stressed because I had no idea how I was going to transform the organization. I knew I couldn't do it on my own. It was going to take a collective effort that included our management team and all of our staff," he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He talked with the CEO who had supported him since the beginning. He also looked to his family for emotional support. Through these conversations he realized that his anxiety stemmed from a desire to be liked by his colleagues and therefore to avoid conflict. "After many discussions with my CEO and observing how he handled these situations, I learned that it is better to strive to be well-respected than well-liked," he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This was a turning point for Mark. Instead of worrying so much about what others thought of him, he focused on doing what was best for the patient and the institution. In December, he presented the vision for the program to the entire medical staff. While he was nervous about how it would be received, he knew this was a critical moment. "I was able to get up in front of one our toughest constituencies and present the vision that we had been developing over the past few months," he says. His presentation was met with applause. "In the end, my confidence grew by leaps and bounds and we were able to design a program that has since taken off with great success across the hospital. I was able to overcome my mental blocks and knowledge deficits to build a program that will truly help transform how we approach performance improvement and patient care," he says. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case Study #2: Know the value you bring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Julie Zhou knew she had things to say but she wasn't sure how to get heard. As a product design manager at Facebook, she had developed valuable expertise in the products she worked on. Yet, she lacked the confidence to share her ideas. She was used to being one of very few women in the room. That had been the case when she was studying computer science at Stanford and it was still true now that she was at Facebook. She knew this meant she needed to make a concerted effort to speak up. But being the minority voice wasn't the only reason she felt unsure of herself. She says that she also suffered from "imposter syndrome," feeling as if she hadn't earned a right to her ideas; she had somehow ended up where she was accidently, not through hard work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Last November, she published a &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/11/30/opinion/30zhuo.html"&gt;piece in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the danger of anonymity in online discussions. "It was a matter of someone saying you can do it," she explains. "It had never occurred to me that I could be published. But it actually wasn't hard at all." The reaction she got in the workshop and afterward back at Facebook boosted her confidence. "Since then, she's gotten a lot of support from colleagues, which has emboldened her to speak her mind. "Of course it's still a work in progress, but now I'm a much more confident speaker and writer," she says. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.harvardbusiness.org/~ff/harvardbusiness?a=9QfCOWWYkQk:n2PvEfojNjI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/harvardbusiness?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.harvardbusiness.org/~ff/harvardbusiness?a=9QfCOWWYkQk:n2PvEfojNjI:bcOpcFrp8Mo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/harvardbusiness?d=bcOpcFrp8Mo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/harvardbusiness/~4/9QfCOWWYkQk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://blogs.hbr.org/hmu/2011/04/how-to-build-confidence.html</link>
      <guid>http://blogs.hbr.org/hmu/2011/04/how-to-build-confidence.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Little Red (Face)Book</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-34225" title="zuck_mao" src="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/epicenter/2011/05/zuck_mao.jpg" alt="" width="497" height="236" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I spoke at Facebook about &lt;em&gt;In The Plex&lt;/em&gt; recently, &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/facebook-baidu-2011-4"&gt;rumors&lt;/a&gt; were swirling that the social networking giant was about to enter China, supposedly in a partnership with the search engine Baidu. So I made sure that my talk to a dining hall full of FB&#8217;ers included the cautionary tale of what happened when Google met China. (An &lt;a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/04/15/googles-ordeal-in-china/"&gt;excerpt&lt;/a&gt; of the saga as detailed in my book appeared in Fortune.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Though similar in some ways &amp;#8212; focus on engineering, full-on embrace of Internet values &amp;#8212; Facebook and Google are quite different companies. Their China efforts will also undoubtedly vary. But some of the challenges that Facebook will encounter will be just as tricky as the ones Google faced. Those problems ultimately led to Google&#8217;s reconsideration of the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I suggest to Facebook that its leaders think hard before taking the leap.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&#8217;s some areas where Facebook must find good answers to tough questions before it makes that China leap.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Censorship&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to do business in China, Google had to make a horrendous compromise: agreeing to filter its search results according to the demands of an oppressive government striving to deny vital information to its citizens. Facebook will have to make a different kind of compromise: somehow preventing free discourse when it comes to speech that threatens the authoritarians in charge of China.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This may not affect the core of Facebook&#8217;s activities, most of which are prosaic. But how will the lines be drawn?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will there be an agreement in principle of verboten content, or will Facebook have to remove offending posts and pages every time China demands it?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What happens when an international friend of a Chinese Facebook user posts something&#8212;or sends a message&#8212;with content that the Government doesn&#8217;t like?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will Chinese censors monitor Facebook friend feeds?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Privacy&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of the most shameful corporate episodes in Internet history was &lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/asia-pacific/4221538.stm"&gt;Yahoo&#8217;s decision&lt;/a&gt; to turn over to the Chinese government the identity of a dissident who assumed anonymity. The user got a ten-year jail sentence, and Yahoo is still scorned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What will happen to Facebook&#8217;s users when they come under scrutiny from the government?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will Baidu/Facebook turn over private information with a single phone call from an official? What about the connections between Chinese citizens and Facebook users on other countries.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If I, as a US citizen using Facebook in the United States, is a &#8220;friend&#8221; of a Chinese user and that user has access to my private information, what assurances will I have that the Chinese government doesn&#8217;t have that access too?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Conversely, will Chinese Facebook users be walled off from the rest of the world?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/epicenter/2011/05/the-little-red-facebook/2/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Continue reading &amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.wired.com/epicenter/2011/05/the-little-red-facebook/</link>
      <guid>http://www.wired.com/epicenter/2011/05/the-little-red-facebook/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bank Lets Customers Pay Friends By Bumping iPhones</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/&amp;title=Bank Lets Customers Pay Friends By Bumping iPhones&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/bump-225.jpg" alt="" title="bump-225" width="225" height="225" class="alignright size-full wp-image-495813" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ING Direct customers can now transfer payments to friends with the bump of a cellphone &amp;#8212; no account numbers needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bank released an updated version of its &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ing-direct/id329508084?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;iPhone app&lt;/a&gt; [iTunes link] on Wednesday morning that integrates an API from &lt;a href="http://www.mashable.com/tag/bump"&gt;Bump Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, a startup that makes it easy to transfer information between phones by tapping them together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously Bump&amp;#8217;s technology has been used to exchange contact information, photos and music between users. This is the first time that a bank has leveraged it for person-to-person payments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many banks (including &lt;a href="https://home.ingdirect.com/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;ING Direct&lt;/a&gt;) are experimenting with another technology called &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/12/15/smartphone-wallet/" target="_blank"&gt;near field communication&lt;/a&gt; (NFC), which could one day power phone-to-phone transactions. But there are a limited number of NFC-enabled devices in the market, and security standards have yet to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bump is much simpler.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The startup&amp;#8217;s app and API recognize tapping motions and maps them. When a Bump is recognized, a signal is sent to cloud servers that match it with another Bump that occurred at the exact same place and time. It decides those two Bumps are a match, and exchanges information between them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In ING&amp;#8217;s case, each user will need to log into his or her secure account to send or receive payment. Bump&amp;#8217;s role is to ID participants in a &lt;a href="https://home.ingdirect.com/products/htmls_content/demo_p2p.html" target="_blank"&gt;person-to-person transaction&lt;/a&gt; instead of requiring them to type and verify account numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both participants in an ING Direct Bump transaction need to have ING Electric Orange online checking accounts in order to use the new feature. In the future, says ING Direct CIO Rudy Wolfs, ING Direct account holders will also be able to Bump payments to friends who have accounts at other banks. Bump&amp;#8217;s API is free and open, so we wouldn&amp;#8217;t be surprised to see other banks implement similar features into their apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For now, the feature is only useful in limited circumstances: if you happen to be in the same place as the person who you want to pay, if you both bank with ING Direct and if you both have iPhones. However, if the stars do happen to align just right, you&amp;#8217;ll easily be able to reimburse your half of a meal or the cost of a group gift without cash, checks, plastic or even account numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/bump_app.jpg" alt="" title="" width="640" height="" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-285526" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/banks/"&gt;banks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/bump/"&gt;bump&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/ing-direct/"&gt;ING Direct&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/nfc/"&gt;nfc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/payments/"&gt;payments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/startups/"&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/MashStartups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Startups on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Startups channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHcEF0gXXYEEoAfukn0quptRLds/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHcEF0gXXYEEoAfukn0quptRLds/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHcEF0gXXYEEoAfukn0quptRLds/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHcEF0gXXYEEoAfukn0quptRLds/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=Sr7nwybjcjQ:0zWJuoMzjbo:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/Sr7nwybjcjQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/04/29/ing-direct-customers-bump/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Location-Based Services Will be the Killer App of the 2012 Elections</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/&amp;title=Why Location-Based Services Will be the Killer App of the 2012 Elections&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/Voting-Machines-Image-Mashable.jpg" alt="" title="Voting Machines Image Mashable" width="225" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-603071" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The last presidential election was only three years ago, but that seems like a generation in the social media age.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just think, back then &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; was a novelty. &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; was popular, but started spent the first half of the year being the second-biggest social network next to &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/myspace/"&gt;MySpace&lt;/a&gt;. U.S. smartphone penetration in the U.S. was &lt;a href="http://blog.kelseygroup.com/index.php/2008/11/03/new-tkg-data-smart-phone-penetration-nears-20-percent" target="_blank"&gt;just 20%&lt;/a&gt; by the close of 2008 vs. a &lt;a href="http://www.mobilemarketingwatch.com/2011-to-become-the-year-of-the-smartphone-12814/" target="_blank"&gt;projected 50%&lt;/a&gt; by the end of this year. The biggest political marketing innovator in 2008 was &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/barack-obama/"&gt;Barack Obama&lt;/a&gt;, who employed Facebook, Twitter and other social networks to great effect, and took Howard Dean&amp;#8217;s online micro-donation idea to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, 2012 will be a different landscape for several reasons, but the biggest is the ascendance of mobile and, in particular, location-based services. Up until now, such services have been a curiosity driven by early adopters who have no issues about broadcasting their whereabouts to the whole world. In a nation of 310 million people, this is still a niche market. The biggest of the services, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/foursquare/"&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;, has about &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/04/22/foursquare-funding-report/"&gt;8 million users&lt;/a&gt;, which is respectable, but not mass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of the issue is a lack of purpose for the activity. Let&amp;#8217;s face it, being mayor of your local Chinese food joint has limited appeal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All that could change in the coming election. In this deeply polarized nation, a fair amount of people care who wins in November 2012 which gives them a reason to make sure their like-minded friends hit the polls. Until now, the only way you could do that was to drive them there yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine, however, a grass roots organization that depended, in part, on committed volunteers who were charged with getting as many people in their Facebook and Twitter networks to commit to vote. Then, when Election Day rolls around, they can prove that they at least got those people to go to their local polling places. Finally, a scientific way to prove political marketing efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure is already in place for such a plan. Thanks to a nonpartisan, get-out-the-vote effort in 2010, Foursquare made it possible to check in at any of the country&amp;#8217;s polling places and then broadcast it. Of course, Foursquare&#8217;s not the only game in town; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/19/facebook-places-guide/"&gt;Facebook Places&lt;/a&gt; lets you check in at the polls and tell all your Facebook friends about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That ability &amp;#8212; to check in to a physical location and thus bridge the offline and online world &amp;#8212; didn&#8217;t really exist in 2008 and could be a game changer in the coming election. The major challenge for political marketing has always been getting voters to actually go to the polls. In the past, get-out-the-vote campaigns have consisted of a combination of door-to-door, telephone and snail mail reminders. For a portion of the population &#8211;- say those over 65 or so -&#8211; this will still have to be the case, but for younger voters, an email plus a pledge to vote -&#8211; to be verified with a location-based check-in, will do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some politicians are already seeing the potential of LBS. It&amp;#8217;s unclear at this point whether President Obama&amp;#8217;s campaign will lean heavily on such services, but likely Republican candidate Tim Pawlenty&amp;#8217;s campaign &lt;a href="http://www.startribune.com/politics/national/119575059.html?page=1&amp;#038;c=y" target="_blank"&gt;is already&lt;/a&gt; awarding points and badges to supporters a la Foursquare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will it work? Don&amp;#8217;t underestimate the value of peer pressure. On November 6, 2012 everyone will know if you actually voted. Not doing so will effectively disqualify you from kvetching about either political party. At that point, being a voter may trump being a mayor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joeshlabotnik/"target="_blank"&gt;Flickr, Joe Shlabotnik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/2012-election/"&gt;2012 election&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-places/"&gt;Facebook Places&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/foursquare/"&gt;foursquare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/location/"&gt;location&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/location-based-services/"&gt;Location-based services&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/politics/"&gt;politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/n70aDeEu8Vvc-gH3vts3VPIYgCw/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/n70aDeEu8Vvc-gH3vts3VPIYgCw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/n70aDeEu8Vvc-gH3vts3VPIYgCw/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/n70aDeEu8Vvc-gH3vts3VPIYgCw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=pt-0SoCCC4c:RI2mKdlOQ6E:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/pt-0SoCCC4c" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/2012-election-killer-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOW TO: Ask For an Online Recommendation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/&amp;title=HOW TO: Ask For an Online Recommendation&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/jobs.jpg" alt="" title="jobs" width="225" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-603167" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Whether it&#8217;s for a job or our own &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/04/24/freelance-work/"&gt;freelance&lt;/a&gt; work, getting a recommendation from someone is valuable and can help you nab a gig. Recommendations show the world we know our stuff. They tell others more about us, maybe a quality or skill we are a bit shy to disclose about ourselves. And they explain what it&amp;#8217;s like to work with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many social media sites, such as &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/linkedin"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/branchout"&gt;BranchOut&lt;/a&gt;, offer the ability for people to post recommendations or endorsements. These features, if used wisely, can be used to separate you and your talents from the crowd. But first you have to learn the strategy for asking for a recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for asking for a recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Plan a Recommendation Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hrfishbowl.com" target="_blank"&gt;Charlie Judy&lt;/a&gt;, global director of human capital strategy and operations at &lt;a href="http://www.navigant.com" target="_blank"&gt;Navigant Consulting&lt;/a&gt;, a company that provides financial, economics, and business consulting, says online recommendations can help your audience get some level of comfort for who you are as a person. &#8220;Having at least a few well-placed recommendations can help show that you&#8217;re not completely fabricating your profile, that you actually are connected with people who are willing to put themselves out there for you, and that you&#8217;ve taken the time to develop your online presence is at least welcomed from most employers who use LinkedIn or BranchOut for sourcing,&#8221; he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/silkroadtweets" target="_blank"&gt;Tracy McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;, senior vice president of human resources at &lt;a href="http://www.silkroad.com" target="_blank"&gt;SilkRoad Technology&lt;/a&gt;, a software-as-a-service solutions provider that manages career cycles within companies, recommends having a clear strategy for why you want a recommendation in the first place. &#8220;If you can&#8217;t articulate why, then why are you going through the motions? Once you have a clear picture in your mind, develop your short story around it. Then, go to people whom you respect, internally and externally, tell them and sell them on your story and ask for the recommendation.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judy adds, &#8220;In a world of slight distinctions, anything that might give you an edge as a candidate really can&#8217;t hurt. It&#8217;s also a good way to point out something positive about you that may not be front and center on your resume or online profile.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Balance is the Key&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you figure out why you&#8217;re asking for recommendations, then figure out who you should ask. McCarthy recommends getting a good mix of people -&#8211; direct boss, peers, subordinates and customers or vendors &amp;#8212; to provide a better sense of who you are as the whole person. McCarthy also offers some food for thought to managers who might be asked for employee recommendations. &#8220;Direct bosses are often difficult to obtain, as many companies frown on providing written recommendations (for fear of lawsuits), and I think we need to get over this practice. If you are going to write something, it is likely going to be positive, so what&#8217;s the big deal as long as it is accurate?&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judy agrees that getting recommendations from a variety of people is a good approach, and he adds one more thing to consider. &#8220;I also think it&#8217;s a great idea to get a recommendation from an organization that you may have left under less than &#8216;favorable terms.&#8217; If you&#8217;re going to have to explain a departure from an organization on terms other than yours, it would be nice to demonstrate you had a positive impact on their environment nonetheless.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Volunteerism Demonstrates Skills&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you think about the skills you want to profile, don&#8217;t dismiss the accomplishments you weren&#8217;t paid for. &lt;a href="http://www.mysensay.com/blog" target="_blank"&gt;Omowale Casselle&lt;/a&gt;, chief executive officer at &lt;a href="http://www.mysensay.com" target="_blank"&gt;mySenSay, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, a social recruiting community that helps undergraduate and graduate students find the right opportunity, recommends using your volunteer connections. &#8220;A fellow volunteer is often one of the best people to ask for a recommendation. As a volunteer, there are often unique resource constraints that are associated with achieving measurable results. If you have been able to achieve results within this environment, the lack of compensation shouldn&#8217;t be a limiting factor in asking for a recommendation. This can be especially helpful for those who might be switching careers.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/meghanmbiro" target="_blank"&gt;Meghan Biro&lt;/a&gt;, principal and founder of &lt;a href="http://talentculture.com" target="_blank"&gt;TalentCulture, LLC&lt;/a&gt;, which provides recruiting and strategy services along with workplace culture branding, agrees. &#8220;Volunteering shows you have genuine passion and are willing to work beyond 9 to 5 to support a worthy cause. This step can also bring additional perspective to your presentation for a new career opportunity.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Selecting the Person to Ask&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to asking for the recommendation itself, it boils down to your relationship with the person. It takes time to build the kind of trust and shared experience on which to base a recommendation. Biro offers some guidelines. &#8220;While every workplace relationship is different, I recommend giving it at least one year before asking for a recommendation. It&#8217;s also useful to make a practice of asking for recommendations once a year &amp;#8212; treat it as a task and choose your targets carefully. Think about what you want said about your accomplishments and skills, and who among your contacts is best positioned to provide you with a solid recommendation.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judy shares another way to decide the best person to ask. &#8220;You ought to know them well enough that you could actually write the recommendation yourself, send it to them, and they would be comfortable posting it under their name. Accordingly, they should know you well enough that they would give a recommendation for you over the phone. After all, some recruiters may go as far as to request it.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After identifying the perfect person, be sure to ask for your recommendation in just the right way. McCarthy says, &#8220;I always find that picking up the phone or asking in person is far better than in email. I personally won&#8217;t recommend anyone who asks for my recommendation over email. And if the person you are asking for a recommendation expects quid pro quo, he probably isn&#8217;t the right person. It can really discount the recommendation if you are recommending the same people who recommend you &#8211;- it seems a bit disingenuous!&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Finding the Right Number&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A common question about recommendations is &lt;a href="http://www.keppiecareers.com/2011/01/16/how-to-ask-for-linkedin-recommendations/" target="_blank"&gt;how many is the right number&lt;/a&gt;. Is it possible to have too many recommendations? Yes, &amp;#8220;especially if they&#8217;re clustered around one job or employer, or repetitive in content,&amp;#8221; says Biro. &amp;#8220;Ideally, recommendations should highlight a different competency, so one or two per job is ideal.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Casselle reminds candidates to keep the reader in mind. &#8220;Just like, recruiters or hiring managers won&#8217;t read through more than two pages of a resume, people may not read through the information if your number of recommendations becomes excessive.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Curate Your Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all &lt;a href="http://www.dailywritingtips.com/writing-a-reference-letter-with-examples/"&gt;recommendations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; are created alike &amp;#8212; a badly written recommendation can do more harm than good. Biro suggests being the &#8220;curator&#8221; of your own recommendations. &#8220;When you ask for one, politely ask for the opportunity to review before it&#8217;s posted.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you receive a recommendation that isn&#8217;t exactly what you&#8217;d hope for, Casselle points out &#8220;one of the great features on LinkedIn is that you can choose to selectively hide recommendations. So, based on a position you are seeking you can optimize your profile recommendations to include only those aspects that most strongly support your target opportunity.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recommendation you&#8217;re asking for is not a trivial exercise for someone else &amp;#8212; they&#8217;re usually a sacrifice of time and energy. Be thankful and let your recommenders know that you appreciate their effort, says Casselle. &amp;#8220;Always ask how you can repay the favor, not necessarily through a reciprocal recommendation, unless appropriate.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What advice can you offer when asking for a recommendation? Leave a note in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Social Media Job Listings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every week we put out a list of &lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/find-jobs"&gt;social media and web job opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. While we post a huge range of job listings, we&amp;#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/492416" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Social Marketing Program Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at IMRE, LLC in Maryland&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/492238" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Business Logic Corporation in Chicago, Illinois&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/491657" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Graphic Designer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Wine&amp;#8217;s Up in New York, New York&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;More Job Search Resources from Mashable:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/01/17/tips-video-resumes/"&gt;Top 5 Tips for Creating Impressive Video Resumes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/02/05/cover-letter-tech-jobs/"&gt;Are Cover Letters Still Relevant For Social Media and Tech Jobs?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/03/14/linkedin-skills/"&gt;HOW TO: Optimize Your LinkedIn Profile&amp;#8217;s New Skills Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/01/23/online-entry-level-communities/"&gt;Top 5 Online Communities for Starting Your Career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; - &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/11/13/biz-dev-tips/"&gt;HOW TO: Land a Business Development Job&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-search/"&gt;job search&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-search-series/"&gt;job search series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/recommendation/"&gt;recommendation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/aLRr8oJy-8Y5tb81yXSXxVAb4dI/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/aLRr8oJy-8Y5tb81yXSXxVAb4dI/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/aLRr8oJy-8Y5tb81yXSXxVAb4dI/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/aLRr8oJy-8Y5tb81yXSXxVAb4dI/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=GFNgetcg2K8:WnK47dMI-Eg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/GFNgetcg2K8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/job-recommendation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Pogoplug Software Creates a Personal Computing Cloud</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/&amp;title=Review: Pogoplug Software Creates a Personal Computing Cloud&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/&amp;service=bit.ly"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/pogoplug-picon.jpg" alt="" title="pogoplug-picon" width="225" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-603915" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pogoplug started its life as hardware. Plug a USB drive into it and it lets you access those files from anywhere. Now, Pogoplug is available in a software version, substituting your &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/windows/"&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mac/"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/linux/"&gt;Linux &lt;/a&gt;machine for that hardware and letting you share pictures, music, videos and data with any of your devices or with anyone else. Let&amp;#8217;s try it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downloading and installing the &lt;a href="http://www.pogoplug.com/downloads.html" target="_blank"&gt;Pogoplug software&lt;/a&gt; is quick and simple. You can get the free version which lets you remotely access all the content on your computer, essentially turning your PC into your own personal cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The $29 Pogoplug Premium version&lt;/strong&gt; lets you do all that, plus it has the ability to stream media from your computer to your &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/iphone/"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/ipad/"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/android/"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; smartphone, all three of which have free Pogoplug apps available. Or, you can access everything from any computer with a web browser by going to your account at &lt;a href="http://pogoplug.com" target="_blank"&gt;Pogoplug.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the Pogoplug server software is installed on your computer, it finds all your photos, music, and video, as well as data in your Desktop and Documents folder. After a few minutes, I loaded the free iPhone app and iPad app on those two devices, and suddenly I wasw streaming music, video and files with ease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This could hardly get any easier.&lt;/strong&gt; Movies played smoothly even over AT&amp;#038;T&amp;#8217;s 3G network, and on the iPhone and iPad, they looked slightly grainy but watchable. In addition, it was easy to share files with anyone with an email address with a few taps on a touchscreen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are drawbacks.&lt;/strong&gt; For one thing, only certain types of video files are recognized. For instance, .AVI and .MOV files play back quickly and look good, where the computer is converting them to the Pogoplug&amp;#8217;s streaming file format. However, file formats such as the popular &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mkv/"&gt;.MKV&lt;/a&gt; are not recognized as video. You can share them with whomever you like &amp;#8212; however, they won&amp;#8217;t stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music streamed particularly well&lt;/strong&gt; on the iPhone and iPad, sounding just as good as it did when played directly from the PC. However, you don&amp;#8217;t get that same iPod interface you normally do on the iPhone, but a bare subset that&amp;#8217;s Spartan yet functional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uh-oh. &lt;/strong&gt;Perhaps the worst drawback I noticed was the instability of Pogoplug&amp;#8217;s iPhone and iPad applications. About half the time, when I&amp;#8217;d try to share a file or start playing video, the app would inexplicably shut down. That&amp;#8217;s just not acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verdict: &lt;/strong&gt;Pogoplug is a great idea, and the fact that you don&amp;#8217;t need to buy a $200 hardware device to use its convenient features makes it even more attractive. However, in my testing, the associated software doesn&amp;#8217;t feel ready yet. Its instability marred its powerful capabilities, rendering Pogoplug almost unusable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might want to try the free version first, and see if it&amp;#8217;s stable on your combination of devices. Wait before you spend your $29, and hopefully in the meantime Pogoplug will fix those bugs residing in its apps for iPhone and iPad.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;First Screen&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13355First-Screen"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="First Screen" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0056.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pogoplug asks you to designate which folders will be available via remote access.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Software Tour&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13357Software-Tour"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Software Tour" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0057.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can turn off remote access.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Desktop Access&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13359Desktop-Access"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Desktop Access" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0058.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can control everything from your PC, Mac, or Linux machine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Web Access&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13361Web-Access"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Web Access" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0059.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have web access, you have access to your files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Mobile Devices&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13363Mobile-Devices"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Mobile Devices" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0060.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the iPhone and iPad apps are pretty shaky thus far.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Great Way to Share Files&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13365Great-Way-to-Share-Files"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Great Way to Share Files" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0061.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, this is almost as good as Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Premium Feature&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13367Premium-Feature"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Premium Feature" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0062.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;here's what you pay your $29 for, but it doesn't work very well yet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Pogoplug Hardware&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13369Pogoplug-Hardware"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Pogoplug Hardware" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0063.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buy the Pogoplug hardware device, and you don't need to keep your computer running when you want to access your files remotely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Drop-Down Menu&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/#13371DropDown-Menu"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Drop-Down Menu" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/pogoplug-software/screenshot0065.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the web, you can perform lots of file management functions, as well as share files or or publish photos to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/cloud/"&gt;cloud&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/pogoplug/"&gt;pogoplug&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/review/"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/sharing/"&gt;sharing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/software/"&gt;software&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/streaming/"&gt;streaming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech &amp;amp; Gadgets channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4aruGxnyzBubqK-sc2mP7fhnVvE/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4aruGxnyzBubqK-sc2mP7fhnVvE/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4aruGxnyzBubqK-sc2mP7fhnVvE/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/4aruGxnyzBubqK-sc2mP7fhnVvE/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=1tKtZNUj41o:ME-CZ29L9FM:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/1tKtZNUj41o" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/05/01/pogoplug-software-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%253A+Mashable+%2528Mashable%2529</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
