<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Sets IPO at $28 to $35 a Share [BREAKING]</title>
      <description>Facebook has set the price for its initial public offering at $28-$35 a share, reportedly valuing the company between $85 and $95 billion. Facebook, Inc. is offering 180,000,000 shares of its Class A common stock and the selling stockholders are offering 157,415,352 shares of Class A common stock. We will not receive any proceeds from the sale of shares by the selling stockholders. This is our initial public offering and no public market currently exists for our shares of Class A common stock. We anticipate that the initial public offering price will be between $28.00 and $35.00 per share. This is a developing story. Stay tuned for more details 2004: First Offers Turned Down Facebook launches with humble beginnings that most people have seen dramatized in The Social Network by now. It was a small social site backed by only a little money, and limited just to the undergrads at Harvard. Right out of the gate, Facebook turned down offers from an unknown investor and Friendster, each offering $10 million. This was, of course, when the company was still called TheFacebook. Image courtesy of Flickr.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, ipo, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/facebook-sets-ipo-at-28-to-35-a-share-breaking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/facebook-sets-ipo-at-28-to-35-a-share-breaking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Acquires Professional Content Sharing Platform SlideShare For $119M</title>
      <description>Professional social networking site LinkedIn is reportedly set to acquire SlideShare for $119 million in cash and stock according to a release from LinkedIn: &#8220;LinkedIn (NYSE:LNKD), the world&#8217;s largest professional network on the Internet with 161 million members worldwide, today announced it agreed to acquire SlideShare, a leading professional content sharing community. The transaction is valued at approximately $118.75 million, subject to adjustment, in a combination of approximately 45 percent cash and approximately 55 percent stock. Subject to the completion of customary conditions, the acquisition is expected to close during the second quarter of 2012.&#8221; The move appears to be a feature grab for LinkedIn, with the release specifically mentioning the 7.4 million SlideShare presentations that are embedded onto over 1.4 million sites around the internet. This is a developing story. Refresh for updates.</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/insider/2012/05/03/linkedin-acquires-slideshare-for-119-million-in-cash-and-stock/</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/insider/2012/05/03/linkedin-acquires-slideshare-for-119-million-in-cash-and-stock/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Acquires Professional Content Sharing Platform SlideShare For $119M</title>
      <description>LinkedIn has just acquired professional content sharing platform SlideShare for $119 million in cash and stock. We&#8217;ve pasted the release below. UPDATING LinkedIn (NYSE:LNKD), the world&#8217;s largest professional network on the Internet with 161 million members worldwide, today announced it agreed to acquire SlideShare, a leading professional content sharing community. The transaction is valued at approximately $118.75 million, subject to adjustment, in a combination of approximately 45 percent cash and approximately 55 percent stock. Subject to the completion of customary conditions, the acquisition is expected to close during the second quarter of 2012. Founded in October 2006, SlideShare helps professionals discover people through content, and content through people. SlideShare users have uploaded more than nine million presentations, and according to comScore, in March SlideShare had nearly 29 million unique visitors, ranking it among the most heavily trafficked sites for professional content. SlideShare is also enabling the sharing of presentations across the Web; nearly 7.4 million presentations hosted by SlideShare are embedded across more than 1.4 million unique domains. &#8220;Presentations are one of the main ways in which professionals capture and share their experiences and knowledge, which in turn helps shape their professional identity,&#8221; said LinkedIn CEO Jeff Weiner. &#8220;These presentations also enable professionals to discover new connections and gain the insights they need to become more productive and successful in their careers, aligning perfectly with LinkedIn&#8217;s mission and helping us deliver even more value for our members. We&#8217;re very excited to welcome the SlideShare team to LinkedIn.&#8221; Rashmi Sinha, CEO of SlideShare commented, &#8220;We built SlideShare to help professionals share presentations and connect people through content. What we can build with LinkedIn, the largest professional network on the Internet, is the most natural extension of this vision. I am excited about what we can build together.&#8221;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/03/linkedin-acquires-professional-content-sharing-platform-slideshare-for-119m/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/03/linkedin-acquires-professional-content-sharing-platform-slideshare-for-119m/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OperationSAFE is going back to China this summer to work with abandoned children. You can help! http://t.co/U6t67lkm #DT @operationSAFE</title>
      <description>CathPrisk: OperationSAFE is going back to China this summer to work with abandoned children. You can help! http://t.co/U6t67lkm #DT @operationSAFE &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.firstgiving.com/fundraiser/jonathan-wilson-1/opsafe</link>
      <guid>http://www.firstgiving.com/fundraiser/jonathan-wilson-1/opsafe</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Too Much Tech Bad for the Modern Teenager? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Is tech saturation good or bad for the modern teenager? Arguments can be made either way, but there&#8217;s no debating that today&#8217;s teens are more wired than ever. And digital permeates the lives of young people in general, too. People aged 18-34 have an average of 319 online connections, according to a recent Pew Research Center study. That&#8217;s compared to an average of 198 connections for the 35-46 group, and the numbers continue to decrease from there. Pew also recently reported that 63% of teenagers text message with friends on a daily basis, compared to 39% who speak on the phone daily and just 35% who interact face-to-face outside of school. Other research has found that text-happy teens send more than 100 messages per day. But the digital revolution comes with drawbacks. A 2010 Kaiser Family Foundation study found a correlation between media consumption and poor academic performance. The study found that 21% of young people between the ages of eight and 18 consume at least 16 hours of media per day, while 17% consume less than three hours per day. 47% of the heavy users reported typically earning grades of C or below in school, compared to just 23% of the light users. Twice as many heavy users as light users reported getting in trouble frequently. The Internet education portal OnlineSchools.com combined the Kaiser and Pew findings with research from Common Sense Media and other organizations to put together an infographic showing how technology is affecting young people. Some of the findings are a couple years old, but the infographic does provide interesting food for thought. Check it out below for a fuller picture. Do you think total tech immersion does more to help or hurt teenagers? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, Damircudic More About: android, infographics, iphone, smartphones, tablets, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/teenager-infographi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/teenager-infographi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bing Takes on Google With Simple New Design</title>
      <description>Microsoft&#8217;s search engine Bing has done some heavy spring cleaning as a part of an effort to de-clutter its search result pages &#8212; and the new design looks a lot like Google. Bing rolled out a new look that is designed to help users get results faster than ever. But the seamless design bears a striking resemblance to Google Search&#8217;s simple layout. See below. &#8220;Over the past few months, we&#8217;ve run dozens of experiments to determine how you read our pages to deliver the link you&#8217;re looking for,&#8221; Sally Salas, principal group program manager at Bing, said on its official blog. &#8220;Based on that feedback, we&#8217;ve tuned the site to make the entire page easier to scan, removing unnecessary distractions, and making the overall experience more predictable and useful.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Despite Bing&#8217;s Rise, Google Still Dominates Search [INFOGRAPHIC] In addition to faster page-load times and more relevant search results, Bing tightened the header and removed the &#8220;left rail&#8221; related-search section, making it easier to find the information and links you want. It also enlarged the space between lines to increase readability and optimize the page for touch devices. Bing said it is working on updating its search page even more in the future. &#8220;We&#8217;re not finished, &#8221; Salas wrote. &#8220;Today, we&#8217;re also testing out some new ideas for the homepage, including a larger version of the popular daily image. If you happen upon the homepage changes, please let us know what you think.&#8221; What do you think of Bing&#8217;s new search results page? Do you think the site looks too much like Google? Let us know in the comments. BONUS: 12 Mysterious Google Maps Sightings 1. The Badlands Guardian This natural formation in Alberta, Canada is known as the Badlands Guardian and looks strikingly similar to a native American wearing a headdress. If you look close enough, it looks like he's wearing a pair of earphones, but that section is actually a man-made road and oil well.Click here to view this gallery. More About: bing, GoogleFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/bing-new-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/bing-new-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How 7 Top Brands Are Using Facebook&#8217;s New Ad Tools</title>
      <description>The Facebook Marketing Series is presented by Webtrends, enabling real-time relevance across digital channels for more effective marketing. Learn about the new consumer dynamic in our webinar with Altimeter Group. View now. On Leap Day 2012, Facebook gathered all its marketing executives in New York City for a coming-out party of sorts for a slew of new ad products. To people outside the industry, the promise of new initiatives might appear a bit on the dull side. But for advertisers, anything that Facebook does for advertising is of interest. Among the products Facebook introduced were Premium on Facebook, Reach Generator, Offers and Logged Out ads. The company also asked brands to embrace a paradigm shift from advertising to &#8220;Stories,&#8221; Facebook&#8217;s preferred term for brand-related messages. Since that time, a few big brands have experimented with the new tools. Here are a few examples or, if you prefer, Stories. Is there a standout brand campaign that you enjoy? Let us know in the comments. 1. Premium Ads: Tide The Procter &amp; Gamble detergent brand Tide turned a PR event into advertising in March. The program started when officials used Tide to clean up the chemical residue on a racetrack after a big fire at a NASCAR course in March. Tide&#8217;s program, which included outreach on Twitter, public relations and search, also leaned heavily on Facebook&#8217;s Premium ad products. Tide used the format to draw attention to the brand&#8217;s role in the incident. As with other Premium ads, the status update went out across the network, but it was especially focused on Tide fans and friends of Tide fans. If you or your friend interacted with the Tide brand page, then you might have seen it in your News Feed. Tide&#8217;s initial post was a link to a Business Insider article about the event, which included photos of people hauling boxes of Tide to the scene. Tide used Premium on Facebook to blast the post and further boosted engagement with a post asking fans to fill in a caption for a photo of workers cleaning up the mess. Facebook says that the NASCAR ad had a 62% higher engagement rate than previous ads the brand has run. The premium buy also got the post in front of 1 million people, more than doubling the usual reach of a Tide post. (Tide has close to 2.8 million fans, but only a portion see a post at any given time.) Sarah Pasquinucci, external relations manager for North American fabric at P&amp;G, says the brand has experimented with other premium posts but can&#8217;t say how they perform versus standard Facebook ads. &#8220;We&#8217;re always looking to reach consumers in the right place at the right time in the right way,&#8221; she adds. 2. Premium and Logged Out Ads: Subway Subway used the new Premium and Logged Out ads on Facebook to highlight spokesman Blake Griffin. The sandwich chain ran an update that featured a video with fun outtakes of Blake on the log-out screen and used the Page ad unit to promote it. People interacted nearly 1 million times with the ads and video, which hit nearly 500,000 plays. As a result, Subway&#8217;s reach during the week-long campaign increased tenfold. Tony Pace, the SVP and CMO of the Subway Franchisee Advertising Trust Fund, says the brand takes a &#8220;test and learn&#8221; approach to Facebook advertising and jumped at the opportunity to do something different. Pace says the Stories, in this case, performed better than his expectations and were a good way to reward fans without alienating consumers. &#8220;People who are really into our brand are surprisingly happy to get lots of content from us,&#8221; he says. &#8220;This was a good way of rewarding folks that want to see a lot from us.&#8221; Pace says the Logged Out ad did well because the content was compelling. &#8220;If people are logging out, they probably don&#8217;t want to spend more time there unless it&#8217;s something really interesting,&#8221; he says. 3. Reach Generator: Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s and Dr Pepper The Unilever-owned ice cream brand Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s took advantage of Reach Generator to make sure all its fans got the latest updates. Reach Generator is designed to expose fans to updates they might not otherwise see. As Facebook noted back in February, the typical post on a brand site only reaches 16% of fans. With Reach Generator, Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s hit 98% of fans during a 28-day period and saw twice as much engagement. Another early adopter of Reach Generator, Dr Pepper, hit 83% of its 8 million U.S. fans over a 28-day period and saw a 140% jump in &#8220;People Talking About This&#8221; (PTAT) with the tool. 4. Offers: Einstein Bros. Bagels and Chili&#8217;s Einstein Bros. availed itself of another new Facebook ad product, Offers, with a buy-one-get-one offer from Feb. 29 through March 4. Some 32,000 people (out of 690,000 fans) took the chain up on its offer, and Einstein Bros. logged a &#8220;significant&#8221; spike in PTAT during that time. Offers is an evolution of &#8220;Check-in Deals,&#8221; a mobile-only Facebook product. With Offers, consumers can redeem the deals on their desktop or mobile, since they live on a Brand Page. Meanwhile, Chili&#8217;s ran an Offers promotion offering a free appetizer or dessert with an entree purchase for three days. The chain, which has 1.9 million Facebook fans, saw 433,773 people claim the offer &#8212; around 20% of whom were on Facebook. About 30% of redemptions also came from Facebook, which is about three times higher than average. 5. Logged Out Ads: Ford Ford tried its hand at a Logged Out ad on March 20. The video, a Mustang commercial, got more than 1 million plays and boosted Ford&#8217;s PTAT that day by 180%. Thomais Zaremba, digital marketing manager at Ford, says she wasn&#8217;t sure that people would stick around to watch an ad when they were logging out, but many did. &#8220;I was surprised,&#8221; she says, noting that the number of people who log out every day &#8212; 40 million &#8212; was way more than she thought. Zaremba hasn&#8217;t tried another Logged Out ad since, but plans to. Says Zaremba: &#8220;We&#8217;re always interested in testing new spaces.&#8221; Series presented by Webtrends The Facebook Marketing Series is presented by Webtrends. Have consumers taken control of brands? Do friends, reviews and social spheres have more influence than brand marketing? Customers are changing the dynamic of the sales funnel. Find out from the experts at Webtrends and Altimeter Group how a measurement strategy can deliver relevant messaging for greater conversions and revenue. Watch our webinar now. More About: facebook ads, Facebook brand pages, Facebook Marketing Series, features, mashable</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/brands-facebook-ad-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/brands-facebook-ad-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Signal, the Instagram of Citizen Journalism</title>
      <description>What do you get when you combine a photo-sharing mobile platform like Instagram with more geo-location awareness and a Reddit-style voting system for stories breaking all over the world? Answer: Signal, the app citizen journalism may well have been been waiting for. The Signal app is currently in private beta launch, and will hit app stores for the iPhone in the next few months. You can sign up to test the app here. Signal is the brainchild of Lebanese entrepreneur Mark Malkoun, who says it will address the fundamental limitations of sharing stories on social media. &#8220;Initially, Twitter and Facebook were designed to get news from people or brands or celebrities,&#8221; Malkoun told Mashable. &#8220;Now, if something is happening say three miles away from you, say something really important, Twitter won&#8217;t systematically inform you unless you follow someone who happens to be there.&#8221; Facebook has since expanded to allow people to subscribe to others, and anyone could still search for news on Twitter via hashtags. Still, actual news can become muddied in other posts that have nothing to do with these news stories, Malkoun said. And needing to follow or subscribe to people first still gives weight to &#8220;power users.&#8221; But what if you just happen to be at the right place at the right time when it comes to breaking news? With Signal, the emphasis is on quick and easy photojournalism. Users capture media that they then upload to the app with a geo-tagged location and a short caption of around 60 characters. And if multiple people happen to be covering the same story, an algorithm for the app pushes the photos together, so the content becomes classified under the same story. Signal&#8217;s strategy hinges on an idea that has already turned Instagram into one of the hottest digital platforms &#8212; oneworth $1 billion to Facebook. As Instagram&#8217;s 50 million users can attest, there&#8217;s a strong desire to share visual, mobile stories with the world. When users open the app, they can view news photos according to their location, most recent upload or what others have voted top news. You can choose to see the top stories by country, continent or the world as a whole. Signal iPhone Screenshots &#8220;The idea is that you find out what is happening in a very simple way, and more importantly, a democratic way,&#8221; Malkoun said. &#8220;We chose [the name] Signal because it&#8217;s based on the territory, and the signal has a frequency. The more votes you collect, the bigger the verification.&#8221; But will people actually vote for newsworthy photos, or will it simply become a popularity contest? After all, the 25 most popular users on Instagram are already famous in real life. The Signal team acknowledges this concern, but the goal of the app is to steer clear of it, Malkoun said. The point is for the stories behind the photos &#8212; not necessarily the people taking them &#8212; to have influence. To make sure that people aren&#8217;t posting old stories or promoting personal agendas, every photo must be geo-tagged within the past 72 hours. &#8220;Usually, the power of a story diminishes the further you are from it geographically,&#8221; Malkoun said. &#8220;For example, if you live in the United States and there&#8217;s a car accident in Germany, you might not be interested. But take the tsunami and earthquake in Japan. If you were in Japan [at the time], anything might be interesting.&#8221; The Signal app is coming out of Lebanon, and Malkoun acknowledges the Arab Spring helped him consider what a citizen journalism app needed. &#8220;Everything we took in developing Signal, we took from reality&#8230;Of course, the whole environment here was inspired by the Arab Spring, no matter what,&#8221; he said. .&#8221;When we started, the whole news was about Gaddafi and Syria.&#8221; SEE ALSO: How Citizen Journalism Is Reshaping Media and Democracy Although the app only supports photos for now, Malkoun and the Signal team plan to add a video component in the future. The app&#8217;s emphasis on photos should help break down language barriers. Still, heavily-signaled stories &#8212; those that users like or vote for the most &#8212; will be translated so that audiences can have a better understanding of on-the-ground events across the world. The kind of news people will document and share with the app is not so much as important as the fact that they will have a chance to get their stories out, and determine what&#8217;s important themselves, Malkoun said. &#8220;It could range from breaking news to social news, but most importantly&#8230;A lot of times, there are a lot of subjects that are not talked about,&#8221; he said. &#8220;As soon as one reporter talks about it, that&#8217;s when it becomes news. [But] this person just spoke about it for one reason or another. Here, every story that gets in the system will have an equal chance.&#8221; Do you think Signal will revolutionize citizen journalism? Will stories around the world really have an equal chance to come to light? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. Photos courtesy of the Signal Team More About: apps, Arab Spring, citizen journalism, instagram, reddit</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/instagram-citizen-journalism/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/instagram-citizen-journalism/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teen Demands Seventeen Magazine Publish Non-Photoshopped Spread</title>
      <description>Another teen is using Change.org to make her voice heard. This time, it&#8217;s 14-year-old Julia Bluhm, who has rallied more than 7,000 signatures on a petition calling for Seventeen Magazine to print one unaltered photo spread in each of its monthly issues. &#8220;I&#8217;m a teenage girl, and I know how it feels to think you&#8217;re not good enough,&#8221; Bluhm says. &#8220;I want girls to be able to feel good about themselves, and being able to relate to the images in the magazines we read will help.&#8221; Bluhm, a ballet dancer from Maine, hopes Seventeen will follow Glamour&#8216;s lead, which recently announced it would stop altering images of models to make them look thinner. The 8th grader&#8217;s petition says Seventeen should use its platform to promote positive body images to its teenage readers. &#8220;Seventeen Magazine is supposed to be a relatable magazine, right? How can we relate to computer altered photos?&#8221; Bluhm says. &#8220;Seventeen is popular with my friends and lots of teen girls. If they agree to print one unaltered spread a month, they could start a trend that will help so many girls like me feel better about their bodies.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Facebook Campaign for &#8216;Bald Barbie&#8217; Gains Steam Bluhm, who describes herself as a feminist and an activist, blogs for the SPARK Movement, a girl-led movement fighting the sexualization of women in the media. Another Change.org campaign started by Michigan teen Katy Butler, petitioning the MPAA to change the rating of Bully, amassed more than half a million signatures last month. While Bluhm&#8217;s petition still has a long way to go before reaching the hundreds of thousands of signatures threshold, it joins a growing social media conversation about the promotion of positive body image. Tumblr and Pinterest have recently updated their policies regarding the promotion of pro-anorexia content. Is it the responsibility of teen-focused magazines to use their platforms to promote positive body image for young woman? Let us know in the comments if Bluhm has it right. BONUS: 15 Photoshopped Transformations of Celebs and Models hr&gt; Fergie Click here to view this gallery. More About: change.org, online activism, online petition, seventeenFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/seventeen-photoshop-petition/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/30/seventeen-photoshop-petition/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Startups Launch Out Of NewMe Accelerator&#8217;s Spring 2012 Demo Day [TCTV]</title>
      <description>The NewMe Accelerator, a startup incubation program founded last year aimed at under-represented minorities in the tech world (namely African Americans, Latinos, and women), held its second-ever Demo Day today for its latest class of entrepreneurs. A total of seven startups presented their wares to a packed room full of investors, reporters, and fellow entrepreneurs at Google&#8217;s downtown San Francisco office &#8212; the energy was high and the crowd&#8217;s response seemed really strong. TechCrunch TV was on site, and you can watch the video embedded above to get a look at the general demo day scene and see our interview with NewMe&#8217;s founder Angela Benton about the program&#8217;s growth so far and its plans for the future. A bit about NewMe&#8217;s program: It&#8217;s intense. For twelve weeks, the entrepreneurs all live together in the same house in San Francisco, where they are meant to &#8220;eat, sleep, and breathe&#8221; their respective tech-focused projects day and night. Meanwhile, big-name mentors such as Mitch Kapor, Ben Horowitz, Vivek Wadhwa and others drop by regularly to offer up advice and insight. Diversity In More Ways Than One What most people first notice about NewMe is its focus on gender and racial diversity, but at Demo Day it became apparent that the diversity angle extends to all aspects of the program. From a super modern restaurant menu app, to a system that connects local farms directly to consumers, to a website that lets clothing and accessory companies let their customers design their own individually-customized apparel, each NewMe company was totally unique from the next, making this Demo Day especially fun to watch. What is also cool about NewMe to me is that it&#8217;s not just about encouraging racial and gender diversity &#8212; geographical diversity is important as well. Talking to NewMe&#8217;s entrepreneurs, who hail from all over the United States and even other parts of the world, it becomes clear that each startup has been inspired and influenced in some way or another by the geographical history of its founders. A Closer Look At NewMe&#8217;s Latest We also spent time at the NewMe house last month when this class of startups was in the thick of the experience, about halfway through the 12-week program. At the bottom of this post, I&#8217;ve embedded the two videos we shot there &#8212; one in which we interview NewMe partner Wayne Sutton, and another in which we get full pitches from each of the Spring 2012 NewMe startups. First though, in alphabetical order, here is the full list of NewMe&#8217;s Spring 2012 class: AgLocal, Founder: Naithan Jones This is a web and mobile marketplace aimed at connecting regular consumers and restaurant owners with local farms that supply meat products. Butlr, Founder: Andre Gabriel This is a social shopping game that gives users virtual currency that can be put toward purchasing real-world items. Citizen Made (formerly The Modulus), Founder: Rachel Brooks Citizen Made is a software platform that lets any e-commerce company include the ability for their customers to customize and live-render their own individually designed versions of their products on the web. Helpr, Founder: Tendekai Muchenje This is a social media-enabled web and mobile platform that lets people make customer care inquiries and complaints through the Internet, rather than telephone help lines. Kairos, Co-Founders: Brian Brackeen and Amanda McClure This is a suite of software tools to help retail and service companies manage their employees&#8217; schedules and performances using facial recognition and augmented reality technology. PictureMenu, Founder: Christopher Lyons Aiming to put an end to outdated, dog-eared menus, PictureMenu replaces paper menus by bringing photo-rich restaurant menus to diners&#8217; smartphones and tablets. Ubi Video, Founder: James Norman This is a multi-platform video delivery program that provides a single place to watch all types of online video through one portal, with features that let you create personalized viewing schedules and more. Here is our interview with Wayne Sutton and a sneak peak at the vibe of the house: And here are the full pitches we received from the founders during our visit, mid-way through the Spring 2012 program:</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/02/newme-accelerator-spring-2012-demo-day-tctv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/02/newme-accelerator-spring-2012-demo-day-tctv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Quirky, Comical and Downright Weird YouTube Channels</title>
      <description>iJustine Justine Ezarick is all over the place. With more than 1,700 online videos and five YouTube channels she does everything from video blogging about her life to giving product reviews and video game commentary. There are also the random spurts of dancing in Apple stores. The result? The 28 year old has gotten a couple of small acting parts and an award at the 2011 Webby Awards for "choice web personality."Click here to view this gallery.It&#8217;s hard enough to make one viral-worthy video. Now imagine creating and running an actual YouTube channel with weekly video updates for millions of viewers who expect this all the time? That&#8217;s basically a full-time job in itself. Still, the people behind these seven channels have managed to do it pretty well. So, put the headphones on, close the office door, and don&#8217;t drink any liquids, because these videos will have you rolling over in laughter. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, ozgurdonmaz More About: contributor, features, ONLINE VIDEO, YouTubeFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/comical-weird-youtube-channels/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/03/comical-weird-youtube-channels/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
