<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>25 Women-Run Startups to Watch</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We continue our Women in Tech coverage with a list of startups with female founders and CEOs by Allyson Kapin, one of our Most Influential Women in Technology in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/women-in-tech/2011"&gt;&lt;img class="float-center" src="http://images.fastcompany.com/upload/1-25-women-start-ups.jpg" border="0" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Think women don't launch startups? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;1) You're not alone, and 2) Think again!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of months there has been another round of &lt;a href="http://geofflivingston.com/2010/12/29/tech-women-better-than-arrington/" target="_blank"&gt;women in tech and startup debates&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Robert Scoble says in a Facebook Group that he wants to write about women launching world-changing startups but struggles to find them. Michael Arrington over at &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/08/28/women-in-tech-stop-blaming-me/" target="_blank"&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt; says "the press is dying to write about [women startups]." Over on &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/Who-is-the-smartest-female-startup-founder-What-are-the-hottest-companies-started-by-women" target="_blank"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, there is a discussion about the hottest companies started by women. Caterina Fake, co-founder of Flickr and &lt;a href="http://www.hunch.com" target="_blank"&gt;Hunch&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most popular answers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It's easy to complain that it's hard to find women run startups--or to provide excuses. But instead, let's focus on 25 women running kick-ass startups. Will they change the world? I don't use crystal balls, but I sure do think that they have huge potential to make a serious mark.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Pauline Alker, Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.a-la-mobile.com/" target="_blank"&gt;a la Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Streamlining the way mobile handsets are developed and deployed. They aim to be the independent, open Linux system platform for the mobile phone industry. They adhere to design and development disciplines of openness, innovation and freedom of choice with configurable and customizable architecture. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A, B&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Alexa Andrzejewski, CEO and Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.foodspotting.com/ " target="_blank"&gt;Foodspotting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;A visual guide to good food and where to find it. Foodspotting lets consumers find and share the foods they love: Instead of reviewing restaurants, consumers can recommend their favorite dishes and see what others have recommended wherever you go. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A &lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Kris Appel, Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.tailwindtherapy.com" target="_blank"&gt;Encore Path&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Encore Path developed Tailwind, a device that helps improve arm function and range of motion for people with stroke or other brain injury. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linda Avey and Anne Wojcicki, Co-Founders, &lt;a href="http://www.23andme.com " target="_blank"&gt;23andme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Genetics just got personal. 23andme is a human genome indexing/application. They analyze your genetics through saliva testing and store the results online and help you interpret the data. You can keep it private or you can share it with family and doctors. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series B&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patricia Bright, Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.BioFuelBox.com " target="_blank"&gt;BioFuelBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Provides modular bio-refineries for converting waste materials into biodiesel.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annie Chang, Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://lolapps.com" target="_blank"&gt;LOLapps&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;LOLapps builds quizzes, gifts, and game platforms that provide user-generated, customizable applications. They are a growing social games company with over 300,000 user generated applications and 11 games in their portfolio.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rachna Choudhry and Marci Harries Co-Founders, &lt;a href="http://www.popvox.com" target="_blank"&gt;Popvox&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;POPVOX bridges the gap between the input the public wants to provide and the information Members of Congress want and need to receive. The product is based on the founders experience working with Congress and research with Congressional staff. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cathy Edwards, Co-Founder &amp;amp; CTO, &lt;a href="http://www.chomp.com" target="_blank"&gt;Chomp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Billed as a "a sort-of Yelp for iPhone apps" by TechCrunch, Chomp is an app discovery engine that enables users to search for iPhone apps on the Apple App Store, through a combination of app search and personalized recommendations. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Cindy Gallop, Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.IfWeRantheWorld.com" target="_blank"&gt;IfWeRantheWorld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ran the world, what would you do? IfWeRanTheWorld is a crowdsourced, collective action-generating platform, that makes things happen in the real world and reports back on the results. "If Facebook is the social graph, and Twitter is the interest graph, then IfWeRanTheWorld is designed to be the action graph," said Gallop.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kaliya Hamlin, Founder, &lt;a href="http://personaldataecosystem.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Personal Data Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;A leader and vocal advocate in the user-centric identity movement, Hamlin recently launched a new nonprofit to focus on how people control and access their own data online. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seeking funding to support their 501C3.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Julia Hartz, Co-Founder and President, &lt;a href="http://www.eventbrite.com " target="_blank"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Eventbrite is a social commerce platform for ticketing and event management. They processed $207 million in ticket sales in 2010, more than double from 2009. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A, B, C, D&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Tara Hunt, Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://shwowp.com/ " target="_blank"&gt;Shwowp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Shwowp helps you gather your purchase history in one place. It's a purchase sharing site where you can input product purchases, share items on Twitter or Facebook, follow friends' purchase activity and start conversations around products. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seeking funding&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Amy Jo Kim, Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.shufflebrain.com/" target="_blank"&gt;ShuffleBrain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Inspired by the explosion of Brain Games, and passionate about creating games that keep you sharp and socially connected, Shufflebrain builds games for a connected world. They've helped design games including Bejewelled 2, The Sims, and Rock Band. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Annalea Krebs, Founder, &lt;a href="http://ethicaldeal.com/" target="_blank"&gt;ethicalDeal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Similar to the Groupon and LivingSocial model but aimed at green consumers who love local deals on green products, ethicalDeal launched in November 2010 in Vancouver. Krebs expects they'll launch in Toronto and San Francisco in early in 2011 and a new city every three months thereafter.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown &lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Kristen Kuhns, Co-Founder and COO, &lt;a href="http://www.storyofmylife.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Story of My Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;A collection of online stories of people's lives. The site helps users build an interactive 360-degree view of who you are: your accomplishments, your feelings and thoughts, your narrative--the essence of who you are and what you will leave behind. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Angel&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Jen Pahlka, Founder, &lt;a href="http://codeforamerica.org" target="_blank"&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Code for America recruits savvy web industry folks into public service to use their skills to solve core problems facing communities. They help talented technologists leverage the power of the Internet to make governments more open and efficient, and become civic leaders able to realize transformational change with technology. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Grants&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;April Pedersen, Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.salsalabs.com" target="_blank"&gt;Salsa Labs&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Salsa Labs has grown into one of the most established online organizing and fundraising platforms for the nonprofit and political sectors. The platform allows over 3K nonprofits to organize and communicate with their supporters, activists, fans, and donors all managed through a single, hosted application. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seeking funding&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Elisabet de los Pinos, Founder: &lt;a href="http://www.aurabiosciences.com" target="_blank"&gt;Aura Biosciences&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Elisabet and her team are pioneering the development of nano-delivered drugs through its proprietary Nanosmart platform. In layman's terms? They are working on a chemotherapy agent that will have the ability to treat, target and be monitored in the body. Hat tip to Robert Scoble who highlighted her work while he was at &lt;a href="http://scobleizer.com/2011/01/26/davos-hero-elisabet-de-los-pinos/" target="_blank"&gt;Davos&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Charlotte Rademaekers, Founder and CEO, &lt;a href="http://www.call2action.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Call2Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Call2Action puts videos and action tools together in a portable online engagement and marketing tool. Their current product is a widget, called Spark to support social justice causes. The company says that they have an average interaction rate (number of actions taken anywhere on a widget divided by the number of times it has been loaded) of 6 times the industry standard at 28%.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Seeking funding&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Victoria Ransom, Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.wildfireapp.com " target="_blank"&gt;Wildfire Interactive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Their patent-pending technology allows corporations, small businesses, marketing agencies, bloggers and nonprofits to easily create their own branded interactive campaigns (e.g. sweepstakes, contests, give-aways, incentive-based surveys, etc) and to simultaneously publish them in multiple social networks and on their website. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carol Realini, Founder &amp;amp; CEO, &lt;a href="http://www.obopay.com" target="_blank"&gt;Obopay&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;A pioneer in mobile payments, Obopay lets consumers pay anyone, anywhere in the U.S. in just a few seconds using your phone. It offers flexible, instant mobile money that lets you send money to family, collect or make online payments, get a prepaid debit card or send a remittance. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A, B, C, D, and E&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Birame Sock, Founder, &lt;a href="http://myreceipts.com/" target="_blank"&gt;MyReceipts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;A green solution for consumers to receive and file receipts. Participating retailers include Whole Foods (who also offer digital coupons to MyReceipts users), Best Buy, Amazon, and more.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Uknown&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Wendy Tan White, Co-Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.moonfruit.com" target="_blank"&gt;MoonFruit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moonfruit provides software that allows users, with no previous web technology experience, to build and develop websites. Over 1.2 million business and individual websites have been built by people around the world using Moonfruit's website building tool SiteMaker. The company started in 1999, endured the dot com bust and made a big come back in 2009. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Amra Tareen, Founder and CEO, &lt;a href="http://www.allvoices.com" target="_blank"&gt;Allvoices.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;A global community that shares and validates user-generated news, videos, images and opinions tied to news events and people from all over the world. In January the site received over 11 million unique web visitors. &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexa von Tobel, Founder, &lt;a href="http://www.learnvest.com" target="_blank"&gt;Learnvest&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;p&gt;Learnvest makes personal finance fun (well as fun as you can possibly make it). Whether you're buying a home, saving for grad school, or simply trying to become a better 'budgeter,' LearnVest provides products, content, and a community to make personal financial information accessible to millions of women. Learnvest offers a customized financial action plan, a budgeting tool, and more.&lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt; Series A&#8232;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Resources:&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to the following organizations, the women run startup community is energized and flourishing. All of these groups helped contribute to the &lt;strong&gt;25 Women Run Startups to Watch&lt;/strong&gt; list by not only supporting women entrepreneurs but by building comprehensive databases of women run startups.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.pathforwardcenter.org/index.php?ht=d/sp/i/3374/pid/3374/" target="_blank"&gt;ACTIVate/Pathforward&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.asita.org/" target="_blank"&gt;ASTIA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.goldenseeds.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Golden Seeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ncwit.org/" target="_blank"&gt;NCWIT&lt;/a&gt; - Be sure and check out the &lt;a href="http://ncwit.org/heroes" target="_blank"&gt;Entrepreneurial Heroes interview series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href="http://www.springboardenterprises.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Springboard Enterprises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.springworks.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Springworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thenextwomen.com/" target="_blank"&gt;The Next Woman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wellconnectedleader.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Well Connected Leader, Inc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.women2.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Women 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;What women-led startups are you most excited about?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="font-size:small"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read about &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/women-in-tech/2011"&gt;The Most Influential Women in Technology&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/tag/women-in-technology-2011"&gt;expert views on Women in Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="font-size:small"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The funding information was compiled through public and organizational databases. In some cases, the funding information maybe incomplete if the databases were not updated in time for the publication of this article.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="font-size:small"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt; My web firm &lt;a href="http://www.radcampaign.com" target="_blank"&gt;Rad Campaign&lt;/a&gt; has worked with Salsa Labs. Annie Chang, Kaliya Hamlin, Tara Hunt, and Amra Tareen have participated in the &lt;a href="http://www.womenwhotech.com" target="_blank"&gt;Women Who Tech TeleSummit&lt;/a&gt;, which I founded in 2008.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/FastCoLeaders" target="_new"&gt;&lt;img class="float-left" src="http://images.fastcompany.com/upload/fastcoleaders.jpg" border="0" alt="@FastCoLeaders" width="70" /&gt;Follow @FastCoLeaders for all of our leadership news, expert bloggers, and book excerpts.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style="font-size:small"&gt;Allyson Kapin is the Founder of the award winning web agency &lt;a href="http://www.radcampaign.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Rad Campaign&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.womenwhotech.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Women Who Tech&lt;/a&gt;, and the Blogger-in-Chief for &lt;a href="http://www.frogloop.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Care2's Frogloop&lt;/a&gt; blog. You can follow her on Twitter at &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/womenwhotech" target="_blank"&gt;@WomenWhoTech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="font-size:small"&gt;[Image by &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ooocha/2631610399/sizes/l/" target="_blank"&gt;Marion Doss&lt;/a&gt; | illustration by AH]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.fastcompany.com/1722401/25-women-run-startups-to-watch?partner=rss</link>
      <guid>http://www.fastcompany.com/1722401/25-women-run-startups-to-watch?partner=rss</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Reason To Love Cyndi Lauper</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;object style="height: 390px; width: 445px"&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/4PrBnG9E4I4?version=3"&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt; &lt;param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/4PrBnG9E4I4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" width="445" height="390"&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When your flight has been canceled and your frustrated anxiousness is cooking to a boiling point under the fluorescent airport lights, the only thing you want to hear on the PA loudspeaker is your name being called from the stand-by list. But now the other thing you won't mind hearing on the loudspeaker is &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Cyndi Lauper &lt;/span&gt;singing the fuck out of&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt; Girls Just Want To Have Fun&lt;/span&gt;. That's what happened at Jorge Newbery Airport in Buenos Aires on Friday after airlines canceled flight after flight.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When the steam rising off of everybody's asshole started to cause the sprinklers to shake, Cyndi helped out the airline staff by trying to lift everybody's spirit with SONG! It's not an open bar, but it's the next best thing. And I don't think anybody cared that she was dressed like a Sith Lordess who just raided the sunglasses section of Duty Free.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href="http://thedailywh.at/2011/03/05/so-this-happened-of-the-day-6/"&gt;TDW &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://dlisted.com/node/41087</link>
      <guid>http://dlisted.com/node/41087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sony Shares Holiday Sales Numbers For The PlayStation</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/playstation-default-554x341.jpeg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="playstation-default-554x341" title="playstation-default-554x341" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sony Computer Entertainment &lt;a href="http://www.scei.co.jp/corporate/release/120110_e.html"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; some solid sales numbers for its various &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/playstation/"&gt;PlayStation&lt;/a&gt; systems for the past holiday season today. Sony says that they moved a total of 6.5 million PlayStation 2/3/PSP/Vita units worldwide (Sony defines &amp;#8220;holiday season&amp;#8221; as between November 21 and January 5 in Asia, November 21 through December 31 in America, and November 18 through December 31 in Europe).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To be more specific, the company sold:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;500,000 units of the PlayStation &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/tag/vita"&gt;Vita&lt;/a&gt; (which &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/20/sony-sells-321407-ps-vitas-in-2-days-apologizes-for-technical-problems-at-japan-launch/"&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; in Japan on December 7 and in Hong Kong and Taiwan on December 23)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;3.9+ million PS3s (Sony says the system is on track to sell 15 million units in the fiscal year through March 31)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;1.6 million PSPs (all models combined)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;500,000 PS2 systems&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;1.7 PlayStation Moves (not part of the 6.5 million total)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sony also said that Vita owners can choose between 24 different games at the moment and that 70 additional titles are currently in development. The company&amp;#8217;s newest video game system will hit Europe, Australia, and America on February 22, 2012.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/480542/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/01/10/sony-holiday-playstation-sales/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/01/10/sony-holiday-playstation-sales/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reilly: I believe in Tim Tebow</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://espn.go.com/espn/story/_/id/7455943/believing-tim-tebow&amp;amp;service=tinyurl.com&amp;amp;source=espn"&gt;&lt;img style="padding-left:10px;" align="right" border="0" style="border:none;" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://espn.go.com/espn/story/_/id/7455943/believing-tim-tebow" height="49" width="41" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Rick Reilly says Tim Tebow's ability to inspire is his greatest talent.</description>
      <link>http://espn.go.com/espn/story/_/id/7455943/believing-tim-tebow</link>
      <guid>http://espn.go.com/espn/story/_/id/7455943/believing-tim-tebow</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Nemo Leads Charge of Classic Pixar Films Turned 3D</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-3y-6LDArp0?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Turns out that Disney loves the fishes because they&amp;#8217;re going to be in 3D. Disney has announced that Pixar&amp;#8217;s animated classic &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0266543/" target="_blank"&gt;Finding Nemo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; will hit theaters this Fall for a limited, three-dimensional run. This isn&amp;#8217;t the first time Disney has re-released 2D Pixar films in 3D. In the lead-up to &lt;em&gt;Toy Story 3&lt;/em&gt;, the studio released &lt;em&gt;Toy Story&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Toy Story 2&lt;/em&gt; in a 3D double feature.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finding Nemo 3D&lt;/em&gt; follows in the footsteps of Disney&amp;#8217;s first 3D successes including &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/09/15/lion-king-3d/"&gt;The Lion King&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; which earned $30 million when it was re-released in September and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0101414/" target="_blank"&gt;Beauty and the Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; which hit theaters on Jan. 13.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The studio is hoping that &lt;em&gt;Finding Nemo 3D&lt;/em&gt; will have similar success. That shouldn&amp;#8217;t be a problem given that a film about an animated clownfish trying to find his son broke some impressive records. &lt;em&gt;Finding Nemo&lt;/em&gt; won the 2003 Oscar for best animated feature, at release it was the highest grossing G-rated movie ever, and was named one of the 10 greatest animated films by the American Film Institute in 2008.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Disney is also eyeing re-releases of &lt;em&gt;The Little Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Monsters Inc.&lt;/em&gt; in 3D. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finding Nemo 3D&lt;/em&gt; will have to deal with some interesting competition. Disney isn&amp;#8217;t the only studio getting into the 3D re-release race. Fox is re-releasing &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace&lt;/em&gt; in February. This April, Paramount is helping Fox put out a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/03/15/titanic-3d/"&gt;3D version of James Cameron&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Titanic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which was the highest grossing film of all time until it was beat by the 3D film &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/avatar"&gt;Avatar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which Cameron also directed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/10/04/disney-3d-releases/"&gt;Disney to Re-release 4 Hit Animated Movies in 3D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The films all play on a certain amount of viewer nostalgia. They also introduce classic franchises &amp;#8212; especially in Disney&amp;#8217;s case &amp;#8212; to a younger audience. The question is whether the 3D updates can justify people throwing down the extra money to go see a film they already saw.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The advantage of a Pixar film is that the digital nature of the source content lends itself well to 3D post-production. For certain films &amp;#8212; especially &lt;em&gt;Nemo&lt;/em&gt;, we&amp;#8217;re downright excited about the possibilities. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Is the 3D re-release craze exciting or frustrating? Should all classic Disney films be released in 3D or does Disney need to slow down? Sound of in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/3d/"&gt;3D&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/3d-movies/"&gt;3d movies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/disney/"&gt;disney&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/entertainment/"&gt;Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/film/"&gt;Film&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/finding-nemo-3d/"&gt;Finding Nemo 3D&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/pixar/"&gt;pixar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/the-lion-king/"&gt;the lion king&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/video/"&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/entertainment/"&gt;Entertainment&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashentertain" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Entertainment on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/entertainment" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Entertainment channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/B9bWeZ27b4hnTfAHRbx2Rf-DB9U/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/B9bWeZ27b4hnTfAHRbx2Rf-DB9U/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/B9bWeZ27b4hnTfAHRbx2Rf-DB9U/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/B9bWeZ27b4hnTfAHRbx2Rf-DB9U/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=zlf_GWkQa6s:P2vdcUjuF1I:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/zlf_GWkQa6s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/finding-nemo-3d/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/finding-nemo-3d/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Time-Lapse Video Takes You Around the World in 6,237 Photos</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/viral-video-of-day/"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/&amp;title=Beautiful Time-Lapse Video Takes You Around the World in 6,237 Photos&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/mashable_youtube_video_of_the_day_logo.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Each day, Mashable highlights one noteworthy &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/youtube"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; video. Check out all our &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/viral-video-of-day/"&gt;viral video picks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UGnrT0F-Igs?rel=0&amp;wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This stunning time-lapse video puts you in the passenger seat of one man&amp;#8217;s almost year-long adventure across 17 countries. In it, you&amp;#8217;ll see 6,237 pictures spliced together to create several beautiful, fast-paced montages that surely will make you want to pack your suitcase and take a trip this year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Equipped with a &lt;a href="http://panasonic.net/avc/lumix/systemcamera/gms/gf1/" target="_blank"&gt;Panasonic Lumix GF-1&lt;/a&gt; camera, San Francisco-based &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/kiendlam" target="_blank"&gt;Kien Lam&lt;/a&gt; quit his job, bought a plane ticket to London and then spent 343 days traversing the globe and snapping photos along the way. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wanting to inspire others to travel, Lam returned home and whipped up the 290-second video, which was edited in &lt;a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshoplightroom/" target="_blank"&gt;Adobe Lightroom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/aftereffects.html" target="_blank"&gt;Adobe After Effects&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/final-cut-pro/id424389933?mt=12" target="_blank"&gt;Final Cut Pro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;To capture the spirit of the trip, I took time-lapse photographs at practically every city I traveled to,&amp;#8221; he told to &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; in an email. &amp;#8220;Each two-second scene is comprised of about 40 to 60 photographs.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/01/07/exhilarating-film-move/" target="_blank"&gt;Exhilarating Film Takes You Through 11 Countries in 1 Minute [VIRAL VIDEO]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Music from his brother William Lam complements the visuals in the clip. The song, &amp;#8220;Places and Faces,&amp;#8221; will be available to buy on iTunes and Amazon on Jan. 15. To learn more about Kien Lam&amp;#8217;s trip or get notified when the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/logicpro/" target="_blank"&gt;Logic Pro&lt;/a&gt;-produced song is out, visit his &lt;a href="http://kienlam.net/travel-faq" target="_blank"&gt;travel blog&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fun fact: Lam rode in 19 planes, 58 buses and 18 boats during his trip.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; has featured other badass &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/time-lapse/" target="_blank"&gt;time-lapse videos&lt;/a&gt; in the past. Below, you&amp;#8217;ll find galleries filled with nature- and design-related clips.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. Oak Tree &lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="616" height="400"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/-bUDylndVoY&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;param value="transparent" name="wmode"/&gt; &lt;embed width="616" height="400" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/-bUDylndVoY&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Short but sweet, this video encompasses all four seasons with photographs taken of an oak tree as it changes during a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/#129951-Oak-Tree'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. Tim Potter &lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;object width="616" height="400"&gt; &lt;param value="http://www.youtube.com/v/laoS5r8UnVc&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0" name="movie"/&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"/&gt; &lt;param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/&gt; &lt;param value="transparent" name="wmode"/&gt; &lt;embed width="616" height="400" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/laoS5r8UnVc&amp;amp;border=0&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;loop=0"/&gt; &lt;/object&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here you can see how an HTML5 website is created by building upon the wireframe in Photoshop - from "concept to comp," as the designer states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/#46231-Tim-Potter'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/travel/"&gt;travel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/trending/"&gt;trending&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/viral-video/"&gt;viral video&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/viral-video-of-the-day/"&gt;viral-video-of-the-day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/entertainment/"&gt;Entertainment&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashentertain" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Entertainment on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/entertainment" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Entertainment channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kIt8hCiMEiWFpiAhKyDFF0VmMp8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kIt8hCiMEiWFpiAhKyDFF0VmMp8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kIt8hCiMEiWFpiAhKyDFF0VmMp8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kIt8hCiMEiWFpiAhKyDFF0VmMp8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=DeneXk4O818:NrQwdgPd87c:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/DeneXk4O818" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/time-lapse-video-around-the-world/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Timeline vs. Old Profiles: How People View Them Differently [STUDY]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/screen-shot-2011-12-29-at-1-40-18-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-859875"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/&amp;title=Facebook Timeline vs. Old Profiles: How People View Them Differently [STUDY]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Screen-shot-2011-12-29-at-1.40.18-PM-275x147.png" alt="" title="Screen shot 2011-12-29 at 1.40.18 PM" width="275" height="147" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-859875" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Your social media profiles have morphed as the sites they live on have changed. So has the way people view them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To get a better idea of how profile design affects profile viewers, &lt;i&gt;Mashable&lt;/i&gt; asked eye-tracking research startup &lt;a href="http://eyetrackshop.com/" target="_blank"&gt;EyeTrackShop&lt;/a&gt; to compare visual statistics for Twitter, Facebook and MySpace profiles before and after major site redesigns. The company had 30 people to look at the profiles while tracking their eye movements. Here are some interesting observations from the resulting data:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/14/eyetracking-facebook-brand-pages/" target="_blank"&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s What People Look at on Facebok Brand Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Facebook Timeline cover photos get noticed first.&lt;/b&gt; However, study participants still spent a longer time looking at the Facebook Timeline profile photo than the cover photo.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Facebook ads get noticed more in Facebook Timeline.&lt;/b&gt; While 43% of participants noticed Facebook &amp;#8220;sponsored stories&amp;#8221; in the old profile format, 63% noticed the ads in the Timeline format. Participants spent the same amount of time on average looking at the ads in each profile.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Personal information such as employer and location gets more attention in the new Facebook Timeline.&lt;/b&gt; Viewers spent an average 2.2 seconds looking at this section in the new format, which includes images, but only 1.6 seconds looking at this section in the old format.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;MySpace text gets read last and least.&lt;/b&gt; In both the new and old versions of MySpace, top photos were noticed first and viewers spent the most time looking at them. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;The New MySpace makes soundtracks more prominent.&lt;/b&gt; Ninety-seven percent of viewers noticed the section of songs you can click on to play in the new profile, but only 53% noticed them in the old profile.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Profile information is easier to find in the new Twitter.&lt;/b&gt; While viewing the old profile, participants noticed tweets before they noticed profiles. While viewing the new version, that pattern was reversed.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take a look at the full results in the slideshow below and add your own observations to the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Facebook&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/#40295Facebook"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Facebook" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/new-and-old-social-media-profiles/screen-shot-2011-12-29-at-9-58-02-am.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-timeline"&gt;Facebook Timeline&lt;/a&gt; became available to all Facebook users in &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/15/facebook-timeline-everyone/"&gt;December&lt;/a&gt;, replacing the Facebook Wall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/#40295Facebook'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/eyetrackshop/"&gt;EyeTrackShop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/myspace/"&gt;myspace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/AArF3h8ROi7abAkc53vhhuMnaYI/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/AArF3h8ROi7abAkc53vhhuMnaYI/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/AArF3h8ROi7abAkc53vhhuMnaYI/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/AArF3h8ROi7abAkc53vhhuMnaYI/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/business?a=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/business?i=w5-3PfhsWow:TKrfktrzYi4:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/business/~4/w5-3PfhsWow" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/12/29/eyetracking-study-new-vs-old-profiles/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Plan Your Social Integration Strategy</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/&amp;title=How to Plan Your Social Integration Strategy&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/facebook-login-360.jpg" alt="" title="Facebook login" width="275" height="171" class="alignright size-full wp-image-883907" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Brian Sullivan is vice president of client services at &lt;a href="http://www.gigya.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Gigya&lt;/a&gt;, where he advises clients on implementing social technology. Gigya offers websites a suite of social technology like &lt;a href="http://www.gigya.com/social-login/" target="_blank"&gt;social login&lt;/a&gt;, comments, game mechanics and a social identity management platform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;No longer does a business wonder whether its site should contain social components and functionality. The utility of social plugins on websites has been established. Now the question is how to implement social technologies correctly &amp;#8212; merely adding technologies like social login, sharing, commenting and game mechanics is not enough. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the web is ripe with sites that offer social implementations that miss the mark. And often, businesses suffer from a &#8220;set it and forget&#8221; mentality, in which a product manager will slap a Facebook Like button on his sites and declare the business&#8217;s website now social. Quite frankly, that is not enough. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instead, for marketers and IT professionals, it&#8217;s critical to ask &amp;#8220;why do we have this technology?&#8221; and &#8220;how do we define success?&#8221; For a vast majority of sites, some combination of social plugins is worth the effort. The best way to figure out what works for your site is to test, test and test again. Be it A/B or multivariate testing, here are my thoughts on why testing is so important, and how to get the most from your site&#8217;s social technology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Which Social Login Provider Should I Choose?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Testing your site&#8217;s social functionality starts with testing your social login providers. You can go to any number of sites across the web that only offer &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/facebook-connect/"&gt;Facebook Connect&lt;/a&gt; for social login. (My company&amp;#8217;s CEO, Patrick Salyer, &lt;a href="http://venturebeat.com/2011/09/21/your-users-have-multiple-online-personas-can-they-all-log-in-to-your-site/" target="_blank"&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt; why multiple online personas make it imperative that companies offer social logins beyond Facebook Connect.) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I&#8217;m helping clients conduct these tests, I almost always find that a great way to start is by offering user-sets different login options to determine which social network APIs should be implemented. Sure, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; will almost always be the dominant player in share-of-logins, but we&#8217;ve seen the other players account for up to a combined 60% share of social logins. Are you willing to throw away those users and the insight that comes with them? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There&#8217;s huge value in adding a mix of other login options such as &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/linkedin/"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/yahoo/"&gt;Yahoo&lt;/a&gt;. We know from reviewing our client base that one set of social login providers that works for one site doesn&#8217;t necessarily work for another. Sure, you don&#8217;t need to run a test to realize LinkedIn probably doesn&#8217;t work for a site targeting preteens, but do you have a higher than expected number of visitors that prefer to use Google? You won&#8217;t know until you test. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, if your site has a user base in other markets like Europe, South America or Asia, you may also want to offer login through various international social networks like &lt;a href="http://vk.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Vkontakte&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.orkut.com/PreSignup" target="_blank"&gt;Orkut&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.renren.com/" target="_blank"&gt;RenRen&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://mixi.jp/" target="_blank"&gt;Mixi&lt;/a&gt; to ensure your site appeals to global users. The only way to accurately find out which of these networks and identity providers should be offered is through testing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;What Is the Best Testing Strategy?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;A/B testing is a great place to start finding out what does and doesn&#8217;t work for your site. A/B testing means having one control group and one variant group (sites often overlook the need for a second control group, which we&amp;#8217;ll call &amp;#8220;C&amp;#8221;) to establish that the control group has a large enough sample size. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rather than use a formula used in hypothesis testing, I prefer to use convergence testing. Convergence testing effectively means &#8220;A/B/C&#8221; testing, where A and C offer the same login options, and B offers a different set of login options. The &#8220;convergence&#8221; part means that A and C will eventually yield similar conversion rates (conversion in this case being whether users logged in or not). If A and C have no variable other than the being presented to different user sets, they should quickly see the same results. If the result varies it means you haven&#8217;t seen enough traffic to reach convergence (the point at which both controls yield the same result), and you should keep the test running until you do. B poses a different set of login options placed in a different order from A and C. That&#8217;s the delta you&#8217;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that a successful A/B test is any test that yields insight into visitor behavior. If the change you introduce from testing yields a 2% decrease in conversion rates, the test was still successful &#8211; you learned the lesson quickly and now have confidence that your control is still the best way to go. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In today&#8217;s business climate, it&#8217;s crucial for sites to integrate with social networks and, with focused testing, to capitalize on that integration to realize a number of benefits. For example, by discovering 30% of your site&#8217;s users prefer to share via Twitter versus Facebook, you would likely offer Twitter as a prominent authentication option. While Facebook almost always leads in number of logins, Twitter tends to drive the most referral traffic per share of any social network (data my company has collected shows that shares from Twitter drive five click-backs, on average). Chances are that you probably would want to take advantage of that valuable referral traffic, and the only way to effectively optimize your site for Twitter sharing is through testing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The above just scratches the surface of ways to better leverage social via testing. The key concept to remember is that in order to ensure successful testing, you need to let the process run until you see convergence. Keep that in mind and you&#8217;ll be well on your way toward making the best use of your site&#8217;s social technology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/stock-photo-17274934-facebook-on-smart-phone.php?st=343ebc2" target="_blank"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=1879217" target="_blank"&gt;arakonyunus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-connect/"&gt;facebook connect&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/linkedin/"&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-plugins/"&gt;social plugins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/2pVzTAnuFjQ0SMZeWYaBGlKHBpQ/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/2pVzTAnuFjQ0SMZeWYaBGlKHBpQ/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/2pVzTAnuFjQ0SMZeWYaBGlKHBpQ/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/2pVzTAnuFjQ0SMZeWYaBGlKHBpQ/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=H8DXiXnnsVo:17oRGe5p5A8:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/H8DXiXnnsVo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/01/13/social-integration-strategy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What just happened at Foursquare? Widespread reports of user accounts being deleted.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of Foursquare users have found this morning that if they try to log onto their accounts, they have been deleted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If users try to log in, the are met with the error message:&lt;strong&gt; The email/phone you entered is incorrect. Please try again &lt;/strong&gt;and even visiting a Foursquare profile without logging in brings up a 404 Not Found message that suggests the profile no longer exists:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-13-at-08.28.49.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-313121" title="Screen Shot 2012-01-13 at 08.28.49" src="http://thenextweb.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-13-at-08.28.49-520x202.jpg" alt="Screen Shot 2012 01 13 at 08.28.49 520x202 What just happened at Foursquare? Widespread reports of user accounts being deleted." width="520" height="202" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/foursquare%20deleted"&gt;Users have taken to Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to voice their frustration, some believing they have been hacked and others wondering why they are unable to access their accounts via their mobile devices or on the Foursquare website.&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/wp-content/blogs.dir/1/files/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-13-at-08.28.49.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ooooops, looks like @&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/foursquare"&gt;foursquare&lt;/a&gt; deleted all of their user accounts over night.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&#8212; Frau H&#246;lle (@FrauHoelle) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FrauHoelle/status/157738939942322176" data-datetime="2012-01-13T08:21:08+00:00"&gt;January 13, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Foursquare hasn&amp;#8217;t updated its Status website to note any issues, with the last post dating back to December 18.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/01/13/what-just-happened-at-foursquare-widespread-reports-of-user-accounts-being-deleted/</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/01/13/what-just-happened-at-foursquare-widespread-reports-of-user-accounts-being-deleted/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Goes On Strike: Jan 18th! All-out blackout 2 stop #SOPA #PIPA. Petition @twitter and other sites to join us. http://t.co/vbM6tqyr</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a1.twimg.com/profile_images/601982398/rom_normal.png" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/davidanaxagoras"&gt;David Anaxagoras&lt;/a&gt;: Web Goes On Strike: Jan 18th! All-out blackout 2 stop &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=SOPA" target="_blank"&gt;#SOPA&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=PIPA" target="_blank"&gt;#PIPA&lt;/a&gt;. Petition &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/twitter" target="_blank"&gt;@twitter&lt;/a&gt; and other sites to join us. &lt;a href="http://t.co/vbM6tqyr" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/vbM6tqyr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/davidanaxagoras/status/158010248697872384"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://sopastrike.com/</link>
      <guid>http://sopastrike.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Brands Can Use Pinterest to Boost Consumer Engagement</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/&amp;title=5 Ways Brands Can Use Pinterest to Boost Consumer Engagement&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/pinterest-pin-360.jpeg" alt="" title="Pinterest Pin" width="275" height="171" class="alignright size-full wp-image-875971" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Constance Aguilar is a social media strategist and account manager at &lt;a href="http://www.abbipr.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Abbi Public Relations&lt;/a&gt;, where she oversees client strategy on social media channels, through traditional media relations and event production. You can follow her on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/ConnieAguilar" target="_blank"&gt;@ConnieAguilar&lt;/a&gt; and read her blog posts at &lt;a href="http://abbipublicrelations.wordpress.com/" target="_blank"&gt;abbipublicrelations.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The surprise smash-hit social networking site of 2011 wasn&#8217;t &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/tumblr/" target="_blank"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/google-plus/" target="_blank"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, it was a site that, even today, is still an invite-only social network. The Palo Alto site Pinterest skyrocketed into the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/22/pinterest-video/"&gt;top ten most visited social networks&lt;/a&gt; of the past year and continues to gain traction and popularity. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The image-based platform is a simple enough concept: Users create and name Boards anything they like (Places I&amp;#8217;d Like to Visit, Pretty Dresses, My Cookie Creations, etc.) and post relevant photos on corresponding Boards, while categorizing Boards under one of the 32 general Pinterest categories. Users follow one another based on interests, and photos are displayed in a pin board-type feed that is simple, yet visually stunning. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But how can brands and companies utilize this platform to their advantage? Here are five ways to jump on the Pinterest bandwagon to reach an already established female audience and a rising male audience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Contests&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Brands and companies can connect and build buzz among their audiences by hosting various types of contests on Pinterest. Contests can range from creating the &#8220;Best Board&#8221; to a earning the most Repins. Users could post photos of the best outfits they put together or of sculptures built from products bought at a specific store. Similar to photo contests on Facebook or Twitter, Pinterest offers a way for brands to build visually stunning interaction between themselves and their patrons. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. New Product Approval&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/TIME.png" alt="" title="TIME" width="640" height="345" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-875951" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When launching a new product, whether a new dress, dinner dish or cellphone, companies want to determine initial reactions to the product&amp;#8217;s look and feel. Because of Pinterest&#8217;s commenting ability, it&amp;#8217;s an ideal platform on which to introduce a new product and gather firsthand opinions. Because Pinterest&#8217;s popularity hasn&#8217;t reached the caliber of Facebook, brand managers can easily organize, analyze and determine sentiment from the results. As users Repin a photo, brand managers can gather more intelligence, and ultimately decide whether their companies should move forward with mass production. Think of it as a social media focus group. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Showcase Brand Personality&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;For companies that don&#8217;t necessarily have product lines to show off, the social networks allows photos to communicate a brand&amp;#8217;s personality. For instance, a mayoral candidate could have a Pinterest Board of photos that features his philanthropic outreach and community relations. A magazines can post past and present photos that showcase places it has sent journalists, events it has covered, etc. Each Pin allows for a description and a link to the original story. Therefore, any company can quickly connect an audience with its story, mission and future plans, all via photo Pin. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. Display Various Sectors of a Company&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Employee-Lounge.png" alt="" title="Employee Lounge" width="640" height="287" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-875967" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Larger operations can use Pinterest to nicely organize areas of focus and relay them to the public. For instance, an integrated marketing agency may host several individually themed Boards. One Board showcases photos of its public relations efforts, while a design department Board displays logos and web pages it has created, and a final Board hosts photos of employees in action. These types of organized displays would also allow other businesses to view similar work, effective strategies and innovative teams, making Pinterest a strong B2B community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. Creative Communication Between Brands and Customers&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Using Pinterest, brands can create Pins and Boards that feature customers&amp;#8217; product interpretations, and then showcase them for entire audiences. This way customers can further relate to products, and brands have a way to thank to their supporters by integrating them into their communities. For example, a clothing company Pins a photo of a shopper in one of its outfits, and writes caption &#8220;Brandy A. paired this floral dress with our black lace stockings and brown leather boots to create the perfect fall ensemble.&amp;#8221; Brandy feels special because the brand recognized her involvement and creativity, and thus is inspired to return, and the company creates content that keeps fans constantly involved. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pinterest holds immense potential for brands to interact with their audiences and to visually entice current and potential customers. Using the power of image, companies can create buzz around products, display more in-depth aspects of their businesses, and ultimately create more personal and visually pleasing social experiences for their audiences. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/community/"&gt;community&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/customer-engagement/"&gt;customer engagement&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/gamification/"&gt;gamification&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/pinterest/"&gt;pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oqMnE6ZFyglyYA-yjASua5kpZdA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oqMnE6ZFyglyYA-yjASua5kpZdA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oqMnE6ZFyglyYA-yjASua5kpZdA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oqMnE6ZFyglyYA-yjASua5kpZdA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=qk_tpSUbFfs:Xqs5VNbCi9s:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/qk_tpSUbFfs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/01/10/pinterest-business-consumer-engagement/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
