<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Apple-Like Solar-Powered Keyboard Controls Mac, iPad, iPhone</title>
      <description>Love portable keyboards? You&#8217;re going to want to see Logitech&#8217;s latest offering. The Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K760 for Mac, iPad and iPhone lets you pair up to three of those devices at a time. That means no more disconnecting and re-entering a code each time you want to switch between devices, from your Mac to your iPad, say. Just one push of a button does it. The Solar panel means never having to change batteries again. The keyboard can be charged either from sunlight, if you like to work outside, or from indoor lamp light. Logitech says that fully powered, the keyboard will run for three months, based on an average 8 hours of use a day. The new solar keyboard is an upgrade from the Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K750 we reviewed in 2010, and has some welcome improvements for Apple users. For starters, it looks a lot like the regular Apple Wireless Keyboard; Logitech has designed the layout and keys to more closely resemble those on a Mac. The dedicated Home key works like the Home button on your iPad or iPhone. The Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K760 hits stores in the U.S. and Europe in June with a list price of $80. If this report is correct, it may be followed by another hot sun-fueled Apple gadget from Logitech: a solar-powered iPad case that can charge your tablet. Logitech Brand Manager Todd Walker demos the keyboard in the video below: Are you using a portable keyboard with your tablet? Have you tried a solar keyboard? Let us know how it&#8217;s working for you in the comments. More About: Bluetooth Keyboard, logitech, solar power, wireless keyboard</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/wireless-solar-keyboard/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/wireless-solar-keyboard/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too Funny: Google wants .LOL Domain</title>
      <description>Google has applied to control a slew of domain names that are not only related to its core business but have &#8220;interesting and creative potential.&#8221; The company announced on its blog on Thursday that it has submitted applications to the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) for the following domains: .google, .youtube, .doc and .lol. ICANN, which assigns top-level domains to sites worldwide, will announce in June which domains will be added to the existing list that includes &#8220;.com&#8221; or &#8220;.gov.&#8221; &#8220;In 2016, it&#8217;s estimated that almost half of the world&#8217;s population will be online, yet nearly 50 percent of the websites we visit are found in the .com top-level domain (TLD), which was among the first TLDs created in 1984,&#8221; Google wrote on its Official Blog. &#8220;Despite the great opportunities the web has enabled for people around the world, there is still a lingering question about the diversity of the domain space (given that the number of generic TLDs has only increased by 14 in the last 28 years).&#8221; Google aims to grow the number of TLDs in four categories, such as trademarks (such as .google), those related to its core business (.docs), ones that improve the user experience and increase the identification of certain genres (.youtube) and fun options (.lol). The search engine giant also noted that it plans to keep security and abuse prevention top of mind in creating a positive experience for web users. &#8220;We&#8217;re just beginning to explore this potential source of innovation on the web, and we are curious to see how these proposed new TLDs will fare in the existing TLD environment,&#8221; the company says. &#8220;By opening up more choices for Internet domain names, we hope people will find options for more diverse &#8212; and perhaps shorter &#8212; signposts in cyberspace.&#8221; What do you think of Google&#8217;s choice for new top-level domain names? Which ones would you like to see pop up on the web? Let us know in the comments. More About: Google, ICANNFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/google-domain/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/google-domain/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Finally Lets Page Admins Schedule Posts, Have Different Roles</title>
      <description>Third-party apps like HootSuite just got a little less relevant with an update from Facebook that lets Page admins schedule posts. A new help center page from Facebook also outlines how brand pages can now dole out specific duties to multiple page admins, each with varying degrees of permissions. The chart below outlines the new roles of manager, content creator, moderator, advertiser and insights analyst. A separate help center page from Facebook also provides an answer to one question many Facebook Page admins have been asking for some time: How do I schedule a post to appear later? The answer: Posts can be scheduled up to six months in advance at 15-minute intervals. Facebook Page admins, are these features you&#8217;ve been waiting for? How does this change your Facebook marketing strategy? BONUS: Facebook Promoted Posts: A Step-By-Step Guide Want to Promote a Post? Click "Promote" to open this drop-down menu. Clicking on the denomination pulls up another drop-down menu.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, facebook page, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/facebook-page-schedule-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/facebook-page-schedule-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX Dragon to Return Home Today</title>
      <description>SpaceX&#8217;s Dragon capsule, which has successfully docked with the International Space Station on Friday, is scheduled to return to Earth today. While Dragon was attached to the ISS, astronauts unloaded 1,146 pounds of supplies, including food and other crew provisions. Then they packed the Dragon &#8212; the only spacecraft capable of returning a significant amount of cargo from the space station &#8212; with 1,455 pounds of cargo that will be returned to Earth, including hardware used for experiments, spacewalks and station systems. At 4:07 a.m. ED this morning, the SpaceX Dragon capsule was unberthed from the ISS, and is now preparing for the return. If everything goes as planned, Dragon should land in the Pacific Ocean at 11:44 a.m. ET, hundreds of miles off the west coast of California. Check out a gallery of photos from the mission tweeted by SpaceX below and our interview with SpaceX&#8217;s founder and chief designer Elon Musk here. SpaceX Dragon Capsule flying in formation with the ISS Click here to view this gallery. More About: NASA, SpaceX, SpaceX DragonFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/spacex-dragon-returns-home/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/spacex-dragon-returns-home/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube</title>
      <description>Jeff Pidgeon: SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Fantastic Memorial Day Weekend Instagram Shots [GALLERY]</title>
      <description>Celebrating Memorial Day A collection of photos from Memorial Day celebrations. Courtesy @melissa_marlowClick here to view this gallery. It&#8217;s Memorial Day weekend in the United States, and Americans are spending time with friends and family, enjoying the first barbecue of the summer and remembering their fallen military heroes. While people are soaking up some rays or paying tribute to lost heroes, they&#8217;re posting some fantastic snapshots to Instagram. SEE ALSO: Freedom Tower: 11 Beautiful Instagrams of NYC&#8217;s Tallest Building Mashable has collected some of our favorites in the gallery above. Show us your Memorial Day weekend Instagram pictures and tell us about your long weekend in the comments below! More About: gallery, instagram, memorial day, pictures, Social Media, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/26/memorial-day-instragram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/26/memorial-day-instragram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Facebook Integration Shows What Your Friends Are Learning</title>
      <description>The Pinterest-like website for learning that the founders of Grockit launched Thursday now has a Facebook integration that shows your friends what you&#8217;re learning. Learnist, the newly launched product, allows anyone to compile content pieces onto a board (they call it a &#8220;learning&#8221;) that may look familiar. Unlike Pinterest, however, creators suggest a path in which to consume each content component. Users can check off each component as they go or &#8220;re-add&#8221; it to one of their own learnings. The idea is to avoid the misinformation, hacked-together how-to articles and other useless content one must weed through in a typical Google search and instead provide a clear learning path that will eventually include some form of assessment. Topics range from the frivolous &#8212; like how to find the best pizza in Brooklyn &#8212; to common core standards taught in classrooms. Regardless of which of them you look at, you can now assure your Facebook friends you&#8217;re getting smarter. More About: education, Grockit, learnist</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/learnist-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/learnist-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Productivity Hacks for the Startup CEO</title>
      <description>Ashish Rangnekar is the CEO and Co-Founder of BenchPrep, a marketplace and learning platform for exam prep and assessment courses. Follow him @ashishrangnekar. Startups are all about speed, efficiency, and maniacal focus. It&#8217;s exactly this breakneck pace and agility that enables them to beat large corporations at their own game. The startup CEO must also embody this speed and efficiency while managing exponential growth and, very often, the pains that come with it. SEE ALSO: Bad Tech Etiquette to Avoid at Work While a startup can grow from two to 100 employees and one to one million users, its CEO remains with just 24 hours a day to manage it all. That can be daunting, overwhelming, and exhausting if you lose focus. To stay on top, here are five simple, yet very powerful, productivity hacks. 1. Focus on Three Priorities a Day Before you start the day &#8212; at the office, home or on the road &#8212; jot down three important tasks that you must finish that day at any cost. No more, no less. Just three. Of course, you may have to work on ten other things and stop to put out fires, but identifying and planning your entire day around these priorities enables you to maintain focus and keep critical tasks from getting lost in the fray. 2. Leave 10 Minutes for Email Continuous access to an avalanche of emails can make you feel obligated to frequently check your email. But few emails require immediate attention, and taming the email beast can be a tremendous drain on productivity. Instead, set aside 10 minutes each hour to check and reply to emails. There is no need to write long dissertations with thoughtfully articulated openings and endings. You are busy and so is the next person. Keep it short. When necessary, handle critical issues that demand immediate attention with internal chat. 3. Make 20-Minute Meetings the Norm As your team and responsibility grows, so can the number of meetings that sap your productivity, and that of your team. Every discussion does not require a 60-minute session. In fact, probably 95% of these conversations can be handled in 20 minutes or less. But you have to set appropriate expectations. Start by changing the default meeting length in your calendar tool to 20 minutes. In the long term, this will improve the overall efficiency and clarity of your communication, and encourage the entire team to communicate more quickly and with fewer words. 4. Give Yourself a 30-Minute Head Start A CEO should be three steps ahead of the competition, two steps ahead of investors/partners, and a step ahead of other team members. An easy way to stay ahead is to start ahead. Begin your day 30 minutes before your stakeholders. This doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean you have to be in the office 30 minutes before everyone. The idea is to anticipate issues and tasks before anyone else and get a jump on them early in the day. Also, before leaving the office each day, plan for things you know will need to be handled the next day. Perhaps even drop an email to your team so that it&#8217;s waiting in their inbox the next morning. 5. Have a 40-Minute Chill Out Hacks or no hacks, managing time is a challenging task and it can wear you down quickly. Be smart about productivity and don&#8217;t adhere to the theory of &#8220;just work hard&#8221; no matter what the cost. You must make time to clear your head, focus your thoughts, and relax. Otherwise, you&#8217;ll burn out. Step away for about 40 minutes every five hours to re-energize and regain your focus. Lunch with the team is a great way to relax, yet utilize the time toward achieving a greater goal. Casual lunch conversations will help take your mind off work while building a great relationship with colleagues. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, andrearoad More About: Business, contributor, features, Small Business, StartupsFor more Startups coverage:Follow Mashable Startups on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Startups channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/productivity-hacks-ceo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/productivity-hacks-ceo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can &#8216;Call Me Maybe&#8217; Work as Job Recruitment? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>A New Jersey public relations firm has embraced the &#8220;Call Me Maybe&#8221; voice-dub trend by posting a choreographed video to YouTube &#8212; as a part of an effort to look for job candidates. The catchy song from Carly Rae Jepsen has been endlessly covered over the past few weeks, but this is the first time we&#8217;ve seen a business use the hit song to reach job applicants. Litsky Public Relations, a boutique PR agency in Hoboken, New Jersey, aims to attract young staffers with pop culture and social media knowledge. &#8220;With two open positions and tons of recent grads entering the job market, Litzky PR wanted to connect with potential candidates in a unique, engaging format that allowed our agency to stand out from the crowd,&#8221; Michele Litzky, president and founder of Litzky Public Relations, told Mashable. SEE ALSO: &#8216;Call Me Maybe&#8217; Parody Features Digital Obama, Romney [VIDEO] The video starts with an employee &#8212; who carries publications such as Advertising Age and PRWeek &#8212; entering the firm&#8217;s office building, while lip-syncing the lyrics to Jepsen&#8217;s song. The clip then shows staffers dancing and singing along throughout the office &#8212; from meeting rooms to in front of the coffee machine &#8212; as well as on the streets of Hoboken. &#8220;By using the power of social media and tapping into a pop culture phenom, we are connecting with candidates where and how they live,&#8221; Litzky said. &#8220;The video immediately communicates our playful office culture and showcases the pride each employee takes in being a &#8216;Litzky Lady.&#8217;&#8221; Ironically, despite the song&#8217;s lyrics, the firm doesn&#8217;t actually want candidates to call. At the end of the video, an employee holds up a sign that says, &#8220;No calls, please. Visit LitzkyPR.com/Jobs.&#8221; What do you think of the strategy to lure potential job candidates? Is it all good fun, or a sign of trying too hard? Let us know your opinion in the comments. More About: Call Me Maybe, Entertainment, Music, PUBLIC RELATIONS, Social Media, viral, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/call-me-maybe-covers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/call-me-maybe-covers/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adorable Kids Try to Read Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Like Mary Poppins swooping in to bring joy to children, two volunteer English teachers recently descended on a rural Cambodian school for three weeks, at one point challenging young students to recite a 34-letter word. Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious, wrote Mathieu Cuvelier and Lucy Crook. The word &#8212; popularized by the 1964 Disney flick Mary Poppins &#8212; initially stumps the ABOUTAsia Schools students. But as the above clip from marketing agency The Viral Factory shows, the children eventually learn how to say the challenging word. SEE ALSO: Boy Ages From Birth to 9 in 127 Seconds [VIDEO] More About: Children, education, Movies, viral videos, YouTubeFor more Video coverage:Follow Mashable Video on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Video channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/adorable-kids-try-to-read-supercalifragilisticexpialidocious-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/adorable-kids-try-to-read-supercalifragilisticexpialidocious-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which DSLR Camera Is Right for You?</title>
      <description>The Documenting Your Life Series is presented by Western Digital. We believe your life&#8217;s most valuable moments should always be close and accessible. My Passport 2 TB portable hard drives let you dream big and carry small. Whether you use a smartphone or a point-and-shoot as your primary camera, if you&#8217;re serious about photography, all paths lead toward a digital SLR (single-lens reflex) model. With their large image sensors, interchangeable lenses and a seemingly endless supply of tweakable features, DSLRs maximize both flexibility and mobility. They look pretty hot, too. Since the debut of the Nikon D1 in 1999 &#8212; the world&#8217;s first modern DSLR &#8212; the technology has advanced considerably. Once for still pictures only, almost all DSLRs manufactured today record video, too. Camera makers have enhanced autofocus mechanisms with swarms of extra focus points and added high-tech features, such as face detection. Some even have swiveling LCDs for hard-to-get shots. But those are extras. The reason you get a DSLR is so you can take great pictures. The large image sensors in DSLR cameras capture more light than those in smaller models, and they&#8217;re paired with high-performing image sensors. That lets many DSLRs shoot still photos in RAW format &#8212; which records all light data (except for direction, right Lytro?) with no compression. Shooting in RAW results in very large files, but it also ensures photographers get the most accurate pictures possible. Finally, DLSRs are made to be the center of a photography experience that goes beyond the camera. Almost all have ports and jacks for accessories, and there&#8217;s also a &#8220;hot shoe&#8221; on top, where you can attach powered items, typically an external flash. DSLRs are the gateway to building a photography arsenal, but they&#8217;ll also take great pics on their own. When you desire a new DSLR, the right camera depends mainly on what you&#8217;re looking to do with it. Below, we outline some typical use cases and suggest a model for each situation. The Graduate You&#8217;ve liked the simplicity of point-and-shoots, but their limitations are starting to frustrate you more and more. You need something that performs better in low light and can capture fast motion when needed &#8212; with minimal blur. Still, you don&#8217;t want to get overwhelmed by features. Entry-level DSLRs were made with you in mind. Models like the Canon EOS Rebel T3 and Nikon D3100 have all you need to get started. Although they give the full-manual flexibility of any DSLR, they also have many simplified exposure presets. Just switch the dial to, say, landscape photography, and the camera will automatically configure its settings to capture a crisp shot of that mountain range. Today, even basic DSLR cameras can capture HD video. But if that&#8217;s not important to you, you can still find some cheaper older models, such as the Nikon D3000, which shoots stills only. But the ability to switch is a very handy feature, so there&#8217;s a good chance it&#8217;s well worth the extra coin to get a camera that does both. The Videographer Buying a stand-alone video camera almost seems anachronistic today. However, still cameras don&#8217;t often make for the best video cameras. Because of differences in optics and image processing, cameras that are primarily used for taking stills often don&#8217;t capture high-quality video. Fortunately, DSLRs have tremendous advantages over cameraphones and point-and-shoots in those areas, and can make excellent video cameras &#8212; as long as you know what to look for. The Canon T3i and Nikon D5100 are great choices for budding videographers. Both capture video in full 1080p resolution, and that speedy image processing means they have good &#8220;burst&#8221; modes. Nikon also offers continuous autofocus while shooting video, keeping your target sharp as it moves (however, this usually results in noise from the servos getting captured). Looking beyond the usual suspects, Sony&#8217;s Alpha DSLRs have impressive video-capturing abilities, sometimes at a better price. The Sony Alpha a57 can capture 1080p video at 60 frames per second &#8212; Canon and Nikon cameras in its price range max out at 30. It also has nice bonuses, like a swiveling LCD screen and HDMI output for connecting to a big-screen TV (also available on the D5100). The Upgrader If you have an older or lower-end DSLR and are looking to upgrade, there&#8217;s lots to choose from. Going to a mid-level camera won&#8217;t just improve your photos, but also the overall photography experience. With better image processing and bigger camera bodies, you&#8217;ll enjoy faster burst mode rates and longer-lasting batteries, plus those swiveling LCDs become more common. The Canon EOS 7D is an excellent choice for upgraders, able to capture full HD video and shoot up to eight still photos per second. &#8220;Prosumers&#8221; will love the 19-point autofocus system and the intelligent viewfinder, which is more graphically dynamic than previous models. If the 7D is a little on the pricey side for you, you might want to check out the 60D, which has many of the same features. Nikon&#8217;s mid-level DSLRs start with the D7000, which has two user-definable exposure settings, letting you instantly configure the camera for your most common environments. There&#8217;s a 39-point autofocus system, and it can shoot up to six still pics per second. It also has continuous autofocus when shooting video. Sony gives you great bang for your buck with its mid-level DSLR. The Alpha a65 captures pics with a massive 24.3 megapixels, and its Burst mode is an impressive 10 frames per second. Like the a57, it can record 1080p video at up to 60 frames per second, and you have full control of shutter speed and aperture while recording. The LCD can swivel, and the viewfinder is a high-resolution OLED screen that can show the results of camera adjustments in real time. Finally, if you&#8217;ve broken more than one DSLR while shooting in extreme situations, the Pentax K-30 (due in July) is made with you in mind. It&#8217;s fully weather-sealed, so it&#8217;s up to the task of shooting on the beach or a mountaintop, and it can withstand cold temperatures and dust. It shoots 1080p video (30 frames per second) and can capture six stills per second in burst mode. The Serious Photographer If you want a taste of what it&#8217;s like for pro photographers &#8212; or simply want the best of the best &#8212; you&#8217;ll want a high-end DSLR. These are serious image-capturing devices that pour on the megapixels and customized settings. With so much tweakability, they often do away with some automatic features common on lower-end models (like exposure presets and a built-in flash) entirely. The Canon EOS 5D Mark II is a great step toward true pro photography. Its full-frame image sensor can take 21-megapixel shots, and if your situation is less than ideal, you can improve your pics with features like an &#8220;Auto Lighting Optimizer&#8221; and &#8220;Peripheral Illumination Correction.&#8221; If you have a little more money to burn, there&#8217;s also the more recent 5D Mark III, which has better image processing and a few more tricks. For Nikon, the D300s will get your feet wet with pro features, like in-camera image editing, a 51-point autofocus and nine customizable picture settings. But if its 12.3 megapixels aren&#8217;t enough for you, cast your eyes toward the D800, the highest-resolution full-frame DSLR on the market, at 36.3 megapixels. Both capture 1080p video at 30 frames per second. If you think you&#8217;re ready for the extreme high end, you&#8217;ll want either the Nikon D4 or Canon EOS-1D X. Both have too many features to summarize well here, but each will satisfy the pro within you. Their bulky camera bodies provide lots of extra power and a convenient handgrip for portrait shots, but that also means they&#8217;re not for casual shooting. What&#8217;s Your Shot? Buying a DSLR is a lot like buying a computer or a car &#8212; it&#8217;s a commitment to both a product and a company. It&#8217;s not to be taken lightly, but if you can match the right model with your goals, it&#8217;ll unshackle the shutterbug within you and you&#8217;ll soon be taken better pictures than you ever have. We&#8217;ve covered just some of the options here &#8212; there are lots more to explore, so browse the web, visit your local camera shop and find your perfect model. Once you go DSLR, you&#8217;ll never go back. What&#8217;s your model? Let us know in the comments. Series presented by Western Digital The Documenting Your Life Series is is presented by Western Digital. We believe your life&#8217;s most valuable moments should always be close and accessible. My Passport 2 TB portable hard drives let you dream big and carry small. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, by_nicholas More About: Canon, digital cameras, Documenting Your Life Series, DSLR, features, mashable, Nikon, pentax, sony</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/dslr-camera-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/dslr-camera-guide/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: Here&#8217;s How You Pay to Promote Posts</title>
      <description>Facebook has released details about a new feature that allows businesses to easily promote their posts and get updates in front of more eyes &#8212; for a fee. Although it was reported earlier this month that Facebook was testing a &#8220;highlighted posts&#8221; feature, the company has now made it official &#8212; with a page that explains how the promoted posts will work. &#8220;When you post on your page, it currently may only reach a limited amount of the people that Like your page each week,&#8221; a Facebook staffer says via a video posted on the social network. &#8220;Promoted posts help increase the people you reach for any eligible post. It&#8217;s an easy and fast way to reach more of the people that Like your page and your friends.&#8221; If a coffee shop wants to let its Facebook fans know that it&#8217;s having a 20% discount special, for example, the merchant can promote that post so it gets better placement in its Facebook fans news feeds. Businesses can also target posts based on specific location or language, and will be able to keep track of how many people saw the post. Any post that is less than three days old can be promoted. To do so, visit the sharing tool to create a post and located next to the &#8220;Post&#8221; and &#8220;Public&#8221; buttons will be a &#8220;Promote&#8221; tab. Clicking on the &#8220;Promote&#8221; drop-down menu will allow you to set your budget of how much you want to spend (such as $5 or $10) to highlight the post throughout the duration of the promotion. &#8220;Your promoted posts will be seen by a larger percentage of the people who like your Page than would normally see it,&#8221; Facebook noted on its site. &#8220;It will also be seen by a larger percentage of the friends of people who interact with your post.&#8221; People will see promoted posts labeled with &#8220;Sponsored&#8221; in their news feed (not with other ads located in the right column of Facebook), whether they are accessing Facebook on a PC or mobile device. When they Like the post, comment or share, their friends will see it as well. Similar with ads, you will be billed to the primary funding source designated in the Ads Manager section of your account, Facebook noted on the site. For more information on how to promote posts, visit Facebook.com/help/promote. What&#8217;s your take on promoted posts? Do you think they&#8217;re a great way for businesses to get more attention, or will it clutter users&#8217; news feeds? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Facebook, facebook ads</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/facebook-promoted-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/facebook-promoted-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
