<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Adorable Kids Try to Read Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Like Mary Poppins swooping in to bring joy to children, two volunteer English teachers recently descended on a rural Cambodian school for three weeks, at one point challenging young students to recite a 34-letter word. Supercalifragilisticexpialidocious, wrote Mathieu Cuvelier and Lucy Crook. The word &#8212; popularized by the 1964 Disney flick Mary Poppins &#8212; initially stumps the ABOUTAsia Schools students. But as the above clip from marketing agency The Viral Factory shows, the children eventually learn how to say the challenging word. SEE ALSO: Boy Ages From Birth to 9 in 127 Seconds [VIDEO] More About: Children, education, Movies, viral videos, YouTubeFor more Video coverage:Follow Mashable Video on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Video channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/adorable-kids-try-to-read-supercalifragilisticexpialidocious-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/adorable-kids-try-to-read-supercalifragilisticexpialidocious-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook: Here&#8217;s How You Pay to Promote Posts</title>
      <description>Facebook has released details about a new feature that allows businesses to easily promote their posts and get updates in front of more eyes &#8212; for a fee. Although it was reported earlier this month that Facebook was testing a &#8220;highlighted posts&#8221; feature, the company has now made it official &#8212; with a page that explains how the promoted posts will work. &#8220;When you post on your page, it currently may only reach a limited amount of the people that Like your page each week,&#8221; a Facebook staffer says via a video posted on the social network. &#8220;Promoted posts help increase the people you reach for any eligible post. It&#8217;s an easy and fast way to reach more of the people that Like your page and your friends.&#8221; If a coffee shop wants to let its Facebook fans know that it&#8217;s having a 20% discount special, for example, the merchant can promote that post so it gets better placement in its Facebook fans news feeds. Businesses can also target posts based on specific location or language, and will be able to keep track of how many people saw the post. Any post that is less than three days old can be promoted. To do so, visit the sharing tool to create a post and located next to the &#8220;Post&#8221; and &#8220;Public&#8221; buttons will be a &#8220;Promote&#8221; tab. Clicking on the &#8220;Promote&#8221; drop-down menu will allow you to set your budget of how much you want to spend (such as $5 or $10) to highlight the post throughout the duration of the promotion. &#8220;Your promoted posts will be seen by a larger percentage of the people who like your Page than would normally see it,&#8221; Facebook noted on its site. &#8220;It will also be seen by a larger percentage of the friends of people who interact with your post.&#8221; People will see promoted posts labeled with &#8220;Sponsored&#8221; in their news feed (not with other ads located in the right column of Facebook), whether they are accessing Facebook on a PC or mobile device. When they Like the post, comment or share, their friends will see it as well. Similar with ads, you will be billed to the primary funding source designated in the Ads Manager section of your account, Facebook noted on the site. For more information on how to promote posts, visit Facebook.com/help/promote. What&#8217;s your take on promoted posts? Do you think they&#8217;re a great way for businesses to get more attention, or will it clutter users&#8217; news feeds? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: Facebook, facebook ads</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/facebook-promoted-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/facebook-promoted-posts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find a Digital Job in Real-Time at Mashable&#8217;s Online Career Expo</title>
      <description>Mashable is excited to announce its first ever online career expo, an event that will bring together job seekers and employers in the digital space without leaving your laptop. The event, created in partnership with Brazen Careerist, will take place on July 31 and consist of a 3-hour online career fair where employers from New York to Washington, D.C. can interact with professionals looking for positions in areas like social media marketing, product management, web development, content creation and more. Early registration for both employers and job seekers is now open. Space is limited, so sign up today to make sure you get a spot. Here&#8217;s how the career expo will work: Employers and job seekers from Washington D.C. to New York City (including Baltimore and Philadelphia) will sign up through our partner, Brazen Careerist. Participating employers will get a fully customized page where they can list opportunities and share information about their company. During the career expo on July 31, one-on-one real-time chat will connect employers and job seekers, and allow them to quickly share resumes, background and social profiles. The online career expo builds on Mashable&#8217;s ongoing commitment to connect the best careers and candidates in digital. Our job board lists hundreds of current opportunities, and our editorial team consistently offers resources ranging from &#8220;The Beginner&#8217;s Guide to LinkedIn&#8221; to &#8220;6 Ways to Get a Tech Job Without a Tech Degree.&#8221; We think the online career expo adds a new, real-time twist to the digital career space, and hope to bring it to more regions in the future. More About: jobs</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/mashable-online-career-expo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/mashable-online-career-expo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the L.A. Kings Are Redefining Sports Social Media</title>
      <description>Among professional sports teams, the social media playbook is pretty cut and dried &#8212; be enthusiastic yet conservative, engage but don&#8217;t offend and it&#8217;s definitely better to err on the side of blandness. The NHL&#8217;s Los Angeles Kings, however, are tearing that playbook to bits &#8212; and it&#8217;s working. The Kings&#8217; Twitter account and social media team have an unabashedly biased voice, regularly poke fun at opposing teams&#8217; fans and hometowns and pull comedic stunts other pro sports teams would likely deem too lively. The Kings play in the first game of the NHL&#8217;s Stanley Cup Finals Wednesday night. Since the playoffs began in early April, the @LAKings Twitter account has added about 60,000 followers. Their Stanley Cup opponent, the New Jersey Devils, have gained about 20,000 new Twitter followers over the same time span. After the Kings beat the Vancouver Canucks in an early playoff game, the official account posted a tweet reading, &#8220;To everyone outside of BC you&#8217;re welcome.&#8221; Before the Finals matchup with the Devils, the Kings posted this tweet: Aside from fist pumping, what else is there do in NJ? &#8212; LA Kings (@LAKings) May 28, 2012 The Canucks tweet in particular caused a stir in sports business circles. Some were aghast at the flippancy and called it a major breach of etiquette. But Pat Donahue, the Kings employee who sent the tweet, says his boss Dewayne Hankins &#8220;texted me a few minutes later and said, &#8216;Hall of Fame tweet,&#8217; or something like that.&#8221; Donahue and Hankins run the Kings&#8217; social media presence. Hankins says their approach deviates from the traditional pro sports strategy intentionally, and also benefits from the social media team being a part of the Kings&#8217; marketing department as opposed to its public relations arm. &#8220;We think there&#8217;s an ability to engage our own fans and not be so straight down the line,&#8221; he told Mashable in an interview. &#8220;We look at it as we&#8217;re sort of like the scoreboard &#8212; we&#8217;re going to give you plenty of information, but look to get fans riled up too.&#8221; In the case of the Canucks post &#8212; Hankins calls it &#8220;the tweet that shook Canada&#8221; &#8212; the duo only felt it may have crossed a line once media began bringing it up with Kings players. Many of the team&#8217;s ribbing tweets are actually inspired by fans of other teams, Hankins and Donahue say. So many fans of other Canadian teams expressed hatred for the Canucks, saying &#8220;you&#8217;re welcome&#8221; seemed a natural reaction. The Kings poke fun at sports media as well. After noticing a couple mistakes in stories about the team, Donahue decided to capitalize on the web&#8217;s current infographic obsession by producing this tongue-in-cheek graphic to set the record straight on key franchise details. SEE ALSO: NHL&#8217;s Boston Bruins Launch One Digital Network to Rule Them All Celebrities are also a target for banter. Rainn Wilson, who plays Dwight Schrute in the hit show The Office, recently tweeted the team about potentially scoring some playoff tickets. The team responded by sending him tickets &#8212; encased in Jell-O to riff off a scene from The Office. Might other sports teams begin adopting a less staid social media approach in the wake of the Kings&#8217; success? Hankins says it&#8217;s something he&#8217;d like to see, but that he also has no misconceptions about his team&#8217;s social eminence. &#8220;We&#8217;ve doing this for some time and it&#8217;s a lot of fun,&#8221; he says. &#8220;But there&#8217;s no way we&#8217;re getting this kind of publicity if the team&#8217;s not performing as well as they are.&#8221; Do you think more sports teams should follow the Kings&#8217; lead in social media, or is it better to stick to a more conservative approach? Share your opinion in the comments. Image courtesy TAZphotos, Flickr. More About: Social Media, sports, trending, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/kings-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/kings-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthony Bourdain Joins CNN to Host New Weekend Program - CNN</title>
      <description>Launching in Early 2013 on CNN &amp; CNNI, Program Expands CNN&#8217;s Coverage of Food and Travel; Bourdain to Also Offer Commentary Across CNN Programs World-renowned chef, bestselling author and Emmy winning television personality Anthony Bourdain will join CNN as host of a new weekend program, creating a signature showcase for the network&#8217;s coverage of food and travel. The announcement was made by CNN Worldwide Executive Vice President and Managing Editor, Mark Whitaker. &#8220;For more than a decade, Anthony Bourdain has been a trailblazer in educating Americans about different cuisines and cultures around the world, as well as an outspoken commentator on social trends ranging from the rise of celebrity chefs to the impact of fast food chains to the spread of vegetarianism and veganism,&#8221; said Whitaker. &#8220;Examining the world through the prism of Tony&#8217;s unique expertise and passions continues CNN&#8217;s long-standing commitment to international reporting and to promoting global understanding.&#8221; Launching in early 2013, the show will be shot on location and examine cultures from around the world through their food and dining and travel rituals. Slated to air domestically on Sundays in prime time with repeat airings on Saturday nights, it will mark a further step in broadening and distinguishing CNN&#8217;s weekend programming from its traditional weekday news coverage. The series will be produced by Zero Point Zero Production with Executive Producers and Founders Chris Collins and Lydia Tenaglia, along with Executive Producer Sandy Zweig. The Emmy award winning Zero Point Zero Production has been working with Anthony Bourdain for over a decade, producing Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations, The Layover, A Cook's Tour, and Decoding Ferran Adria. Bourdain, whose reporting has taken him from the culinary capitals of Europe, Asia and North and South America to such historically war-torn or isolated regions as Vietnam, Mozambique, Uzbekistan and Romania, will also offer commentary on other CNN programs and platforms, domestically and internationally, providing insights into current events and debates around food and health and other cultural conversations. &#8220;I&#8217;m really looking forward to coming over to CNN. I think the world is going to get a whole lot bigger for me,&#8221; said Bourdain. &#8220;I hope that old fans and new ones will be excited about what&#8217;s coming down the road.&#8221; Bourdain has been the host of the award-winning Travel Channel series Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations since 2005. He previously hosted A Cook&#8217;s Tour on the Food Network and has appeared on Bravo&#8217;s competition series Top Chef and written for HBO&#8217;s New Orleans-based drama Treme. He is also the author of critically acclaimed non-fiction and fiction books, including the New York Times bestsellers &#8220;Kitchen Confidential" and "A Cook&#8217;s Tour." He now oversees his own line of books from Ecco, a division of HarperCollins, the first three of which are scheduled to be released in 2013. Bourdain&#8217;s many accolades include Emmy awards for programs on Haiti and Laos, and an Emmy nomination for an episode of Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations, which was shot in Beirut during the 2006 Lebanon War.</description>
      <link>http://cnnpressroom.blogs.cnn.com/2012/05/29/anthony-bourdain-joins-cnn-to-host-new-weekend-program/</link>
      <guid>http://cnnpressroom.blogs.cnn.com/2012/05/29/anthony-bourdain-joins-cnn-to-host-new-weekend-program/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes On Pinterest: How People Look at Your Boards</title>
      <description>Pinterest doesn&#8217;t just look different than other social networks &#8212; it&#8217;s looked at in a different way, too. While most websites draw users&#8217; gazes toward the left-hand side of the page, participants in a recent eye-tracking study for Mashable instead shifted their eyes from the top down the middle of the page. They also spent relatively less time looking at profile information than their counterparts who looked at Facebook pages. The study, which was conducted by EyeTrackShop, used the webcams of 600 participants to track their eye movements as they looked at top category and brand Pinterest pages for 10-second intervals. They answered a quick survey about each page after viewing it. Here are some more interesting observations from the results: Top pins pop. Pins that were front and center were seen by the highest percentage of viewers. Faces attract attention. As with most social media sites, respondents looked at faces on Pinterest at more than objects. Profile information isn&#8217;t always as noticeable as profile content. Profile image and information may dominate attention on Facebook, but on Pinterest fewer people noticed it than noticed content. The percentage of people who looked at profile information at the top of brand pages in the study was the same or lower than that of the pages&#8217; most-looked-at pins. On average, this info was looked at second, not first. Brand pages are just as popular as category pages. Participants were slightly more likely to say brand pages made them want to repin stuff, recommend the page to friends and tell their friends about it. More of them also said the pages were definitely inspiring and had good pieces of advice. People like brands better after viewing their Pinterest pages. The majority of participants said that viewing a brand&#8217;s page improved their opinion about the brand and said they were more likely to purchase something from it. Take a look at the findings from each category and brand page in the study, and let us know your observations in the comments. Pinterest Homepage Red on the heat map indicate areas that received the most attention. The graph on the right shows results from a survey that each study participant filled out after viewing the page.Click here to view this gallery. -center -random order, not like fb and other social media pages More About: EyeTrackShop, pinterest</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/pinterest-eye-tracking-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/pinterest-eye-tracking-study/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women Are Bigger Fans of Social Media than Men, Survey Says</title>
      <description>If social media sites ceased to exist, you would miss them &#8212; unless you&#8217;re a man living in the U.K., according to a recent survey by British Telecom. More than 2,000 Brits were questioned for a survey commissioned by BT about the social media habits of men and women. The results showed that more than half of the women surveyed (54%) use social media sites like Facebook and Twitter, compared to 34% of men. And of those social media users, more women than men reported they would miss those sites if the Internet ceased to exist. SEE ALSO: How Pinterest&#8217;s Female Audience is Changing Social Marketing The survey also debunked a common misconception about Internet usage. Turns out, slightly more women than men reported playing online games, according to this survey. It&#8217;s no secret that women tend to use Pinterest more than men. Women are also more likely to have a blog than men. And the usage of social media by women influences advertisers and shapes web content. Do you think this survey got it right? Is it applicable beyond the UK? Tell us your thoughts in the comments. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, Yuri_Arcurs&#8236; More About: open social, United Kingdom</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/women-men-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/29/women-men-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Instagram Foodie Accounts to Make Your Mouth Water</title>
      <description>Food52 Food52, a blog that shares tons of cooking tips, also runs a well-curated Instagram account full of simple food snapshots from the staff. The pic to the left shows a cool way to cut up a mango.Click here to view this gallery.If you&#8217;re on Instagram, you&#8217;ve undoubtedly noticed people love posting pictures of their food. Whether they are cooking it themselves or eating out, food is just fun to share visually. If you want even more delicious noms filling up your feed, check out the list we&#8217;ve assembled of the 10 best foodie accounts to follow. We&#8217;ve found fantastically talented chefs and food bloggers who have seen more dishes than most. SEE ALSO: 12 Extravagant Instagram Pics by the Rich and Famous Check out the gallery above for some choice snapshots. Know of anyone we missed? One image really make you drool? Let us know in the comments. More About: features, Food, foodies, instagram, photographyFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/foodies-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/foodies-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;You Don&#8217;t Know Jack&#8217; Returns as Facebook Game</title>
      <description>The trivia classic with twisted sense of humor is back. You Don&#8217;t Know Jack launched a Facebook game on Tuesday that promises to bring deep social integration to the title. The newest incarnation of You Don&#8217;t Know Jack was developed by Jellyvision, and will be a freemium-style game that pits users&#8217; scores in chapters against their friends. It represents Jellyvision&#8217;s second recent attempt to reboot the franchise, after console and iOS games were released in 2011. &#8220;Self-publishing on Facebook was the perfect spot for us to make the game really social,&#8221; Jellyvision General Manager Mike Bilder said. The episodes run asynchronously, so Facebook users can play against their friends&#8217; previous performances. Players can even select to challenge specific friends in one of the currently available episodes, or post their score to their Facebook Wall, which will provide a direct link to the episode. If you&#8217;ve already played an episode that your friend is playing, you can earn points if you beat their answers, or even if you show up in their game. Jellyvision has recorded 165 new episodes for the Facebook launch. Each is five questions long, intended to take about five minutes, said Bilder. They incorporate all the popular question types from previous games, such as &#8220;Dis or Dat,&#8221; &#8220;Gibberish Questions&#8221;, &#8220;Cookie&#8217;s Fortune Cookie&#8221; and the final &#8220;Jack Attack.&#8221; There are also new types of questions. You Don&#8217;t Know Jack falls under the freemium umbrella; Facebook users are given one free episode a day. Additional episodes can be unlocked either with achievements earned from game play, or by purchasing more episode tokens from the game&#8217;s store. Other purchase options include gameplay upgrades that improve scores, and achievements. Jellyvision said even if players burn through all the new episodes, they plan on producing about three new episodes a week that will include topical questions based on pop culture topics. Bilder said those episodes will integrate right into the Facebook News Feed just like regular posts. For those who want to play on a mobile device, the game will be released for iOS and Android (the current iOS release has been pulled from the App Store), and will sync with the player&#8217;s Facebook log in, meaning users can play against each other across platforms. We rounded up some screenshots of the game. Check them out below, and let us know if you are excited to play the game in the comments below. Title Screen The loading screen when you launch You Don't Know Jack on Facebook, with that familiar bald head.Click here to view this gallery. More About: facebook games</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/you-dont-know-jack-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/you-dont-know-jack-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are you leaving behind?</title>
      <description>I love watching contrails, those streams of white frozen exhaust that jets leave behind. It's a temporary track in the sand, and then the sun melts them and they're gone. Go to Montana and you might see the tracks dinosaurs left a bazillion years ago. Same sort of travel, very different half-life of their passage. All day long you're emailing or tweeting or liking or meeting... and every once in a while, something tangible is produced. But is there a mark of your passage? Fifty years later, we might hear a demo tape or an outtake of something a musician scratched together while making an album. Often, though, there's no trace. I'm fascinated by blogs like this one, which are basically public notes and coffee breaks by a brilliant designer in between her 'real' work. Unlike tweets, which vanish, Tina's posts are here for a long time and much easier to share and bookmark. Her trail becomes useful not just to her, but to everyone who is interested. What would happen if you took ten minutes of coffeebreak downtime every day and produced an online artifact instead? What if your collected thoughts about your industry became an ebook or a series of useful instructions or pages or videos? What if we all did that?</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/what-are-you-leaving-behind.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/05/what-are-you-leaving-behind.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grockit Wants to Build a Pinterest for Learning</title>
      <description>Search engines may make it easy to find information, but they don&#8217;t necessarily do the same for learning it. That&#8217;s why the founders of social test prep startup Grockit want to re-configure online content such as YouTube videos, Wikipedia entries and ebooks into ordered lesson plans. Their new product, Learnist, works a bit like a Pinterest for learning. Soon anyone (the capability is still invite-only at launch) will be able to compile content pieces onto a board or &#8220;learning.&#8221; A nifty bookmarklet makes it easy to collect content from other sites. Unlike Pinterest, however, creators suggest a path in which to consume each content component. Users can check off each component as they go or &#8220;re-add&#8221; it to one of their own learnings. So how does Learnist beat Google as a learning tool? Or Pinterest, for that matter? Grockit founder Farbood Nivi argues that expert curation helps avoid the misinformation, hacked-together how-to articles and other useless content one must weed through in a typical Google search. It also provides a clear learning path and eventually, he hopes, will include some form of assessment. &#8220;We don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a Wikipedia replacement,&#8221; he says. &#8220;We think it&#8217;s a Wikipedia enhancement.&#8221; The scope of content he has in mind is larger than that of both online course platforms such as Udemy as well as that of Sophia, a startup with a similar mission of helping experts curate content that focuses on academics. Along with lessons about common core standards, it includes topics such as &#8220;how to find the best pizza in Brooklyn&#8221; or &#8220;how to hack your kitchen&#8221; that don&#8217;t require courses. He wants to replace not just textbooks, but also how-to articles. Grockit will continue to offer its test-prep service for $30 per month, but it is focusing on Learnist going forward. Grockit&#8217;s social, adaptive learning question sets are now embeddable within Learnist boards. &#8220;Test prep was always a stepping stone to larger learning,&#8221; Nivi says about the change in direction. &#8220;We always knew this was coming. We just didn&#8217;t know what it would look like.&#8221; Image courtesy of istockPhoto, fotosipsak More About: clearspring widget, education, Grockit</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/learnist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/learnist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce Ready to Buy Buddy Media For $800 Million [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Cloud enterprise powerhouse Salesforce is in talks to buy social media and brand management business Buddy Media for more than $800 million, according to an AllThingsD report. Buddy Media helps many major brands manage their Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, and Google+ presence. Presumably, Salesforce could add Buddy Media to its long roster of services targeting the enterprise like Chatter and Force.com. It&#8217;s unclear how much crossover there would be with Salesforce-owned Radian6, another social media management service. New York City-based Buddy Media raised a monster $54 million round of funding last August at a rumored $500 million valuation. Buddy Media&#8217;s total funding sits at $90 million. We chatted with Buddy Media a few months ago if you want to see what&#8217;s been happening with the company as of late: Photo credit: Andy Dean Photography/Shutterstock Filed under: deals, social</description>
      <link>http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/29/salesforce-buddy-media-buy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</link>
      <guid>http://venturebeat.com/2012/05/29/salesforce-buddy-media-buy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Venturebeat+%28VentureBeat%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
