<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>3 Ways Marketers Can Reach Facebook&#8217;s Mobile Audience</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/&amp;title=3 Ways Marketers Can Reach Facebook&amp;#8217;s Mobile Audience&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/facebook-mobile-app-600.jpg" alt="facebook-mobile-app-600" title="facebook-mobile-app-600" width="275" height="171" class="alignright size-full wp-image-958137" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Victoria Ransom is founder and CEO of &lt;a href="http://www.wildfireapp.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Wildfire Interactive&lt;/a&gt;, the global leader in social media marketing software. Victoria and Wildfire will host a free &lt;a href="http://lp.wildfireapp.com/WildfireBreakingWebinarTimelineForBrandsMarch2012.html" target="_blank"&gt;webinar&lt;/a&gt; on March 2 at 10 a.m. PT, entitled &#8220;Timeline for Brands: How to Make the Switch,&#8221; further outlining best practices for brands in transitioning to Facebook&#8217;s new Timeline format.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; recently revealed big plans for the mobile platform, for instance, that the new Timeline format for brands will be available on mobile. Facebook also revealed that more than &lt;a href="http://www.newsy.com/videos/analysis-media-react-to-facebook-ipo/" target="_blank"&gt;450 million&lt;/a&gt; people use Facebook Mobile on a monthly basis, and more importantly, that mobile is outgrowing desktop use on the social network 2:1. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For these reasons, Facebook has planned a variety of mobile-centric products, including last week&#8217;s announcement that brands will now be able to advertise in mobile news feeds through &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/12/20/facebook-sponsored-stories-news-feeds/"&gt;Sponsored Stories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;These game-changing trends mean that marketers need to get serious about mobile in 2012. Here are three new ways you can build mobile into your Facebook marketing plan.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. Mobile-Optimize All Your Content.&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Timeline for brands is coming to the mobile platform in 2012. When you consider that brand pages on Facebook Mobile have had almost no functionality &#8212; custom apps haven&#8217;t worked without a complicated hack-job, tabs haven&#8217;t translated, etc. &#8212; it seems possible that Timeline for brands was launched specifically to enable brands&#8217; mobile Facebook capabilities. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And since users&amp;#8217; Timelines function on Facebook Mobile, Timeline for brands should be equally versatile, giving brands the ability to provide engaging mobile experiences for the first time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since nearly half of Facebook users access the site through a mobile device, your brand&#8217;s reach could effectively double if you mobile-optimize your social content. And because users will soon be able to experience the same workflow on their desktops as their smartphones, page managers will now be able to curate an identical experience for all users, regardless of viewing device.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/29/facebook-brand-timelines-changes-marketing/"&gt;Facebook Brand Timelines: 6 Big Changes Every Marketer Needs to Understand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Whether you&#8217;re building engagement applications in-house or with a social marketing software vendor, make sure the applications are seamlessly viewable across all platforms and devices. Ideally, you&#8217;ll be able to design once and deploy anywhere. That way, you&amp;#8217;ll avoid messy synchronization issues, duplication of effort between creative teams, and working around multiple content channels.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Applications that use a &#8220;responsive design&#8221; framework are gaining popularity. The framework employs specific HTML5, CSS and Javascript technologies to ensure that the same content displays well on devices of any screen size. In the context of Facebook mobile pages, apps built within this framework can morph Facebook page tabs &amp;#8212; for mobile, tablets and desktops &amp;#8212; with one build.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Integrate Sponsored Stories Into Your Marketing.&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/sponsored-stories.jpg" alt="" title="sponsored-stories" width="289" height="241" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-995591" /&gt;To date, there has been no way to advertise to Facebook users on mobile devices. This has been an enormous lost opportunity for marketers &#8212; until now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now, Sponsored Stories premium ad units will not only appear in users&#8217; news feeds (a huge announcement on its own), but also in mobile news feeds. Considering the many users who access Facebook from a mobile device, marketers now have a big opportunity to embed sponsored advertisements within mobile feeds. The challenge is how to make this work with your existing Facebook marketing program.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most effective way to integrate Sponsored Stories into your marketing is to work them into an editorial calendar. Since Sponsored Stories stem from the activities of users on your brand&#8217;s Page, create a calendar of activities that translate well to the Sponsored Story format. For example, a local retail store could plan its weekly status updates, featuring in-store specials and colorful coupons as Sponsored Stories. Just make sure to use eye-catching images to help your promoted posts attract attention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Use Facebook Mobile to Fuel Offline Campaigns.&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mobile-optimized social campaign marketing can also be used to enhance consumers&#8217; in-store experiences. In fact, according to comScore, &lt;a href="http://www.comscore.com/Press_Events/Press_Releases/2011/12/Mobile_Shopping_Goes_Mainstream" target="_blank"&gt;36%&lt;/a&gt; of the U.S. smartphone population used their phones to perform retail research while inside a store in 2011. And &lt;a href="http://www.marketingcharts.com/direct/gender-differences-emerge-in-smartphone-shopping-behavior-21237/nielsen-mobile-shopping-activities-q32011-feb-2012jpg/" target="_blank"&gt;Nielsen&lt;/a&gt; states that, by the end of 2011, nearly one in five smartphone users scanned product barcodes, and nearly one in eight compared prices while in a store.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is a lot of room for creating social campaigns with seamless mobile components, such as unique codes for scanning, in addition to more traditional social campaign approaches like promotions and exclusive content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/sprinkles-facebook.jpg" alt="" title="sprinkles-facebook" width="313" height="374" class="alignright size-full wp-image-995615" /&gt;When planning online and offline campaigns, include in-store signage. This is crucial to the success of a mobile campaign, and is a key driver of participation. Many brands will advertise promotions on their Pages, designed to drive activity in-store, but do not replicate this messaging in the store. Unfortunately, this misses the in-store consumers who haven&#8217;t interacted on your fan page beforehand. Capture their interest socially first, then reinforce your message in-store to create a deeper, longer-term connection with the consumer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The next thing to keep in mind is simplicity, which is the key to a successful social-to-in-store campaign. That multi-step scavenger hunt, which extends from your Page all the way into the shelves of your store may sound like a creative idea, but it will most certainly narrow engagement. Keep the proposition simple so users can easily get involved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, Sprinkles Cupcakes consistently posts messages to its Page, encouraging fans to check in daily for a &#8220;secret word.&#8221; Fans who discover the secret word on Sprinkles&#8217; Facebook Timeline can whisper it, in-store, to get a free cupcake. Sprinkles&#8217; approach yields continuous check-ins on its Page, where other marketing messages appear alongside the secret word.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Marketers cannot ignore the staggering growth of users who access the Internet and social networks via mobile. Get mobile right and you&#8217;ve effectively doubled your social network reach. Start by mobile-optimizing your content, testing mobile Sponsored Stories, and linking mobile to your in-store campaigns. And please share more mobile marketing strategies in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php" target="_blank"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=2313083" target="_blank"&gt;ymgerman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-mobile/"&gt;facebook mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-pages/"&gt;facebook pages&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/marketing/"&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/sponsored-stories/"&gt;Sponsored Stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/8b8h1mFAC_KUs2H4y1RokMN3Rks/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/8b8h1mFAC_KUs2H4y1RokMN3Rks/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/8b8h1mFAC_KUs2H4y1RokMN3Rks/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/8b8h1mFAC_KUs2H4y1RokMN3Rks/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=5TrG4RfW5Xg:KgKqLXqy1lU:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/5TrG4RfW5Xg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/facebook-mobile-marketing/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Photos: The Key to a Successful Social Media Campaign</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Matt Handy leads the social-local-mobile practice at Brand Networks, a leading Facebook Preferred Developer and Ads API Vendor. Brand Networks engineers social, local and mobile experiences to amplify stories for the world&#8217;s most liked companies including AMEX, JetBlue, Diageo and Starbucks.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/facebook-photos-key-successful-social-media-campaign-113759883.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/facebook-photos-key-successful-social-media-campaign-113759883.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KISSmetrics Looks To Turn Your Customer Data Into An Interactive Infographic</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/screen-shot-2012-03-19-at-2-00-19-am.png?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Screen shot 2012-03-19 at 2.00.19 AM" title="Screen shot 2012-03-19 at 2.00.19 AM" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/"&gt;KISSmetrics&lt;/a&gt;, an analytics startup that wants to help you boost your user acquisition and retention rates by providing a more robust picture of how your customers are using your site, is today announcing &amp;#8220;KISSmetrics Experiments.&amp;#8221; A la &lt;a href="http://support.google.com/mail/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=29418"&gt;Gmail Labs&lt;/a&gt;, Experiments enables KISSmetrics users to access and test out experimental new features and help decide whether they become lasting parts of the product. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first experiment KISSmetrics unveiled today is a visualization feature that customers can use to view data on how their users interact with their site, web apps, and mobile products. The new experiment expands on its so-called &lt;a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/features/people"&gt;&amp;#8220;People Views,&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; which &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/07/05/kissmetrics-now-lets-sites-analyze-their-users-browsing-habits-%E2%80%94%C2%A0before-they-even-sign-up/"&gt;Jason first covered last year&lt;/a&gt;, that essentially allow site administrators to drill down into the way that individual users are browsing and using their sites &amp;#8212; as well as their history before they actually signed up for an account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Among other things, KISSmetrics shows its customers acquisition data for every one of their users, including a timeline feature that lets site administrators see how customer behavior has changed over time, identifying common usage patterns, or viewing the most recent referrers, average time between visits, etc. This timeline feature shows how many times a user made certain actions, when they signed up, how many times they&amp;#8217;ve upgraded, viewed their dashboards, and so on &amp;#8212; presenting all this data in an intuitive visual format, so that the size of the circle on the timeline corresponds with how many times the customer took action.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/noname.png" rel="lightbox[521986]"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As you can see in the above image, when lines connect with these circles, it represents a step-by-step funnel that the customer went through during the sign-up process. KISSmetrics co-founder Neil Patel explains that the experience of his &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2007/06/18/track-every-click-with-crazy-eggs-confetti/"&gt;his first company, Crazy Egg&lt;/a&gt;, led he and his team to the conclusion that &amp;#8220;the future of analytics and customer data will involve interactive visualizations.&amp;#8221; Certainly Google Analytics and others have proven that site owners, technically advanced or not, need more complete data on user behavior, especially that which is visual and easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thus, with its new experimental data visualization tool, Patel said that the team wants to make data that is typically boring and difficult to understand simpler, more elegant, and easier to turn into definitive action. Because KISSmetrics provides a full history of a company&amp;#8217;s customer interactions, whether they be on the Web, mobile, and Facebook apps, or other platforms, Patel thinks that KISSmetrics can offer a truly 360-degree view of user behavior. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They have added Experiments to their product, he said, so that they can more easily experiment with visualizations like the &amp;#8220;Timeline View&amp;#8221; above. While there other startups like Mixpanel and RJMetrics that offer &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/09/23/kissmetrics-helps-you-hone-in-on-stats-that-actually-matter-with-cohort-reports/"&gt;&amp;#8220;Cohort Reports&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; and individual user data, the co-founder believes that KISSmetrics is the first to allow customers to view individual user data in a visual format. Most simply offer the traditional data table layout, while KISSmetrics believes it&amp;#8217;s going one step further. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Patel said that this is the &amp;#8220;first of many&amp;#8221; experiments and visualizations the startup will be using to try to find the best and most intuitive ways to understand customer data. Having more complete, accurate, and visual representations of the conversion funnel can be a powerful weapon for companies. Being able to measure how many users are dropping off during the signup and onboarding cycle (and where) helps them enhance or correct the facets of each step &amp;#8212; and see the impact new features or upgrades are having on their overall site experience. That&amp;#8217;s huge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because t&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/epicenter/2011/07/undeletable-cookie/"&gt;he company took some heat last year&lt;/a&gt; for the way they track visitor data, KISSmetrics has updated &lt;a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/user-privacy"&gt;its user privacy policies, which you can view here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For more, &lt;a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/"&gt;check out KISSmetrics at home here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521986/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/19/kissmetrics-experiments/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/19/kissmetrics-experiments/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#8217;t Tag Me, Bro: How to Control Facebook Photo Tags</title>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. Unwanted Photo Tags&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-untag-facebook-photos/#535051-Unwanted-Photo-Tags"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. Unwanted Photo Tags" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/facebook-photos-privacy/f0.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's happened to all of us -- we've all been tagged in an unflattering or inappropriate image at some point.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don't panic though, we will take you through first how to get rid of that unwanted tag, and then how to manage your privacy settings so it doesn't happen again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-untag-facebook-photos/#535051-Unwanted-Photo-Tags'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook&amp;#8217;s photography features and photo-tagging functionality are an awesome way to share your images with friends and family. Sometimes, however, a few photos might show up that you&amp;#8217;d rather not draw attention to.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We can show you how to remove undesirable photo tags, and more importantly, how to tweak your Facebook privacy settings to make sure an unapproved photo tag never appears on your Timeline ever again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/02/24/hide-facebook-chat/"&gt;How to Hide From Annoying Friends on Facebook Chat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Take a look through our simple, step-by-step walk-through. Let us know in the comments about any Facebook photo tag horror stories &lt;em&gt;you&amp;#8217;ve&lt;/em&gt; experienced!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/how-to/"&gt;How-To&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/privacy/"&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/tips-and-tricks/"&gt;tips and tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/0iNiWLQHQNk_5lyAakAODlEjulA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/0iNiWLQHQNk_5lyAakAODlEjulA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/0iNiWLQHQNk_5lyAakAODlEjulA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/0iNiWLQHQNk_5lyAakAODlEjulA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?i=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?i=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?i=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?a=9PDiDKq3528:KsZgbLMNfEw:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/SocialMedia?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/SocialMedia/~4/9PDiDKq3528" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-untag-facebook-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-untag-facebook-photos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Game On&#8217; Tribute to Rick Santorum Hits Million Views [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/U7pv7sO5Gng?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;President Obama may be trying to strike a name for himself as the &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/01/20/obama-singing-apollo/" target="_blank"&gt;singing president&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;#8221; but Republican White House hopeful Rick Santorum has at least two vocalists in his corner: Camille and Haley Harris of Tulsa, Oklahoma. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Together, the girls are &amp;#8220;First Love Band,&amp;#8221; a country-folk Christian band. They recorded the above song and video for Santorum after meeting him at a campaign event just before Super Tuesday (March 6, 2012). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As of Sunday afternoon, it&amp;#8217;s gained more than one million YouTube views.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We wrote it Sunday night, March 4 until three in the morning and woke up on March 5 to finish it,&amp;#8221; wrote the girls on their YouTube page. &amp;#8220;We believe in Santorum&amp;#8217;s character and his ability to boldly lead this country in the right direction. It was 100% our idea to write this for them &amp;#8212; he deserves it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The same day the two sisters uploaded the video, it appeared on the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/RickSantorum" target="_blank"&gt;Santorum campaign&amp;#8217;s Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;. There, it generated more than 1,400 &amp;#8220;likes&amp;#8221; and 400 &amp;#8220;shares.&amp;#8221; Santorum&amp;#8217;s campaign also tweeted a link and a #GameOn hashtag to more than 170,000 followers:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet tw-align-center"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wow! I love this &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search/%2523GameOn"&gt;#GameOn&lt;/a&gt; song and video! Thank you Harris Family from Oklahoma! &lt;a href="http://t.co/WczMttqP" title="http://ht.ly/9uzsb"&gt;ht.ly/9uzsb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rick Santorum (@RickSantorum) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RickSantorum/status/177135164437180417" data-datetime="2012-03-06T20:54:48+00:00"&gt;March 6, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It was soon picked up by Yahoo, where it got more than 250,000 views, and Fox News, which gave it another 69,000. Almost 16,500 views came from &lt;a href="http://spreadingsantorum.com/" target="_blank"&gt;SpreadingSantorum.com&lt;/a&gt;, an anti-Santorum website critical of his views on gay marriage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the video was released in early March, the Harris sisters have become celebrities among Santorum supporters. They have appeared, sung and spoken at several of the former Senator&amp;#8217;s campaign events.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/&amp;title=&amp;#8216;Game On&amp;#8217; Tribute to Rick Santorum Hits Million Views [VIDEO]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/c753ee28710611e1989612313815112c_7.jpg" alt="" title="c753ee28710611e1989612313815112c_7" width="612" height="612" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-994897" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt; has attempted to contact to the Harrises and Santorum&amp;#8217;s campaign for any comment on their sudden viral success and their inclusion in Santorum events. We&amp;#8217;ll update this post when we get a response.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Is the girls&amp;#8217; video a catchy tune, or does it fall flat? Sound off in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/2012-presidential-campaign/"&gt;2012 presidential campaign&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/politics/"&gt;Politics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/us/"&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/youtube/"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Pyv3Udq5l3OEGc5LdwW3ss_GySo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Pyv3Udq5l3OEGc5LdwW3ss_GySo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Pyv3Udq5l3OEGc5LdwW3ss_GySo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Pyv3Udq5l3OEGc5LdwW3ss_GySo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=BjPO0UL5bLU:zaAzFI6jgpQ:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/BjPO0UL5bLU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/game-on-tribute-santorum/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Apple Could Fight The Bots, Scams And Other App Store Junk</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/app-store-fakes-removed2.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="App Store Fakes Removed" title="App Store Fakes Removed" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;No platform is perfect. Not even Apple&amp;#8217;s. Over the last few weeks, there has been a flood of news about malfeasance in the app store from download bots to credit card scams to address-book sharing. I broke a few stories about &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2012/02/22/chinese-developer-hoolai-on-how-half-its-revenue-got-eaten-by-virtual-currency-scams-last-fall/"&gt;app-related credit card fraud originating from Taobao, the eBay of China&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2012/02/14/download-bots-were-the-well-known-secret-of-the-app-ecosystem/"&gt;automated bots that download apps thousands of times&lt;/a&gt; to drive them up the charts. Then &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/03/16/technology/pressure-on-apple-builds-over-app-store-fraud.html"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-03-15/anarchy-in-the-app-store"&gt;BusinessWeek&lt;/a&gt; came in with their own takes this week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This puts the heat on Apple to further regulate the store, which is long overdue. Though to be fair, I still think that the iOS platform is more egalitarian than Facebook, which lends itself to a winner-take-all dynamic. iOS is also more lucrative per user than Android or Facebook, &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/12/13/android-24-percent-ios/"&gt;according to data from analytics provider Flurry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2012/03/07/bejeweled-blitz-free/"&gt;top-tier developers like EA Popcap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are a few solutions:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;1) &lt;strong&gt;Change the app store ranking algorithm so it doesn&amp;#8217;t rely so much on raw download rates.&lt;/strong&gt; A ranking algorithm that simple is &lt;em&gt;just begging&lt;/em&gt; to be gamed. Developers have been doing it for years in ways that range from legitimate to totally unscrupulous. When the ecosystem was less mature, developers used to do burst advertising campaigns, where they would pay for a load of display ads right at launch. That became pretty expensive very quickly. Then in late 2010, &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2011/01/03/tapjoy-rebound/"&gt;developers started using offer walls, which would give players of other games&lt;/a&gt; rewards like virtual currency if they downloaded apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2011/04/19/apps-apple-rejected-pay-per-install/"&gt;Apple cracked down on this practice last April&lt;/a&gt;. Ironically, &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2012/02/14/download-bots-were-the-well-known-secret-of-the-app-ecosystem/"&gt;an even less savory practice benefited as developers stepped up spending on marketing agencies&lt;/a&gt; that used bots to download their apps thousands of times. While none of the top tier developers admitted to intentionally doing this, &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2012/02/14/download-bots-were-the-well-known-secret-of-the-app-ecosystem/"&gt;it was a widely-known practice&lt;/a&gt;. Marketing companies like &lt;a href="http://www.insidemobileapps.com/2012/02/14/download-bots-were-the-well-known-secret-of-the-app-ecosystem/"&gt;Charles River Ventures-backed Fiksu ran a test with one of these services&lt;/a&gt;, and saw thousands of downloads. But mysteriously, none of these users ever actually opened the app, so they company knew something was awry.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is actually a really easy fix to this Whack-a-Mole problem. Just change the ranking algorithm. Factor in more than download rates. If Apple does that, then it will be more challenging for developers to game the system beyond creating just genuinely good apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google Android doesn&amp;#8217;t reveal its secret sauce but it is widely understood that the store&amp;#8217;s ranking algorithm considers user ratings and the &amp;#8220;long install&amp;#8221; rate, or whether consumers keep the apps they have downloaded. The downside of Google&amp;#8217;s approach is that it makes the charts less volatile, so it can be harder for newer apps to break through. But Google compensated for this last May by changing the design of the store and adding more categories like Top New Free and Top New Paid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;2) &lt;strong&gt;Give data on app store referral traffic to developers.&lt;/strong&gt; Developers are basically flying blind when it comes to understanding how people find their iPhone and iPad apps. They do not definitively know how people end up on their landing pages in the app store. Did they get there by search? By their ranking in the top charts? By Facebook? By a link shared by a friend? They have no clue! In fact, there is a whole cottage industry of services like &lt;a href="http://www.appfigures.com/"&gt;AppFigures&lt;/a&gt; which turns iTunes download data into something more usable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If developers don&amp;#8217;t have proof that other marketing channels work, that just makes it tempting to keep gaming rankings. Even Android&amp;#8217;s app store (now called Google Play) gives developers statistics in a more Google Analytics-like format and provides tools for basic referral tracking.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;3) &lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can shut down the bots. &lt;/strong&gt;Apple &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/"&gt;has so far given a written warning to developers&lt;/a&gt;, urging them to stopping using services that guarantee top placement. But it&amp;#8217;s not clear how actively they&amp;#8217;re enforcing it. Many developers have shied away from touching any of these services in recent weeks out of pure fear. But that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean they&amp;#8217;re gone forever. &lt;a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-03-15/anarchy-in-the-app-store"&gt;Even BusinessWeek said that GTekna, a suspected bot marketing company&lt;/a&gt;, is still signing up new clientele.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Apple should have the ability to know when bursts of downloads doesn&amp;#8217;t create a commensurate burst in usage. It&amp;#8217;s just a question of whether they want it known that they can track app usage. Facebook routinely clamps down on applications that grow in highly suspicious ways through a mix of human reviews and algorithms that flag apps with anomalous growth patterns.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;4) &lt;strong&gt;Apple&amp;#8217;s deal to acquire Chomp is a step in the right direction, and suggests that search engine optimization or SEO for the app store will start mattering more. &lt;/strong&gt;With &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/23/apple-chomp/"&gt;Apple&amp;#8217;s deal to buy app search engine Chomp&lt;/a&gt;, there are signs that an overhaul of the app store is coming. With more than 550,000 apps, the store is getting too crowded for a directory-based approach to work anymore. It&amp;#8217;s going to require a better search engine and viral channels for applications. The Chomp deal should lay the groundwork and it looks like the Twitter-iOS integration and Facebook&amp;#8217;s new mobile platform are starting to help with the second part.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/521609/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/18/how-apple-could-fight-the-bots-scams-and-other-app-store-junk/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/18/how-apple-could-fight-the-bots-scams-and-other-app-store-junk/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>greenmachine019: redscharlach: Otters Who Look...</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Ah, so #Sherlock did it by throwing an otter off the hospital roof&#8230; http://t.co/RiGFTSrE</description>
      <link>http://gunslingerannie.tumblr.com/post/19566671961/greenmachine019-redscharlach-otters-who-look</link>
      <guid>http://gunslingerannie.tumblr.com/post/19566671961/greenmachine019-redscharlach-otters-who-look</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Pinterest Can Turn Your Brand Red-Hot [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; If your brand isn&amp;#39;t on Pinterest, you could be missing out on a growing stream of potential customers.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/pinterest-brand-attention-infographic-140109922.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/pinterest-brand-attention-infographic-140109922.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple to Announce Plans for Its Hoard of Cash Monday</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/&amp;title=Apple to Announce Plans for Its Hoard of Cash Monday&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img width="275" height="161" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-990717" title="Apple Image 640" alt="" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/Apple-Image-6402-275x161.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/apple"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; will today host a conference call to announce what it will do with its $97 billion cash balance, the company has announced. The call is scheduled for Monday, March 19, 2012 at 6:00 a.m. PDT / 9:00 a.m. EDT. The details in the call announcement were scarce: All Apple was willing to say is that it will announce "the outcome of the Company&#8217;s discussions concerning its cash balance." Apple's hoard of cash has been a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/01/28/apple-100-billion-comic/"&gt;subject of discussions&lt;/a&gt; for quite some time. Some call for the world's biggest company to pay out a dividend to its shareholders (Apple has last done this in 1995), and others would like to see Apple eat up other companies. While any company dreams of having such an enormous pile of cash on its hands (coupled with very little or no debt), the truth is that Apple's cash balance is becoming somewhat of a burden for the company, and &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-03-18/apple-to-discuss-outcome-of-discussions-over-handling-its-cash.html" target="_blank"&gt;large shareholders&lt;/a&gt; are getting restless. We'll follow Apple's conference call here at Mashable. In the meantime, let us know what you think: will Apple pay out a dividend, will it announce a major acquisition, or something else entirely? Share your opinions in the comments. &lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SEYQehnEj6gedHm8J0T0dk8rO94/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SEYQehnEj6gedHm8J0T0dk8rO94/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SEYQehnEj6gedHm8J0T0dk8rO94/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/SEYQehnEj6gedHm8J0T0dk8rO94/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:TzevzKxY174"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?d=TzevzKxY174" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/apple?a=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/apple?i=bkBY79OnBRY:vpEPZ61fRjA:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/apple/~4/bkBY79OnBRY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/19/apple-cash/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Work With A Recruiter To Find Social Media Talent</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/&amp;title=How To Work With A Recruiter To Find Social Media Talent&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/handshake-partner-600-275x171.jpg" alt="Partner Handshake" title="Partner Handshake" width="275" height="171" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-973317" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Heather R. Huhman is the founder and president of &lt;a href="http://www.comerecommended.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Come Recommended&lt;/a&gt;, a content marketing and digital PR consultancy for organizations with products that target job seekers and/or employers. You can connect with Heather and Come Recommended on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/comerecommended" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/comerecommended" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Social media has become a hot new job opportunity in the past few years and companies are snatching up the social media pros left and right. Brand managers, community managers, social media strategists, content creators &amp;#8212; the social media job titles go on and on. So how does any employer find the right social media talent?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The answer: Hire a recruiter. In an industry such as social media, people are claiming &#8220;guru&#8221; status if they know how to use &lt;a href="http://www.mashable.com/tag/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. A recruiter can help you find truly talented social media professionals who have the skills you&amp;#8217;re looking for and the right cultural fit for your organization. Plus, having the help of a recruiter to hire the right person the first time around can reduce employee turnover, ultimately saving you money; the average entry-level hire costs $5,700 to $8,900, not to mention the added expense of training.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Think about it: You have a doctor to treat your illness and a mechanic to fix your car. Why not hire a recruiter to find your talent? Select a recruiter who has experience in identifying social media talent. Many recruiters specialize in different industries, so find one who knows the social media market like the back of his hand. Some key questions to ask a potential recruiter:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What is your recruiting background?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This will give you an idea of this recruiter&#8217;s experience. Has he worked with social media talent before? Has she been successful?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What are some key skills that you look for in a social media professional?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The recruiter should be able to answer this question clearly and directly; he or she should know off the bat what skills are essential for social media talent and be able to give you examples of what he or she will be looking for when searching for a candidate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Where do you begin looking for a social media professional?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Again, a recruiter with relevant experience will be able to answer this question without hesitation. This will show you that the recruiter has a plan in mind of how to find social media talent; he or she knows where to look to deliver you results.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. How do you determine cultural fit?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is important when hiring for any position; even if a potential candidate has every skill you need down pat, if they don&#8217;t fit into your organization&#8217;s corporate culture, you&#8217;ll likely lose them down the line. A good recruiter will know this, and take cultural fit into account when identifying potential talent for your organization.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve hired a recruiter, three things are important when working with them to find social media talent:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt; 1. Clarity&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Be clear when conveying your needs to a recruiter. Maybe you don&#8217;t know exactly what the title of the social media professional you need is, but you should be able to convey what goals and tasks you&amp;#8217;re expecting an employee to accomplish. Your recruiter, with his or her experience in the social media industry, should be able to work with you to help clarify exactly what you&#8217;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. Expectations&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/Highbar_640.jpg" alt="" title="Highbar_640" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-992979" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Be realistic with your expectations; no &#8220;perfect&#8221; employee exists. You should be seeking realistic skill-sets and backgrounds and offering a reasonable salary for a potential candidate before you can expect your recruiter to find talent. Your recruiter should be able to tell you if your expectations are realistic and if not, what you should expect from the social media talent market.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. Communication&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keep the lines of communication open between you and your recruiter. Continuous discussion of your expectations and your recruiter&#8217;s progress will help keep you both on the same page when seeking social media talent. Social media is an industry with many specific talents, roles and niches. To find the best talent to play the right roles in your organization&#8217;s social media efforts, hire a recruiter with relevant experience, and focus on continuous communication to set clear, realistic goals.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Have you ever worked with a recruiter before? Tell us about your experience below!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Social Media Job Listings&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every week we post a list of &lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/find-jobs"&gt;social media and web job opportunities&lt;/a&gt;. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&amp;#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/668505" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Web Developer, Online Publications &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York City&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/668438" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Social Media Specialist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at the Environmental Defense Fund in Washington, D.C.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://jobs.mashable.com/a/jbb/job-details/668016" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt; Director of Acquisition/Strategic Partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at Hot Topic Media in Santa Monica, CA&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=555372"&gt;webphotographeer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=4859063"&gt;andrearoad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-recruiting/"&gt;job recruiting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/job-search-series/"&gt;job search series&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/recruiter/"&gt;recruiter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/LkZh4sYB-mfmdL9KB7oSwHYonMk/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/LkZh4sYB-mfmdL9KB7oSwHYonMk/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/LkZh4sYB-mfmdL9KB7oSwHYonMk/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/LkZh4sYB-mfmdL9KB7oSwHYonMk/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NoZ49OERqbs:I8CQtv0HEY8:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/NoZ49OERqbs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/18/how-to-social-media-recruiter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muamba's crucial 24 hours - Coyle</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Bolton midfielder Fabrice Muamba faces a crucial 24 hours says manager Owen Coyle after he collapsed during an FA Cup quarter-final against Tottenham.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/17419654</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/football/17419654</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
