<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Explorer 7 'tax' a first</title>
      <description>The Australian online retailer Kogan.com has introduced the world's first "tax" on use of Microsoft's Internet Explorer 7 (IE7) browser.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-18440979</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-18440979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Mystify Drive-Thru Employees [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>A YouTube magician used a simple magic trick to get some astonished responses from drive-thru workers. More About: viral, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/magic-trick-drive-thru/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/magic-trick-drive-thru/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS 6: Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <description>If you were looking for new mobile features, then iOS 6, which Apple unveiled on Monday at WWDC, does not disappoint. At WWDC 2012, Scott Forstall took the stage to unveil iOS 6 to developers. iOS 6 features more than 200 updates and improvements when compared to iOS 5. iOS 5 already boasts more than 80% adoption rate across devices and Apple boasted figures about iMessage, Twitter stats, Game Center and push notifications. So what's new in iOS 6? Siri Siri can now launch apps Siri can now Tweet (no hacks required!) Siri is smart about sports. It can pull in scores, game summaries and player stats. Siri integrates with Yelp and OpenTable for restaurant reviews an&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, apple maps, Facebook, iOS 6, siri, trending, wwdc, WWDC 2012</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/ios-6-revaled/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/11/ios-6-revaled/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Note for note</title>
      <description>I'm listening to an obscure CD of the Silver Beats, a group of four Japanese lads who play note for note renditions of Beatles songs. They don't speak a word of English. And yet they sing beautifully. I saw them as an opening act a few years ago, and the novelty was extraordinary. The thing is, I don't want to see them again. Why would I? It's note for note. No chance for random rhapsodic moments. No chance for total disaster. Part of the magic of our work is that it's not guaranteed. As soon as it is, we can digitize it or mechanize it or outsource it.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/note-for-note.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/note-for-note.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nokia&#8217;s Restructuring and Two Other Stories You Need to Know</title>
      <description>Welcome to this morning&#8217;s edition of &#8220;First To Know,&#8221; a series in which we keep you in the know on what&#8217;s happening in the digital world. Today, we&#8217;re looking at three particularly interesting stories. Nokia Sells Vertu, Announces Major Layoffs Nokia has announced it will close its factories in Finland, Germany and Canada and lay off up to 10,000 workers before the end of 2013. The company has also shuffled a couple of its key executives, and sold its luxury phone brand Vertu to private equity group EQT VI. Amongst all these cuts, the Finnish giant managed to find the funds for an acquisition. Nokia will acquire specialists, technologies and intellectual property from&#8230; Continue reading... More About: features, first to know series, mashable, microsoft, Nokia, samsung, yammer</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/nokia-restructuring/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/nokia-restructuring/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Battery Life Do Your Apps Zap? This Tool Will Check</title>
      <description>A group of UC Berkeley scientists has turned their research about battery life into a handy app that can extend yours. Carat, which is available for iOS and Android, measures your phone's energy use and suggests actions that will make it more efficient. It tells you which of your apps are using the most battery and which may have energy-hogging bugs that can be fixed by re-downloading them. Carat also tells you how your average battery life compares to that of other users. What is hogging battery life on your phone? Let us know in the comments. More About: App, Carat, UC Berkeley</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/carat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/carat/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week</title>
      <description>From a ridiculously extravagant piece of bread to the NBA Finals, this week's top 10 Twitter pics gives us a truly diverse look into the Internet. Sports ruled the net this week as Euro 2012 heats up Europe and the NBA Finals power on in America. Sports fans took full advantage of their phones to snap photos of the big games and share their images via Twitter. SEE MORE: Top 10 Twitter Pics of the Week In addition to sports, Twitter users also displayed their reliable sense of humor with a ludicrous viral bucket list and a rule-defying 9Gag photo. The top 10 Twitter pics are gathered and captioned by our partner at Skylines, Julie Donders (@lkbenJulie). Skylines uses&#8230; Continue reading... More About: justin bieber, sports, Top 10 Twitter Pics, trending, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/top-10-twitter-pics-21/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/top-10-twitter-pics-21/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Confirms Testing &#8216;Call&#8217; Button for Online Video Chats</title>
      <description>Facebook is reminding users how to make video calls via the social network by testing a "Call" button on member Timeline pages. The button, which was first spotted by TechCrunch, is located next to the "Message" option on Facebook Timeline's layout. The "Chat" button would replace the subtle video-camera icon now used to start an online video chat. A Facebook spokesperson confirmed to Mashable that the button is only a test, so it's unknown at this time if it will become a permanent part of Timeline. In the meantime, some members using a desktop version of Facebook will be able to test the feature. Although Facebook partnered with popular online chat service Skype nearly a year&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Airtime, Facebook, Google, Google Hangouts, Skype</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/facebook-call-button/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/facebook-call-button/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Dads Are Plugging In, Getting Social [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do you consider yourself to be a &#8220;digital dad?&#8221; If you use social media to connect with your kids or other parents, count yourself as part of this savvy group. With Father&#8217;s Day around the corner, Euro RSCG Worldwide asked 1,000 dads across the U.S. how the Internet and social media has affected their parenting style, dividing the respondents into groups of &#8220;digital dads&#8221; and &#8220;Average Joes.&#8221; The survey shows dads are plugging in just as much as their teens. In fact, 62% of digital dads say they&#8217;re more tech-savvy than the average 15-year-old. Similarly, more than three-quarters of digital dads and 57% of Average Joes use Facebook, YouTube, Twitter and other sites to monitor their kids&#8217; interactions on the web. While you may think those watchful eyes create friction between parents and teens, the study finds just the opposite. &#8220;Social media is now providing new ways to engage with your family, and also is bringing families closer together,&#8221; says Tom Morton, chief strategy officer, New York and co-chief strategy officer, North America. In the same sentiment, digital dads are forming their own online communities &#8212; 64% have used social media to connect with other parents. Those dads are also sharing more as 52% have written about a parenting experience on the web, and 66% have posted a photo of their child on a social networking site or blog. SEE ALSO: 10 Father&#8217;s Day Gifts For Geeky Dads The survey also finds that the majority of fathers think their kids are smarter as the result of new technology and greater access to information, but they are increasingly becoming less proficient in the English language. Around 76% of digital dads and 68% of Average Joes agree that kids who grow up without access to the Internet are at a serious disadvantage. But those same dads say increasing technology can distract kids, impairing their ability to communicate face to face. And while &#8220;ttyl&#8221; and &#8220;ur&#8221; may be faster to text, dads think this is hurting their kids&#8217; ability to read and write English at expected levels. Check out the infographic below, and tell us how you&#8217;re a &#8220;digital dad&#8221; in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/digital-dads-are-plugging-in-getting-social-infographic/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/digital-dads-are-plugging-in-getting-social-infographic/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Apps You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss</title>
      <description>Temple Run Brave Brave, Pixar's newest film, officially hits theaters on June 22, but the mobile game for the movie became available this week. Based on popular endless-runner game Temple Run, Temple Run Brave is a new take on the game, where you play the part of Merida, the lead character in the film. Available for iOS and Android, gameplay involves running through environments that resemble the Scotish landscape from the film and collecting coins. The game also has an archery element &#8211; a huge part of the movie itself &#8211; where you can tap targets along your journey to earn extra points. Click here to view this gallery. It can be tough to keep up with all the new apps released each week. But you&#8217;re in luck: We take care of a lot of that for you, creating a roundup each weekend of some of our own highlights from the week. This week we found a new app to edit photos on your iPhone, as well as another that lets you heavily customize the videos you record with your phone. If you're looking for a deal, a new coupon app will help you make sure you're getting the best discounts possible while you shop. If you're walking, running, or biking to your favorite store, another app will help you donate some cash to charity while working off those pounds. While you're out and about, it's important to stay safe.&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, App, apps, iphone, mobile app, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/apps-roundup-6-15/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/apps-roundup-6-15/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Introduces &#8216;Radical&#8217; MacBook Pro in New Ad [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>It's been a while since Apple devoted a TV spot to a Mac product, but the company has now decided to give the star treatment to its new MacBook Pro with Retina display. The ad, by longtime Apple ad agency TBWA|Media Arts Lab, features the usual product-as-hero theme common to many Apple ads. "The radical new MacBook Pro with Retina display," narrator Peter Coyote says over a shot of the MacBook Pro displaying high-res photos of waves and other colorful images. Then the camera reveals the laptop's thin silhouette to set up the double-entendre: "Innovation in every dimension." Interested? Well, first you'll have to get at least $2,200 together. We're sure that that won't be a proble&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Advertising, apple, Macbook Pro</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/apple-macbook-pro-retina-ad/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/13/apple-macbook-pro-retina-ad/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tweet Bieber a Question, He Might Answer it on YouTube</title>
      <description>Whether you count yourself as a "Belieber" or simply a fan, YouTube is giving you the chance to ask Justin Bieber a question. Jimmy Fallon and Justin Bieber posted a video (above) on YouTube's blog on Friday asking fans to tweet Justin questions using the hashtag #AskJustin, or by visiting youtube.com/kidrauhl and clicking the "Ask Justin" tab. Tweet the questions before Bieber's album release date next Tuesday, June 19 and Fallon just may choose to ask Bieber one of those questions for an interview that will be live streamed on YouTube Presents on June 21 at 7:15 p.m. ET. YouTube users can also vote on which questions they like, in addition to submitting their own. As of this wr&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Beliebers Unite, jimmy fallon, justin bieber, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/justin-bieber-question-youtube/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/15/justin-bieber-question-youtube/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
