<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JustCoz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1681631298/SteveKnight_headshot_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia"&gt;Steve Knight&lt;/a&gt;: 560 of U signed up 2 donate a tweet 4 a great cause @ &lt;a href="http://t.co/kYQoWEtt" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/kYQoWEtt&lt;/a&gt; :: Hoping 440 more of U will join us! &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/hope" target="_blank"&gt;@hope&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/knightopia/status/150403803001270272"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</link>
      <guid>http://justcoz.org/operationSAFE</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winklevoss Twins Start Up a Venture Capital Firm [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss, the twins who claimed to have played a big part in starting up Facebook and sued CEO Mark Zuckerberg for their share, have now become venture capitalists, announcing their new firm Friday morning on the CNBC show Squawk Box. They&#8217;re off to a good start, considering that Winklevoss Capital is presumably financed by the equity they drew from the settlement with Facebook CEO Zuckerberg. Apparently the Winklevoss twins have polished up their Silicon Valley-esque lingo, uttering such chestnuts as &#8220;We focus on early-stage, disruptive startups.&#8221; Armed with that sort of jargon, what could go wrong? Could the timing of the launch of Winklevoss Capital have anything to do with the upcoming Facebook IPO, which might happen on May 17? Perhaps the Winklevi are anticipating a big payout for their 1.2 million shares, with which to fund the various ventures they plan to take under their collective wings. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, Winklevoss twinsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/winklevoss-venture-capital/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/winklevoss-venture-capital/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google+ Share Button: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Google+ Introduces the Share Button: Use the new Google+ Share button to encourage visitors to share your content with their friends.This button is perfect for content that users may want to share but not +1.Google AdWords Come to YouTube: &#8220;With Google AdWords for video, you only pay when someone chooses to watch your ad, and you can create and manage video campaigns from the same platform as your search and display ads.&#8221;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rJ_aKjy0wjsDiscussion from our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:Turning Facebook Fans Into CustomersCompanies Using Company Pages WellMake an Income From BloggingLinkedIn Introduces iPad App: &#8220;The Linkedin iPad app was handcrafted to provide the most engaging experience,&#8221; and is getting good reviews.The Linkedin iPad dashboard contains all of the features you expect on a mobile application.Pinterest Improves Group Boards: Pinterest has made it &#8220;easier to pin with others while giving you more control over your profile.&#8221; New features include group board invitations and enhanced board settings."Pinners will now be asked to join a group board before it&#8217;s added to their profile."HootSuite Adds New Apps: The latest HootSuite apps &#8220;help you engage with communities, manage email campaigns, perform surveys, view RSS feeds and more.&#8221;HootSuite's Vision Critical Surveys app "allows you to easily share surveys with your social networks, monitor results in real time and more."Here are a couple of social media tools worth noting:Chirpify: The Twitter commerce platform where you can buy, sell, donate and transact on Twitter.Chirpify turns tweets into transactions, enabling consumers and businesses to buy, sell, donate and transact on Twitter.Offerpop Fan Profiles: A Facebook app to &#8220;give fans a way to discover and interact with each other on your brand page. Showcase your most active and influential fans while growing your &#8216;talking about this&#8217; score. Track all fan activity on your page and newsfeed.&#8221; And don&#8217;t miss this:Starting May 1st! Social Media Examiner presents Social Media Success Summit 2012! (online conference)Join 27 social media experts at Social Media Examiner&#8217;s big online conference! Go here to learn more.What social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-share-button-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-share-button-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook adds names to Timeline Friend photos, makes it easier to find new friends</title>
      <description>Facebook has made another minor change to users&#8217; Timeline profiles, incorporating a new design for Friend listings that include both a person&#8217;s name and profile photo, making it easier for other users to make new connections via their existing connections. The update appears to have rolled out over the past 24 hours, ensuring that when a user visits their friend&#8217;s Facebook profile, the Friends box immediately draws the their attention: Before, friends were listed but a user had to mouseover the person&#8217;s image to view their name on the resulting popup. You could argue that Facebook&#8217;s new design has elements of Microsoft&#8217;s Windows Phone/Metro interface, a layout that is both simple but effective at encouraging users to click through to other people&#8217;s profiles and expand connections. Facebook recently increased the size of Timeline profile images, just days after Google updated Google+ profiles to sport a larger photo. It appears that Facebook has been working to make the most of images on the social network, helping with the identification of its users and driving interaction between them.</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2012/04/28/facebook-adds-names-to-timeline-friend-photos-makes-it-easier-to-find-new-friends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2012/04/28/facebook-adds-names-to-timeline-friend-photos-makes-it-easier-to-find-new-friends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Great Entrepreneurs Create Their Own Luck</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: This post is authored by guest contributor Thor Muller, a New York Times best selling author. His latest book, &#8220;Get Lucky: How to Put Planned Serendipity to Work for You and Your Business&#8221; is available now. This is the story of how a young British fine artist accidentally became a materials scientist, founding a high-growth company that created a whole new product category. It&#8217;s also a parable for how great entrepreneurs systematically create their own luck. Jane ni Dhulchaointigh is the founder and CEO of Sugru, a London-based startup that makes an amazing moldable adhesive for repairing any physical object. It&#8217;s a cross between silly putty and duct tape, a space age rubber that can be molded into any desired shape by hand, and that sticks to a vast array of surfaces. With customers in over 100 countries, and all seven continents, Sugru has taken the world by storm. What we see in Jane&#8217;s journey, so far from California&#8217;s tech startup scene, is the same thing we see in virtually all startups that work: the ability to harness serendipity, the unplanned discoveries, large or small, that end up being the turning points in careers and businesses. Hard work, training and process may be the foundation of success, but serendipity is where the magic happens. And even though serendipity is by definition unpredictable, its appearance is anything but random. Jane&#8217;s stunning rise is the result of her mastering what we call the skills of planned serendipity, a set of behaviors that have allowed her, over and over again, to generate the chance discoveries, recognize the good ones, and take action on those that matter most. Here&#8217;s how it happened, and what we can learn from her breakout success. Start With A &#8220;Geek Brain&#8221; Jane originally studied to be a sculptor, an interest that had possessed her for years. She returned to school in 2003 to study commercial product design at the Royal College of Art. It seemed a prudent career move given the high demand for designers (and the lack of jobs for sculptors), but it was a switch that proved difficult. Her impulse was to follow her own interests over solving the narrowly defined product problems discussed in class. Before long, her background in sculpture combined with her insatiable curiosity led her to begin experimenting with new materials. Jane was equipped with one of the great advantages in cultivating serendipity, a geek brain&#8211;what we define as an obsessive curiosity in an area of interest and the ability to notice anomalies, overcoming the conventional wisdom that constrains others. The geek brain gave Jane distance from the rote conventions of design school, allowing her to connect ideas from across domains in unusual ways. Find Space to Play Having a mindset geared for recognizing unexpected ideas is rarely enough on its own&#8212;Jane needed an environment that allowed her to explore and put this geek brain to good use. The workshop at her college served this purpose well: I was destroying things and putting them back together: chipping blocks of wood apart and putting them back together with other materials&#8230;One experiment I did was combining silicone caulk with very fine wood dust from the workshop. From that combination I made these fancy wooden balls. I found it fascinating that you could make something that looked like wood but had other properties&#8212;if you threw them on the floor they&#8217;d bounce. Jane&#8217;s early explorations with her strange rubbery material was driven by a fascination with the possibilities of what she could make, rather than any specific purpose to which it could be put. This is the hallmark of a true exploratory mode, as premature focus can kill good ideas before they ever emerge. Still, as her discovery started to take shape, she began to spend more and more time wondering what it might actually be good for. Be Opinionated Jane&#8217;s boyfriend noticed that she had been using her funny rubber to repair or customize things around the house&#8212;enlarging a sink plug that was too small, or making a more ergonomic knife handle. It had been so natural for her to use the rubber in this way because she personally believed in the value of repairing her things rather than running out and buying a replacement. The instinct was so natural, in fact, that she hadn&#8217;t even consciously registered what she was doing. It was only when her boyfriend drew her attention to it that she saw the opportunity in a flash. Jane had stumbled on a product idea that mapped perfectly to a deeply held conviction: she hated waste. She was fed up with it and knew she wasn&#8217;t alone. &#8220;In the past, some people would have thought that repairing something is a compromise because you couldn&#8217;t afford to buy it new again,&#8221; Jane says. &#8220;But now there are increasing numbers of people who would rather repair or reuse than throw something out and needlessly buy something new because of the waste involved.&#8221; Her insight was that this space-age rubber she&#8217;d invented could be an essential innovation in this cause. She saw the potential in her chance discovery only because she had an overriding purpose that gave her a unique perspective. &#8220;Every granny who finds it hard to open a jam jar can manipulate this material,&#8221; she said. &#8220;Anyone who has a stiff part on their bike can adapt it to be whatever the bike needs.&#8221; Project the Possibility The only problem was that the material didn&#8217;t actually exist yet. The makeshift rubber Jane had been playing with had all kinds of problems: it didn&#8217;t adhere to enough surfaces, it had a terribly short shelf-life, and it was too high maintenance to make a successful commercial product. This was the do-or-die moment. As an artist, there was every reason in the world to give up&#8212;she had no business thinking she could solve this incredibly technical problem. Instead, Jane pulled a Jujitsu serendipity move: employing only her faulty prototype and her storytelling skills, she projected her vision as broadly as she could, telling anyone who would listen about it. Early stage entrepreneurs like Jane don&#8217;t always know what exact outcomes to expect, but they are willing to publicly put their ideas into the world, allowing them to connect with the as yet unknown people and opportunities that make their products possible. It worked. Attention followed from the strength of her vision, attracting local press mentions, a set of science advisors, and a grant from the National Endowment for Science, Technology, and Arts. Follow Unplanned Paths The grant wasn&#8217;t huge, a mere &#163;35,000, but it was enough to start testing materials&#8212;as long as Jane did the testing herself. To do that, she realized, she would have to do something that was not only unexpected, but would have seemed absurd a few months before: she&#8217;d have to diverge from her career path and be trained as a lab technician and set up her own laboratory. She wasn&#8217;t waiting around to find a CTO who knew better. This former art student must learn to be a materials scientist. It took her two years of painstaking trial-and-error, but eventually she created a brand new, patented class of silicone that worked for her aims. Only Jane&#8217;s immovable sense of purpose kept her going through month after month of laborious formulation and failure, long before her work would bear fruit. This is a recurring paradox of serendipity: stick-to-itness&#8212;the ability to stay committed to a purpose&#8212;is often the very thing that allows new paths to be recognized and taken. Design Openness into the Product and Company Initially there was tremendous pressure to fit the new product into a well-worn category that the traditional business world would understand. Then it struck Jane that she could create a brand designed to activate the creative spark in people. She could leave the product&#8217;s purpose intentionally open&#8212;the tagline would become &#8220;Hack Things Better&#8221;&#8212;so that customers could use their own imagination. One of the first things she did after launching the product was create an online community for customers to share their ideas. Creating permeability at the edge of her company allowed new directions and opportunities to serendipitously emerge. As a result the company and its customers have developed a truly symbiotic relationship. That &#8220;perfect fit&#8221; Jane had been seeking for her unusual rubber years ago? Her customers are telling her what it is&#8212;or rather, all of the perfect fits they&#8217;ve found. Repairing computers, cables for laptop chargers, phones, and outdoor equipment have emerged as the leading uses for her one-of-a-kind product. Jane is finding the company being pulled by customers in directions she could never have imagined during those years of painstaking materials research, but in each case the path is perfectly aligned with the company&#8217;s purpose. The Kind of Luck That Matters Entrepreneurs often cite &#8220;luck&#8221; as a key ingredient of success, yet this means far more than just being in the right time, right place. The luck that builds careers and companies is the kind that unfolds gradually, choice by choice, as people recognize and seize surprise opportunities, attracting others to them long before it&#8217;s obvious that their business is the next big thing. These skills of planned serendipity are not vague, metaphysical concepts; they can be mastered by any of us, and can shape how we run our startups as they grow. We can learn how to make our businesses luckier.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/28/how-great-entrepreneurs-create-their-own-luck/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/28/how-great-entrepreneurs-create-their-own-luck/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sarkozy-Kadhafi: la preuve du financement</title>
      <description>Fabrice Arfi Karl Laske &#169; ReutersSelon un document officiel libyen dat&#233; du 10 d&#233;cembre 2006, le r&#233;gime Kadhafi a d&#233;cid&#233; de d&#233;bloquer une somme de 50 millions d'euros pour la campagne pr&#233;sidentielle de Nicolas Sarkozy en 2007. Dans cette note que nous publions, Moussa Koussa, alors chef des services de renseignements ext&#233;rieurs libyens, autorise le directeur de cabinet de Kadhafi, B&#233;chir Saleh, &#224; entreprendre les versements secrets. M. Koussa &#233;voque dans ce document des r&#233;unions pr&#233;paratoires avec Brice Hortefeux et l'interm&#233;diaire Ziad Takieddine. &#171; Ce document prouve qu'on est en pr&#233;sence d'une affaire d'Etat &#187;, confirme ce dernier &#224; Mediapart. Le r&#233;gime de Mouammar Kadhafi a bien d&#233;cid&#233; de financer la campagne pr&#233;sidentielle de Nicolas Sarkozy en 2007. Mediapart a retrouv&#233; un document officiel libyen qui le prouve.Le version compl&#232;te de ce contenu est disponible pour les seuls abonn&#233;slire la suite</description>
      <link>http://www.mediapart.fr/journal/international/280412/sarkozy-kadhafi-la-preuve-du-financement</link>
      <guid>http://www.mediapart.fr/journal/international/280412/sarkozy-kadhafi-la-preuve-du-financement</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hobbit&#8217;s 48 FPS Format Ruins Film&#8217;s Artistry, Previewers Complain</title>
      <description>Cinematography has advanced considerably in the decade since Peter Jackson ceased filming The Lord of the Rings, a three-part epic based on the novels of J.R.R. Tolkien, at the standard film rate of 24 frames per second. In keeping with technological advances, Jackson shot the adaption of the prequel to the trilogy, The Hobbit, at 48 fps &#8212; but not everyone is happy about the change. Exhibitioners and press, who were treated to a 10-minute preview of The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey in Las Vegas earlier this week, complained that the new frame rate makes the film look jarringly realistic &#8212; more like ESPN broadcasts, which run as high as 60 fps in HD, or a daytime TV program. &#8220;It reminds me of when I first saw Blu-ray, in that it takes away that warm feeling of film,&#8221; one exhibitor told Variety. &#8220;It looked to me like a behind-the-scenes featurette.&#8221; Jackson defended his decision to shoot in 48 fps in a lengthy note posted to his Facebook page in April 2011. Shooting at the higher rate &#8220;hugely enhance[s] clarity and smoothness&#8230; Looks much more like life, and it is much easier to watch, especially in 3D,&#8221; he wrote. &#8220;I see it as a way of future-proofing The Hobbit,&#8221; he added. The Hobbit, which chronicles the journey of a hobbit (played by Martin Freeman) swept into an epic quest to reclaim treasure taken by a dragon, will be released in theaters in two parts. The first part, The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey, is scheduled to arrive Dec. 14. The film&#8217;s other stars include many who appeared in The Lord of the Rings, including Elijah Wood, Cate Blanchett, Orlando Bloom and Ian McKellen. The first trailer for the film was released on Facebook last December. More About: the lord of the rings, the-hobbitFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/the-hobbit-2/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/the-hobbit-2/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget Emoticons &#8212; Skype Wants You to Use &#8216;Humoticons&#8217;</title>
      <description>As part of Skype&#8217;s latest marketing campaign, the video call service has launched a Facebook app geared at making our interactions more human: Skype Humoticons. The app basically allows us to recreate classic emoticon images &#8212; such as the smiley face, sad face or tongue-out face &#8212; with our own real-life expressions. You can post existing photos to a &#8220;Humoticon gallery,&#8221; or snap new pictures within the app. The results can be shared on a Facebook wall, downloaded, or turned into a URL to share in an Instant Message. The &#8220;It&#8217;s Time to Skype&#8221; campaign launched earlier this month, is based on the premise that social networks such as Twitter and Facebook are &#8220;degrading humanity.&#8221; Some of the slogans Skype is using for the campaign: &#8220;140 characters doesn&#8217;t equal staying in touch&#8221; and &#8220;Upgrade from a wall post to a first class conversation.&#8221; Photo courtesy of Adweek The reasoning behind Skype Humoticons? &#8220;Because nothing can replace the look on your face,&#8221; according to a Skype blog post. There is a distinct irony in the campaign. At the same time it blasts Facebook and Twitter, Skype isn&#8217;t above using both social networks for promotion purposes. As part of the &#8220;It&#8217;s Time for Skype&#8221; social media campaign, for example, the hashtag #timeforskype will be used on Twitter. And not only does Skype have a video call integration feature on Facebook, but the entire Humoticons campaign is housed on a Facebook page. Do we really need to mimic emoticons to put the humanity back in our conversations? Will you use them, or are they just another superficial way to show what we&#8217;re feeling? Sound off in the comments. Photo courtesy of Skype Humoticons More About: Facebook, Marketing, Skype</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/skype-humanity-humoticons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/skype-humanity-humoticons/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Leverage Applicant Tracking Systems To Land a Job</title>
      <description>Sharlyn Lauby, SPHR, CPLP, is the HR Bartender, whose blog is a friendly place to discuss workplace issues. When not &#8220;bartending,&#8221; Sharlyn is president of Internal Talent Management, which specializes in leadership training and human resources consulting. Since paper applications are going the way of the dinosaur in favor of digital job postings, it only seems logical to have more automated recruitment processes. Along with increased technology in the hiring process, there can also be some challenges for the average jobseeker. One frustration is the electronic application submission process, commonly known as Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS). Applicants regularly complain about the proverbial &#8220;black hole&#8221; their resumes are sent off to when they hit the submit button, never to be seen by anyone again. It&#8217;s doubtful that we will return to old school recruitment, so it&#8217;s time to demystify Applicant Tracking Systems. Let&#8217;s take a look behind the curtain to find out how to make an ATS work for you. ATS Defined SilkRoad Technology provides a full suite of cloud-based social talent management software that encompasses all employee milestones from pre-hire to retire. Their ATS is called OpenHire, which is used as an enterprise solution for companies all over the country. Thomas Boyle, the director of product strategy, explains how Applicant Tracking Systems work: &#8220;Applicant tracking systems provide a software interface for companies to manage their hiring process. At a base level, this consists of opening new positions and advertising them online &#8212; either on a corporate home page or job boards. Once recruiters open the position and advertise it, the ATS provides an interface for candidates to apply online and for managers and recruiters to view and search though those candidate submissions before moving them through the hiring processing &#8212; typically from screening to interview to offer and, of course, hire.&#8221; Why Companies use an ATS We can&#8217;t forget there&#8217;s a clear business reason why companies utilize an ATS. Colin Day, CEO and president of talent acquisition software company iCIMS, Inc., says an ATS is becoming a must-have in today&#8217;s recruitment world because it allows companies of all sizes to streamline and automate HR responsibilities. &#8220;Recruiters are adopting them for a number of reasons, including social media outreach capabilities, the need to more effectively manage candidate data, and the desire to achieve significant cost and time savings,&#8221; Day explains. &#8220;With an ATS, HR can automate and store hiring documents online so HR professionals never have to worry about sifting through stacks of paperwork or hundreds of emails to find what they need.&#8221; Advantages for Job Seekers It&#8217;s clear to see the efficiency advantage for a company using an ATS, but what are the advantages to the job seeker? Lisa Sterling, director of people engagement at cloud and software provider Ultimate Software, says speed is the answer. &#8220;With an ATS, especially one that can give hiring managers &#8212; not just recruiters &#8212; control of the hiring process, job applicants can get their resumes, cover letters and data in front of the appropriate hiring authority quicker for faster review of qualifications, making the application-submission process much more efficient for applicants,&#8221; Sterling says. The other benefit is better information. &#8220;Applicants can better position their resumes with job-related keywords to take advantage of a solution&#8217;s automated screening tools that index and crawl submissions,&#8221; Sterling explains. &#8220;This might bring an applicant&#8217;s resume to the forefront, where otherwise it might have been overlooked through manual submission and review.&#8221; How to Use the ATS for Success As with any kind of technology, ATS software can only work with what it&#8217;s given. If you submit garbage &#8230; well, you know the rest. Applicants need to know how to position themselves for success. Day recommends getting a clear understanding of the position before applying. &#8220;Do not become a serial candidate &#8212; one who skims through job descriptions and applies to every position a company has available. Read descriptions more than once and get an understanding of what a company wants from you.&#8221; Sterling notes the unique features of Ultimate Software&#8217;s solution have carefully considered the candidate experience: &#8220;We take a different approach to applicant tracking with our talent acquisition solution, because traditional systems aren&#8217;t designed with the candidate in mind.&#8221; Nonetheless, some tips to help candidates optimize submissions for a typical ATS include: Tailoring your resume and job application to the specific job requirements referenced in the posting &#8212; emphasize your relevant experience and skills in the areas that are critical to that position, rather than submitting your standard resume. Adding specific keywords into the application that are referenced in the job posting, so that applicant screening tools that index and crawl submissions for certain key terms and phrases will pick them up. Adding additional instances of keywords from the job posting to your resume in white font. The additional instances of the keywords won&#8217;t be visible when recruiters read the resume, but they increase the likelihood that the resume will be tagged as a good fit by search tools. Including your Twitter handle and LinkedIn profile to give recruiters a way to access more information about you. The Importance of Keywords Jason Buss, founder of the talent site Talent HQ, echoes the comments about the importance of keywords. &#8220;The biggest thing most recruiting professionals will highlight is the effective use of keywords on your resume when applying using an applicant tracking system,&#8221; Buss explains. &#8220;Leverage sites like LinkedIn to see what connections you have within an organization when you are applying.&#8221; However, Buss does caution that keywords are important when applying: They aren&#8217;t a silver bullet when it comes to getting a job. &#8220;Keywords play an important role in an ATS, given that recruiting professionals primarily use keyword searches to find candidates that most closely match the requirements of a position. However, the best written resume isn&#8217;t as valuable as having contacts, a network and connections within a company.&#8221; Leverage the System Day reminds us that the goal of an ATS is to free up a recruiter&#8217;s time to spend with candidates. &#8220;Recruiters should focus on building a quality workforce. Applicant tracking systems allow HR professionals to focus on that and not the administration often associated with the hiring process.&#8221; Optimizing your resume, focusing on keywords in the ATS interface and still getting out to network are the steps to finding a new opportunity. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Sr. Producer at Rokkan in New York Director of Content Development at Massachusetts Institute of Technology in Cambridge, Mass. Manager, Social Media at Epson in Long Beach, Calif. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, tumpikuja, kroach, eyeidea More About: features, human resources, job applications, job search, job search series, mashable, Recruiting, resume</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/applicant-tracking-systems/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/28/applicant-tracking-systems/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tear gas fired at Malaysia rally</title>
      <description>Malaysian police fired tear gas and chemical laced water at protesters in Kuala Lumpur campaigning for cleaner elections.</description>
      <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304811304577371110260111368.html?mod=asia_home</link>
      <guid>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304811304577371110260111368.html?mod=asia_home</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
