<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Gorgeous Look at the Aurora Borealis Took Three Years to Create [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>This stunning time-lapse video of the Aurora Borealis was created over the course of three years. It was shot with a DSLR camera and used thousands of hours of footage to create the final breathtaking effect. SEE ALSO: Boy Ages From Birth to 9 in 127 Seconds [VIDEO] It's readily evident that a tremendous amount of time and careful skill went into creating this project. Chad Blakley, the creator of the video, called the labor-of-love "one of the most amazing experiences of my life." The video was shot in Abisko National Park, Sweden and created by photography tour group Lights Over Lapland. More About: aurora borealis, time-lapse, Vimeo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/aurora-borealis-time-lapse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/aurora-borealis-time-lapse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gen Y Scores Jobs With Social Search</title>
      <description>In an era when 50% of recent college graduates are unemployed or underemployed, according to government data analyzed by the Associated Press, the U.S. tech industry shines brightly in a dreary hiring climate. &#8232;&#8232;According to the Bureau of Labor Statistics, technology has shown a relatively steady increase in jobs created since June 2009. As a generation, millennials have an advantage when it comes searching online for job opportunities.&#8232; &#8220;I definitely think that my generation is more technologically dexterous, so we have the advantage in using social media,&#8221; explains Francesca Krihely, an online community manager from San Francisco. &#8220;I also think that we are&#8230; Continue reading... More About: features, job search, job search series, mashable, social media jobs</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/gen-y-social-media-search/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/gen-y-social-media-search/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45% of Executives Think Social Media Has a Positive Impact on the Workplace</title>
      <description>More executives than employees think social media has a positive impact on workplace culture. While 45% of executives believe social media is good for their companies&#8217; culture, only 27% of employees agree, finds a recent survey by Deloitte. Executives think social media has a positive impact because it allows managers to be more transparent (38%), helps build and maintain relationships among colleagues (46%), helps build company culture (41%), and fosters a feeling of connection to the company and its leadership (37%). What factors do executives think are more important to culture building than social media? Some 65% say financial performance and 62% say compensation. However, employees disagree with their workplace superiors. Only 33% saying compensation and 24% saying financial performance have effects on company culture. Employees rank regular and candid communications (50%), employee recognition (49%) and access to management and leadership (47%) as having the largest impact. SEE ALSO: 6 Mobile Apps for Your Job Hunt The survey&#8217;s findings say that though some executives may use social media as a crutch to enhance workplace culture, it cannot replace solid leadership and communications. What&#8217;s your company&#8217;s relationship with social media? Should executives do more to encourage the use of social media or is online networking better left for our personal lives?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/?p=1176429&amp;preview=true</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/?p=1176429&amp;preview=true</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google: Redesigned Ads Will Increase Click-Through Rates 100% [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>As Google works to improve its mobile product, the company says its redesigned ads in Google Maps will increase click-through rates by 100%. The changes will being rolling out for all users Friday. The new search results feature larger and more clickable buttons to place calls or find directions. Websites will load within maps, rather than launching a separate browser page. Google is also launching a blue hyperlocal marker, showing your distance from nearby businesses. Maps is an important opportunity for advertisers, because 94% of smartphone users search for local business information. Of those searchers, 90% make decisions based on the res&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Advertising, Google, Google Maps, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/google-redesigned-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/google-redesigned-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Van Gogh&#8217;s &#8216;Starry Night&#8217; Is Beautifully Recreated From 7,000 Dominoes [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>What would celebrated painter Vincent van Gogh's Starry Night look like if it were constructed out of thousands of dominoes? YouTube video maker FlippyCat found out, successfully recreating the masterpiece on his second try. During the first attempt, a screw from the camera he had affixed overhead fell and sent the dominoes spiraling to the ground. Though he didn't time his first attempt, his second and final go at creating the domino version of "Starry Night" took 11 hours. SEE ALSO: 30,000 Dominoes Capture the History of Nintendo in 3 Minutes [VIDEO] FlippyCat has previously made Leonardo da Vinci's Mona Lisa from dominoes, capturing his creation in a YouTube video since view&#8230; Continue reading... More About: art, Video, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/starry-night-dominoes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/starry-night-dominoes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Big Brands Create Social Media Campaigns</title>
      <description>Ad execs who work for brands that regularly advertise during the Super Bowl often say they begin planning for the following year shortly after the winning team heads to the locker room. But for Fiat, it only took a mere five to six weeks to put together a social media campaign built around its Super Bowl ad. Coca-Cola's social campaign for Coke Zero, "Make It Possible," took about six months to create. Meanwhile, Ford's "Doug" spokespuppet campaign took about a year from inception to the bitter end. How did it happen? Fiat went to its social media agency, Ignite, asked it to come up with ideas and then picked the best one. Ford also relied on its agency, Team Detroit, for ideation. Bu&#8230; Continue reading... More About: coca cola, features, ford, mashable, social media for business leaders series, social media strategy</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Big Brands Create Social Media Campaigns</title>
      <description>Ad execs who work for brands that regularly advertise during the Super Bowl often say they begin planning for the following year shortly after the winning team heads to the locker room. But for Fiat, it only took a mere five to six weeks to put together a social media campaign built around its Super Bowl ad. Coca-Cola's social campaign for Coke Zero, "Make It Possible," took about six months to create. Meanwhile, Ford's "Doug" spokespuppet campaign took about a year from inception to the bitter end. How did it happen? Fiat went to its social media agency, Ignite, asked it to come up with ideas and then picked the best one. Ford also relied on its agency, Team Detroit, for ideation. Bu&#8230; Continue reading... More About: coca cola, features, ford, mashable, social media for business leaders series, social media strategy</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/big-brands-social-media-campaigns/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do You Suffer From Social Media FOMO? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do you know FOMO? That's not some fancy latte -- it's Fear Of Missing Out, and something that's become a recognized thing by many social media users these days. You're probably familiar with the concept, if not the name. Here's an example: It's been a long workweek and you really just want to spend Friday night at home watching a movie. But then that old familiar urge hits, and you can't resist grabbing your smartphone for a jolty fix of quick-burst information. One friend's Twitter post mentions an awesome concert. On Facebook, someone else put up photos of a raging house party. Suddenly, your mellow evening feels entirely inadequate and you wonder what else you're missing out on. Y&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/fomo-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/fomo-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do You Suffer From Social Media FOMO? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do you know FOMO? That's not some fancy latte -- it's Fear Of Missing Out, and something that's become a recognized thing by many social media users these days. You're probably familiar with the concept, if not the name. Here's an example: It's been a long workweek and you really just want to spend Friday night at home watching a movie. But then that old familiar urge hits, and you can't resist grabbing your smartphone for a jolty fix of quick-burst information. One friend's Twitter post mentions an awesome concert. On Facebook, someone else put up photos of a raging house party. Suddenly, your mellow evening feels entirely inadequate and you wonder what else you're missing out on. Y&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/fomo-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/22/fomo-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friendshake: Facebook&#8217;s New Mobile Feature For Finding People Nearby (And A Highlight Killer?)</title>
      <description>Facebook has created a new feature that lets users find friends and potential friends nearby. Called &#8220;Friendshake&#8221; (for now), it&#8217;s another step in Facebook furthering its reach into mobile, and creating services to meet new people &#8212; rather than build more connections up with the ones you already know. And, in keeping with Facebook&#8217;s emphasis on being as ubiquitous as possible, it&#8217;s not in a native app, but via the mobile web. The feature follows a little under two months after Facebook announced the acquisition of Glancee, a mobile app that helps users discover people near them with similar interests, whose three founders have now joined Facebook and closed down their app. It is not clear if Friendshake has been created out of that acquisition, or if it has been developed along an altogether different thread &#8212; and how the functions of the two may eventually dovetail. We first heard about Friendshake from developer Roger Pincombe, who himself got the info from a Facebook developer at the Angelhack event going on this weekend: Facebook is a title sponsor, and at the San Francisco event (Angelhack&#8217;s taking place also in Seattle, Boston and NYC), and one of its engineers was on site showing off how the app worked with developers. The feature has not been officially launched, but it is live and visible for those seeking it out. &#8220;He specifically said I should tell other people about it,&#8221; he told me in an email. &#8220;I (semi-jokingly) asked &#8216;even TechCrunch?&#8217; and he said sure.&#8221; So here we are. For now, the app works like this. Users have to be logged into Facebook and also into the Friendshake URL, and then others who are near can pick each other up. You can see both your own friends, as well as those you may not know. For now it looks like the main purpose is to quickly add people who you meet at a specific event &#8212; like a hackathon, or a bar. As Pincombe points out, &#8220;Before you would need to tell them your name, probably spell it for them, and then depending on how common your name is, you&#8217;d have to tell them which of the results is actually you. This makes it 2 taps if you save a bookmark.&#8221; And there is, of course, the potential of how this basic service could be further developed: finding people who are friends of friends, or who have flagged similar interests in their social graphs; and it potentially could be something to incorporate as a push service, rather than one you have to be activate to use every time. All of these features could make Friendshake into a Highlight killer &#8212; which can already do all of the above &#8212; and a lot more like Glancee, too. And as with so many of these kinds of features, you have to wonder how and if it will be abused &#8212; random people you would like to shake off suddenly start asking you to friend them on Facebook, for example. However, it appears that, even if Friendshake is already publicly available, this is still a work in progress being tested out, and so we may see more controls getting put in place, in addition to the fact that you have to activate the service to use it. &#8220;To my knowledge, the few people here at AngelHack that the Facebook employee tested it with are the only people to know about it yet,&#8221; said Pincombe. Before this, Facebook already had an ambient location feature, but it worked somewhat less in real time, and it is more about friends you have rather than making new ones. Facebook&#8217;s Check-In feature, when enabled, lets users see contacts who have visited the same places they have, or who has checked-in to a Facebook event.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friendshake: Facebook&#8217;s New Mobile Feature For Finding People Nearby (And A Highlight Killer?)</title>
      <description>Facebook has created a new feature that lets users find friends and potential friends nearby. Called &#8220;Friendshake&#8221; (for now), it&#8217;s another step in Facebook furthering its reach into mobile, and creating services to meet new people &#8212; rather than build more connections up with the ones you already know. And, in keeping with Facebook&#8217;s emphasis on being as ubiquitous as possible, it&#8217;s not in a native app, but via the mobile web. The feature follows a little under two months after Facebook announced the acquisition of Glancee, a mobile app that helps users discover people near them with similar interests, whose three founders have now joined Facebook and closed down their app. It is not clear if Friendshake has been created out of that acquisition, or if it has been developed along an altogether different thread &#8212; and how the functions of the two may eventually dovetail. We first heard about Friendshake from developer Roger Pincombe, who himself got the info from a Facebook developer at the Angelhack event going on this weekend: Facebook is a title sponsor, and at the San Francisco event (Angelhack&#8217;s taking place also in Seattle, Boston and NYC), and one of its engineers was on site showing off how the app worked with developers. The feature has not been officially launched, but it is live and visible for those seeking it out. &#8220;He specifically said I should tell other people about it,&#8221; he told me in an email. &#8220;I (semi-jokingly) asked &#8216;even TechCrunch?&#8217; and he said sure.&#8221; So here we are. For now, the app works like this. Users have to be logged into Facebook and also into the Friendshake URL, and then others who are near can pick each other up. You can see both your own friends, as well as those you may not know. For now it looks like the main purpose is to quickly add people who you meet at a specific event &#8212; like a hackathon, or a bar. As Pincombe points out, &#8220;Before you would need to tell them your name, probably spell it for them, and then depending on how common your name is, you&#8217;d have to tell them which of the results is actually you. This makes it 2 taps if you save a bookmark.&#8221; And there is, of course, the potential of how this basic service could be further developed: finding people who are friends of friends, or who have flagged similar interests in their social graphs; and it potentially could be something to incorporate as a push service, rather than one you have to be activate to use every time. All of these features could make Friendshake into a Highlight killer &#8212; which can already do all of the above &#8212; and a lot more like Glancee, too. And as with so many of these kinds of features, you have to wonder how and if it will be abused &#8212; random people you would like to shake off suddenly start asking you to friend them on Facebook, for example. However, it appears that, even if Friendshake is already publicly available, this is still a work in progress being tested out, and so we may see more controls getting put in place, in addition to the fact that you have to activate the service to use it. &#8220;To my knowledge, the few people here at AngelHack that the Facebook employee tested it with are the only people to know about it yet,&#8221; said Pincombe. Before this, Facebook already had an ambient location feature, but it worked somewhat less in real time, and it is more about friends you have rather than making new ones. Facebook&#8217;s Check-In feature, when enabled, lets users see contacts who have visited the same places they have, or who has checked-in to a Facebook event.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
