<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>A DRAMATIC SURPRISE ON A QUIET SQUARE</title>
      <description>(18 votes - 1 comment - 127 views)YT: "To launch the high quality TV channel TNT in Belgium we placed a big red push button on an average Flemish square of an average Flemish town. A sign with the text "Push to add drama" invited people to use the button. And then we waited"</description>
      <link>http://music.videosift.com/video/So-they-installed-a-Push-to-add-drama-button-in-Belgium</link>
      <guid>http://music.videosift.com/video/So-they-installed-a-Push-to-add-drama-button-in-Belgium</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Official Dropbox Guide To Getting More Space!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We get asked a lot how to get more space in your Dropbox, and we realized that we&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve never put an official guide together. So here it is! When people start using Dropbox, they start small but often need more and more space over time. We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve created a bunch of free ways to get more space, but also make it simple to get loads of space really fast.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/gs"&gt;Take A Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; For people new to Dropbox, there are a few things you should try out first &amp;#8212; we want you to install Dropbox on a bunch of computers, use our sharing features, and more. We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve put together &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/gs"&gt;a list of tasks to get started&lt;/a&gt;; and when you finish this quest, you&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ll get an extra 250MB free.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/referrals"&gt;Tell Your Friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; A while back, we noticed that most of our growth was from word of mouth: people that love Dropbox tell their friends. We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve built a way to invite your friends to Dropbox that gives you both extra space (250MB for free)! We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve made it really easy to email your friends from your address book and post to Twitter or Facebook. We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve also given you a link to put anywhere on the web. The more people you invite, the more space you get!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/edu"&gt;Be A Student&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Dropbox was started back when our cofounder Drew Houston was still in school and forgot his USB key on a bus ride. To commemorate our victory over USB keys, and to make the lives of students even easier, students with a valid school email address get a whopping 500MB for each person they invite to Dropbox. All you need to do is &lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/edu"&gt;confirm that you&amp;#8217;re a student&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have Fun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve done a bunch of fun challenges and quests where the prize was more space. In January, we had our first DropQuest, which was a scavenger hunt across our site. It was a race to the finish to get some really special prizes, and every person that finished also got a bonus. Last October, Reddit stole our logo, so to say thanks we made a post where the top commenter got a 100GB boost to their Dropbox. We&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ve made a fun little quest to make your Dropbox a little more social. A while back when we made an announcement on twitter, we gave a random re-tweeter 100GB to get the word out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We do this stuff all the time! The best way to keep up with the games is to &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/dropbox"&gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/dropbox"&gt;like us on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://dropbox.com/pricing"&gt;One More Thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If you ever need even more space, you can always subscribe to Dropbox Pro, available in 50GB or 100GB. Furthermore, referrals double to 500MB (1GB for students) per person you invite! But if you need even more than 100GB, or if you run your own business; you should check out &lt;a href="http://www.dropbox.com/teams"&gt;Dropbox for Teams&lt;/a&gt;, which is designed specifically for educators, non-profits, and businesses. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hopefully this gave you a good idea of how to get even more space for your Dropbox! Happy Dropboxing! Ohh, and just for good measure, we&#226;&#8364;&#8482;ll pick someone who retweets our tweet about this post and give them a 100GB bonus!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://blog.dropbox.com/?p=938&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dropbox+%28The+Dropbox+Blog%29</link>
      <guid>http://blog.dropbox.com/?p=938&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+dropbox+%28The+Dropbox+Blog%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Apps to Help Manage Your Twitter Account</title>
      <description>&lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;a href="http://www.tweepi.com" target="_blank"&gt;Tweepi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/01/19/twitter-helpful-apps/#440331-Tweepi"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. Tweepi" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/5-helpful-apps-to-manage-your-twitter/Twitter%201.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tweepi's "Flush" option allows you to see the users you follow who are not following you back. Its "Reciprocate" option allows you to see the users following you who you're not following back. And the "Cleanup" option allows you to see everyone who you're following so you can unfollow as many users as you like.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can also see who your friends are following, follow full lists and follow other users based on who they follow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tweepi displays the users in helpful columns by showing their names, bios, locations, number of tweets, number of followers, number of users they follow, dates of their last tweets, their &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/klout/"&gt;Klout&lt;/a&gt; scores and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2012/01/19/twitter-helpful-apps/#440331-Tweepi'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Elijah Daniel is an up-and-coming writer and comedian. He aims to make people smile via his &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/aguywithnolife" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/ROCParasyte" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; accounts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; enthusiast, it&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s always nice to find useful apps that help to manage my account. Check out five of the best apps I use regularly by clicking through the gallery above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/apps/"&gt;apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/3RhF8O8NjSDjCAnBTxX6ZNLoYyU/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/3RhF8O8NjSDjCAnBTxX6ZNLoYyU/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/3RhF8O8NjSDjCAnBTxX6ZNLoYyU/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/3RhF8O8NjSDjCAnBTxX6ZNLoYyU/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=91Y3DQ3JQms:9gaZqfnwcEg:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/91Y3DQ3JQms" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/01/19/twitter-helpful-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/01/19/twitter-helpful-apps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Tech-Forward Concepts Reshaping Our Future</title>
      <description>For the Global Innovation Series, presented by BMW, we&#8217;re focused on one simple question: In what ways is technology drastically changing our lives for the better? In a lot of ways, living in a city is challenging &#8212; urban citizens are constantly thinking about mobility, energy, shelter, safety and efficiency as they go about their daily lives. Many projects and startups in cities all around the globe are developing and implementing new technology to ameliorate these daily problems. If these concepts come to fruition, then the future of cities is looking bright. Whether you&#8217;re thinking easier ways to park your car or ideas for the home of the future, studying how we&#8217;ll live in the next 10, 50 or 100 years can reshape the habits and challenges we have today. Take a look at a roundup of 14 of these revolutionary ideas below. Looking for more? Make sure to follow the series &#8212; each week, you&#8217;ll get a new article on the future of urban life. 1. 4 Innovative Solar Tech Projects From Around the World The sun may be our greatest energy resource, but we still rely on fossil fuels in the United States. According to the Energy Department, solar power accounts for just 1% of America&#8217;s alternative energy production. While the industry isn&#8217;t booming just yet, it is growing quickly and there is promise &#8212; Google invested $280 million in solar energy in June and another $94 million in December, and Warren Buffett recently bought a photovoltaic farm for $2 billion. Read the full story here. 2. How One App Empowers Citizens to Take Control of Urban Noise Pollution We live in a loud world. With cars whizzing past, construction sites pounding away, ambulances roaring around and the dull ache of idle chatter constantly bombarding the sound wall, it&#8217;s easy to get overwhelmed in a noisy environment. And there&#8217;s good reason for that: Although it&#8217;s usually pushed into the background, noise is a form of pollution. Read the full story here. 3. Pedestrian Safety: How Innovative Tech Could Save Your Life When it comes to pedestrian traffic, safety should be the number-one concern, but transportation infrastructure in the United States is built to accommodate cars, not people. This focus is putting lives at risk and the data shows it &#8212; in 2010, pedestrian fatalities rose 4.2%, and pedestrian injuries due to motor vehicle crashes increased by 19% from the previous year, according to data from the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. With 4,280 pedestrians killed and 70,000 injured in 2010 in the U.S. alone, cities are installing technologies that will improve pedestrian safety on busy streets. Read the full story here. 4. How Video Chat Is Creating a Global Classroom Tasked with teaching an elementary school class stories, customs, holidays, foods and popular culture of many different cultures, student-teacher Maggie Holmes hopes to squeeze in some first-hand accounts. She&#8217;s asked teachers of global elementary schools to set up an exchange with her class. Until recently, connecting students with those living elsewhere would have likely been a bigger headache than it was worth. But as more teachers look to the Internet to make such global connections, it&#8217;s become a matter of posting a short blog post in the right place. Read the full story here. 5. The Future of Food: 11 Unique Urban Farming Projects Farming has a lot of romance in it. The idea of tilling the land, growing something from scratch and providing for yourself from the gifts of the land is a primal urge that runs through even the most cynical techie. Well, you don&#8217;t have to give up your iPad to get a piece of the farming pie with the growing interest in &#8220;urban farming,&#8221; which is finding ways to bring the farming lifestyle to cities, high-rises and other urban environments. Read the full story here. 6. 8 Amazing Green Buildings That Break Even on Energy Consumption Worldwide revenues from zero-energy buildings are predicted to increase to just under $1.3 trillion by 2035, according to a recent report published by Pike Research. The report also noted that the market for such buildings, including both commercial and residential real estate, currently sits at $225 million. A zero-energy building is one that produces as much energy as it consumes, making it a net-zero energy property and eliminating energy bills for its owners. Although zero-energy homes and buildings are quite rare today, increasing concerns about energy waste have set the stage for a growing market. Read the full story here. 7. 4 Unique Ways to Generate Renewable Energy Finding sources of renewable energy is a growing challenge for the modern world. As we strive for energy efficiency and sustainable resources, avenues are opening up for different and exciting ways to power our lifestyles. Companies across the globe are harnessing the potential of renewable energies, including solar and geothermal methods. Read the full story here. 8. How Mobile Payments Are Revolutionizing Public Transit If modern technology is a universal language, the world is getting schooled in innovation, especially in the public transportation sector. The global transportation industry has become a proving ground for new payment systems, as cutting-edge technologies have been introduced to taxis, buses and trains worldwide to streamline jaunts around town. From reserving and paying for a cab with an app to purchasing train tickets via an iPod, various countries are experimenting with new ways to reach out to travelers and make payment and transport a whole lot easier. Read the full story here. 9. Reimagining City Life: One Startup&#8217;s Vision of the Future &#8220;A lot of people face pretty profound constraints on mobility, enjoy only limited access to opportunity, and face serious difficulty in getting timely, accurate information about services available to them,&#8221; says Adam Greenfield, founder of Urbanscale. &#8220;As far as we&#8217;re concerned, it&#8217;s both a matter of basic morality and in our own long-term best interest, to ensure that everyone living in a society has open and unfettered access to these things.&#8221; And that&#8217;s exactly what his Manhattan-based company is working toward. Read the full story here. 10. Live Greener: 3 Energy-Saving Technologies for Your Home In a perfect world, with perfect circumstances, who wouldn&#8217;t want a self-sustaining smart home? These days, there are so many goals towards home efficiency and sustainability that many are clamoring to &#8220;green&#8221; their homes as best as possible &#8212; with the ultimate achievement of creating a zero-energy home on the horizon. In the real world, building an energy-friendly home is a lot more difficult than it sounds. While you can make a fairly sustainable home simply by employing sensible green building adjustments to insulation, home materials, lighting and heating, that&#8217;s not all that goes into a truly efficient home. Read the full story here. 11. 7 City Parking Apps to Save You Time, Money and Gas Yellow curb, red curb, white curb, blue curb &#8212; figuring out where to park, especially in a big city, can make you feel like you&#8217;re in a zany Dr. Seuss story. And when you do snag a sweet street spot, it can feel like a mini moment of glory. If you live in a crowded metropolis, then finding a parking spot is a task you&#8217;d like to see simplified. Here are seven helpful parking apps to help you find a safe place to park. Read the full story here. 12. 5 Home Technologies That Will Save You Energy and Money Tech manufacturers are making it easier for eco-conscious consumers to welcome a greener lifestyle. But going green doesn&#8217;t mean sacrificing the allure of cutting-edge technology. From controlling lights at home through a mobile app to investing in smart appliances that cut down on energy use and costs, there are myriad high-tech options on the market that make the home more sustainable. Read the full story here. 13. This Is What Your Future Home Might Look Like The urban environment is daunting. In a bustling community of millions and millions of citizens, the mere constraints of having so many people in one place can force innovation to materialize out of sheer need. Over the years, popular culture has tried to mold and shape the way an urban environment will look an act ten, fifty or even a hundred years from now. Will the cities of the future look like The Jetsons or Blade Runner? Well, if current, feasible development is any indication, the answer is actually neither. Read the full story here. 14. High-Tech Threads: Can Your Clothes Do This? Today&#8217;s clothing isn&#8217;t just about fashion &#8212; it&#8217;s about function. We&#8217;re not talking about Scottevest&#8217;s Inspector Gadget-esque trenchcoat to store your iPhone, iPad, iPod and even a few changes of clothes. Sure, that&#8217;s handy, but the jacket itself isn&#8217;t high-tech (though it is well designed). Mashable has explored ways in which tech companies and fashion brands have come together to create prototypes of new kinds of apparel, and we spoke with independent designers who&#8217;ve conceived mind-blowing gear that essentially transforms your body into a generator. Read the full story here. Looking for more great ideas? Take a look at past roundups here and here. Image courtesy of Flickr, frogman2212 More About: features, Global Innovation Series, mashable, roundupFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/urban-future-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/urban-future-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lunching with strangers: The rise of social meals</title>
      <description>I never expected to pay to lunch with a bunch of strangers. I&#8217;m increasingly cynical about social media and the new social-local-mobile startups, which seem to emerge daily. The craze of collaborative consumption is no exception. From sharing your apartment, to sharing your car, and even to sharing your home-cooked meals, collaborative consumption offers technology that helps you share your goods and experiences. Social eating startups are one flavor currently flooding the collaborative consumption space, with names such as GrubWithUs, LetsLunch, and local DC startup Wednesdays.com. Although I&#8217;m addicted to going out for lunch, the reasons to use Wednesday.com escaped me. What was wrong with the people I was lunching with regularly? However, the technology angel on my shoulder encouraged me to be open-minded. So when an email arrived from Wednesdays.com inviting me to a &#8220;Lean Startup Club Lunch,&#8221; I signed-up. The lunch was billed as a way to discuss the previous night&#8217;s Lean Startup Club meeting (&#8220;Love&#8217;d it? Share your opinion of yesterday&#8217;s meetup with your fellow LSCers over lunch!&#8221;). I imagined meeting a group of diverse people who spanned generations, race, and gender, yet were all interested in entrepreneurship. I had two practical problems here. First, I wasn&#8217;t going to attend the meet-up. Second, at that time I hadn&#8217;t actually read Eric Ries&#8217; The Lean Startup (which I since have, and is worth picking-up). But the lunch was being hosted at a local Turkish restaurant, and the half Turkish side in me required me to hit sign-up. Five other people confirmed for the lunch, which meant five people who could quiz me on my non-existent knowledge of Lean Startup. Not surprisingly, the lunch was on a Wednesday. On my way there, I worried about how I would recognize the other &#8220;social lunchers.&#8221; Thankfully, when I got to the restaurant I noticed a guy who looked similarly confused. We quickly acknowledged our mutual Wednesdays.com connection. Doug Naegele is the founder of infieldhealth, a company he&#8217;s boot-strapped to date, has customers, and is looking to hire in the coming year. He&#8217;s a community leader in mobile health, regularly speaking at various mHealth conferences and events around DC. Soon after, Ben Willman came up and introduced himself. Seeing two awkward guys at a table talking about technology presumably caught his attention. Ben was clearly the most knowledgeable about Lean Startup. He was working on ClientHat to help make virtual assistants more efficient, and told us about his process for customer development as well as his intense customer interviews. It seemed as though he had talked with every virtual assistant on eLance. Even though five others had RSVP&#8217;d, only two had shown up at this point. Right as we were ordering, Todd Fisk came in and quickly joined the table. His startup was chartme.net, an iPad app that allows you to build beautiful charts of any data you want. You could use it to chart your running times, how much you&#8217;ve put in your 401(k), or anything else that might be worth tracking. Todd also didn&#8217;t seem to have read Eric&#8217;s book, but he was interested in how people were integrating its general principles into their work. We had each paid a set $14.55 to sign-up, which included the restaurant&#8217;s lunch special, gratuity, and a $3.50 service fee to Wednesdays.com. The restaurant was semi-aware of what was going on, and gave us a menu of things to pick from. I had an amazing falafel sandwich and hummus sampler, which I enjoyed as I semi-deftly avoided exposing my non-knowledge of Eric&#8217;s new book. I came into the lunch excited for an example of forced serendipity. I assumed that it would be a way to meet people from various points and facets of life, connected merely by our theoretical passion for a book about startup companies. I was wrong. The pre-selection filter that we voluntarily put ourselves through&#8211;our willingness to use a social eating startup, and our interest in a lunch discussing Lean Startup&#8212;resulted in a group of people shockingly similar. Four guys talking about technology is not exactly Earth-shattering. Will I spend future lunch hours eating with strangers from Wednesday.com? To my pride&#8217;s chagrin, yes. While I had brought the wrong expectations, it was a way to take myself out of my usual group of friends and lunch buddies and discover new people to learn from. And if collaborative consumption startups lead me to new experiences and new people, I&#8217;ll ease off the skepticism. Jandrie Lombard, mehmetcan via shutterstock</description>
      <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/04/14/lunching-with-strangers-the-rise-of-social-meals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2012/04/14/lunching-with-strangers-the-rise-of-social-meals/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+TheNextWeb+%28The+Next+Web+All+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Google+ Design: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&amp;#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention. What&amp;#8217;s New This Week? Google+ Introduces a New Look and New Navigation: There&amp;#8217;s a new Google+ interface. These design changes add more white space,</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/new-google-design-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/new-google-design-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On making a ruckus in your industry</title>
      <description>Bring forward a new idea or technology that disrupts and demands a response Change pricing dramatically Redefine a service as a product (or vice versa) Organize the disorganized, connect the disconnected Alter the speed to market radically Change the infrastructure, the rules or the flow of information Give away what used to be expensive and charge for something else Cater to the weird, bypassing the masses Take the lead on ethics (Or you could just wait for someone to tell you what they want you to do)</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/04/on-making-a-ruckus-in-your-industry.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/04/on-making-a-ruckus-in-your-industry.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CEO Bloggers: To Blog or Not to Blog</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s note: Contributor Ashkan Karbasfrooshan is the founder and CEO of WatchMojo, he hosts a show on business and has published books on success. Follow him @ashkan. &#8220;Where do you get the time to write so much as a company CEO, and more importantly, shouldn&#8217;t you be closing deals or doing something more useful?&#8221; Fair enough. Do What Comes Naturally To You Some entrepreneurs are technologists, others are salespeople, a few are storytellers. The best coders don&#8217;t stop coding even if they run the company. The best cooks never stop cooking even when they open their restaurant. Musicians are always jamming no matter what. Similarly, a storyteller doesn&#8217;t put the pen down because he&#8217;s in pursuit of profit, too. He finds a way to marry the two. If you enjoy writing and happen to be the CEO, then it&#8217;s a marriage made in heaven if you can balance your duties. Regardless of your craft, once you&#8217;re an entrepreneur, you&#8217;re the eternal cheerleader, finding yourself shilling one thing or another. It comes with the territory. When it comes to writing articles &#8211; be it on industry publications or on your company/personal blog &#8211; it&#8217;s actually ineffective to come across as a booster. You&#8217;re better off developing your voice as a contrarian that highlights the macro opportunity in a more realistic and sober way. If you can pull that off, writing will pay dividends, but you will have to address the odd doubter who may wonder if you&#8217;re wasting your time writing. The Obvious Reasons for Blogging #1 &#8211; Own Thyself Anthony Robbins put it best when he said: &#8220;We&#8217;re defined by the stories we tell ourselves.&#8221; Indeed, in a world where others&#8217; perception of you is a function of a Google query, you need to own your online presence, especially as we move away from the Algorithm to an increasingly social world. #2 &#8211; Influence, Authority, and Brand Value is driven by goodwill (defined simply as the value of your brand). Brand building is an exercise done through B2B and B2C initiatives. B2B tools include trade advertising, press releases, the conference circuit as well as writing about the industry you&#8217;re in (and as the CEO of a startup, lessons in entrepreneurship and management, as well). You are competing with many others, some of whom the press will be more enamored with. PR is one of the tools in your arsenal to level the playing field. However, the industry&#8217;s three worst-kept secrets are: - Press releases are ineffective and generally viewed as noise. - Blogs are always looking for more content, so they tend to welcome new guest authors. - Traditional industry publications are seeing their resources reduced, so they will rely on social media and writers on blogs more than ever, creating an opportunity for you to land on big name websites. In any case, once they decide to start writing, initially many executives offer their worldview on their company blogs. This is a sound strategy early-on as you test the waters and hone your style and skill. Before long, publishing on your own blog yields diminishing returns as you won&#8217;t cut through the clutter. As you migrate to publishing on third-party sites, you have to invest the time to embrace and learn the sites&#8217; editorial voice. Then, once you clear that hurdle, you face a cynical audience that assumes you&#8217;re merely shilling. To win them over, you need at least three things: impartiality, authority and repetition, but oftentimes to accomplish any success you need to invest way too much time. It certainly is worth it though, in ways you may find surprising. Less Well-Known Benefits of Becoming the Chief Pontificator #3 &#8211; Leave Your Staff Alone The cardinal sin many CEOs make is micromanaging and suffocating talented employees. Worst even, many try to manage what they don&#8217;t understand. This isn&#8217;t always a result of ego or bad faith. True, some CEOs have a tendency to think they are the lord&#8217;s gift to management and their &#8220;hands-on&#8221; experience knows no boundaries and as such they over-extend themselves. But frequently it&#8217;s because they&#8217;re bored. #4 &#8211; Bide your time Everything takes longer than anticipated. You submit a proposal, then wait. You ask one of your lieutenants to work on something, then wait. More often than not, CEOs find themselves waiting even though few would be considered patient. As such, CEOs look for things to focus their attention to. Effective blogging will keeping a CEO busy and avoid him from micromanaging staff and lieutenants, allowing even the best of teams the time and freedom to do their job. Externally, conventional wisdom suggests that you spend all of your time closing deals. But, the fact is: blogging will be the best lead generator you can imagine, and the point isn&#8217;t to sign as many deals as possible, it&#8217;s to sign the right deals under the right terms. Developing a reputation as an industry leader will enable that. #5 &#8211; Efficiency CEOs field the same questions and repeat answers to multiple stakeholders all the time. Verbal communication is undervalued these days, but people don&#8217;t listen, so sending an article that you wrote (and one that was published on a leading and respected publication) is a powerful way to convey the message. Blogging is also far more efficient and effective than attending conferences. As one industry acquaintance once told me, conferences are akin to AA meetings where you sit around and realize everyone else has the same problems you do. Pick an industry, any industry &#8211; chances are that if you compare the speaker and panelists you will find the same people across the board. Writing on a big platform allows you to reach far more people than attending conferences will, and it will save you tens of thousands of dollars. #6 &#8211; Shutting Up The best part of writing so much is that when you meet people, there&#8217;s a good chance they&#8217;ve read your work, so you can shut up and listen, letting others do the talking because you don&#8217;t need to shill and give them your pitch. #7 &#8211; Learn To publish, you not only need to research your topic, but you need to distill a lot of information into a coherent and cohesive argument or summary. But the true learning starts after you press publish and readers chime in via email, in the comments section and on counter-posts. Yes, Writing is Risky (but so is eating shellfish, get over it) A word to the wise: - You want to avoid giving your team the impression that you&#8217;re communicating through [the Word]Press (even when you are). - People will misinterpret you. That&#8217;s their problem, not yours. But be prepared for it. - You can divulge too much (perhaps, but no one really cares about you that much anyway). - Sure, it&#8217;s nice to build your personal brand, but the focus ought to be on the company &#8211; 100% of the time. There are risks, but writing is one way to strike balance against the rigors of entrepreneurship. After all, if you wake up in the morning and are greeted with bad news, don&#8217;t worry too much because you&#8217;re bound to get worst news later on in the day. And if ever you are greeted with some good news, enjoy it cause it won&#8217;t last, something is bound to go awry. That&#8217;s the startup life. It&#8217;s the end result that matters most (while the journey is a learning experience to you, too). Writing gives you the perspective to be able to see through the trees. To quote Steve Jobs, &#8220;you can&#8217;t connect the dots looking forward&#8220;, but provided writing comes naturally to you, then over time you look back and realize why it always made sense. When it&#8217;s said and done, blogging is a means to an end, so long as it helps you accomplish your objectives, keep writing no matter what some may say. Eventually you realize you no longer need to blog. Then, you can put the pen down and step away from the machine, (or not).</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/14/ceo-bloggers-to-blog-or-not-to-blog/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/14/ceo-bloggers-to-blog-or-not-to-blog/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Mistrust: Are Texters Cheaters? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do mobile phones make you suspicious? Do texters have something to hide? That&#8217;s what a couple of recent studies suggest. College students trust text messages less than phone calls, video chats and face-to-face conversation when communicating with their peers. And it may be a case of guilty consciences &#8212; 35% of teens admit to having used their mobile devices to cheat on a test. Nearly one-fifth say they use their phones to take photos of test questions and send them to others, 20% say they search the Internet via cellphone and 26% say they use their devices to store information. This all comes from Online-Education.net, which pulled together separate studies by the University of British Columbia and Common Sense Media to create the below infographic. Check it out to get the full picture of how mobile devices relate to mistrust. Do you feel like texters have something to hide? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of Flickr, real.tingley More About: infographics, MobileFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/mobile-texters-cheaters/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/mobile-texters-cheaters/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Was Apple Meeting with Game Developer Valve? [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Apple CEO Tim Cook might want to consider sneaking around in disguise, because when he was spotted meeting with game developer Valve at the gaming company&#8217;s headquarters, rumors immediately began to fly. What should we make of this? Could Apple be working on a game console to go into its rumored Apple TV? Might Apple want enhanced games for its iOS, making iPhones, iPods and iPads even more game-centric? Is there &#8220;wearable computing&#8221; in the offing for the Cupertino company? Let&#8217;s see if we can get to the bottom of Tim Cook&#8216;s rendezvous &#8212; or at least into the middle of it &#8212; in this video. However, before you watch, we must warn you: Reading the Apple tea leaves always involves guesswork and speculation, so we&#8217;re inviting you to join us in the comments, adding your guesses to those that have already been posited around the echo chamber that is the blogosphere. More About: apple, Gaming, rumorsFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/apple-valve-meeting/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/apple-valve-meeting/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
