<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Surprisingly entertained by http://t.co/FrO3KhwG, probably mostly because the random metrics it chose seemed to consider me quite pleasant.</title>
      <description>Tom Coates: Surprisingly entertained by http://t.co/FrO3KhwG, probably mostly because the random metrics it chose seemed to consider me quite pleasant. &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://Klouchebag.com</link>
      <guid>http://Klouchebag.com</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Klouchebag Site Mocks Klout, Measures Your &#8216;Asshattery&#8217;</title>
      <description>1) Justin Bieber on Klouchebag While Klout measures influence on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and Foursquare to assign its users scores from 0 to 100, Klouchebag calculates "how much of an asshat you are on Twitter." How? Klouchebag judges your tweets based on four criteria: Anger (&#8220;profanity and rage"), Retweets "&#8220;&#8216;please RT&#8217;s, no or constant retweeting, and old-style&#8221;), Social Apps (&#8220;every useless checkin on foursquare or its horrible brethren&#8221;), and English Usage (&#8220;if you use EXCLAMATION MARKS OMG!!! or no capitals at all, this&#8217;ll be quite high&#8221;).Click here to view this gallery. Whether you love or hate Klout, you&#8217;ll get a kick out of Klouchebag. The website went live Friday morning and pokes fun at what Klout is trying to do: gauge online users&#8217; influence across social networks. While Klout measures influence on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and Foursquare to assign its users scores from 0 to 100, Klouchebag calculates &#8220;how much of an asshat you are on Twitter.&#8221; Klouchebag obviously mashes together two familiar words &#8212; Klout and douchebag. The lower your Klouchebag score, the less of a douchebag you are. Two accounts have the perfect asshat score of 100. We won&#8217;t spoil the fun of discovering them for yourself, but if you really want to know quickly, flip through the gallery above to see one and click here to see the other. London native Tom Scott created the site in one day after reading a Wired article about Klout on Thursday that irritated him, he told Mashable shortly after launching the Klouchebag. &#8220;Klout annoys me for the same reason that search engine optimization annoys me &#8212; it&#8217;s an enormous amount of effort designed to game an arbitrary and often-changing system,&#8221; Scott says. &#8220;Imagine if all that time went into actually making interesting things or caring about the people around you.&#8221; To pinpoint your score, Klouchebag judges your tweets based on four criteria: Anger: &#8220;profanity and rage.&#8221; Retweets: &#8220;&#8216;please RT&#8217;s, no or constant retweeting, and old-style.&#8221; Social Apps: &#8220;every useless checkin on foursquare or its horrible brethren.&#8221; English Usage: &#8220;if you use EXCLAMATION MARKS OMG!!! or no capitals at all, this&#8217;ll be quite high.&#8221; If your Klouchebag score is high, don&#8217;t fret. Scott apologizes to you in advance: &#8220;Sorry. Don&#8217;t take it personally. This is about as scientific as Klout&#8217;s own measurements &#8212; which is to say, it&#8217;s pretty much a crapshoot. You&#8217;re probably a lovely person. Although you might want to cut down on the swearing a bit.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Man Hysterically Fails at Explaining Klout to His Boss [VIDEO] Scott initially wanted to name the site Klunt.com, but the domain was already taken. On Klout&#8217;s end, the San Francisco-based startup has had a busy 2012. Just in April, Klout launched brand pages and an iPhone app. More About: humor, klout, online influence, Social Media, trending, Twitter, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/klouchebag-klout-score/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/klouchebag-klout-score/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Space Shuttle Enterprise Hitches 10 Absurd Rides</title>
      <description>Here She Is! Enterprise treats the crowd at John F. Kennedy Airport to a low-and-slow fly-by. Image Credit: Alex FitzpatrickClick here to view this gallery. The Space Shuttle Enterprise arrived at New York&#8217;s John F. Kennedy Airport Friday morning. Mashable was on the scene for a special event celebrating her arrival to New York. Enterprise will temporarily reside at a JFK hangar before being loaded aboard a barge and shipped via the Hudson River to her new home at the Intrepid Sea, Air and Space Museum. As astrophysicist Neil deGrasse Tyson told Mashable, this is a hugely significant event for NASA and New York City. &#8220;New York City will now be the northern-most outpost for NASA,&#8221; he said. SEE ALSO: Spot the Space Shuttle Enterprise With Mashable More About: NASA, space, space shuttle, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/photos-of-space-shuttle-enterprise/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/photos-of-space-shuttle-enterprise/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Projector Lets You Watch TV, Play Games on Any Wall</title>
      <description>The Summer Gadget Series is presented by the Galaxy Nexus from Sprint. Android 4.0, Google Wallet and Google Play make it pure Google. Truly Unlimited data from Sprint makes it unstoppable. Check it out. Product: WowWee Cinemin Slice Pico Projector Price: $429.99 What It&#8217;s Good For: Projecting movies, video games and photos onto your walls, ceilings or even the side of your house. Limitations: You&#8217;ll need to be in a dark place to get the best video quality, and the projector is only capable of displaying images 60 inches in size. Bottom Line: The Cinemin Slice can spice up your traditional movie watching experience, and it lets you show videos from your smartphone, computer or tablet with several people at once in a unique way. Sure, you can watch movies on your couch, but where&#8217;s the fun in that? WowWee&#8217;s Cinemin Slice pico projector lets you display everything from your favorite films to your favorite video games anywhere you have a blank wall. The Slice can display a 60-inch image from up to 10 feet away, so you can use it to show Hulu or Netflix on your bedroom wall or ceiling while you&#8217;re trying to sleep, or use it to play your favorite Xbox game on the side of your house while lounging in the backyard. While the projector produces a bright image, you&#8217;ll need to be somewhere pretty dark to display the best quality. The Cinemin Slice also has a 30-pin Apple connector so you can connect your iPod, iPod touch, iPhone or iPad to play media, as well as a mini-HDMI/AV port for connecting other types of devices and a VGA port for connecting up your laptop. The projector is also plug-and-play, which means you can just connect up your device of choice and start watching videos with no additional software or setup required. Visuals on the machine are pretty solid, but not high definition. Images are displayed at a 854 x 480 resolution, at a 16:9 aspect ratio and 1000:1 contrast ratio. The projector has a manual focus and a 90-degree hinge so you can position it to display video at just the right angle and sharpness. The Cinemin Slice comes with an infrared remote control for changing tracks and adjusting volume. When you&#8217;re watching your video with others, the Slice plays audio through its built-in 6-watt stereo speakers. And for times when you&#8217;re viewing solo, you can use the projector&#8217;s headphone jack to listen privately. The Cinemin Slice is available now at select retailers for around $430. WowWee also manufactures a more portable version of the Cinemin Slice, the Cinemin Swivel, for those on-the-go. Series presented by the Sprint Galaxy Nexus The Summer Gadget Series is presented by the Galaxy Nexus from Sprint. Android 4.0, Google Wallet and Google Play make it pure Google. Truly Unlimited data from Sprint makes it unstoppable. Check it out. More About: features, ipad, iphone, mashable, Movies, pico projector, Summer Gadget Series</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/cinemin-slice/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/cinemin-slice/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This $20 Trillion Rock Could Turn a Startup Into Earth&#8217;s Richest Company</title>
      <description>Meet Amun 3554. Doesn&#8217;t look like much, right? Little more than a mile wide, it&#8217;s one of the smallest M-class (metal-bearing) asteroids yet discovered. Unless it ever decides to smash into us &#8212; a theoretical possibility, but extremely unlikely over the next few centuries &#8212; it will continue orbiting the sun, unknown and unmolested. That is, unless Planetary Resources has its way. Planetary Resources is the asteroid-mining company launched Tuesday in Seattle, with backing from Microsoft and Google billionaires, along with the equally prominent James Cameron and Ross Perot Jr. Its object is to completely dismember poor little rocks like Amun. That&#8217;s because Amun is a goldmine &#8212; well, not gold so much. But it does contain a cool $8 trillion worth of platinum, an essential precious metal used in everything from jewelry to fuel cells to computers (and one that&#8217;s currently trading at the same rate as gold &#8212; $1500 an ounce.) On Earth, only a few hundred tonnes of the stuff are produced every year. The $8 trillion figure is an estimate based on observations by John S. Lewis, professor of planetary science, author of Mining the Sky: Untold Riches from the Asteroids, Comets, and Planets, and now a consultant to Planetary Resources. He also found 3554 Amun to contain another $8 trillion in iron and nickel, and a mere $6 trillion worth of cobalt. So, the total payout from one unassuming asteroid? $20,000,000,000,000. That&#8217;s what got Planetary Resources co-founder Peter Diamandis so excited. &#8220;There are $20 trillion checks up there waiting to be cashed,&#8221; he enthused at a space development conference in 2006. Trillions and Trillions And 3554 Amun is hardly alone; it&#8217;s just one of the few asteroids that has been submitted to rigorous chemical analysis. Another mile-wide Near-Earth Asteroid, known as 1986 DA, is said to contain 100,000 tonnes of platinum and 10,000 tonnes of gold. That&#8217;s worth another couple of trillion. Not too shabby. How many of these mile-wide metal paydays are up there? We have only a vague idea. Nearly 9,000 Near-Earth Asteroids have been discovered so far. Planetary Resources&#8217; best guess is that represents just 1% of the total. That&#8217;s why the company is focusing its efforts on launching space telescopes first; they&#8217;ll do the prospecting, then report back on the lowest-hanging fruit. It&#8217;s not inconceivable that Amun could be worth pennies compared to its compadres. Then the asteroid retrieval and mining process &#8212; all done by robotic spacecraft &#8212; can begin in earnest. Beating Apple with Ease? To become the wealthiest company in the world, Planetary Resources need only capture one rock. Less than that, in fact. Apple, currently the world&#8217;s most valuable company, has a market cap of $500 billion. To match that in resources, let alone market cap, Planetary Resources need only mine one-fortieth of 3554 Amun. Of course, there&#8217;s a catch. You couldn&#8217;t offload all those metals on the world market at once, for fear of crashing their prices. But the company would still own that much in equity, which would allow them to borrow against it. They would be that wealthy, to all intents and purposes. That&#8217;s just how capitalism works. Still, for all this wealth, platinum and gold may not be the most important thing the asteroid miners are hunting. The water on some ice-bound asteroids could count for more in the long run. Not only does it make the existence of life in space that much easier, but it can also be broken down into the perfect rocket fuels: hydrogen and oxygen. The more Planetary Resources starts a gold rush, the more important water in space becomes. No wonder the company is already talking about building a chain of orbital and space-bound refueling stations. Ice from asteroids and comets could be the next oil industry. Check out these interviews with the Planetary Resources team, and let us know in the comments: have they got what it takes to make it? More About: asteroid mining, Asteroids, planetary resources, spaceFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/planetary-resources-asteroid-mining-trillions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/planetary-resources-asteroid-mining-trillions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the 80-Year-Old Grandma on a Quest for 80,000 Twitter Followers</title>
      <description>When the poet Dylan Thomas wrote of growing old, &#8220;do not go gently into that good night,&#8221; it&#8217;s a safe bet he didn&#8217;t have Twitter in mind. But Josephine Lamberti does. The 80-year-old Staten Island grandma is, as her @J_DIMPS Twitter bio puts it, on a quest for &#8220;80K followers (or maybe a million) before I die!&#8221; And she&#8217;s getting close, having already racked up more about 65,000 in less than two years on the network. She&#8217;s become a hit with celebrities, getting retweets and DMs from pop stars and pro athletes alike and becoming something of an online celebrity in her own right. Earlier this year, the NBA player Nate Robinson invited her and her grandson to a game after chatting over Twitter. &#8220;We went and he met us after the game,&#8221; J. Dimps says. &#8220;He wanted to meet me more than I wanted to meet him. It was awesome.&#8221; J. Dimps &#8212; short for dimples &#8212; originally joined Twitter and began her quest for followers with the help of 24-year-old grandson Donny Brandefine. &#8220;Well, it was getting a little boring, so he came over and we tried to figure out something to keep me busy,&#8221; she says. &#8220;We came up with this idea, and it&#8217;s been good.&#8221; Brandefine &#8212; who Dimps calls &#8220;my right arm&#8221; &#8212; says his grandmother has always had a rambunctious personalty and that she&#8217;s taken her online celebrity acquaintances in stride. A list called MyAdoptedGrandchildren contains more than 300 celebrities she&#8217;s interacted with on Twitter or is especially fond of. &#8220;Thats all the big stars she has following her,&#8221; Brandefine says. &#8220;To me its crazy seeing her just sit there like, &#8216;Yeah, Jose Canseco&#8217;s reading me, Rihanna&#8217;s reading me.&#8217; She thinks she&#8217;s a big shot over here!&#8221; Dimps says she remains young at heart, as if her social media presence &#8212; she&#8217;s also on Facebook and YouTube &#8212; wasn&#8217;t proof enough. She Tebows, and she represents the hashtag #OLDladySWAG. What&#8217;s old lady swag mean? &#8220;I&#8217;m really cool, stylish,&#8221; she says. &#8220;Funny. That&#8217;s about it. I really don&#8217;t act my age.&#8221; Dimps says she acts &#8220;maybe 21,&#8221; and her tastes have evolved since she used to ballroom dance at the Palladium concert hall. &#8220;Now I dance to the Rihanna music,&#8221; she says. &#8220;I don&#8217;t do the lindy or things like that no more.&#8221; Despite racking up the Twitter followers, Dimps has managed to keep her followed-by-to-following ratio proper, at about 63,000 to 5,500. So how can you get a follow back from Dimps as she makes her way to 80K? &#8220;If they make me laugh,&#8221; she says, &#8220;I&#8217;ll follow them back.&#8221; Will you help 80-year-old J. Dimps meet her goal of 80,000 followers? Let us know in the comments. More About: TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/grandma-on-a-twitter-quest/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/grandma-on-a-twitter-quest/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung Now the World&#8217;s No. 1 Handset Maker [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Samsung became the world&#8217;s top handset maker by units, ousting Nokia, which had held that title for the past 14 years, according to a researcher. Strategy Analytics estimates that Samsung shipped 93.5 million handsets in the first quarter, besting Nokia&#8217;s 82.7 million. Samsung&#8217;s market share is now 25% vs. Nokia&#8217;s 23%. Nokia had been the world&#8217;s top producer of handsets by units since 1998, when it overtook Motorola. Most troubling number for Nokia perhaps: Sales in China fell 62%. The changing of the guard came as Nokia is in the process of switching over its smartphones to the Windows Phone OS. Nokia told analysts this month that it sold more than 2 million Windows Phone-based units in the first quarter. Windows Phone is still a distant competitor to Apple&#8217;s iOS and Google&#8217;s Android platforms, which controlled 23.8% and 50.9% of the global smartphone market, by units, in the fourth quarter of 2011, according to Gartner. (Gartner hasn&#8217;t released its estimates for Q1 global sales. In 4Q, it pegged Nokia&#8217;s global market share at 23.4% compared to Samsung&#8217;s 19.4%.) Samsung didn&#8217;t forsake profits for the sake of market share. The company posted a $4.5 billion profit in its most-recent quarter, nearly doubling last year&#8217;s figure and beating analysts&#8217; estimates. Though Samsung had a comfortable lead in Q1, it&#8217;s unclear whether the Korean electronics giant will be able to keep its dominance. Tom Kang, a Seoul-based research analyst at Strategy Analytics, told Bloomberg that &#8220;Samsung will probably still be number one in the second quarter, but the full year will be a close call because the third and fourth quarters are traditionally Nokia&#8217;s best.&#8221; Samsung Galaxy Note, Default Lock Screen The Samsung Galaxy Note has a 5-inch screen, positively massive for a smartphone. Note the choice of imagery.Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, itchySan More About: Nokia, samsung, smartphonesFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/samsung-number-one/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/samsung-number-one/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type &#8216;Zerg Rush&#8217; Into Google for a Pleasant Surprise</title>
      <description>Google is giving us another reason to goof off on a Friday with an Easter egg related to the popular game StarCraft. If you type &#8220;Zerg Rush&#8221; into Google, the &#8220;O&#8217;s&#8221; in Google take over the page. If you double click, your cursor turns into a plus sign. Click on the O&#8217;s and you wipe them out. Google then tabulates your score and, in a social media twist, lets you post your score on Google+. For the uninitiated, Zergs are an alien race of insectoids in Blizzard Entertainment&#8217;s StarCraft. In the game you &#8220;rush&#8221; them by amassing your battle units and blitz them. Google&#8217;s motivation for this latest Easter egg is unclear, except perhaps as a way to migrate more users to Google+. Gravity Enter "Google Gravity" in the search bar. Hit "I'm feeling lucky" (if you have Google Instant enabled, it's on the right hand side of the suggested searches). Then watch your world fall down.Click here to view this gallery. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, alija More About: easter eggs, Gaming, Google, StarcraftFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/zerg-rush-google/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/zerg-rush-google/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Translate Draws 200 Million Users Each Month</title>
      <description>Google announced on Thursday that its popular language translator service Google Translate now boasts 200 million monthly users, and many of which are accessing it outside the U.S. and via mobile devices. The news &#8212; which comes just two days before Google Translate&#8217;s sixth anniversary &#8212; shows an increasing desire to communicate with others regardless of language, not only online but offline too. Google Translate allows users to access and interpret webpages on servers thousands of miles away. The company started to offer a basic translating service in 2001 for eight languages and later expanded to more languages in 2003. SEE ALSO: 20 Strange and Hilarious Google Street View Sightings &#8220;But at that time our system was too slow to run as a practical service&#8212;it took us 40 hours and 1,000 machines to translate 1,000 sentences,&#8221; Franz Och, principal scientist at Google, said in a company statement. &#8220;So we focused on speed, and a year later our system could translate a sentence in under a second, and with better quality. In early 2006, we rolled out our first languages: Chinese, then Arabic.&#8221; The service now offers 64 languages, including many with a small web presence such as Bengali, Yiddish and Esperanto. In addition to the 200 million monthly active users on translate.google.com, consumers are also accessing Google Translate in other ways, such as via Chrome, mobile apps and YouTube. More consumers are also accessing Google Translate while traveling than ever before. The company reported its mobile traffic to the service has more than quadrupled year over year. Meanwhile, more than 92% of traffic from Google Translate comes from international users outside the U.S. Usage is so high that it translates the equivalent of 1 million books each day. &#8220;We imagine a future where anyone in the world can consume and share any information, no matter what language it&#8217;s in, and no matter where it pops up,&#8221; Och said. &#8220;We already provide translation for webpages on the fly as you browse in Chrome, text in mobile photos, YouTube video captions, and speech-to-speech &#8220;conversation mode&#8221; on smartphones. We want to knock down the language barrier wherever it trips people up, and we can&#8217;t wait to see what the next six years will bring.&#8221; Thumbnail via iStockphoto, franckreporter. BONUS: 10 Places You&#8217;re Not Allowed to See on Google Maps 1. The Royal Residence, The Netherlands The Royal Palace of Amsterdam in the Netherlands -- called Koninklijk Paleis Amsterdam -- joins a long list of places blurred on Google Maps related to the Dutch royal family, including the Royal Stables and another residence called Huis ten Bosch.Click here to view this gallery. More About: apps, chrome, Google, google translate, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/google-translate-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/google-translate-users/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet @TextInstagram &#8212; Instagram Without Photos</title>
      <description>The sometimes clich&#233; photographs popping up in Instagram feeds have inspired a clever 22-year-old to create Twitter&#8217;s latest parody account. Less than 24 hours ago, Hollywood-based Josh Helfferich launched @TextInstagram, which posts &#8220;your personal Instagram feed in a lightweight text format.&#8221; The account skewers common photography trends exhibited by Instagram users, and it&#8217;s an overnight success, having gone from 400 followers Wednesday at 7 p.m. ET to more than 10,000 followers at noon Thursday. Here&#8217;s a sampling of @TextInstagram&#8217;s first 14 tweets: Feet. &#8212; Text-Only Instagram (@textinstagram) April 25, 2012 Blurry photo of three hot chicks you&#8217;ll never date &#8212; Text-Only Instagram (@textinstagram) April 25, 2012 Tilt-shift fortune cookie &#8212; Text-Only Instagram (@textinstagram) April 26, 2012 Airplane wing as viewed from two seats back &#8212; Text-Only Instagram (@textinstagram) April 26, 2012 &#8220;It&#8217;s been said that the most effective type of humor is that which has at least a little bit of truth to it, and I think people are seeing a little bit of their own feed &#8212; or their own photos &#8212; in the text-only posts,&#8221; Helfferich, a director and producer, told Mashable. &#8220;I mean, I don&#8217;t know too many people who haven&#8217;t Instagrammed a photo of an airplane wing. It&#8217;s the kind of jokes that make you go, &#8216;Ah dammit, that&#8217;s true.&#8217;&#8221; Helfferich, one of the masterminds behind 2011&#8242;s funny &#8220;Facebook Official&#8221; video, doesn&#8217;t hate Instagram. &#8220;Believe it or not, I actually love Instagram. &#8230; I see Instagram as a challenge to create miniature works of art with limited equipment, but there are just some photos that are too easy or too tempting to create with the built-in filters,&#8221; he says. &#8220;I mean, think about it. It&#8217;s a chilly, brisk November morning. The barista hands you an absolutely gorgeous caramel drizzled hazelnut latte with foam in the shape of a heart. How are you not going to Instagram that shit with an Earlybird filter? It&#8217;s irresistible.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Animation Mocks Instagram Fans [VIDEO] The text-only Twitter account coincidentally rolled out on the same day The New York Times reported on the &#8220;Descriptive Camera,&#8221; a prototype gadget that describes photographs in words. And last week, @PicturelessPinterest emerged, applying a similar treatment to Pinterest trends. For now, Helfferich is riding high on his swift success with @TextInstagram. But what&#8217;s next? &#8220;If all goes well, I&#8217;m planning to ask Taylor Swift out on a date,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Let&#8217;s bake sugar cookies!&#8221; What are the most clich&#233; snaps you see infiltrating your Instagram feed? Let us know. BONUS: 20 Witty Reactions to Facebook&#8217;s Acquisition of Instagram Comparing Instagram to Kodak On April 9, Facebook announced plans to acquire popular photo-sharing app Instagram. Earlier this year, 131-year-old film pioneer Kodak filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy.Click here to view this gallery. More About: humor, instagram, parody, photography, spoof, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/textinstagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/textinstagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Mark Cuban Does Business [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Jesse Draper is creator and host of &#8220;The Valley Girl Show&#8221; through which she&#8217;s become a spokesperson for startups and helped pioneer the way of new media content distribution. Formerly a Nickelodeon star, Draper is now CEO of Valley Girl&#8482; where she oversees the show and runs technology blog Lalawag.com. Mark Cuban, the &#8220;Shark&#8221; in Shark Tank, had a giggly time with us while he told us about one of his investments coming out in Walmart later this year: Lipstixx, a lip balm company that changes flavor when you kiss someone. But when Cuban does business, it&#8217;s all about email. &#8220;I&#8217;ve literally invested $4 million in people I&#8217;ve never met,&#8221; he says while explaining his process of investing in people via email as long as they can prove themselves to him, also via email, by answering his tough as nails questions on their business models. SEE ALSO: 5 Things You Didn&#8217;t Know About Mark Cuban It may be all about virtual communication for Mark Cuban when it comes to business, but it&#8217;s definitely about face time when he is on the basketball court. Cuban has been fined over $100,000 by the NBA for various misconducts surrounding the game. &#8220;I&#8217;m just a fan,&#8221; he told us, so we had a little fun and suggested something to help him stay in his seat: duct tape. It&#8217;s certainly cheaper than those fines. Take a look. More Video from The Valley Girl Show 5 Things You Didn&#8217;t Know About Mark Cuban Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg Offers Career Advice Jimmy Wales Shares Wikipedia&#8217;s Growth Story More About: entrepreneurship, mark cuban, sports, trendingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/mark-cuban-business-secrets/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/mark-cuban-business-secrets/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
