<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Former Yahoo COO Who Almost Bought Facebook Shows Up on IPO Day</title>
      <description>Back in 2006, Facebook was only a shadow of the company it would become, tech giant Yahoo was attempting to buy the social network for $1 billion &#8212; and Dan Rosenweig was the man who got Zuckerberg&#8217;s handshake on that offer. Rosenweig the Chief Operating Officer of Yahoo from 2002 to 2007 &#8212; Facebook founder to acquire the company &#8212; an offer which Zuckerberg accepted at first, but declined after Yahoo lowered the price. &#8220;I&#8217;d like to think I was way ahead of the curve of most people, because they only had four million users and zero revenue and I did offer them a billion dollars,&#8221; Rosenweig said during a brief conversation with a group of journalists in the parking lot of Facebook HQ before heading off to a scheduled interview. &#8220;I assure you as ahead of the curve I thought I might have been, I don&#8217;t think anybody would have imagined all of this,&#8221; he said shortly after Facebook&#8217;s stock went up for sale Friday. Zuckerberg reportedly accepted Yahoo&#8217;s $1 billion offer with a handshake. Yahoo&#8217;s stock tumbled shortly after, and the company lowered its offer to $850 million &#8212; an offer which Zuckerberg refused. Yahoo had reportedly separated into two camps on the issue, one that believed in the future of Facebook, and another that thought a $1 billion investment in a network that was currently making no money was unwise. SEE ALSO: Facebook Opens at $42, Valued at $116.6 Billion Rosenweig built a relationship with Zuckerberg during the time Yahoo was considering the acquisition, and impressed him with his forward-thinking. When most people were still thinking about building single applications, Zuckerberg was thinking about building a platform. &#8220;He was talking about a platform before platform was cool,&#8221; says Rosenweig. &#8220;He had a vision for connecting people of all kinds.&#8221; At the time, Facebook was only available to college students &#8212; and only allowed them to connect to students at their own school. &#8220;He had pretty big ambitions, and I think it&#8217;s pretty clear he was way ahead of everybody &#8211;- and still is frankly.&#8221; Rosensweig described Facebook&#8217;s move to Menlo Park as representative of a rebirth in the area. &#8220;When I moved here 10 years ago this building was Sun Micro, and it&#8217;s sort of the changing of guard. Menlo went from Sun Micro, to being sold to Oracle, to now resurrecting it as Facebook.&#8221; SEE ALSO: The Early Hours of Facebook HQ on IPO Day Would Facebook would be following in the footsteps of the building&#8217;s previous tenant 10 years from now and moving out? &#8220;My guess is only if they need a bigger building,&#8221; Rosenweig said. The number of developers growing up today would only help grow companies like Facebook in the future, he added. &#8220;It&#8217;s an absolutely wonderful time to be in Silicon Valley &#8230; A lot more of these companies are generating revenue. A lot more are generating profits. That wasn&#8217;t the case 10 years ago.&#8221; More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, ipo, YahooFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/rosenwig-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/rosenwig-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Branding: It All Began With A Picture</title>
      <description>Your photo speaks volumes about you: make sure those volumes are filled in with your hopes, aspirations, personality and talent and not the result of a haphazard occurrence that you have been too careless to display. Your quality picture will pay off big: and the more visible you are, the higher the return. So get ready to collect.</description>
      <link>http://socialmediatoday.com/danielschawbel/510460/it-all-began-picture</link>
      <guid>http://socialmediatoday.com/danielschawbel/510460/it-all-began-picture</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dan Harmon Poops, HEY, DID I MISS ANYTHING?</title>
      <description>HEY, DID I MISS ANYTHING? - Kids: A few hours ago, I landed in Los Angeles, turned on my phone, and</description>
      <link>http://danharmon.tumblr.com/post/23339272200/hey-did-i-miss-anything</link>
      <guid>http://danharmon.tumblr.com/post/23339272200/hey-did-i-miss-anything</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dan Harmon Poops, HEY, DID I MISS ANYTHING?</title>
      <description>HEY, DID I MISS ANYTHING? - Kids: A few hours ago, I landed in Los Angeles, turned on my phone, and</description>
      <link>http://danharmon.tumblr.com/post/23339272200/hey-did-i-miss-anything</link>
      <guid>http://danharmon.tumblr.com/post/23339272200/hey-did-i-miss-anything</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>101 Ways to Be Healthy - Android Apps on Google Play</title>
      <description>Doco: Instagram for Android is here: http://t.co/XbpfZkBz #instagram #android ^KJL &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instagram.android</link>
      <guid>https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instagram.android</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Hot Startup Tips for Raising a Killer Seed Round</title>
      <description>Mashable&#8217;s new video series, Behind the Launch, follows Vungle on its startup journey toward a June launch. Each week on Mashable, the Vungle team offers tips and lessons learned from its own startup experience. This week, we saw Vungle court big-name investors, so co-founder and CEO Zain Jaffer offers tips for courting investors. Watch the episode above, and be sure to tune in to Behind the Launch every Monday and Wednesday. There are many stories of hot startups raising killer seed rounds, and it can feel like money is flowing everywhere. Times might be good right now, but raising external capital is a complicated process, and it&#8217;s something every entrepreneur needs to think about carefully. Here are tips that can help you achieve your goals as quickly and pain-free as possible. 1. Be Hungry As Steve Jobs said, &#8220;Stay hungry.&#8221; The first thing that will lead you to success in fundraising (and anything in life) is hunger. The moment you get complacent, the game is over. Naturally, most entrepreneurs are hungry because they have little money, but once things start to look good and investors start showing interest, there is a tendency for entrepreneurs to get excited and celebrate prematurely. The deal isn&#8217;t closed until the money hits the bank, so stay hungry. 2. Adjust Your Mindset Change your mindset when thinking about investors &#8212; they are not evil opponents who are out to destroy your business. Instead, think of investors as partners for life, who will continue to back you in subsequent ventures. Changing your perspective will mean you will treat potential investors with respect, and will naturally focus on the value-add they bring beyond just finance. Missed earlier episodes? Watch them here! Ep. 1: Meet Vungle Ep. 2: Bringing in a Closer Ep. 3: How to Court Startup Investors Ep. 4. A Promising, Yet Controversial Job Candidate 3. Have Integrity You need to have integrity in everything you do. When you pitch an investor, make sure you are honest but firm. Investors expect you to learn quickly but don&#8217;t expect you to have all the right answers. So if you&#8217;re asked a question and you don&#8217;t know the answer, don&#8217;t make up something or deflect the question. Investors are quite measured with the questions they ask, and they&#8217;ll quickly detect that you don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;re talking about. 4. Maintain Confidentiality When an investor asks who else you are pitching to, don&#8217;t disclose names without permission &#8212; this puts you in an awkward position. It signals to investors that you can&#8217;t maintain confidentiality, but also harms your negotiating position, as investors may collude in hopes of getting a better deal. 5. Have a Big Vision Investors are mandated to invest in high-growth businesses with multi-billion dollar potential. So make sure you clearly articulate your big vision and where you want to be in the longer term. Nothing turns off investors more than entrepreneurs who think small. 6. Target a Big Market Investors put a lot of focus on funding startups in high-growth and emerging markets. You need to be able show investors that the market you are targeting has the potential to be worth billions of dollars. More importantly, you need to show you understand the key trends that make a market big. It also helps to try and quantify the size of a market &#8212; even though it may seem useless, it will lead you to appreciate the key factors that drive the value of a market. 7. Know How to Frame the Product You&#8217;ll be surprised to find that few investors will test your product (especially at the seed stage), so it&#8217;s important to speak about your product on a higher level. Always stress the benefits about how your product solves a key problem, rather than getting caught up in the details of features. Remember: Investors don&#8217;t invest in features, they invest in real businesses. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Behind the Launch Series, contributor, features, fundraising, investors, mashable, Startups, Tech, VungleFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/startup-investor-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/startup-investor-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Companies That Could Have Been Facebook</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s been a long road for Facebook. What began as an intimate platform has turned into a social networking giant serving more than 900 million users. Facebook may be cashing in on its intial public offering this week, but it wasn&#8217;t the first to introduce the world to online social networking &#8212; many other sites were once recognized as the most popular. What made them fall by the wayside? For some, it was server instability or lack of financial support to hit the ground running. Other formerly popular networks received the necessary monetary backing, but were inhibited by the corporation that had acquired them &#8212; and some went on to morph the company into something broader than just social networking. SEE ALSO: Mark Zuckerberg: Smart or Lucky? [POLL] But perhaps the most important reason why other sites couldn&#8217;t compete with Facebook&#8217;s current growth is timing. Today, the web is stronger, faster and more crowded than ever &#8212; people rely on an Internet connection to communicate, earn revenue and entertain, among many other things. That wasn&#8217;t the case 10 to 20 years ago. Take a look at some of the past social networking kings that existed before Facebook. That&#8217;s not to say all weren&#8217;t successful. Most are still around, but in a different form from which they originated. 1. AOL For many computer users in the mid &#8217;90s, the Internet was AOL. From chat rooms to the ubiqutous AOL Instant Messenger (AIM), AOL was the center of online activity. The company acquired one of the dominant desktop browsers (Netscape), the leading streaming music and MP3 services (WinAmp) and was the king of Web 1.0. SEE ALSO: AOL Founder Warns Zuckerberg: Don&#8217;t Get Distracted by Facebook IPO Then in 2001, AOL acquired Time Warner in its bid to become a media company. The merger was a disaster &#8212; one of the worst in business history. The fallout from the merger prevented AOL from keeping its eye on the evolving nature of technology, including broadband and real-time social channels. AOL tried to compete again in the social space in the mid &#8217;00s, but blunders like 2008&#8242;s $1 billion acquisition prevented success. Today, AOL is known as a media and advertising company and owner of such properties as The Huffington Post. 2. GeoCities GeoCities was originally founded as a web hosting service that let users create communities of homepages on like-minded topics. The pages were hosted by specific &#8220;cities&#8221; &#8212; for example, &#8220;Silicon Valley&#8221; (computers/electronics) or &#8220;Hollywood&#8221; (Entertainment). Near its peak, GeoCities was acquired by Yahoo for $3 billion. New copyright rules upset members and some left in protest. Among other issues, Yahoo was unable to make the site profitable and it was shut down in 2009. 3. SixDegrees.com SixDegrees.com, named after the six degrees of separation concept, was one of the first social networking sites to exist. Users list friends and family, invite external contacts to join, then see if there were connections with other users on the site. At its peak, SixDegrees.com had 1 million members and partnered with NADP. The site simply wasn&#8217;t profitable at the time, and shut down in 2001. It has since been revived, but is only open to former members and those who get an invite. 4. Friendster Friendster was once considered the top online social network. It allowed users to connect, communicate and share online content with other members. Within a few months of launching, it had more than 3 million users. During Friendster&#8217;s peak in 2003, Google offered founder Jonathan Abrams $30 billion, however he chose to be funded by Kleiner, Perkins, Caufield &amp; Byers and Benchmark Capital. The decline is considered one of the biggest blunders in the history of Silicon Valley. The site could hardly keep up with demand, and had trouble serving web pages. It was eclipsed by MySpace in 2004. Friendster shifted in 2011 to focus on its expansion in Asia, and is now a social gaming site. Today, more than 90% of new users are based in Asia, and monthly users have increased by 50%. 5. MySpace In 2003, Tom Anderson, Chris DeWolf and a few other Friendster users saw potential in the site, but felt it was lacking infrastructure. The MySpace team and its resources were supported by eUniverse. The new platform had the programmers it needed as it rapidly grew in popularity. By 2006, MySpace was bought by NewsCorp for $580 million and had 100 million accounts. It peaked in 2007 when it was considered the leading social networking site, valued at $12 billion. The site&#8217;s downfall began in 2008, when Facebook eventually caught up and overtook the Alexa ratings. Among other issues, Myspace struggled with a decline in ad revenue, failure to innovate and Facebook&#8217;s expansive membership to users under 18. The downfall accelerated in 2009, when it lost millions of followers monthly. MySpace was bought for $35 million by advertising network Specific Media, and Justin Timberlake took ownership stake. Recently, Timberlake introduced MySpace TV. The site gained a million new followers in February 2012. 6. Second Life Second Life&#8217;s online virtual world was developed in 2003 by Linden Lab. The service enables users to interact with others, create and trade virtual property, and participate in jobs and activities through an avatar. As of 2011, there were 1 million active users on the site. Though Second Life was not necessarily a direct competitor to Facebook, the site became so popular that people made a living through their avatar. Some quit their jobs and others felt happier in a virtual life instead of reality. Due to Second Life&#8217;s rapid growth rate, its servers struggled with instability. Eventual changes to the terms of service in order to comply with various international laws regulated or banned many Second Life businesses that once thrived. 7. Orkut Orkut was quietly designed by Google in 2004. The social networking site was originally hosted in California, but today it is one of the most popular social networks in Brazil. The site intended to help users connect with new and familiar people. It became popular in Brazil, India and Estonia &#8212; until 2010, when many users in Estonia and India switched over to Facebook. Due to its prominence in Brazil, as well as its legal issues, the company moved its operation and management there to continue business. Today there are 66 million users on orkut. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, blackred More About: aim, aol, Facebook, faceboook ipo, features, friendster, geocities, myspace, orkut, Second Life, Social Media, trendingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/companies-before-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/17/companies-before-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook&#8217;s IPO: Who Got Rich</title>
      <description>Mark Zuckerberg Zuck, who owns 503.6 million shares, is now worth $19.14 billion, though his personal fortune surpassed the $20 billion mark several times.Click here to view this gallery.OK, so Facebook&#8217;s IPO may have seemed like a lot of sound and fury for 23 cents, but there will still doubtlessly be some celebrating in Menlo Park Friday night. That&#8217;s because a lot of Facebookers got fabulously rich on Friday. True, it probably would have been an even more festive occasion if the stock had hit the $54 that Twitter had predicted, but Facebook&#8217;s measly gain on its first day of trading was still worth $115.7 million to Mark Zuckerberg. Here&#8217;s why Zuck and some other big Facebook investors still have cause to pop the Champagne. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, AUDINDesign More About: bono, Facebook, facebook ipo, Greylock partners, mark zuckerberg, sean parker</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-winners/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/18/facebook-winners/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Marketing by the Numbers [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>The number of Americans who own smartphones rocketed past the number who own basic mobile phones this year, and marketers have been expanding their mobile budgets at a similarly rapid rate. One study estimated mobile advertising will be $5.04 billion industry by 2015. HighTable, a startup social website for professionals, compiled data about the key factors in the growing mobile marketing space in the infographic below. More About: infographic, mobile marketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/mobile-marketing-infographic-smartphones/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/mobile-marketing-infographic-smartphones/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Marketing by the Numbers [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>The number of Americans who own smartphones rocketed past the number who own basic mobile phones this year, and marketers have been expanding their mobile budgets at a similarly rapid rate. One study estimated mobile advertising will be $5.04 billion industry by 2015. HighTable, a startup social website for professionals, compiled data about the key factors in the growing mobile marketing space in the infographic below. More About: infographic, mobile marketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/mobile-marketing-infographic-smartphones/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/mobile-marketing-infographic-smartphones/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Facebook IPO Day, Twitter Sentiment Correlated With Share Price</title>
      <description>Twitter users who participated in a crowdsourced prediction for Facebook&#8217;s IPO day closing price collectively missed the mark, but another analysis suggests that changes in Twitter sentiment accurately predicted how Facebook&#8217;s share price turned throughout the day. The crowdsourced prediction was inspired by a tweet from investor Chris Sacca, in which he wondered if a crowd could accurately predict the closing price of Facebook during its first day of trading. Programmer James Proud put up a website called Facebookipodayclosingprice.com to find out. He accepted 2,261 predictions from anyone who wanted to make one. The result? Submissions, solicited mostly via Twitter, predicted on average that Facebook&#8217;s stock price would soar from the opening price of $38 to $54. The reality? Facebook&#8217;s stock gained a measly $0.23 during its first day of trading. Only 26 people correctly predicted that Facebook&#8217;s stock would close at about $38, and crowdsourced predictions unsurprisingly gained no clout as tools for predicting stock prices as a result of the experiment. Another analysis, however, says that Twitter sentiment correlated with how the price turned throughout the day. In an examination of tweets that were published Friday related to the Facebook IPO, Social media data firm DataSift found that every time the volume of negative comments increased, Facebook&#8217;s share price dropped within 20 minutes. Conversely, when positive sentiment increased, the share price rose within a short timeframe. But don&#8217;t start basing your trading decisions on Twitter sentiment just yet. Though the analysis is not the first to find a link between Twitter data and stock price, its authors aren&#8217;t willing to call it any more than &#8220;an interesting correlation between Twitter sentiment and stock price fluctuations.&#8221; Image courtesy of iStockphoto, blackred More About: facebook ipo, TwitterFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/facebook-ipo-twitter-prediction/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/facebook-ipo-twitter-prediction/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China Approves Google&#8217;s Motorola Mobility Deal [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Authorities in China have cleared Google&#8217;s plan to acquire Motorola Mobility for $12.5 billion. If the deal closes, it will be Google&#8217;s first hardware acquisition. It will also give the company access to Motorola&#8217;s treasure trove of 17,000 patents. Chinese regulators attached one big condition to their approval, according to the Associated Press: That Android for mobile devices will remain free for at least five years. Google has also received the go-ahead from Europeon and American authorities to move forward with the acquisition. More About: china, Google, MotorolaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/china-google-motorola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/19/china-google-motorola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
