<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube, Netflix, Facebook Help Double IPv6 Traffic Overnight</title>
      <description>Was World IPv6 Day successful? The effort to prod Internet companies to adopt the newer, beefier IP-address system garnered a lot of attention, but it's still up to companies whether or not to update their systems to the new standard. Still, preliminary data suggest the switch is already well underway -- thanks mainly to Netflix and Facebook. It's no secret that Netflix's streaming service accounts for a huge chunk of Internet traffic as a whole. Streaming video is by far the most bandwidth-intensive activity online, and the company's entire business model is based around it. Facebook consistently competes with Google as the most-visited site on the Internet, and users engage with&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, IPv6, netflix, world ipv6 day, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/ipv6-traffic-netflix/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/ipv6-traffic-netflix/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Logo Looks Like Batman</title>
      <description>What happens if you turn Twitter's newly redesigned bird sideways? A growing number of users think it looks like Batman. Hollywood-based user Josh Helfferich shared the superhero likeness in a tweet Thursday. It immediately went viral, with nearly 1,000 retweets in the hour-and-a-half since it was posted at 3:05 p.m. ET. Actress Alyssa Milano even tweeted it at 6:22 p.m.: So... if you turn the new Twitter logo upside-down, it's Batman. t.co/hJZ0MBYi /via@JoshHelfferich@heykim&#8212; Alyssa Milano (@Alyssa_Milano) June 7, 2012 But Helfferich wasn't alone. A similar image appeared on Reddit earlier Thursday and has been viewed more than 1,600 times. Twitter user @CarlosRHZ t&#8230; Continue reading... More About: batman, humor, Social Media, Twitter, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/new-twitter-bird-batman/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/new-twitter-bird-batman/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-Fleetwood Mac member found dead</title>
      <description>Nashville police say Bob Welch, a former member of Fleetwood Mac who also had a solo career, has died of a self-inflicted gunshot wound. He was 65.</description>
      <link>http://www.miamiherald.com/2012/06/07/2837905/former-fleetwood-mac-member-bob.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.miamiherald.com/2012/06/07/2837905/former-fleetwood-mac-member-bob.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Easy Ways to Grow Earned Media</title>
      <description>Of the three media types you&#8217;ll find in social marketing -- paid, earned and owned -- earned media is the holy grail because it fulfills the unique promise of creating authentic social proof for your brand. Facebook users want to do, see, and buy what they see other users doing, seeing, and buying. In fact, 68% of Facebook users are more likely to buy based on an earned media recommendation from a Facebook friend. There&#8217;s a catch though: You can&#8217;t buy or create earned media directly. Your brand&#8217;s Facebook page will have to organically develop earned media -- likes, shares and comments -- which means you must run marketing campaigns that are optimized for engagement and sharing&#8230; Continue reading... More About: contributors, earned media, features, Media, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/grow-earned-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/grow-earned-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bit.ly Changes Again: URL Shortening Takes One Less Click</title>
      <description>Bit.ly says it has heard its disgruntled users loud and clear and is ready to change its ways -- again. After a backlash last week following a redesign of the site, Bit.ly announced Wednesday it has made some tweaks to make its beloved URL-shortening feature more prominent. Now the box to shorten your link reads "Paste a link here" instead of "Add a bitmark." Once the link is pasted, it's automatically saved. Just click "copy" and you're good to go. That's one step less than the original re-designed version, and more in line with the simplicity that made the site and service a hit. Last week's redesign, the company hoped, would make the site more social. But response from use&#8230; Continue reading... More About: bit.ly, links, URLs</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/bitly/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/bitly/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Likely Far More Than 1.5 Million Passwords Stolen From eHarmony</title>
      <description>The 8 million LinkedIn and eHarmony passwords that were stolen and posted online by a hacker on Wednesday may just be a part of a much longer list of accounts hacked. &#8220;We are 99% confident this is only a partial list of compromised eHarmony passwords,&#8221; a spokesperson from password management firm LastPass told Mashable. A Russian hacker has posted nearly 6.5 million LinkedIn passwords and 1.5 million eHarmony LinkedIn online under the name &#8220;dfdm.&#8221; However, there are some noticeable differences between the two lists that may indicate there could be more compromised eHarmony passwords that haven&#8217;t been posted online. SEE ALSO: How to Check If Your LinkedIn Password Was Stolen | How to Check If Your eHarmony Password Was Compromised &#8220;The difference is that with the eHarmony list, we&#8217;re not seeing the standard &#8216;bad passwords&#8217; &#8212; 12345, password1 and so on,&#8221; the LastPass spokesperson said. &#8220;The LinkedIn list looks full because it has basic passwords as well as stronger ones. However, we&#8217;re seeing only the harder-to-crack passwords pop up on the eHarmony list, so there&#8217;s a strong indication that the hacker leaked those because he needed help with cracking.&#8221; LastPass &#8212; which created a tool for LinkedIn and eHarmony users to check if their passwords are among the compromised &#8212; believes that because cracking hashes (which are associated with passwords) takes time to compute, the hacker is calling on the hacker community to help complete the list. &#8220;At this rate, the remaining list should be cracked in a few days,&#8221; LastPass said. Both sites have become victims of a huge security breach conducted by a Russian hacker who goes by the name &#8220;dwdm&#8221; and posted a list online of the 6.5 million LinkedIn passwords and 1.5 million eHarmony passwords he stole. eHarmony and LinkedIn have both apologized for the security breach and are urging users to change their passwords as soon as possible. More About: eHarmony, hacking, linkedin, security, Social Media, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/eharmony-password-hacking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/eharmony-password-hacking/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Facebook Marketing Mistakes to Avoid</title>
      <description>The Facebook Marketing Series is presented by Webtrends, helping brands acquire, engage, nurture and optimize Facebook fans. Get the Social Media Marketing Playbook, a guide for maximizing returns. Download now. At this point, most people know to market their business on Facebook &#8212; there are more than 900 million people on tge social platform, constantly &#8220;liking,&#8221; sharing, commenting and posting. We&#8217;ve gone over some best practices for Facebook marketing, discussed hot trends and shared customer service tips, so now you know what you should do. But there are a few things that you shouldn&#8217;t do. Mashable spoke with Facebook&#8217;s Communications Manager Elisabeth Diana, Head of Measurement Platform and Standards Sean Bruich and Director of Online Operations Sarah Smith, as well as Buddy Media CEO Michael Lazerow to learn more about the most common Facebook marketing mistakes. &#8220;There&#8217;s actually a science behind this &#8212; yes, it&#8217;s an art, but we have found some strong conclusions that there are levers that marketers can pull to be more successful,&#8221; says Bruich, whose team recently studied 1,200 posts by 23 brands over a month-long period, using quantitative measurements to determine the unique impact of each post. &#8220;This is not a black box &#8230; there&#8217;s a lot of opportunity to understand how to make your marketing better.&#8221; Below, we outline 10 of the most common Facebook marketing mistakes. Have you fallen victim to any of them? Tell us about your experiences in the comments. 1. Not Filling Out the Page Completely This one&#8217;s obvious, but make sure you&#8217;re using Facebook to its full capacity and fill out your Brand Page. Businesses should have hours, address, photos and more on their Brand Pages, so users can gather this information quickly. And if you&#8217;re opening a new location, either list it or (if you decide it&#8217;s best to create separate Brand Pages for your locations) add a new Page to Facebook. Make sure you also nab a good vanity URL &#8212; bonus points if it&#8217;s also your web URL and Twitter handle. 2. Using an Illegal Cover Photo The cover photo is prime real estate on your Facebook Brand Page, and it&#8217;s the first thing consumers notice. Therefore, it ought to abide by Facebook guidelines, which state that a cover photo can not have: Price or purchase information (including discounts, such as &#8220;40% off&#8221;) A call to action to &#8220;like,&#8221; share, comment, download, &#8220;get it now&#8221; or &#8220;tell your friends&#8221; Contact information, such as web, email or mailing address In your cover photo, use something that flaunts your product and captures the essence of your brand &#8212; a close-up of food is great for restaurants, a shot of a runway show is perfect for fashion labels and a diaper company could have a few cute babies. Don&#8217;t forget to switch your photo up every once in a while &#8212; you can refresh your image to promote a new or different product, an upcoming event or a new location. More than half of the brands Buddy Media recently analyzed had only uploaded one cover photo, and another 21% had only uploaded two cover photos. &#8220;Switch it up to keep things fresh,&#8221; Lazerow says. After all, the cover photo is pretty much a billboard on your Facebook Page &#8212; you should use it to promote your best offerings. Just remember to abide by the guidelines above. 3. Breaking Contest Guidelines While it&#8217;s hard to stay on top of the fine print, it&#8217;s imperative that any Facebook contest you run is legal. Contests always add a layer of complexity, as state and federal laws may differ, so here are a few things you need to know: Contests asking for submissions or votes via comments, &#8220;liking&#8221; or other Facebook UI functions are prohibited You as a brand are responsible for the lawful operation of that promotion, including official rules, terms and eligibility requirements Contests or giveaways must be administered within Apps on Facebook.com &#8212; on a Canvas Page or a Page App Your Page must acknowledge that the promotion is not sponsored, endorsed, administered by or associated with Facebook You cannot notify contest winners through Facebook (wall post, message, chat, etc.) There are several third-party providers that help brands run Facebook promotions legally, and most have free trials. A few prominent ones are Wildfire, Offerpop and Buddy Media. Complete Brand Page guidelines for promotions can be found here. 4. Overposting Less is more. Facebook suggests that brands start out with one or two posts a week to feel out the platform and see what works. Many brands post once per day, and many find that posting more than once per day can actually have an adverse effect on engagement. Facebook indicates that the averages user &#8220;likes&#8221; four to six new Pages each month, so your content is constantly fighting for more attention from its fans. It&#8217;s better to post one excellent item per day instead of two decent ones. Even if you&#8217;re only posting a few days per week, you can still keep your Page active on a daily basis. Check your Page and &#8220;like&#8221; or respond to comments on your Brand Page, and remember to tag the people you&#8217;re replying to &#8212; that&#8217;s a great and easy way to get people to come back to your Page to engage more. And it can be easily done with the new Facebook Brand Page Manager app. (Facebook says tagging features are in the works for a later version of the mobile app.) 5. Focusing Too Much on Likes Sure, Likes are important &#8212; the more Likes you have, the more people your message is reaching. But Likes are just step one. Step two is to confirm that you&#8217;re reaching the right audience and keeping them engaged, says Diana. If they &#8220;like,&#8221; comment and share your content in a regular basis, then they have become brand advocates who are pushing your message to their friends. The post above, from the Book of Mormon Facebook Page, shows solid engagement on all counts &#8212; Likes, comments and shares &#8212; thanks to a quirky photo and a clear call to action. It&#8217;s also important to note that content shares better on certain days &#8212; Buddy Media research has found that engagement rates for Facebook posts are 18% higher on Thursday and Fridays. So if you&#8217;re strategic, you can get more engagement with fewer posts. Using the new posting tools, you can queue up the content you want to share throughout the week and then ride the wave of engagement over the next few days. &#8220;Brands that aren&#8217;t paying attention to their own data and when their fans are engaged will not see the reach and engagement they desire,&#8221; says Lazerow. Last year, Buddy Media released a more granular study of industry-specific engagement stats, indicating what days and times of day are best for certain kinds of content, which also can be useful for planning your editorial calendar. 6. Too Much Text Facebook research has shown that posts between 100 and 250 characters &#8212; one or two lines of text &#8212; get 60% more Likes, comments and shares than ones that are more than 250 characters, says Diana. Buddy Media research found a similar trend, determining that posts with 80 characters or less in length have 27% higher engagement rates. The moral? Like content on Twitter, keep it short and sweet. Of course, your post should be different than your content on Twitter, or else your fans don&#8217;t have a reason to follow you on both platforms. One tip for making sure the post is as engaging and short as possible is to remove the link URL from the text field in the post. Once you paste the URL in the field, the page title, a blurb and a thumbnail will populate &#8212; you can then delete the URL to streamline the post and cut the clutter (see above). 7. Posting Boring or Off-Brand Content This might come as a surprise (well, we hope not), but the things you post on Facebook should be relevant to your brand. If you own a company that makes iPhone cases, it doesn&#8217;t make sense for you to post about a Kickstarter project just because you think it&#8217;s cool. Being on-brand is a significant predictor of engagement &#8212; just because people like your product doesn&#8217;t mean they share all of your interests, so just give them a mix of content related to the product. Since your fans don&#8217;t see every single thing you post, you risk wasting their eyeballs on irrelevance and incurring negative engagement on the post. 8. Ignoring Insights Facebook Insights offer a lot of useful information &#8212; it&#8217;d be silly to not take advantage of the data. The Friends of Fans metric is particularly interesting, as Friends of Fans typically represent a much larger set of consumers than a brand&#8217;s Fans. In fact, for the top 1,000 brands on Facebook, the Friends of Fans number is 81 times larger than the fan count, says Bruich. This means there&#8217;s a huge potential audience that can be tapped into by posting engaging content (because your fans&#8217; activity will show up in friends&#8217; feeds) and by enhancing this content with other Facebook ad tools, such as Promoted Posts. Smith says consumers are 51% more likely to buy something if they know their friends did, so capitalize on the army of advocates who have opted in to learning more about your brand. You should also pay attention to the People Talking About This (PTAT) and reach metrics in Insights to see how your message is faring in the Facebook ecosystem, and create a comprehensive Facebook marketing strategy based off of what works. &#8220;That&#8217;s the kind of media plan that&#8217;s going to lead to results,&#8221; says Bruich. In a sense, you can think of your Facebook audience as a focus group and get a grip on what they want to see more of. Also check out the real-time insights, which help you see the impact of pinning, highlighting and promoting posts. 9. Being Vanilla While Timeline transformed Facebook into a much more image-based platform, it&#8217;s important to spice up your content. Too much of anything is boring, and the right mix of polls, questions, photos and video will keep people engaged and excited about your brand. Humans crave diversity, and different kinds of posts drive different kinds of engagement &#8212; so a smattering will lead to more well rounded engagement. For example, someone might comment on a question post, share a photo and &#8220;like&#8221; a video, so it&#8217;s best to give consumers a wide swath of ways to engage with your brand. Pro tip: Asking questions is typically a driver of additional comments. The post above by Coffee Bean is a great example of engagement &#8212; it&#8217;s and image that promotes a live Q&amp;A session on the brand&#8217;s Facebook Page. If your brand is experimenting with video, Diana has an interesting finding to keep in mind &#8212; videos shared from third-party sites (YouTube, Vimeo) generate less organic activity than videos hosted on Facebook. Regardless of what type of post you&#8217;re sharing, make sure the tone and voice reflects the personality of your brand. Virgin America is cheeky, Birchbox is feminine and chatty, MTV is casual and approachable. What&#8217;s your brand&#8217;s voice? A Facebook user should know it&#8217;s your content in their feed without seeing your brand name next to it. 10. Not Making the Most of Facebook&#8217;s Ad Options Not all businesses have the budget to employ Facebook Ads in their marketing arsenal. But brands that do could benefit from Bruich&#8217;s advice about what makes a good ad. He says the ad needs to be well branded. If it&#8217;s not clear and obvious who and what the ad is promoting, then consumers will be less likely to recall the ad and the brand. It&#8217;s also important to have some sort of reward or &#8220;payoff,&#8221; as ads with a reward tend to be more influential over purchasing decisions. Also, try to have the creative in the ad have one focal point &#8212; with everything else happening on Facebook, a focused creative unit helps fans recall ads. Can&#8217;t figure out what your ad should be? Dig into Facebook Insights and turn the most engaging content into a social ad. &#8220;Your content and ads are one and the same,&#8221; says Lazerow. You can give your recent content an added boost with Promoted Posts, which extend the reach of your post and are easy to do. Sweet Cheeks Diaper Company, a brick-and-mortar and online store in Maine, saw a 49x return (tracked via the unique URL) after promoting a photo on its Brand Page, says Diana. Conclusion Facebook marketing is a crucial way to build a fan base and spread word about your business. But a successful campaign doesn&#8217;t have to be a drain on your time or your wallet. A few minutes a day and a strategic plan can have an immense impact on your brand&#8217;s Facebook presence, as long as you avoid the mistakes above. If you&#8217;re a newbie to Facebook marketing, you can check out a Facebook webinar at facebook.com/classroom. If you&#8217;re more experienced and have a specific question about your Facebook campaign, Facebook encourages you to call 1-800-916-1300. For more information on Facebook Brand Page management, you can go straight to Facebook. Series presented by Webtrends The Facebook Marketing Series is presented by Webtrends. With 850 million fans, Facebook is a marketer&#8217;s dream. Yet many brands are not seeing expected results. With the right tools and a four-step plan, Facebook campaigns can be measured, tested, targeted and optimized with remarkable results. Webtrends shows you how in this step-by-step guide. Get the Social Media Marketing Playbook Now. More About: branding, Facebook, facebook marketing, Facebook Marketing Series, features, Marketing, mashableFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/facebook-marketing-mistakes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/facebook-marketing-mistakes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Check If Your LinkedIn Password Was Stolen</title>
      <description>Worried that your LinkedIn password may be a part of the nearly 6.5 million compromised on Wednesday? Password management firm LastPass has released a secure tool to see if your password was among the stolen. News first surfaced about the security breach after a Russian hacker said he stole 6,458,020 encrypted LinkedIn passwords and posted them online (without usernames) to prove his feat. The breach comes on the heels of news that LinkedIn&#8217;s iOS app potentially violates user privacy by sending detailed calendar entries to its servers. LinkedIn confirmed that some passwords had become compromised and said it would contact affected users with details on how to change their password. Although usernames associated with the passwords were not released, the passwords themselves will surely be used to help reverse-engineer other cryptography systems. We also expect to see these passwords added to dictionary lists of programs that attempt to break into various accounts. In other words &#8212; if you&#8217;re a LinkedIn user, no matter how strong your password seemed &#8212; it&#8217;s a good idea to go ahead and change it. How This Works If you&#8217;re a cynical web user when it comes to privacy and security &#8218;&#196;&#238; of course you are, right? &#8218;&#196;&#238; then you&#8217;re probably asking yourself whether or not a site where you type in your password to see if it&#8217;s been compromised could possibly be legit. But the folks at LastPass ensure that the tool is safe and does not store passwords. Here&#8217;s how it works: After typing your LinkedIn password into LastPass&#8217;s tool, the service computes its SHA-1 hash and sends the result to LastPass.com. It then searches the list of 6.5 million leaked password hashes. &#8220;All that&#8217;s communicated to LastPass is the hash &#8218;&#196;&#238; the result of the one-way function performed on the password that a user enters in that box,&#8221; a LastPass spokesperson told Mashable. &#8220;So let&#8217;s say you enter &#8216;password1.&#8217; You enter it and the tool performs the hashing algorithm. The hash is then sent to LastPass, and if a match is found in the database (of the 6.46 million leaked hashes) on our end, we report back a message saying that your password was compromised.&#8221; The spokesperson also noted that the hashes are not stored on its servers: &#8220;We don&#8217;t store the hash on our end. We only perform the check and then delete it.&#8221; Brooklyn developer Chris Shiflett created a near-identical tool called LeakedIn that appears to operate in the exact same way. On his blog, Shiflett discussed how he built the tool to find out his own password was leaked (and subsequently cracked). Change Your Password If your password is among the millions stolen, you should not only change it as soon as possible but also update other accounts you have that use the same password. If you aren&#8217;t already using a password management tool &#8212; it&#8217;s time to start considering one. Tools such as LastPass and 1Password are invaluable in helping users create and manage unique, secure passwords. Has your password been compromised? Let us know in the comments. Christina Warren contributed to the reporting on this story. More About: LastPass, linkedin, password management, securityFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/06/linkedin-password-check/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/06/linkedin-password-check/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIM Ends 16 GB BlackBerry PlayBook Tablet</title>
      <description>RIM has stopped making the 16 GB version of its PlayBook tablet, Engadget has learned. The 32 GB and 64 GB models will remain available. The report was backed up by the following statement from RIM: RIM will no longer be making the 16 GB model of the BlackBerry PlayBook tablet. The 16 GB PlayBook will continue to be available for distributors and retailers while quantities last. We continue to remain committed to the tablet space and the 32 GB and 64 GB models of the BlackBerry PlayBook continue to be available from our distributors and retailers around the world. There is more value for our customers in the higher capacity models (32 GB, 64 GB), and as such we have decided to focus our efforts here. The news doesn't come as a huge surprise. The PlayBook was trashed by reviewers when it launched more than a year ago. Sales were so bad that RIM had to drop the price several times. It also took RIM about 10 months to issue an update that allowed the PlayBook to access email and calendars. Click here to see the latest software update to the PlayBook. Please follow SAI: Tools on Twitter and Facebook.Join the conversation about this story &#187;</description>
      <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/rim-just-killed-the-16-gb-playbook-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.businessinsider.com/rim-just-killed-the-16-gb-playbook-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Link Building Tools to Boost Your Traffic</title>
      <description>Matt Beswick is Technical Director at Electric Dialogue &#8212; a London based digital agency. He&#8217;s also the co-founder of Pet365. Follow him @mattbeswick. Link building is a concept that anyone involved in online marketing will come across and, more than likely, be involved in. The principle is simple &#8212; get high quality, relevant sites to link to your own. In doing so you not only generating traffic from visitors clicking through but also give search engines an indication as to the importance of your site. In effect a link is like a vote; the more high-quality votes you get the higher you&#8217;ll show up in search rankings. Fortunately, there are many link-building tools. These can roughly be split into two camps: Those that help with the data and analysis side of things, and those that focus more on speeding up the process of building relationships with other site owners. So how does someone decide which tool best suits their needs? I tested six of the most popular link-building tools over the last few months to figure out the pros and cons of each. Here&#8217;s what you need to know. 1. Ontolo Ontolo is a powerful, sometimes complex, tool that can work wonders for someone who knows how to use it. For link prospecting it&#8217;s pretty much unparalleled but search phrases have to be pretty specific. A search phrase essentially tells Ontolo what kind of sites to search for so if you enter something too generic, you may end up with hundreds of generic results. In other words, this is not for the beginner link builder. If anything it&#8217;s better suited for larger companies or seo agencies who have someone dedicated to this kind of work. Pros: + Extremely Powerful + Lots of customization + Allows end-to-end workflow management Cons: - Steep learning curve - Can result in too much data Cost: Starts at $97 per month Value for the Money: For those looking to generate and analyze hundreds (or thousands) of prospects, there&#8217;s no better option. 2. BuzzStream One of the most difficult and time-consuming parts of link building is contacting other site owners for permission to link. This is where BuzzStream comes in. This tool allows you to create your own database of possible link-building sites, lets you assign them to a team member, and then offers options for touching base with site owners. It sounds simple but when you&#8217;re trying to contact hundreds of site owners it gets very complicated very quickly, which is why a tool like this comes in handy. My favorite thing about BuzzStream is the &#8216;bookmarklet&#8217; &#8212; a button that you add to your browser&#8217;s toolbar, which allows you to add any site that you&#8217;re currently visiting with just a couple of clicks. As an added bonus, BuzzStream automatically tries to find the name, email address, and social media profiles of the site you bookmark. BuzzStream also makes it really easy to categorize sites with tags, assign their status (such as &#8216;attempting to contact&#8217; or &#8216;link accepted&#8217;), and even allows you to link up an email account. By doing so you never have to leave the tool, and could even have multiple team members contact different sites using your name and email address. My only criticism of this tool is that it&#8217;s a little hard to navigate. The features are fantastic but many are inexplicably hidden away, meaning that you have to hunt through blog posts and help files to get the most out of it. Be patient though because once you work BuzzStream out there&#8217;s definitely no looking back. Pros: + Massive time saver + Great for team collaboration Cons: - Not very intuitive - Poorly organized help files Cost: Starts at $29 per month Value for the Money: The time you&#8217;ll save in sending emails alone makes BuzzStream excellent value for money, particularly for those working as part of a team. 3. OpenSiteExplorer Rand Fishkin&#8217;s SEOMoz is a very well-known name in the SEO industry with a reputation for delivering high-quality, easy-to-use tools. The program&#8217;s competitor analysis option gives you an easy way to look at and understand what competitors are doing to increase their rankings. This is done by giving you a list of metrics such as inbound links to a page or site, their anchor text, and &#8216;Domain Authority&#8217; (which is a score out of 100 as to the relative power of a domain). It&#8217;s not an end-to-end solution, but does have the ability to export your data to a CSV file. This will contain the raw information on a site or page, as mentioned above, which you can then open as a spreadsheet to work from. An example of this would be to pick your top competitor, find all of their links, export them, and then look to replicate what they&#8217;ve done to build those links. Paid members also get access to the SEOMoz campaign tools, the q&amp;a section, and PRO Perks which give you discounts on a number of different services. Pros: + Very easy to use + Great depth of data + Simple export options Cons: - Only updates once per month - No workflow management Cost: Starts at $99 per month Value for the Money: OpenSiteExplorer and the SEOMoz campaign tools are absolutely fantastic but the added benefits of the community really can&#8217;t be underestimated. 4. Raven Raven&#8217;s suite of SEO tools covers everything from on-page analysis to social media monitoring and link building. The thing that stands out here is the sheer size and scope of the available options which, similarly to Ontolo, can be a little overwhelming at first. The basic UI is reasonably easy to learn, although some of the more advanced features do take a while to get used to. One of the perks of Raven is that it integrates with a number of external services (such as TextBroker and Basecamp) while still retaining a very high standard when it comes to internal features. The link prospecting, monitoring, and acquisition tools are simply fantastic. Also, the recently upgraded CRM section makes it far easier for team collaboration, and there are some more of these types of additions on the way, but It would be great to have the ability to send emails from inside the tool. If that was added then you&#8217;d be hard pushed to find the need to spend money elsewhere. Pros: + Huge range of features + Link monitoring and management + Integrates with Basecamp and TextBroker Cons: - Navigation takes a while to get used to - No internal outreach functionality Cost: Starts at $99 per month Value for the Money: Of all the SEO tools out there, Raven gives you the best value for the money. You get unlimited sites, a wealth of features, and an easy way to buy additional usage as you need it. 5. Citation Labs Originally involved in getting Ontolo up and running, Garrett French has since moved on to start Citation Labs. As a link builder, one of the most time-consuming tasks is to find top quality sites that are both relevant and likely to link to you &#8212; something that Citation Labs makes far easier than any of the other tools that I&#8217;ve come across so far. Simply choose the type of link or site that you&#8217;re looking for, enter a few relevant phrases, and wait for the software to generate your report. You&#8217;ll end up with an exportable, filtered list of sites that are relevant to the terms that you used in your search. My advice from here is to integrate them into your link-building workflow by importing into the likes of Raven or BuzzStream. Pros: + Ridiculously easy to get started + Inexpensive + Returns quality sites Cons: - Prospecting phrases take a while to master - You only get a single report as a freebie! Cost: From $27 per month or $2 per report Value for the Money: The link prospector is extremely well priced. Plus it offers both subscription and pay-as-you go options. 6. Whitespark Showing up at the top of specific search results can be a life-changing event for a local business, which is where Whitespark is aiming to help. Their local citation tool offers an easy solution to finding potential link partners at a local level. Simply enter your location and type of business, fine-tune the search phrase, and that&#8217;s it. Just a few seconds later you&#8217;ll have a list of potential link targets. Although not as advanced as the likes of BuzzStream or Raven there is a basic management tool included with each report which lets you mark each possible link as &#8216;got it!&#8217; or &#8216;useless&#8217;. It also includes a clickable link to the submission page which is a massive time saver. Pros + Simple but effective + Very easy to use + Deceptively powerful Cons - Sometimes returns poor quality sites Cost: From $20 per month Value for the Money: If you&#8217;re a local business looking to give your link-building efforts a boost then $20 per month for Whitespark&#8217;s tool would be a great investment. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, pagadesign More About: contributor, features, linking, search engine optimization, SEOFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/link-building-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/link-building-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech-Savvy Seniors: Half of U.S. Adults Over 65 Are Online</title>
      <description>For the first time ever, more than half of U.S. adults over the age of 65 are online, from surfing the web to checking email, a new study suggests. A report by the Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project found that 53% of seniors use the Internet. Although this demographic is still less likely to go online than younger age groups, it shows that this segment of the population is flocking to the web more than ever before. In total, about 82% of all online Americans over age 18 access the Internet each day, while some 70% of seniors say they go online every day, as well. But Internet usage tends to drop off after age 75, the report said. Only 34% of adults over 75 access the Interne&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, Pew, Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project, Social Media, social networking, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/senior-adults-online/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/senior-adults-online/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionary Paper Scanner Folds Flat, Costs $15 on Kickstarter</title>
      <description>This portable smartphone-enabled scanner is on the verge of changing how we work. The Scanbox on Kickstarter is a foldable scanner that's easy to put together and snaps in place with magnetic buttons. The scanner, made from a high-quality laminated card, works with most smartphones with a back-facing camera. The Scanbox can digitize full-size documents and anything that fits into its dock. Watch the video above to see how the scanner works. The Scanbox has been 702% funded with 31 more days left on the crowdsourced funding platform. Backers can receive the scanner with a $15+ donation. The scanner will go into production once its Kickstarter de&#8230; Continue reading... More About: kickstarter, Tech, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/scanbox-scanner-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/scanbox-scanner-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
