<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU</title>
      <description>Tom Murphy: Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Erik reliving his youth at @thelandofnod space #fallpreview http://t.co/KfiY43zp</title>
      <description>Crate and Barrel: Erik reliving his youth at @thelandofnod space #fallpreview http://t.co/KfiY43zp &#9733; Retweeted by The Land of Nod Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KdN4Ytsvy4/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KdN4Ytsvy4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX</title>
      <description>Scary Mommy: I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yummy catering :) http://t.co/vYGJlLSz</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Yummy catering :) http://t.co/vYGJlLSz &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KcoPEElgMR/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KcoPEElgMR/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Rolls Out File-Sharing for All Groups [EXCLUSIVE]</title>
      <description>Could Facebook become the next Dropbox &#8212; or a haven for sharing files without regard to copyright? The social network has revealed to Mashable that all Groups will now include the ability to send files. This update rolls out to a small percentage of groups Thursday, and will become available to others during the following days. If you don&#8217;t have the feature already, Facebook wants you to know you&#8217;ll have it &#8220;soon.&#8221; Facebook Groups for Schools, launched last month, incorporated the file-sharing feature &#8212; but you needed a .edu address to use it. Users can upload most file types up to 25MB &#8212; the same file size limit as Gmail. The exceptions: music files (sorry, old-school Napster fans) and executable (.exe) files (sorry, hackers). But e-books, comics, music videos and other small movies are fair game. To prevent the spread of malicious, inappropriate or copyrighted files, &#8220;users can report files the same way they can with other content across the site,&#8221; a Facebook spokesperson said. Whether a group that wants to share such things will willingly turn itself in remains to be seen. More than 380 million people use Facebook Groups. Being able to share files was one of the most common requests from groups users, the spokesperson said. This is how the new file sharing feature will look: In October 2010, Facebook acquired simple file sharing service drop.io. Unlike Adobe Connect or Dropbox, users did not have to register to use the site. They could simply upload a file, create a &#8220;drop&#8221; with links to files and share it with others. Drop.io also had free conference call service &#8212; so perhaps Facebook can incorporate this technology into its file sharing feature. Do you use Facebook Groups? What do you think about this latest feature? Sound off in the comments. Christina Warren contributed to this report. More About: Facebook, Social Media, social networkingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/facebook-groups-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/facebook-groups-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Out, Google: Bing Nabs 30% of Search Market [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Microsoft&#8217;s search engine Bing now accounts for 30% of U.S. web searches, according to a Experian Hitwise report. Bing-powered queries &#8212; made up of searches from Bing.com and Bing-powered searches on Yahoo and the websites of other notable partners &#8212; accounted for 30.01% of searches in April, according to the Hitwise report. Bing-powered searches rose 5% and Bing.com searches rose 6% month-over-month, respectively. The number of Google searches dropped 3% from the month previous and 11% from the same period in 2011, accounting for 64.42% of U.S. searches in April. Bing-powered search, on the other hand, gained 11% in year-over-year percentages. Bing, the second most popular search engine in the U.S., unveiled plans for a website redesign this week &#8212; aiming to make search more social. The new social search will compete with Google&#8217;s Search Plus Your World update. Google&#8217;s integration of Google+ data into its search engine was unveiled in January. SEE ALSO: Bing Reinvents Social Search and Discovery Microsoft says the Bing update will introduce &#8220;a better way to search.&#8221; The update will incorporate personal search results into the search engine&#8217;s algorithm. The results will appear in a panel on the side of the page. This includes which &#8220;friends might know,&#8221; &#8220;people who know,&#8221; and related activity recently on Facebook. Microsoft announced updates would come slowly. Do you think Bing&#8217;s new redesign will help the Microsoft search engine catch up to Google? Tell us in the comments if you would consider switching to Bing. More About: bing, Experian Hitwise, Google, YahooFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/bing-google-search/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/bing-google-search/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prince Charles reads BBC weather</title>
      <description>Prince Charles has a go at reading the weather during a tour of BBC Scotland's Pacific Quay headquarters.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-18022243</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-18022243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You always knew "Perfect Strangers" would make a great video game. http://t.co/kgETKri7</title>
      <description>UrbanDaddy: You always knew "Perfect Strangers" would make a great video game. http://t.co/kgETKri7 &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://nothingsgonnastopmenow.com/</link>
      <guid>http://nothingsgonnastopmenow.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BREAKING: Joe Biden Endorses Same-Sex Marriage</title>
      <description>Vice President Joe Biden has endorsed same-sex marriage, becoming the highest ranking American official to back marriage for gay and lesbian people. His comments signify a split within the Obama administration and may pave the way for President Obama &#8212; who says he supports civil unions and is still evolving on the matter &#8212; to also embrace equality. Biden made his remarks during an appearance on Meet the Press, telling host David Gregory that he is &#8220;absolute comfortable with the fact that men marrying men, women marrying women.&#8221; He added, however, that &#8220;the President sets the policy.&#8221; Biden has backed equal rights for the LGBT community throughout his career, but this is the first time he has publicly acknowledged his support of full marriage rights. In December of 2010, Biden predicted, &#8220;I think the country&#8217;s evolving and I think there&#8217;s an inevitability for a national consensus on gay marriage.&#8221; But when asked if he supports gay marriage during the 2008 Vice Presidential debate Biden was far more circumspect, saying, &#8220;No. Barack Obama nor I support redefining from a civil side what constitutes marriage. We do not support that.&#8221; He even sought common ground with Sarah Palin on the issue and noted that both believe that &#8220;there should be no civil rights distinction, none whastsoever between a committed gay couple and a committed heterosexual couple.&#8221; Since that performance, the administration has touted its accomplishments on behalf of the LGBT community &#8212; from the repeal of Don&#8217;t Ask, Don&#8217;t Tell to its refusal to defend the 1996 Defense of Marriage Act. Yet Biden&#8217;s support for marriage could solidify the support of the LGBT community &#8212; many of whom have recently expressed outrage over Obama&#8217;s unwillingness to issue an executive order prohibiting employment discrimination in federal contracting &#8212; just ahead of the 2012 election. Obama first told blogger Joe Sudbay that &#8220;attitudes evolve [on marriage equality] including mine&#8221; in October of 2010 and the administration last commented on his position during a press gaggle on March 30, 2012. &#8220;I don&#8217;t anticipate that the President would make news on [marriage equality],&#8221; Press Deputy Josh Earnest told a reporter en route to Burlington, Vermont when asked about Obama&#8217;s &#8220;evolving position.&#8221; Gay and lesbian couples can wed in six states and the District of Columbia. Washington and Maryland both passed same-sex marriage laws in 2012, but they are currently being challenged by voter referenda.</description>
      <link>http://thinkprogress.org/lgbt/2012/05/06/478786/biden-marriage/?mobile=nc</link>
      <guid>http://thinkprogress.org/lgbt/2012/05/06/478786/biden-marriage/?mobile=nc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[from heyjude] Know and show what you got! - TwentyFeet - TwentyFeet Wiki</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; The performance post for twitter is a cool way to recap your last week for your followers and friends. &lt;p&gt; It's for free. You can do that with your "forever free" twitter account. It contains the changes in your key twitter metrics. We will only post positive changes (e.g. a growing number of followers). The "My week on twitter"-post is published at the beginning of the week automatically (only for authorized accounts and if you choose so).</description>
      <link>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</link>
      <guid>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Drops 4G Branding From New iPad</title>
      <description>Apple is changing the way it&#8217;s marketing the iPad + 4G, dropping the 4G altogether and replacing it with the word &#8220;cellular.&#8221; The move comes after complaints from an Australian competition regulator. While Apple was marketing the tablet as &#8220;4G&#8221; in the country, it currently cannot connect to Australia&#8217;s 4G network or the 4G networks in other countries outside of the U.S. Due to that fact, regulators felt Apple was misleading Australian customers about the device&#8217;s possible data speeds. While much of the iPad&#8217;s website marketing &#8212; at least here in the U.S &#8212; still has the the 4G LTE designation, when it comes time to buy the tablet in the store, you&#8217;re now given the option to purchase just a &#8220;Wi-Fi&#8221; version, or a &#8220;Wi-Fi + Cellular&#8221; model. While the term &#8220;4G&#8221; does refer to the data speed a device can achieve, it simply means that it can connect to a 4th-generation data network faster than its 3G predecessor. In the U.S., many device manufacturers use the &#8220;4G&#8221; label on devices that are not capable of data speeds as fast as some of their 4G competition. SEE ALSO: What is 4G? An FAQ on Next Generation Wireless One example is Apple&#8217;s iPhone 4S on AT&amp;T, which now has a 4G designation, although according to the International Telecommunications Union the network the iPhone specifically runs on (HSDPA) is not a fourth-generation network. It&#8217;s more like 3.5G. The new iPad is currently only capable of connecting to five true 4G networks, all of which are located in the U.S. or Canada. [via 9to5 Mac] More About: 4G, apple, ipad, LTE</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/13/ipad-4g/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/13/ipad-4g/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
