<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Video: Watney 'settles the score' with Doral</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502#42063502"&gt;&lt;img align="left" border="0" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/NBCSports/Components/Video/_NEW/s_nbc_glf_wgccadillacwatneyintv_110313_4x3.thumb.jpg" alt="March 13: Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)" style="margin:0 5px 5px 0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;</description>
      <link>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</link>
      <guid>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Glass: One day... - YouTube</title>
      <description>We believe technology should work for you &#8212; to be there when you need it and get out of your way when you don't. A team within our Google[x] group started Pr...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=9c6W4CCU9M4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24,000 stranded waiting for help...</title>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;font size="3" color="black"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;24,000 stranded waiting for help&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font face="Arial" size="1"&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Second column, 3rd story, &lt;a href="http://www3.nhk.or.jp/daily/english/14_07.html"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;hr style="height: 1px; border-style: none; color: #666666; background-color: #666666;"/&gt;&lt;font face="Arial" size="2"&gt;Related stories:&lt;div class="related-links" id="R:C2:S3"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-pacific-12725646"&gt;Shocking new footage of moment tsunami hit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/mar/13/japan-tsunami-survivor-shinkawa-rescued-fukushima"&gt;Survivor found clinging to ripped-off rooftop 10 miles out to sea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6e4396a0-4d83-11e0-85e4-00144feab49a.html"&gt;400,000 homeless bed down without electricity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.timeslive.co.za/world/article965229.ece/Japanese-volcano-erupts"&gt;Volcano erupts, sends ash two miles into sky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.smh.com.au/environment/monster-aftershock-could-strike-within-days-20110313-1bt2p.html"&gt;SEISMOLOGISTS: Monster aftershock could strike within days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ibtimes.com/articles/122028/20110312/japan.htm"&gt;MASSIVE BLACKOUTS WARNED&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ajc.com/news/nation-world/japan-pmr-quake-crisis-869316.html"&gt;PM calls to build 'New Japan'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.channelnewsasia.com/stories/afp_asiapacific/view/1116155/1/.html"&gt;Deploys 100,000 troops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/asiapcf/03/13/world.quake.response/"&gt;US WARSHIPS OFF JAPAN COAST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/z5q8vs0nyQJ7HQobBHaqdSlIcjo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/z5q8vs0nyQJ7HQobBHaqdSlIcjo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/z5q8vs0nyQJ7HQobBHaqdSlIcjo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/z5q8vs0nyQJ7HQobBHaqdSlIcjo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=p71t2VLLipY:z6CDXWRnYzc:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=p71t2VLLipY:z6CDXWRnYzc:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?i=p71t2VLLipY:z6CDXWRnYzc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=p71t2VLLipY:z6CDXWRnYzc:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?a=p71t2VLLipY:z6CDXWRnYzc:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/DrudgeReportFeed?i=p71t2VLLipY:z6CDXWRnYzc:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DrudgeReportFeed/~4/p71t2VLLipY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www3.nhk.or.jp/daily/english/14_07.html</link>
      <guid>http://www3.nhk.or.jp/daily/english/14_07.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rob Pike: Dennis Ritchie has died</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3105505"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <link>https://accounts.google.com/ServiceLogin?service=profiles&amp;passive=1209600&amp;hl=en</link>
      <guid>https://accounts.google.com/ServiceLogin?service=profiles&amp;passive=1209600&amp;hl=en</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions of Americans Cut the TV Cord [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Users aren&#8217;t completely ditching pay-TV subscriptions, but a new report says 3.58 million people in the U.S. will have cut the TV cord by the end of 2012. A report entitled &#8220;The Battle for the North American Couch Potato: Online &amp; Traditional TV and Movie Distribution&#8221; [PDF] is just one indicator that paid online streaming TV and movie services are growing and pay-TV subscriptions are slowing. From 2008 to 2011, the Convergence Consulting Group estimates 2.65 million &#8212; 2.6% of the U.S. population &#8212; ended their pay-TV subscriptions and replaced them with online streaming services such as Netflix. More than 40% of U.S. pay-TV subscribers became non-subscribers by dropping their service in 2011. According to the report, Canadian TV services have seen a slower bleed &#8212; about 83,000 Canadians, or .7%, dropped their pay-TV subscriptions in 2011 to watch online subscription services. Compared to 2010, U.S. TV services added 160,000 fewer subscribers in 2011. The number dropped from 272,000 in 2010 to 112,000 in 2011. Convergence Consulting estimates 185,000 people will start new TV subscriptions in 2012. SEE ALSO: We Now Watch Less Live TV, But More Programming Thanks to DVRs [STUDY] &#8220;Kiosk, mail and now streaming rental (assuming sufficient usage) offer a lower-price value proposition and have radically altered the rental channel while negatively impacting DVD/Blu-ray/Download sales, and encroaching on TV subscription,&#8221; the report said. Online TV watching is expected to increase in 2012 and years to come. In 2011, about 18% of U.S. broadcast specialty-network viewers watched an average of one to two shows online per week &#8212; an increase from 16% in 2010. Advertisers are following their viewers onto the web. The research firm says online ad revenue is increasing. Broadcast and cable network&#8217;s online TV advertising revenues reached $1.9 billion, or 2.8% of U.S. Broadcast/Cable Network TV advertising revenue, in 2011. Online TV network&#8217;s ad revenue is expected to climb 3% in 2012, Convergence Consulting estimates. Which do you prefer to use: TV subscriptions or online subscriptions? Tell us in the comments. More About: cord cutting, netflix, online tv, TV, TV AdFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/cut-the-tv-cord/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/cut-the-tv-cord/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think Hockey '09: The Secret to Winning Puck Battles</title>
      <description>&lt;a href=http://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.cbc.ca/video/%23/Sports/CBC%27s%2520Hockey%2520Night%2520in%2520Canada/Think%2520Hockey/ID%3D1237582316&amp;source=video&amp;vgc=rss&amp;usg=AFQjCNHnwCoqV449QSCCGkSKpyCuLuxTmQ&gt;&lt;img src=http://2.gvt0.com/ThumbnailServer2?app=vss&amp;contentid=a6ba3e909dbd5216&amp;offsetms=1&amp;itag=w160&amp;hl=en&amp;sigh=__tnEi2mplI4diJ9yEOu5GxzmBqjk= width=160 height=120&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;John Stevens demonstrates the secret to winning puck battles. &lt;p/&gt;&lt;div style="color:green;font-size:smaller;"&gt;cbc.ca&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.cbc.ca/video/#/Sports/CBC's%20Hockey%20Night%20in%20Canada/Think%20Hockey/ID=1237582316</link>
      <guid>http://www.cbc.ca/video/#/Sports/CBC's%20Hockey%20Night%20in%20Canada/Think%20Hockey/ID=1237582316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>These "Texts from Hillary Clinton" are hilarious http://t.co/evUtO0In (via @bostonmamas)</title>
      <description>phdinparenting: These "Texts from Hillary Clinton" are hilarious http://t.co/evUtO0In (via @bostonmamas) &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://textsfromhillaryclinton.tumblr.com/</link>
      <guid>http://textsfromhillaryclinton.tumblr.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac Flashback Trojan: Find Out If You&#8217;re Infected and What to Do About It</title>
      <description>Apple computer users may think they have nothing to worry about when it comes to contracting viruses and malware online, but a Russian antivirus company is reporting that 600,000 Macs are currently infected with a nasty trojan horse virus called &#8220;Flashback.&#8221; Doctor Web issued a report on Wednesday that said 550,000 computers with Mac OSX have picked up the virus. An analyst at Doctor Web later sent a tweet noting that 600,000 Mac computers have actually been infected and some &#8212; about 274 &#8212; are actually based in the same city as Apple&#8217;s headquarters, Cupertino, Calif. About 57% of the infected Macs are said to be in the U.S. and 20% are based in Canada. Flashback was originally discovered in September 2011 and was designed to disguise itself as an Adobe Flash Player installer, using Flash player logos. After installing Flashback, the malware seeks out user names and passwords that are stored on your Mac. SEE ALSO: More Than 600,000 Macs Infected With Flashback Malware [REPORT] &#8220;There are no visible symptoms for this Mac virus, except for making sporadic connections to unknown servers that can be only seen in the Firewall logs, if any firewall is in place,&#8221; Boris Sharov, CEO of Doctor Web, told Mashable. &#8220;The symptoms also depend on the payload that may be downloaded upon the command from the control server.&#8221; Although Sharov said it&#8217;s difficult to prevent contracting the virus, it&#8217;s not impossible. &#8220;The bad thing about these types of infections is that it is hard to prevent them without disconnecting one&#8217;s computer from the Internet all together,&#8221; Sharov said. &#8220;We advise Mac users to strictly follow Apple&#8217;s security updates. Don&#8217;t neglect them.&#8221; To protect your computer from contracting the virus now, download Apple&#8217;s latest software update. Click the Apple logo located in the top-left section of the desktop and select Software Update. Install all of the available updates as soon as possible. &#8220;Unfortunately, the number of infected computers is still increasing,&#8221; Sharov said. &#8220;This means that users are careless about security patches, and they shouldn&#8217;t be.&#8221; Sharov also advised Mac users to install anti-virus software, even though many think it&#8217;s unnecessary to do so for Apple computers. Although symptoms are minimal, there are a few things you can do to see if you are infected. Sharov suggests the following steps (note: we posted the html code below as an image so you could read the full code): Go to the Mac&#8217;s Library folder and select LaunchAgents. There should be several files in that catalog. Search all files in the folder for the following contents: Look for the file name specified in the ProgramArguments key. This is where the file BackDoor.Flashback.39 would be located. To see if this is the trojan, scan it with anti-virus software for Mac OS or upload it to VirusTotal website. To cure the machine, delete both files. Removing the files should restore your computer. The news comes after Apple continues to position OS X as a more secure alternative to other computer makers. &#8220;A Mac isn&#8217;t susceptible to the thousands of viruses plaguing Windows-based computers,&#8221; Apples notes on its homepage. &#8220;That&#8217;s thanks to built-in defenses in Mac OS X that keep you safe, without any work on your part.&#8221; Apple has not responded to Mashable&#8217;s request for a comment. Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, PashaIgnatov More About: antivirus, apple, computers, laptops, mac, trojanFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/05/mac-flashback-trojan/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/05/mac-flashback-trojan/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy 404 Day! Here Are the Web&#8217;s Funniest Error Messages [PICS]</title>
      <description>1. 501st Legion 501st Legion is a Star Wars costume organization. It only makes sense that its 404 page would play on Obiwan's famous jedi mind trick with a "weak-minded" stormtrooper.Click here to view this gallery.Is your Wednesday full of fail? If so, it could be because today is April 4 &#8212; otherwise known as 4/04, the calendar&#8217;s answer to the infamous 404 error message. We&#8217;ve all been there, furiously hitting the refresh button and muttering expletives while that page we just need to read refuses to load. Luckily, in failure lies opportunity &#8212; in this case, the opportunity for humor. Bless the web developers whose creativity dulls our frustration with a bit of funny. From helpful stormtroopers to bawling babies, some sites give a little extra effort to ease those 404 blues. Scroll through the gallery above to see some of Mashable&#8216;s all-time favorite 404 error messages from around the web. If that&#8217;s not enough for you, click on the link below. SEE ALSO: 33 More Entertaining 404 Error Pages And if you want to learn how not to fail on the social web, check out Mashable Connect, our biggest conference of the year. Event Information Our annual destination conference, Mashable Connect, brings our community together for three days to connect offline in an intimate setting at the Contemporary Resort at Walt Disney World&#174;. Registration is now open. Held in a unique location away from everyday distractions, Mashable Connect is a rare and valuable opportunity to be surrounded by digital leaders across industries. You&#8217;ll spend time with Mashable&#8217;s passionate and influential community, hear from top speakers who will provide insight into the the technologies and trends that are shaping the next era of digital innovation, and get to spend time with the Mashable team. To keep Mashable Connect as intimate as possible, only a limited amount of tickets are available. A Look Back at Last Year&#8217;s Mashable Connect 1. Mashable Connect Race Powered by Gowalla Team members check in to a race location at Magic Kingdom during the Mashable Connect Race powered by Gowalla.Click here to view this gallery. Supporting Sponsors Sponsorship Opportunities A limited number of sponsor opportunities are available for Mashable Connect. This is an excellent opportunity to get in front of Mashable&#8217;s passionate and influential audience. Contact sponsorships@mashable.com for opportunities. Image courtesy of Flickr, Frogman! Thumbnail image courtesy of ifolderlinks.ru More About: 404 error, Web DevelopmentFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/funny-404-error-messages/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/04/funny-404-error-messages/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups, This Is How Design Works &#226;&#8364;&#8220; by Wells Riley</title>
      <description>A guide to understanding digital %26 physical product design for startups</description>
      <link>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</link>
      <guid>http://startupsthisishowdesignworks.com/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
