<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>7 Spectacular Fireworks GIFs for the Fourth of July</title>
      <description>1. Fireworx by Alfredo &#193;lvarez Don't try this one at home, kids. Click here to view this gallery. If like us, you consider fireworks to be an absolutely essential part of any Fourth of July celebrations, then we have a treat for you. We have gathered up seven top fireworks-themed GIFs that will see the explosive action continued on your computer screen long after Independence Day is over. SEE ALSO: 10 Patriotic 4th of July Tech Accessories Take a look through our animated gallery for some awesome pyrotechnics. If you've captured any amazing fireworks imagery, then share your links in the comments below. Thumbnail image courtesy of tsuacctnt More About: features, fireworks, fourth of July, gallery</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/fireworks-gifs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/fireworks-gifs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPad Mini, Apple&#8217;s Tablet Trump Card, Is Coming This Year [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Apple is preparing to release a smaller version of the iPad in time for the 2012 holiday season, according to a report just weeks after competitors Google and Microsoft announced their own tablet offerings. The newest iPad would feature a screen measuring between seven and eight inches -- down from the standard 9.7-inch screen of the previous three versions, Bloomberg reports. It would not, however, feature the retina display introduced with the most recent iPad in March. Bloomberg cites "two people with knowledge of the plans" in its Tuesday report, and says the new device could be officially announced as early as October. Some type of "iPad Mini" has been speculated about for a&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, Google, ipad, microsoft, Nexus 7</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/ipad-mini-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/ipad-mini-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways Small Businesses Get Social Media Wrong</title>
      <description>Nellie Akalp is the CEO of CorpNet.com, an online legal document filing service, where she helps entrepreneurs incorporate or form an LLC for their new businesses. Connect with Nellie on Twitter or visit her free resource center. It&#8217;s hard to go anywhere these days and not be bombarded with social media. That&#8217;s because Facebook has 900 million active users, there are more than 200 million Twitter users, and then there&#8217;s Pinterest, the latest darling. Given this reality, it&#8217;s impossible for small business owners not to feel a sense of urgency to master the social media landscape. But in the rush to join the social media party some small businesses are making critical mistakes. Here are five common errors that small businesses make when it comes to social media and how to avoid them. This might be the most difficult lesson for the small business owner. After all, we don&#8217;t have large marketing budgets to waste. Every dollar must count and we&#8217;ve been trained to close every potential sale. However, the social universe requires a subtler approach. This means no BUY ME buttons or blatant promotional copy. In fact, if your social media strategy is just about marketing or sales, then you&#8217;re not approaching it right. Yes, you can use social media for marketing and you can increase your sales figures from it, but it can&#8217;t be your focus 100% of the time. As a general rule of thumb, only 5% to 10% of your social media activity (i.e. status updates or tweets) should be self-promotional. Social media is all about building relationships and growing trust. This means answering questions, providing helpful information, and serving as a trusted resource. These activities should grow your bottom line, but it can be a slower, more nuanced, and potentially more fruitful journey than you&#8217;be come to expect. For this reason, it&#8217;s important to realize that social media shouldn&#8217;t replace all your other traditional marketing practices. It&#8217;s okay to ask for the sale, just not in social channels. You know how painful it is to be stuck at a cocktail party, talking to that self-absorbed person who only talks about him or herself. Small businesses need to treat social media like a cocktail party among friends. To be liked, you&#8217;ve got to be gracious, genuinely interested in others, and not dominate the conversation. What does this mean? Make it easy for people to leave comments on your blog. Engage with everyone who posts on your wall (within reason). Share great content from others in the industry. Ask questions and encourage participation. And most importantly, recognize that sometimes it&#8217;s better to talk less and listen more. There are two facts to keep in mind when it comes to social media and small business. First, there will always be a new network to get involved with. Secondly, a small business owner has a limited amount of time and money to devote to social media. Fortunately, doing social media well doesn&#8217;t mean you need to be anywhere and everywhere. Instead, it&#8217;s about choosing one or two of the most relevant and effective channels for reaching your customers and focusing on them. Remember that a neglected social media presence will reflect poorly on your business. It&#8217;s actually better to not have an account if you don&#8217;t have the time and resources to actively manage it and participate. If you&#8217;re running a small business, you know there&#8217;s a big difference between your budget and that of Virgin America or Starbucks. That&#8217;s OK. Your small business doesn&#8217;t need to try to keep up with these big brands &#8212; particularly when it comes to contests and campaigns. Creating giveaways and contests is one of the most effective ways to generate new likes and improve overall engagement. But small businesses often feel the pressure to offer flashy prizes that are well beyond their budget. For example, for your small business, don&#8217;t give away a bunch of iPads if that&#8217;s not what you can afford. Instead, consider giving away one of your company&#8217;s services. It&#8217;s definitely not the sexiest prize and won&#8217;t generate widespread interest, but it&#8217;s more budget friendly and everyone who participates is sure to be interested in what your company does. Sure, you don&#8217;t have to spend a dime to join Facebook, create a Twitter account, or start a blog. That&#8217;s great news for the small business. However, social media is far from free once you factor in the blood, sweat, and tears it demands. Social media requires constant commitment, from keeping fresh content on your accounts to engaging your community. Unless you consider your time (or the time of your employees) worthless, then there&#8217;s a significant cost involved with social media. For example, if it takes one employee approximately ten hours a week to manage social media accounts, you can assign a hard cost to the effort. The key takeaway is any small business owner needs to understand the numbers behind every campaign, and that means factoring in everyone&#8217;s time and effort. Do any of these pitfalls look familiar to you? Have you struggled with or seen other social media challenges?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/25/small-businesses-social-media-tips/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/25/small-businesses-social-media-tips/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Shutdowns Continue: iGoogle, Google Video, Google Mini &amp; Others Are Killed</title>
      <description>Google is continuing to shut down services which aren&#8217;t core to its business &#8211; something it has been actively doing ever since Google co-founder Larry Page took over as CEO. Today, the tradition continues as Google is announcing the shuttering of five more services, the most notable of which are Google Video and iGoogle, its personalized homepage offering. Clearly iGoogle has outlived its usefulness. The service dates back to a time when homepage portals were people&#8217;s entry points to the Internet. These days, we just never close our browser tabs, it seems. iGoogle is getting the ax on November 1st, 2013, which is far enough away for users to export their data, says Google. Another big-name closure is Google Video, a service which has long been overshadowed by Google-owned YouTube. It&#8217;s actually surprising that Google Video is still up-and-running, given that it stopped accepting uploads in May 2009. Google Video&#8217;s shutdown is arriving much sooner, however, so if you&#8217;ve dragged your feet in moving videos over to YouTube, now is the time. Google Video is no more as of August 20th. Other services fading to black today include Google&#8217;s Symbian Search App (bookmark Google.com, Google advises), Google Talk Chatback (a Google Talk widget for websites &#8211; Google says try its new acquisition Meebo instead) and Google Mini, an enterprise appliance that&#8217;s been around since 2005. Note that Google isn&#8217;t exiting the enterprise by any means, it&#8217;s just that Mini&#8217;s functionality is now offered by other products like Google Search Appliance, Google Site Search and Google Commerce Search, the company blog post reminds us. Google will honor its existing contracts for Mini customers, though. You can read more about the closures here. If you&#8217;re starting to lose track of the services Google&#8217;s has killed off in recent months, here&#8217;s a brief refresher: Google Bookmarks Lists, Google Friend Connect, Google Gears, Google Search Timeline, Google Wave, Knol, Renewable Energy Cheaper than Coal (RE&lt;C), Aardvark, Desktop, Fast Flip, Google Maps API for Flash, Google Pack, Google Web Security, Image Labeler, Notebook, Sidewiki, Subscribed Links,Google Flu Vaccine Finder, Google Related, Google Sync for BlackBerry, mobile web app for Google Talk, One Pass, Patent Search, Picasa for Linux, Picasa Web Albums Uploader for Mac and Picasa Web Albums Plugin for iPhoto, and all Slide products.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/03/google-shutdowns-continue-igoogle-google-video-google-mini-others-are-killed/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/03/google-shutdowns-continue-igoogle-google-video-google-mini-others-are-killed/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>British Comedian Eric Sykes Dies at 89</title>
      <description>Eric Sykes, a British comedian known for his seminal work on the 1950s radio program The Goon Show alongside Peter Sellers and Spike Milligan, has died at age 89. Sykes "died peacefully this morning after a short illness," Norma Farnes, his manager, told the More About: Eric Sykes, Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/eric-sykes-dies/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/eric-sykes-dies/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Clever Ways to Charge Your Devices in a Pinch</title>
      <description>1. Drive If you have a car charger, plug in your device during your next drive to the supermarket. You can find very inexpensive versions compatible with most portable devices on retail sites like Amazon. But try to preserve the environment &#8212; don't cruise your car just to charge your phone. Kill two birds with one stone and make an errand out of it. Image courtesy of Flickr, e_walkClick here to view this gallery. Millions of people in the mid-Atlantic region of the U.S. found themselves without power over the weekend when a force of warm, violent storms swept across the area. But rather than unplug completely, residents of the crippled power grid found creative ways to charge up their devices. We've gathered some of those tips to keep you juiced up for the future. Some require actual gadgets that function on solar or kinetic energy; others will help you find power in unlikely places. SEE ALSO: How Social Media Is Changing Disaster Response Have you ever used creative tactics to power your smartphones, e-readers and other devices? Please share your advice in the comments below so others can&#8230; Continue reading... More About: emergency, features, Gadgets, lifestyle, Mobile, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/charging-solutions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/charging-solutions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mormon Church Uses Facebook, Apps to Increase Political Outreach</title>
      <description>Members of Jesus Christ's Church of Latter Day Saints have begun leveraging their evangelizing networks through smartphone apps to help draw support for Mitt Romney's presidential campaign. By employing specialized apps like LDS Tools to gather phone numbers and addresses of Mormon church members, political supporters can cross-check the contact info with voter registration data to contact other Romney backers. However, Mormon church rules forbid the use of LDS resources for political purposes. Dave Isbell, a Nevada Mormon, tells CNN, the apps are being used despite official church policy. "The church makes it really easy for you to get a hold of anyone in your ward," Isbell says. "I&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, Mitt Romney, mormon, religion, US politics</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/mormons-using-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/mormons-using-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mormon Church Uses Facebook, Apps to Increase Political Outreach</title>
      <description>Members of Jesus Christ's Church of Latter Day Saints have begun leveraging their evangelizing networks through smartphone apps to help draw support for Mitt Romney's presidential campaign. By employing specialized apps like LDS Tools to gather phone numbers and addresses of Mormon church members, political supporters can cross-check the contact info with voter registration data to contact other Romney backers. However, Mormon church rules forbid the use of LDS resources for political purposes. Dave Isbell, a Nevada Mormon, tells CNN, the apps are being used despite official church policy. "The church makes it really easy for you to get a hold of anyone in your ward," Isbell says. "I&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, Mitt Romney, mormon, religion, US politics</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/mormons-using-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/mormons-using-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Visual Portfolios Replace Traditional Online Resumes?</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Pathbrite Quick Pitch: Pathbrite offers students and young job seekers a way to present their accomplishments holistically online. Genius Idea: The digital platform lets users construct visual portfolios by pulling in representative pieces -- pictures, links and published work -- of themselves into one place. From online media to search, the web is becoming more visual. Online resumes may be next for a makeover. Pathbrite is a San Francisco-based startup workin&#8230; Continue reading... More About: internet, linkedin, online, portfolio</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/pathbrite-portfolio/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/pathbrite-portfolio/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Highlights From The Flaming Lips 24-Hour Tour</title>
      <description>After spending 24 hours on the road and playing 8 shows in 8 different cities, the Flaming Lips are Guinness World Record holders. The band broke the previous record of 7 live performances in 24 hours, held by Jay-Z, with a sold out show at the House of Blues in New Orleans, LA. The tour began evening of Wednesday, June 27 in Memphis, TN and stretched overnight, with performances in the middle of the night and early in the morning in towns across Mississippi. Though by mid-afternoon on Thursday it looked as though there was a chance they might not achieve their goal, they eventually broke the record with 20 minutes to spare, finishing their final set around 6:10 P.M. CDT. Represent&#8230; Continue reading... More About: features, flaming-lips, mtv, Music, o music awards</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/flaming-lips-tour-highlights/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/flaming-lips-tour-highlights/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calling All Thieves: Twitter Account Retweets Debit Card Pics</title>
      <description>And now a public service announcement: don't post photos of your debit or credit cards online. That might sound like an incredibly basic security rule, but it's one dozens of Twitter users are breaking -- and now one handle hopes to hold them to account. @NeedADebitCard pillages the Twittersphere for unsuspecting users who posted completely legible photos of their credit and debit cards on the web. Its sole purpose: to shame those foolish enough to post Twitpics or Instagrams that contain their credit or debit card information. "Please quit posting pictures of your debit cards, people," reads the account's bio. It has posted 55 pictures and gained more than 2,000 followers since f&#8230; Continue reading... More About: debit card, finance, needadebitcard, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/debit-card-photos-online/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/debit-card-photos-online/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Pumped For London 2012 With Official Music Video</title>
      <description>The International Olympic Committee (IOC) has posted an epic music video for the official song of the London 2012 Olympics. English rock band Muse wrote the song, titled "Survival," specifically for the games. The track is a perfect anthem for the Olympics, but it's the YouTube video that really gets us excited. The video opens with a reverse highlight reel of the Summer Olympics, beginning in 2008 and going back to the start of the modern games. It then ushers in a more linear and determined timeline of iconic Olympic moments throughout the years. Assistant Editor Alex Hazlett summed up the feeling of the Mashable newsroom best, noting that she's "a sucker for heroic sports hig&#8230; Continue reading... More About: london 2012, muse, music videos, olympics, summer olympics</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/london-2012-song-music-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/04/london-2012-song-music-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
