<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook May Launch Smartphone by Next Year [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Facebook may be gearing up to launch its first-ever smartphone by next year, a new report suggests. According to The New York Times, engineers have been sought by recruiters to work on building hardware for a Facebook smartphone. This would be the social network&#8217;s third attempt to develop a smartphone, the report said, citing sources close to the matter. The news comes as search engine giant Google completed the acquisition of Motorola Mobility for $12.5 billion earlier this week. This move could help Facebook counter that with its own foray into the smartphone hardware business. SEE ALSO: Motorola Under Google: 3 Possible Futures Rumors about a possible Facebook phone have been circulating for the past few years. Although Facebook was reportedly first working on a smartphone in 2010, sources said the initiative stopped due to development complications. Meanwhile, AllThingsD has reported Facebook and manufacturer HTC were working together to develop a mobile device under the code name &#8220;Buffy.&#8221; It&#8217;s believed that &#8220;Buffy&#8221; may still be in development. Hiring engineers to work specifically on building Facebook phones would position the company to explore other smartphone projects, as well. Do you think a move into the smartphone business would be smart for Facebook or would it overextend itself? Would you buy a Facebook phone? More About: Buffy, Facebook, mark zuckerberg, smartphone, smartphonesFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/facebook-smartphone/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/facebook-smartphone/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School Cellphone Ban Spawns Thriving Niche Storage Market</title>
      <description>Mobile devices have become like wallets &#8212; among the must-have items on your person when you leave the house. Teens are no exception to this rule, but for New York City&#8217;s students, this poses a real problem. The New York Board of Education has banned the use of electronics in public schools since the 1980s. For years, there was an &#8220;out of sight, out of trouble&#8221; policy. Recently, new safety precautions such as metal detectors and backpack checks upon entry, have made it harder for middle school and high school students to smuggle their gadgets into classes. Electronics are confiscated on sight. Two years ago Vernon Alcoser, a Bronx businessman and federal correctional officer, came up with a unique solution for the problem. His big idea &#8212; to provide mobile storage for students to store gadgets during the school day. In 2010 Alcoser and his sister Theresa bought a white truck and painted the side with a blue &#8220;Pure Loyalty Electronic Device Storage&#8221; decal. Parked outside Herbert H. Lehman High School in the Bronx, high school students flocked to the truck&#8217;s small window to turn in their electronics for $1 &#8212; two gadgets for $1.50. &#8220;A friend called me and said her daughter was storing her cellphone in grocery stores and bodegas in the area,&#8221; Alcoser tells Mashable. &#8220;[Students] were going away from the direction of school in order to do that. I thought if we brought storage closer to the schools, it would be a favor to the kids.&#8221; The mobile gadget storage business is now booming and the owners expect to expand. There is certainly a ready market for school-day cellphone storage: The NYC Department of Education (DOE) serves 1.1 million students in over 1,700 schools. And unlike their suburban counterparts, New York City students generally take public transportation to school. Their commutes can rival those of adult workers in length and complexity. Every day, Roci Cepeda travels 30 minutes each way from Brooklyn to Washington Irving High School in Manhattan.Students come in to this school from all other boroughs, arriving as early as 7 a.m. &#8220;I need it [my phone] in case I need to communicate with someone,&#8221; Cepeda says. &#8220;In case of an emergency.&#8221; Parents often want to be able to communicate with their children. Many are enthusiastic about Pure Loyalty&#8217;s service. &#8220;We have a lot of parents that call us and ask if we can come to a particular school because they want to stay in contact with their kids that are going and coming home from school,&#8221; says Alcoser. SEE ALSO: Is Total Gadget Immersion Good or Bad for Kids? [INFOGRAPHIC] Jose Garcia, a business student at Bronx Community College, works in the truck each weekday from 7 a.m. to around 5 p.m. &#8212; or when the last phone is returned. At schools where metal detectors have been installed at entrances, current students reported having leaving their cellphones at corner stores, delis and markets nearby where owners would watch them for $1. It&#8217;s a system Garcia is familiar with. &#8220;When I was in high school, we used to leave our phones in grocery stores,&#8221; he says. &#8220;This is a brilliant idea.&#8221; The trucks are staffed with two employees at all times. Once the truck is parked and collecting phones, the vehicle never leaves, so students may retrieve their property whenever it&#8217;s convenient. Phones are stored in sleeves and students are given security cards with a unique word or code to ensure correct returns. At Washington Irving, roughly 300 to 400 phones are stored each day. A other locations, Pure Loyalty collects an average of 500 to 700 gadgets a day. Another sign of the venture&#8217;s success is the number of copycat services that have sprung up since its inception. &#8220;A lot of competition has formed based on them seeing us on the news,&#8221; Alcoser says. &#8220;There are a few other companies &#8212; I don&#8217;t know licensed or insured like us.&#8221; Pure Loyalty pays insurance that protects phones if truck is lost, stolen or damaged. It has a $2 million insurance policy that covers just the phones. NYC DOE officials conducted thorough background checks on the company its staff, according to Alcoser. He says Pure Loyalty is welcomed by the city&#8217;s public schools because the service keeps the students and their property safe. &#8220;The school doesn&#8217;t want the kids to leave,&#8221; he said. &#8220;For them, to send the child who came to school away with a phone is not in the school&#8217;s best interest.&#8221; Check out these photos of the Pure Loyalty storage truck outside Washington Irving High School: Pure Loyalty Electronic Device Storage A team of two parks outside Washington Irving High School in Manhattan -- one of the eight NYC locations. Click here to view this gallery. More About: Business, cellphones, new york city, Social Media, startupFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/26/gadget-storage-trucks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/26/gadget-storage-trucks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tell-Tale Signs Your Employee is Overworked [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Are you stressed at work? You&#8217;re not alone: A recent Gallup poll indicates that on-the-job pressure is the top reason for employee dissatisfaction in the American workforce, and nearly half of American workers say their job is &#8220;very or extremely stressful.&#8221; And whether you notice it or not, you&#8217;re broadcasting clear signs that should indicate to your employer that you are overworked and need a change of pace. The infographic below, developed by Column Five in conjunction with employee wellness company Keas, shows exactly how employees behave when they&#8217;ve been pushed to their limits. Workers tend to develop classic symptoms when their workload gets too much to bear, such as poor memory, fatigue and bad time management. They also exhibit odd behaviors, working too much or too little in response to the level of stress in the workplace. Employers should be watching for these key symptoms and redirecting overworked employees to a more manageable situation. Of course, the consequences of ignoring these signs can be major &#8212; 66% of employees suffer from stress-induced health issues, including but not limited to high blood pressure, headaches, sleeplessness and more frequent periods of sickness. Overworked employees are also more likely to have drastically decreased productivity and play hooky than those who are satisfied with their workload. The overall result is clear: Overworked and stressed workers are never good for a company. Check out the infographic below for an inside look into how overworked employees behave &#8212; and how it all can be fixed. Do you ever feel stressed at your job? Let us know in the comments. Infographic research and design by Column Five Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Social Media Strategy Director at Likeable Media in New York City Online Marketing Manager at USA Football in Indianapolis Social Outreach Manager at Awesomeness TV in Los Angeles More About: features, infographic, job search series, jobs, mashableFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/employee-overworked-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/employee-overworked-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Adorable &#8216;Lip-Dub&#8217; Marriage Proposal Is Worth Watching Now [VIRAL VIDEO]</title>
      <description>It seems as though there&#8217;s a new viral marriage proposal every week, but this delightful &#8220;lip-dub&#8221; effort from a Portland actor who called in some help from family and friends is unlike anything we&#8217;ve ever seen. On Wednesday May 23, Isaac Lamb surprised his girlfriend Amy &#8212; a choreographer with a Broadway dancing background &#8212; with an elaborate proposal that involved more than 60 people performing down a street. Lamb&#8217;s brother sat her in the back of a car with a pair of headphones and told her to listen to the song that played. As the car starts to move, she watches people pop up around her, from a marching band to parent cameos, dancing and lip-syncing along with the song. Social Media Marriage Proposals: 10 Clever Ways to Pop the Question What&#8217;s so charming about the video &#8212; in addition to the heart-warming concept and creative choreographed moves &#8212; is Amy&#8217;s infectious giggles and excitement throughout the video. It will make you smile and tear up at the same time. She, of course, said yes. The video has already reached more than one million views on YouTube. BONUS: 5 Geek Marriage Proposals on Video 1. Internet Memes Timothy Tiah Ewe Tiam snuck up on his long-time love interest, Audrey Ooi Feng Ling, at Neroteca, a restaurant in Malaysia, and began showing her poster-sized printed memes such as Socially Awkward Penguin, Y U NO Guy and Success Kid. At the end of the meme-ridden surprise, he knelt and confessed, &#8220;I&#8217;m very nervous and terrified about this, but I love you and I think you&#8217;re my soul mate. And I can&#8217;t see myself living without you in my life. Will you marry me?&#8221;Click here to view this gallery. More About: marriage proposals, trending, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/lip-dub-marriage-proposal/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/lip-dub-marriage-proposal/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Adorable &#8216;Lip-Dub&#8217; Marriage Proposal Is Worth Watching Now [VIRAL VIDEO]</title>
      <description>It seems as though there&#8217;s a new viral marriage proposal every week, but this delightful &#8220;lip-dub&#8221; effort from a Portland actor who called in some help from family and friends is unlike anything we&#8217;ve ever seen. On Wednesday May 23, Isaac Lamb surprised his girlfriend Amy &#8212; a choreographer with a Broadway dancing background &#8212; with an elaborate proposal that involved more than 60 people performing down a street. Lamb&#8217;s brother sat her in the back of a car with a pair of headphones and told her to listen to the song that played. As the car starts to move, she watches people pop up around her, from a marching band to parent cameos, dancing and lip-syncing along with the song. Social Media Marriage Proposals: 10 Clever Ways to Pop the Question What&#8217;s so charming about the video &#8212; in addition to the heart-warming concept and creative choreographed moves &#8212; is Amy&#8217;s infectious giggles and excitement throughout the video. It will make you smile and tear up at the same time. She, of course, said yes. The video has already reached more than one million views on YouTube. BONUS: 5 Geek Marriage Proposals on Video 1. Internet Memes Timothy Tiah Ewe Tiam snuck up on his long-time love interest, Audrey Ooi Feng Ling, at Neroteca, a restaurant in Malaysia, and began showing her poster-sized printed memes such as Socially Awkward Penguin, Y U NO Guy and Success Kid. At the end of the meme-ridden surprise, he knelt and confessed, &#8220;I&#8217;m very nervous and terrified about this, but I love you and I think you&#8217;re my soul mate. And I can&#8217;t see myself living without you in my life. Will you marry me?&#8221;Click here to view this gallery. More About: marriage proposals, trending, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/lip-dub-marriage-proposal/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/lip-dub-marriage-proposal/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isaac's Live Lip-Dub Proposal</title>
      <description>On Wednesday, May 23rd, 2012, I told my girlfriend to meet me at my parent's house for dinner. When she arrived I had stationed my brother to sit her in the back of an open Honda CRV and give her some headphones. He "wanted to play her a song"... Wha</description>
      <link>http://vimeo.com/42828824</link>
      <guid>http://vimeo.com/42828824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Fantastic Memorial Day Weekend Instagram Shots [GALLERY]</title>
      <description>Celebrating Memorial Day A collection of photos from Memorial Day celebrations. Courtesy @melissa_marlowClick here to view this gallery. It&#8217;s Memorial Day weekend in the United States, and Americans are spending time with friends and family, enjoying the first barbecue of the summer and remembering their fallen military heroes. While people are soaking up some rays or paying tribute to lost heroes, they&#8217;re posting some fantastic snapshots to Instagram. SEE ALSO: Freedom Tower: 11 Beautiful Instagrams of NYC&#8217;s Tallest Building Mashable has collected some of our favorites in the gallery above. Show us your Memorial Day weekend Instagram pictures and tell us about your long weekend in the comments below! More About: gallery, instagram, memorial day, pictures, Social Media, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/26/memorial-day-instragram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/26/memorial-day-instragram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Pushes First Penguin Algorithm Update 1.1</title>
      <description>No matter that it&#8217;s late Friday night on the start of a three-day holiday weekend in the U.S., Google has just pushed out the first update to its recent webspam-fighting Penguin algorithm. Google&#8217;s Matt Cutts announced the news a short time ago on Twitter, calling it a &#8220;data... Please visit Search Engine Land for the full article.</description>
      <link>http://searchengineland.com/google-pushes-first-penguin-algorithm-update-122518?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-main</link>
      <guid>http://searchengineland.com/google-pushes-first-penguin-algorithm-update-122518?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-main</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Brands Get It Right on Viddy</title>
      <description>Viddy, the hot social video editing and sharing app, has racked up millions of ordinary users and a whole host of celebrity participants. Perhaps leery of video, brands are not signing up to the network quite as fast. Nonetheless, there are some early-adopter corporate Viddy accounts worth checking out. We&#8217;ve taken a look at six brands currently using Viddy in smart and savvy ways. SEE ALSO: How to Get Started With Viddy Discover which brands we&#8217;re highlighting and why. We have included a sample clip from each, so have your say in the comments below: which brand is using the service most effectively and why? 1. DVF The Diane von Furstenberg fashion brand is a big user of the social video platform. As well as using Viddy to show mini-clips of Diane and &#8220;everyday&#8221; footage, DVF joined forces with Viddy during New York&#8217;s Mercedes Benz Fashion Week. DVF staffers used the app to shoot exclusive behind-the-scenes footage as they prepped for the show, encountered celebs. The event highlights were then cross-posted to the DVF Facebook page. Giving fans an insider glimpse is a clever way to make the most of short-form video &#8212; viewers feel like they can enjoy special access to a brand they admire. 2. Red Bull UK Because it only recently added its Viddy account, Red Bull UK has only created a handful of viddys, but every single one is worth watching. The beverage brand keeps tight to its sports/action message with footage of the recent Red Bull-sponsored Empire of Dirt BMX contest. Such events are ripe for the &#8220;highlights reel&#8221; treatment. The content is incredibly shareable, and Red Bull&#8217;s editing of the clips is simply superb. We hope to see more of the same in the future from Red Bull &#8212; we think the brand has found a match made in heaven with Viddy. 3. General Electric General Electric has made great use of Viddy with its small selection of well-edited clips, which offer viewers a peek at its cool technology and premises. While the company has only posted three clips so far, they are perfectly suited to Viddy&#8217;s 15-second format. Each provides a visual insight to the brand in a format that is accessible and fun for Viddy&#8217;s youthful audience, especially when longer, more explanatory YouTube videos might not. 4. Warner Bros Records Warner Bros. Records appears to be testing the Viddy waters. It has created a dozen clips, featuring just one artist: American rapper Waka Flocka Flame. The clips are primarily behind-the-scenes footage from music video shoots. They are surprisingly effective, thanks to Viddy&#8217;s cool filters and music effects. While we like the style the Warner Bros. viddys thus far, we might question the need in the future for separate Viddy accounts for individual artists. Perhaps the brand can reserve the main account for a &#8220;best of&#8221; collection of curated content. 5. Southwest Airlines Southwest Airlines has uploaded a variety of content to Viddy, from light-hearted &#8220;guess the airport&#8221; challenges to in-flight footage to what can only be described as good, honest plane porn. Recently, the airline used Viddy to host fun competition. It challenged users to create a Southwest-themed Viddy for the chance to win roundtrip plane tickets to the Sundance Film Festival. With fresh content every few weeks or so, it seems Southwest plans to use the platform as one tool in its wider social media dashboard, taking advantage of the unique proposition Viddy offers brands. 6. The Muppets Finally, The Muppets brand is no stranger to social media, and it got in on the Viddy action quite early on. Ahead of the release of The Muppets movie in November 2011, the Disney-owned entertainment brand teamed up with Viddy for a production pack, which contained content and special effect filters that featured The Muppets. The super-shareable clips featuring each of the main characters were also posted online to promote the movie. The Muppets-Viddy partnership is particularly exciting, as it shows how the tool could play a part in movie marketing. For example, it would be the perfect platform to issue a series of teaser clips. We look forward to seeing how other brands use Viddy, as more sign up to the service. Have you seen any other interesting uses? Have your say in the comments below. More About: apps, Business, features, General Electric, Marketing, red bull, Social Media, Southwest Airlines, the muppets, viddy, Video, warner brosFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/brands-on-viddy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/27/brands-on-viddy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Never Take Your Eyes Off This Hacker Metric</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s Note: Nir Eyal is the founder of two acquired startups and an advisor to several Bay Area companies and incubators. Nir blogs about the intersection of psychology, technology, and business at NirAndFar.com. Follow him on Twitter @nireyal. If you&#8217;re like me, you&#8217;ve had enough of the Facebook IPO story. For tech entrepreneurs struggling to build stuff, the cacophony of recent press is just more noise. That&#8217;s why when my friend Andrew Chen posted an insightful analysis of Facebook user data, I was happy to get back to learning from what the company did right instead of debating what its bankers did wrong. Chen calculated Facebook&#8217;s historical ratio of daily active users (DAU) to monthly active users (MAU) and the stats are startling. Since March 2009, when the earliest data is available, approximately 50% of Facebook users logged in daily. As other technology companies struggle to maintain DAU to MAU ratios of 5% or less, Facebook&#8217;s numbers appear stratospherically high in comparison. But what is equally surprising is the consistency of that ratio over time. Despite periodic user revolts in reaction to changes in the site, the ratio remained strangely stable. In fact, the number has risen over the past year and is now hovering at 58% as of March of this year. It&#8217;s as if Zuckerberg has steered the company by this golden ratio. Which begs the question: is there some wisdom here regarding this ratio as a predictor of Internet success? Obviously, there are no guarantees and starting cutting edge tech companies will always be risky business. But, assuming you have a solid business model, there are good reasons to believe that if there is one metric to focus on while building your business, it&#8217;s the percentage of users who come back daily as expressed by this ratio. As I&#8217;ve written previously, I believe a mastery of the mechanics of habit design is increasingly deciding startup winners and losers. Not only because habits cement user behavior in an increasingly cluttered digital world, but because a high-engagement product is also a high-growth product. The two are one and the same. A high DAU to MAU ratio is a great indicator of the strength of user habits and, ceteris paribus, I&#8217;d bet on a business with the higher ratio over a competitor every time. Here&#8217;s why: More is More When it comes to web and mobile startups, high DAU to MAU is more important than the size or growth rate of an entrenched competitor. Case in point, Facebook defeated much earlier competitors like MySpace and Friendster, both of which had healthy growth rates and millions of users by the time Facebook got started. This is because of what I call the &#8220;more is more principle.&#8221; High user engagement has an exponential effect on user growth. As David Skok points out on his blog, &#8220;The most important factor to increasing growth is not the Viral Coefficient, but the Viral Cycle Time.&#8221; Viral Cycle time is the amount of time it takes to complete a viral loop and it has massive impact on user growth. &#8220;For example, after 20 days with a cycle time of two days, you will have 20,470 users,&#8221; Skok writes. &#8220;But if you halved that cycle time to one day, you would have over 20 million users! It is logical that it would be better to have more cycles occur, but it is less obvious just how much better.&#8221; Having a greater proportion of DAUs dramatically increases Viral Cycle Time for two reasons. First, daily users initiate loops more often &#8211; think tagging a photo on Facebook. Second, more daily active users means more people to respond and react to each invitation. The cycle not only perpetuates; with high DAU to MAU, it accelerates. One Way to Grow Those who talk tech split into two dogmatic camps. Some prioritize growth and accept low engagement, while others believe a company needs to nail engagement before focusing on growth. I believe this is a false dichotomy. If you have only one or the other, congratulations, you&#8217;ve got squat. Let&#8217;s first take a look at user growth. Distribution, of course, is critically important and no company can survive without a sound customer acquisition strategy. Not only is growth essential but it is something engineer-driven companies love to work on. In fact, the title of &#8220;Growth Hacker&#8221; has recently become a badge of honor among Silicon Valley digerati. Tweaking viral coefficients and instantly seeing the results is intoxicating. It&#8217;s startup feedback at its finest. But optimizing growth without engagement has its pitfalls. As Peter Thiel recently told his class at Stanford, the effectiveness of distribution channels tends to follow a power law. Just as businesses tend to have only one revenue stream, they also have only one good growth strategy &#8211; the effectiveness of which is 10x the results of other distribution channels. The problem with having only one real way to grow is that the method becomes obvious to others and is quickly copied. For example, in its early days, Facebook capitalized on users importing their email contact list to drive growth. But soon thereafter, so did everyone else. But having competitors copy you is a high-class problem. It means something is working. Worse yet is discovering a fantastic viral loop that drives growth only to see engagement crater when users realize there&#8217;s little long-term value in the service. Ringtone businesses, sheep-throwing Facebook games circa 2008, and today&#8217;s social video sharing apps using questionable growth tactics, are just a few of the &#8220;leaky bucket&#8221; businesses that occur when distribution outpaces engagement. When it comes to building a big business, clearly a good acquisition channel is mandatory, but not sufficient. Given the power law of user growth, you will likely only have one major way of acquiring customers and it won&#8217;t be much of a secret. You&#8217;ll need some other competitive advantage. Engagement as Advantage As opposed to distribution channels, the mechanics driving user engagement do not follow a power law. In fact, it is the nuances of user behavior that make the competition irrelevant, just as it did in the case of Facebook&#8217;s early rivals. Discovering non-obvious user needs and creating accompanying habits is accomplished through deep observation grounded in solid behavioral theory, followed by methodical trial and error. It takes time to create new habits and getting the user to act the way you&#8217;d hoped is accomplished by uncovering a thousand tiny insights into the user&#8217;s psyche. The process of uncovering latent needs is characterized by understanding more about users than they know about themselves. The distribution strategy will always be obvious, but the behavioral insights are important secrets that can only be discovered through rigorous testing. Zynga had one obvious way to acquire users, namely Facebook ads. But the company has a cadre of behavioral insights it uses to craft addictive games. It collects terabytes of information daily to alter game dynamics to boost user engagement. Quora primarily drives users to its site through Google search traffic. But the conjecture about all the reasons why the service is so sticky spills over a long question thread. Instagram posted images to Twitter and Facebook to drive user acquisition, placing its growth strategy in plain sight. However, the founders, one of whom studied psychology as a Symbolic Systems major at Stanford, acquired a deep understanding of what makes users tick and click. But why can&#8217;t behavioral design be copied like a distribution strategy? Because competitors are not able to recognize and act upon these kinds of insights. You can know the competition&#8217;s product feels better to use, but you won&#8217;t know why. Engaging products gain their advantages by leveraging tiny improvements, which together create huge advantage. From the outside, you can&#8217;t tell what&#8217;s working and what isn&#8217;t. For example, the iPhone is objectively a better designed, more user-friendly, and ultimately more engaging product than the Android experience. But why? Nearly everyone, when given the choice between an Android interface and an iPhone, chooses the iPhone. There are plenty of good reasons to own an Android, but intuitive interface ain&#8217;t one. Google knows this and yet they can&#8217;t replicate Apple because they don&#8217;t know the answer to &#8220;why?&#8221; You can&#8217;t make decisions between seemingly identical interface choices unless you&#8217;ve walked the path of user behavior. Without this knowledge, copying the competition becomes a game of throwing darts at features. Habit design requires a fundamentally different, though complementary skill set to growth hacking. Designing high-engagement products is an art which is increasingly becoming a science. The craft crosses the disciplines of psychology and design &#8211; both fields which are hard to learn in a short period of time. Unfortunately, designing habits often falls in the organisational abyss between the founders&#8217; vision and what is technically feasible. But those companies able to habituate users quickly enjoy massive advantages. Not only does engagement drive growth for the reasons stated above, but users tend to shut out other, sometimes superior, solutions. In fact, business history is peppered with technically inferior products beating competitors because of the fierce loyalty of habituated users (I&#8217;m looking at you Apple addicts). Users only have time and brain cycles for a limited number of services. If a high proportion of users are using your service daily, they aren&#8217;t using the competition&#8217;s. Can&#8217;t Have One Without the Other But focusing on engagement without growth is also a losing proposition. For one, virality is not something that can be bolted on to a product after it is in the wild. Distribution is not an afterthought and it needs to be built into the core of the experience. Either the company has a viral growth mechanic or it doesn&#8217;t. So no matter how engaging your service is, it will remain niche unless there is a way to get it in front of new users en masse. Creating a company with both high engagement and high growth requires a sound distribution engine fueled by active users. Both engagement and growth are essential to a company&#8217;s viability and by adhering to the tao of DAU and MAU, founders have an accurate point of focus to increase their odds of success. Thank you to David King for reading early versions of this essay Photo credit: Pink Sherbet Photography</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/26/never-take-your-eyes-off-this-hacker-metric/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/26/never-take-your-eyes-off-this-hacker-metric/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grown Woman Watches &#8216;Star Wars&#8217; for the First Time [LIVE BLOG]</title>
      <description>Against all odds, there are people on Earth who haven&#8217;t seen Star Wars. And I&#8217;m not talking about hunter-gatherers in the Amazon rainforest. I&#8217;m talking about people who enjoy indoor plumbing, like my colleague Christine Erickson. For 24 years, she&#8217;s been bombarded with quotes, jokes, memes, toys, commercials, sequels, prequels, parodies, marketing and countless cultural references that fly right over her ignorant little head like the Millenium Falcon making the Kessel Run. (She has no idea what I&#8217;m talking about there.) Today is auspicious. Thirty-five years ago, Star Wars Episode IV: A New Hope debuted in theaters, blowing the sideburns off countless &#8217;70s sci-fi nerds. George Lucas created an institution &#8212; dare I say, a cultural prerequisite &#8212; upon which all subsequent sci-fi owes a debt. How dare you, Christine Erickson, work at a nerd emporium like Mashable having never seen this seminal space opera. Do you think you&#8217;re better than us or something? Well, do you? To remedy this affront on humankind, we&#8217;ve locked Christine in a windowless storeroom asked Christine to watch Episode IV for the very first time and share her experience live on the web. At 2:00 p.m. ET, we launch her into a galaxy far, far away, and you can follow her journey right here in this very post. You can also play along on social media: Follow Christine&#8217;s tweets: @christerickson. Follow the official hashtag: #StarWarsVirgin. Lots of awesome people will be chiming in! Follow the plot of the movie in real time as it unfolds: @StarWarsPlot. Lots of people have RSVPed for the event on Facebook. See what they&#8217;re talking about! Check in to Star Wars and follow along with Mashable on GetGlue. Be sure to use the hashtag #StarWarsVirgin when you share your updates. We want to hear from you! Are you shocked that someone has never seen this movie before? Are you a Star Wars virgin yourself? Every tweet with the hashtag #StarWarsVirgin will be seen by our team, and the funniest, nerdiest, craziest ones will be included in our live blog, right here on Mashable. So, fire up your hyperdrive and join us for this special, social experiment. A huge thanks to Nick McKaig for providing the soundtrack to our video above. If you haven&#8217;t checked out his amazing acapella arrangement of the Star Wars theme, you&#8217;re really missing out. You can also download the track from iTunes. What better way to geek out on this holiest of holidays? More About: Entertainment, features, Film, humor, live blog, Movies, Sci-Fi, Social Media, Star Wars, trending, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/star-wars-live-blog/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/25/star-wars-live-blog/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hey Kids, Get Off My Lawn: The Once and Future Visual Programming Environment</title>
      <description>Editor&#8217;s Note: This guest post is written by Kwindla Hultman Kramer, who is the CEO of Oblong Industries &#8212; the company known for developing the gestural interfaces in the film Minority Report. The company&#8217;s current customers and partners include Boeing, SAP, GE, and others. When I was a boy of 14, my father was so ignorant I could hardly stand to have the old man around. But when I got to be 21, I was astonished at how much the old man had learned in seven years Mark Twain, &#8221;Old Times on the Mississippi&#8221; Atlantic Monthly, 1874 When I was a graduate student at the MIT Media Lab fifteen years ago, my research group went on a retreat every year with Famous Computer Scientists from Xerox PARC. I greatly admired these people and their work. But I was young and in a hurry to get where I thought I was going. And it sometimes seemed that every time us young folks talked about our research, or showed a demo, someone would say something like, &#8220;oh, that&#8217;s very nice, when we did that at PARC &#8230;.&#8221; Fast forward to the present. For the last few years, every time I see a new piece of small, open, hackable, networked hardware, or a new reputation engine, or a generative art piece, or a product built around location tracking plus real-time information push, or &#8212; well, you get the idea &#8212; I have to bite my tongue and think of the PARC folks to keep myself from saying, &#8220;oh, that&#8217;s very nice, when we did that at the Media Lab &#8230;.&#8221; All of which just proves that the wheel of history revolves. New work is always new, by definition, even if it&#8217;s not entirely new (which nothing can ever be). That&#8217;s a long introduction to a short essay on programming tools. In particular, I&#8217;ve been intrigued by the online discussion recently around some very nice work on interactive development environments by Bret Victor and a related Kickstarter project &#8212; and now YCombinator company &#8212; called Light Table, by Chris Granger. Bret&#8217;s stuff is great. And Light Table is great. If you&#8217;re anything like me, you want to use the tools these two people are building. Go contribute to the Kickstarter project right now. The funny thing is, though, that we had pretty interesting versions of these tools twenty years ago. By the late 1980s, professional LISP and Smalltalk environments were more than a little like Light Table. When I discovered Visual Age Smalltalk in 1996 I was blown away. Visual Age (and other Smalltalk tools) were built around snippets of code representing objects and methods. There were very few file operations. You could run your code and make live changes to the source, which were reflected in the running process. There was no distinction between the development environment and the runtime. You could save out your working &#8220;image&#8221;. There were good tools for managing forks, versioning and merge &#8212; not just of source code, but of the full system image. If you were writing a GUI application in Visual Age Smalltalk, all the elements on screen were interactively inspectable from inside the debugger. And all the system internals, including the virtual environment, the compiler and the debugger, were introspectible and hackable just by writing a little more Smalltalk code. When I raved about this to my friends, some of whom had old SparcStations sitting in their coat closets running their home networks, they said, &#8220;oh yeah, that&#8217;s nice, when we built all that stuff into our LISP machines ten years ago at Symbolics &#8230;.&#8221; So one question we might ask is why programming tools like this haven&#8217;t taken over, if we&#8217;ve had them for a long time and they are, indeed, generally better in objective or widely agreed upon ways? I can think of a few possible reasons. First, the requirement of a dynamic runtime to build these dynamic environments on top of is actually quite a big deal. Bret&#8217;s work is in JavaScript. Light Table targets JavaScript, Clojure, and Python. These days, we have two classes of languages. We use heavily engineered languages that are very, very static in their aesthetic and implementation choices. Truly interactive development environments are difficult to build for these C-family languages. And C-family languages have remained dominant until very recently, because they have both real advantages and &#8220;worse is better,&#8221; inertial advantages. On the other hand, we have dynamic languages that, relatively speaking, are really just prototypes. Javascript and Ruby and Python are useful and interesting. But much of the work on the dynamic languages side of the fence seems to go into tweaking syntax, reinventing the wheel at the VM level, and community-based library development. All of which I&#8217;m actually a big fan of, but goodness, it does sort of make me pine for that 200-person (I&#8217;m guessing) crackerjack team working on VisualAge for ten years at IBM. Maybe Google &#8212; in some ways the IBM of 2012 &#8212; will get us there again with JavaScript and V8. Then we&#8217;ll have a dynamic language stack that is fully engineered in the same sense that IBM Smalltalk and Symbolics LISP were. Second, I think that the web-enabled explosion of programming and programmers has set back the development of software tooling just as it (temporarily) set back user interface design. Again, I hasten to make clear that I think what the web hath wrought is wonderful, on balance. But there&#8217;s no free lunch, and for ten years most of the tech world turned its attention to building out a new global platform that could not, in its early days, support very much in the way of new user interfaces or sophisticated runtime architecture work. The web has grown up, though. The capabilities of modern JavaScript frameworks attest to that, as does the low-level work on implementations like V8. Third, screen real estate matters. The traditional &#8220;everything is a file&#8221; approach is wonderfully portable. You can build an environment for working with files even for a very small display. Heck, you can work with files if all you have is a line-mode terminal. But flexibly arranged code snippets and fully interactive graphical debuggers require a lot of pixels. And there aren&#8217;t always enough pixels. I&#8217;m amazed at how often I visit Big Companies and see full-time programmers working at their desks on single, 15&#8243; monitors. That&#8217;s an enormous missed opportunity to enable productivity. Pixels have gotten really cheap, though, and come in more and more form factors. We actually could build, today, a development environment designed to make use of a laptop screen and a tablet screen, simultaneously. A MacBook Air and an iPad, used together, would give me more pixels than I had on my dual-monitor desktop back when I fired up Visual Age Smalltalk every day. Finally, if we really want to get away from files and static representations of programs, maybe we want to get away from text altogether. There&#8217;s been lots of good academic work on graphical &#8212; as in, really, graphical &#8212; programming environments over the years. But that&#8217;s another entire conversation. Here are a couple of good pages on LISP Machines, which really were the future before the future was quite possible to build. And, as far as I know, the closest anyone has ever gotten to creating a full dynamic environment for a C-language platform is Alexia Massalin&#8217;s Synthesis operating system. If you are a programmer of any kind, I&#8217;ll wager that Alexia&#8217;s dissertation will blow your mind. So, let&#8217;s make the old tools new again. I want to use Light Table, and whatever Light Table catalyzes that we can&#8217;t yet imagine. But I do promise that when that new thing comes along, I&#8217;ll tell you we built an early version of it at the Media Lab at the tail end of the last century.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/27/hey-kids-get-off-my-lawn-the-once-and-future-visual-programming-environment/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/27/hey-kids-get-off-my-lawn-the-once-and-future-visual-programming-environment/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
