<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>How a High School Prank Call Site Turned Into Serious Business</title>
      <description>When Fahim Saleh bought the domain name &#8220;prankdial.com,&#8221; he fit the demographic one might expect: a high school boy in a small town, an occasional prankster and an Internet geek. The site ran a simple prank call service. Users entered a message, and the computer would call a number of their choice before reading it in a slow, robotic voice. Saleh put the site up, used it a few times, and then pretty much forgot about it while he was at college. That is, until someone copied it. When the nearly identical site &#8220;prankdialer.com&#8221; launched, it inspired Saleh to revive the dinky high school prank site he built on a whim in high school. By that point a serial Internet entrepreneur, he reinvented PrankDial, turning it into a profitable business. Since its revival, PrankDial&#8217;s iPhone app has been downloaded 500,000 times, and its Android app (before it was taken down at Android&#8217;s request) was downloaded 4 million times. The site has been behind nearly 1 million prank calls to date. Saleh &#8212; now 25 &#8212; has used the prank site&#8217;s revenue to found new businesses, relating to everything from Facebook cover photos to iPhone games for kids. &#8220;We&#8217;re probably the number-one prank anything on the web,&#8221; he says. &#8220;If you search &#8216;prank&#8217; or &#8216;prank calls,&#8217; you get PrankDial or one of our properties.&#8221; Here&#8217;s how the high school gag site grew up. Building PrankDial isn&#8217;t the only URL that Saleh purchased in high school. Launching websites was something of a habit &#8212; and a profitable one. The first site he sold, a resource for instant messenger icons called AIMDude.com, went for $1,200 on eBay. As he built more sites, he and his business partner (who he met on AIM) outsourced the actual programming involved to agencies abroad. &#8220;We were basically sitting at home in bedrooms, talking to people three times our age, and they have no idea they&#8217;re talking to a teenager on the other side,&#8221; says Saleh. &#8220;We&#8217;re in our pajamas, writing up specs and telling them how we want the design changed.&#8221; By the time he was 20, the pair had founded a conglomerate of websites called WizTeen, which allowed users to customize their avatars on services such as MySpace, MSN Messenger and AIM (remember them?). At the company&#8217;s peak, Saleh says the sites were pulling in $30,000 to $60,000 every month from Google Ads. In 2007, a reporter from the Poughkeepsie Journal wrote an article about WizTeen, in which she interviewed its 20-year-old co-founder. She asked him where he saw himself in five years. &#8220;I see myself behind one project that I&#8217;m very passionate about, funded by venture capitalists, in California, working full time in an office with like-minded people, working on a project that we&#8217;re all passionate about,&#8221; Saleh told her. &#8220;Everything I&#8217;m doing now is leading up to that.&#8221; Rebuilding Five years later, Saleh is in New York, leading a team of 10 who work on PrankDial, as well as a handful of other services under the umbrella company Tapfury. He says he hasn&#8217;t sought venture capital because the site has been profitable. WizTeen fizzled while Saleh was in college as services like AIM made their way out. Seeing imitator Prankdialer.com launch (he eventually bought the site) was what turned his attention to his own prank site, which at that point was getting 300 or 400 unique visitors per day. It needed a makeover. Sending robot messages over the phone wasn&#8217;t as funny as it was in high school, and Saleh replaced the robot with pre-recorded character messages. The recordings pause periodically to give the illusion of a conversation. You can send your friend the voice of an indignant pregnant woman who is pretty sure her baby is his. Or a desperate man who needs bail money. Or a threat from Batman. &#8220;At first, it was just me,&#8221; says Saleh. &#8220;Basically I just got my really terrible microphone and started blurting out things.&#8221; Now, the site hires voice talent to record the calls. PrankDial charges users who make more than three calls a day, but the service free up until that point. About 2 million people visit the site each month. Saleh swears his users aren&#8217;t just high school boys. &#8220;They don&#8217;t have that much discretionary income to spend on prank calling,&#8221; he reasons. &#8220;I think it&#8217;s about having a laugh with friends.&#8221; Prank Call-Funded At the end of the day, PrankDial sells prank calls &#8212; which, while not without their merits, are unlikely to change the world. &#8220;I really think if you market something properly, it can be anything on the Internet nowadays,&#8221; says Saleh. &#8220;It&#8217;s hard to believe this makes money, but if you&#8217;re the largest prank call website in the world, that generates revenue.&#8221; Just as he funded his college education by customizing AIM icons, he&#8217;s funding new business ventures through prank calls. Though Tapfury runs a handful of businesses, PrankDial &#8212; which requires very little maintenance &#8212; accounts for about 80% of revenue. Saleh is still searching for that one project he told the Poughkeepsie Journal at age 20 &#8212; something to be passionate about. &#8220;I really want to work on one project that has an influence on people&#8217;s lives,&#8221; he tells me, echoing the response he gave that reporter five years ago. Sure, most people fund such ideas through venture capital or loans. But prank calls seem as good a method as any. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, IGphotography More About: entrepreneurship, features, humor, pranks, StartupsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/prank-calls-serious-business/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/prank-calls-serious-business/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conan O&#8217;Brien Unveils the Future of Twitter: Manual Tweets</title>
      <description>Twitter is slow and it doesn&#8217;t work on paper. What if you could change all that? Mashable&#8217;s new CEO Conan O&#8217;Brien has developed a solution: Manual Tweets. They work &#8230; on paper. Watch the video to see this astounding social media innovation for yourself. SEE ALSO: Conan O&#8217;Brien Buys Mashable, Ousts Pete Cashmore as CEO More About: conan o'brien, trending, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/conan-obrien-manual-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/conan-obrien-manual-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This iPhone Platform Will Change The Way You Shoot Videos</title>
      <description>A new Kickstarter project is aiming to redefine how you shoot video with your iPhone. The Galileo is an iOS-controlled robotic iPhone platform that lets you manipulate the angle your iPhone from another iOS device, giving you the ability to adjust your iPhone to almost any angle you could possibly want. For instance, if you were video chatting with a child who moved out of sight of the camera you could move the platform to follow her using your own device. The platform could also be used in situations like meetings so you can can follow all the action going on in the room. The platform&#8217;s inventor originally created the device in order to have better chats with his son while he was away on business. Galileo can be controlled from another iOS device such as an iPad or iPod touch by swiping a finger across the screen, and gives you infinite 360-degree panning and 200-degree tilting. You can see everything around the iPhone and above it, with the only unavailable angle being what&#8217;s going on below. The platform is also offering its SDK (software developers kit) for app development, giving app developers the freedom to integrate Galileo functionality into existing apps or create apps and software specifically designed to work with the product. Galilieo has currently raised close to $270,000 on Kickstarter, and only required $100,000 to go into production. The project will be officially funded on April 21, 2012, after which the device will go into mass production and be sent out to project backers and then likely general consumers. What do you think of the project? Tell us what potential uses you see for Galileo in the comments. More About: apple, iphone, iPod Touch, kickstarterFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/iphone-galileo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/iphone-galileo/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Email and web use 'to be watched'</title>
      <description>The government will be able to monitor the calls, emails, texts and website visits of everyone in the UK under new legislation set to be announced soon.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-17576745</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-17576745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Companies Working Hard to Change the World</title>
      <description>In our new series, The World at Work, Mashable interviews the faces behind the companies that are working to make a global impact. Using the power of digital, these five companies have empowered citizens in need, rewarded innovation and created uniquely shareable tools that are key in affecting real change. Although they range in issues from education to sustainability, the one thing that all of these companies have in common is the drive and passion of those at the helm. Here&#8217;s a roundup of featured programs from the last week, including exclusive video interviews. To read more and watch the videos, click through to the full story, and follow the series to learn about more breakthrough companies. 1. Kaggle Big Idea: Kaggle hosts contests for data scientists. Why It&#8217;s Working: Using competition to perfect predictive models. Kaggle hosts contests for data scientists. Companies that want problems solved post them, along with relevant data sets, on the site. Anyone can submit a solution, and each competitor ranks on a leaderboard throughout the competition. So far about 30,000 people have submitted at least one model to a contest. Read the full story here. 2. Recyclebank Big Idea: Recyclebank gives the planet a rewards system using gamification techniques. Why It&#8217;s Working: Recyclebank rewards environmentally friendly actions with points, which are a monetary incentive to recycle. You can also compare your behavior with others on leaderboards in the Recyclebank Ecosystem. When Recyclebank was founded six years ago, no one had heard of gamification, the concept of rewarding non-game actions with points, scores or other rewards. Thanks to Foursquare, the popular geo-social network that has gamified exploration, many more of us are familiar with the term. Read the full story and see the video here. 3. Pencils of Promise Big Idea: By adopting the pencil, both symbolically and literally, the Pencils of Promise (POP) builds schools and educates children in developing countries. Why It&#8217;s Working: PoP&#8217;s newest campaign, Made With Pencils, engages participants via online art auctions, killer website design and a social media strategy that dates back to the roots of Facebook. PoP is a global project that aims to build schools and establish learning initiatives for millions of children around the globe who lack access to education. The non-profit organization &#8212; or as its 28-year-old founder Adam Braun would call it, the &#8220;for-purpose organization&#8221; &#8212; has already helped lower the number of uneducated children from 75 million in 2006 to 67 million today. Read the full story here. 4. Wefunder Big Idea: Wefunder provides a platform that allows startups to hold fundraising with a crowd of investors. Why It&#8217;s Working: WeFunder drives innovation by giving startups the ability to go through a formal funding series, and it also takes crowdsourcing to a new level by giving equity to funders. In the hard and fast world of startups, it&#8217;s not easy to get your name heard and money in your pocket. Boston-based company Wefunder aims to change that through another buzzword: crowdfunding. Read the full story and see the video here. 5. Reward Volunteers Big Idea: Reward Volunteers is an app for volunteers to log time, share what they&#8217;re doing and earn rewards for themselves and the organizations they serve. Why It&#8217;s Working: Users clock in volunteer time so they can focus on doing more good and less on keeping track of hours. The more hours logged and activity shared, the greater chance both volunteers and organizations have to win cash and prizes. Volunteers deserve a bit of credit for their do-good attitude, and that&#8217;s exactly what Reward Volunteers aims to do &#8212; it is in the name, after all. Read the full story here. What do you think of the efforts of these companies? Let us know in the comments. More About: features, mashable, World at WorkFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/world-at-work-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/world-at-work-1/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Email and web use 'to be watched'</title>
      <description>The government will be able to monitor the calls, emails, texts and website visits of everyone in the UK under new legislation set to be announced soon.</description>
      <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-17576745</link>
      <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-17576745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google News Fooled by April Fools&#8217; Day Prank</title>
      <description>Who doesn&#8217;t love a little April Fool&#8217;s Day fun? Apparently, not Google News. The algorithmic aggregator of the web&#8217;s top breaking headlines confused a spoof story for a serious one on Sunday morning, slating it in the page-view-driving top spot. Business magazine Forbes published a fictional dispatch from the Republican campaign trail, &#8220;Romney Drops Out of Race, Endorses Santorum.&#8221; The media company must have rethought its prank, once the story landed in Google News&#8217;s coveted number one spot, and removed the story. &#8220;In a surprise move, Mitt Romney announced today that he is ending his presidential campaign and throwing his support behind Rick Santorum. The move shocked observers, including Senator Santorum, as Governor Romney seemed poised for a decisive victory in Wisconsin. The governor, however, said he concluded that he has &#8216;no chance&#8217;&#157; to win the general election in December and that a Santorum candidacy in 2012 would be in the &#8216;best interest of the party.&#8217;&#8221; You can read the full text of the removed story on Short Form Blog. Forbes didn&#8217;t beat buzz-blog Gawker, which captured a screenshot while the story was trending on Google News. What do you think of news sites engaging in April Fools&#8217; Day pranks? Have any others caught your eyes today? Image courtesy of Flickr, Gage Skidmore More About: April Fools' Day, Google, google newsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/google-news-april-fools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/google-news-april-fools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April Fools&#8217; Day Classics: Top 10 Viral Pranks on YouTube</title>
      <description>People love a good trolling, whether it&#8217;s online or not, and there&#8217;s nothing like a company having a bit of harmless fun at the expense of a few thousand customers. Whether it&#8217;s a gag product or a fake movie trailer, when an April Fools&#8217; Day prank video is convincing enough, it has the potential to go viral on YouTube. Unfortunately this leaves fans punked, potentially even get their hopes up. (We&#8217;re pretty sure Zelda fans are still a little heartbroken over IGN Entertainment&#8217;s faux trailer.) Our friends at Unruly Media have provided the ten most-shared April Fools&#8217; Day videos on YouTube. Take a look back at some of the best online pranks, and let us know your favorite in the comments. 1. Gmail Motion Last year, Google announced a "new feature" in Gmail that would allow your webcam to recognize simple actions like pretending to open an envelope in order to open your inbox. Because gesture recognition is indeed a hot trend, this video is almost real enough to believe. Click here to view this gallery. More About: April Fools' Day, features, humor, VideoFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/april-fools-day-videos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/april-fools-day-videos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Resume Tips for Technology Professionals</title>
      <description>Tracy Cashman is a partner and general manager in the Information Technology division at Winter, Wyman. Find out more on the Winter, Wyman blog or follow on Twitter @WinterWyman. Everyone can use a little help with their resume, especially if they&#8217;re pursuing a career in a highly technical field. These ten tips can help tech professionals optimize their resumes in order to nab that great gig. Do you have a foolproof tip for a technical resume? Let us know in the comments. 1. Understand Attention Spans Keep in mind that people read resumes about halfway down the page/screen before deciding if they are going to continue reading, save it for later or hit the delete button. Anything marketable about you should be in the top third of the resume. 2. Make It an Appropriate Length The optimal length of the resume will depend on your experience. A person with a single year&#8217;s experience and a four-page resume is in trouble, as is a person with 10 years experience and a one-page resume. Be concise and try to fit your resume into three pages. Need to cut down? You don&#8217;t need an objective &#8212; it&#8217;s a waste of precious space, unless you are a career changer. 3. General Summaries Bad, Technical Summaries Good General summaries can help if used sparingly and appropriately. Technical summaries are more helpful, because the first person reading your resume could be non-technical and only knowledgeable enough to look for keywords. However, there should not be a laundry list of every technology you have ever heard about. 4. Dates Matter Be clear about your dates of employment. Most companies want to see months, not just years &#8212; especially if you have some jumps or if you are currently unemployed (i.e. they want to see how long you have been out). It&#8217;s better to be upfront than to make them guess. 5. Highlight Accomplishments, Not Just Job Functions The descriptions of your positions should ideally be a mix of a broad overview and specific accomplishments. That way, recruiters will know what you did day-to-day, but also what effect your activities had on the overall company or department. 6. Quality Writing Still Matters Long-winded paragraphs or bullets are mind numbing, but short choppy sentences can appear simplistic. The ideal resume should have a combination of short paragraphs and bullets &#8212; or even just bullets. If you opt for bullets, combine related activities into one bullet where appropriate to save room. 7. Use Action Verbs The most overused phrases on resumes are &#8220;responsible for&#8221; or &#8220;participated in.&#8221; It&#8217;s hard to know if you were just a bystander or a true contributor or even a leader on a project. It&#8217;s okay to use these terms once or twice, but it&#8217;s much better to use something like &#8220;managed,&#8221; &#8220;completed,&#8221; &#8220;administered,&#8221; &#8220;developed,&#8221; etc. If you are having trouble coming up with action verbs, Thesaurus.com should be your new best friend. 8. There Are No Rules About Education Placement Education placement is variable. If you went to a particularly good school, have an advanced degree or have a very relevant degree to the types of roles you are pursuing, then it might be worth putting at the top, but it&#8217;s okay for education to be at the bottom, too. The same applies for certifications &#8212; but if you have many, then it might consume too much space at the top. Assuming your resume has the experience to back up the certifications, your prospective employer will be intrigued enough to get to them at the end. 9. People are Not That Interested in Interests The ubiquitous &#8220;Interests&#8221; section isn&#8217;t really necessary; however, if there&#8217;s something you are particularly proud of and it&#8217;s short, then feel free to include it at the end of your resume. There is always the possibility that when you put &#8220;competitive running&#8221; on your resume that the person reading your resume is a marathoner and gives you an interview for that reason. However, you should exclude any activities that could be seen as overly political or offensive. 10. Be Prepared With A Versatile Resume Template Sometimes it&#8217;s valuable to have more than one version of your resume. For example, if your background could be applicable to manager or individual contributor positions, you don&#8217;t want to scare someone off with a heavy manager resume for a contributor role or vice versa. However, you should not make yourself crazy writing a new resume for every position that comes up (an especially tempting habit if you are unemployed). You should develop a resume template you feel comfortable with, and then make minor tweaks if necessary. Also, be sure to update your resume annually to avoid having to revamp it in a panic when you really need it. Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Specialist &#8211; Social Media Community Management at Tiffany &amp; Co. in New York City Director, Field Marketing at Starwood Hotels &amp; Resorts in Scottsdale, AZ Vice President, Digital at Fenton in San Francisco More About: features, job search series, mashable, resume, tech jobsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/tech-resume-tip/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/01/tech-resume-tip/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Networking Gets Easier: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?LinkedIn Makes it Easier to Grow Your Professional Network: LinkedIn rolls out an update for the People You May Know feature with a streamlined user experience and improved accuracy and relevance of your recommendations.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JmvumZbpaNITweetDeck Updates Lists, Activity, Media and More: &#8220;This update introduces some great new features as well as a host of smaller improvements and bug fixes. Check out this video for a quick tour of the updates, and read on for more information.&#8221;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=idEBs_9PGUMGoogle+ Hangouts SlideShare App Rolls Out: Google+ is enabling developers to share any hangout app with the entire Google+ community and SlideShare is one of the featured apps at launch."This new app allows you and your friends and colleagues around the world to present and discuss SlideShare content in real time."Updated Pinterest Terms: These &#8220;updated Terms of Service, Acceptable Use Policy and Privacy Policy are easier to understand and better reflect the direction our company is headed in the future.&#8221;Here are a couple of social media tools worth noting:Cacoo: Check out the new Google+ hangout Cacoo app to wire-frame, mind-map and diagram with others.Using Cacoo for Google+ hangouts, members can share diagrams during a live video chat.Mighty Apps: This new suite of apps, management tools and analytics from Strutta enables marketers to launch apps on an unlimited number of Facebook pages with an unlimited number of fans under a single subscription.Mighty Apps allows marketers to create everyday social experiences for their fans on Facebook.And don&#8217;t miss this:Social Media Examiner presents Social Media Success Summit 2012! (online conference).Join 27 social media experts at Social Media Examiner&#8217;s big online conference! Go here to learn more.What social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/linkedin-networking-gets-easier-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/linkedin-networking-gets-easier-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>39 New Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>Did you spend this week buying lottery tickets and following the Mega Millions jackpot? Well, now that you know you didn&#8217;t win, it&#8217;s time to throw away your tickets and catch up on the new digital media resources you missed on Mashable. This week we have the most-followed men on Pinterest, tips for how to be more genuinely engaging online, and 15 sessions you can&#8217;t miss at Mashable Connect 2012. We&#8217;ve also covered the evolution of Anonymous, cities that are benefiting from mobile apps, and cases that will make your white iPhone pop. We even have photos from an office tour of GetGlue&#8216;s fun-filled space. Here are the best of this week&#8217;s social media, business and technology resources. Editor&#8217;s Picks The Evolution of Anonymous The evolution of Anonymous, a notorious group of hackers that has acquired a worldwide following. Plus, the group&#8217;s top 10 defining hacks. Stickers Galore: Check Out GetGlue&#8217;s Fun-Filled Office [PICS] GetGlue&#8217;s New York City headquarters are full of stickers, pop culture and fun. The 10 Most-Followed Men on Pinterest Men are influential on Pinterest, too. Find out the top 10 male users on the social network. How do their numbers stack up to the gals? Behind the Scenes of the World&#8217;s First Live-Tweeted Open-Heart Surgery Doctors and digital pros from the hospital that pulled off the world&#8217;s first live-tweeted open-heart surgery give their inside story. 10 Tips for Raising Money on Kickstarter The lessons one Kickstarter participant learned are worth knowing. If you&#8217;re looking to get funded on Kickstarter, here are ten tips to help you succeed. Social Media 9 Free Tumblr Themes That Look Like Pinterest Looking to turn your Tumblr into a Pinterest board? Several themes can help make that happen. How to Make Images Stand Out on Pinterest [INFOGRAPHIC] With more than 12 million users on Pinterest it&#8217;s important to make your images stand out. Here&#8217;s how to optimize your pins. 20 TV Shows With the Most Social Media Buzz This Week [CHART] Which TV shows generate the most buzz on social networks? Find out each week from our social TV chart. Mashable Connect Agenda: 15 Exciting Sessions to Learn From We&#8217;re excited to announce the Mashable Connect 2012 agenda. This year&#8217;s lineup covers a wide range of topics on the state and future of digital. 20 Over-The-Top Tweets About the Mega Millions Jackpot The mind-boggling $540 million Mega Millions jackpot spawned multitudes of entertaining Twitter messages about the lottery. The Evolution of Facebook for Brands Facebook Timeline for businesses is officially here. A look back at the major Facebook milestones that lead to this. For more social media news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s social media channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Business &amp; Marketing 5 Key Talents of Successful Startup Founders Some qualities are essential to becoming a successful startup founder. These five talents, in particular, are vital for entrepreneurs. 4 Tips For Authentic Online Engagement When you think about authenticity as it relates to your brand&#8217;s social media efforts, a key factor is what you stand for and what&#8217;s meaningful to you. Attention Marketers: Back-to-School Season Has Already Started [INFOGRAPHIC] Research from Gen Y-focused marketing agency Mr. Youth shows that conversations about the upcoming school year are already happening. How American Express Grows Its Massive Social Media Presence The credit card company is innovating for both customers and merchants on their social media platforms. Check out how AmEx has gone digital. 6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media Facebook, Twitter and Instagram are great for building your brand &#8212; but how do you find new customers? 10 Ways to Humanize Your Brand On Social Media Humanizing a brand is just that: the attempt to interact with each customer on a personal level. Here are 10 ways companies can work to create a more human brand via social media. Shoptiques Lets You Shop Boutiques Like a Local Shop local boutiques online, city by city. For more business news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s business channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Tech &amp; Mobile 5 Exciting Innovations That Will Change Computing in 2012 Technical innovations are on the way that promise to bridge the gap between the physical and digital worlds like never before. 6 Must-Have Apps for the Samsung Galaxy Note Here are six apps that no Samsung Galaxy Note user should be without. Your Profile Pic Has Nothing on These Guys [VIDEO] Think your vacation album is sweet? Think again. These guys take scrapbooking to a whole new level. 4 Hot Apps for Microvideo Blogging With microvideo blogging apps, you can record short video clips and share them instantly over social platforms. Here are our four faves. 18 Amazing Photos of NASA&#8217;s &#8216;Five Rockets in Five Minutes&#8217; Launch NASA launched five rockets, each 80 seconds apart, into the skies over Virginia early on Tuesday. Will This Adorable Robot Rabbit Be Your Next Digital Media Hub? The Karotz is a little rabbit robot with a big personality. Check out how its creators hope to revolutionize the personalized robotics industry. 10 Ice-Cool White iPhone Cases We&#8217;ve found 10 cases that work brilliantly with the white iPhone. 10 Fun Notepads to Geek Up Your Desk From &#8220;social&#8221; sticky notes to LEGO notebooks to Google Doodle notecards, we think you&#8217;ll find something tempting in our selection. How to Avoid the Common Pitfalls of Mobile App Development We asked several leaders in mobile development to share the common issues that come when creating a new app. Here&#8217;s what they had to say. The Future of Funny: How Old and New Media Collaborate on Comedy How old and new media work together in pursuit of comedy. A History of Hacktivism [INFOGRAPHIC] Learn how hacktivism evolved to become a powerful virtual weapon in today&#8217;s digital age. 10 Classic Gadgets Upcycled Into Fashion Accessories We&#8217;ve collected 10 fashion accessories upcycled from the gadgets of your youth. These 10 Hilarious Podcasts Will Make You LOL If you&#8217;re looking for some of the funniest podcasts, we&#8217;ve rounded up 10 channels. Plug in your headphones and get ready to LOL in public. 5 Cities Benefiting From Mobile Apps Check out how a handful of cities across the U.S. takes advantage of mobile to improve their communities and government efficiency. 3 Reasons Facebook Brand Pages Are Good for Businesses Not everyone is cheering about Facebook Timeline for businesses. The reality is, the new layout will present many great opportunities for companies using it to merchandise their products. Here are three reasons why Facebook&#8217;s new brand pages will benefit sellers and social commerce as a whole. 8 Easy PC Pranks to Trick Your Friends With April Fools&#8217; Day on the horizon, it&#8217;s the perfect time to play some epic pranks on your PC-using co-workers, friends, family and frenemies. 10 Excellent PC Games for Less Than $10 Need a gaming fix on the cheap? Check out these 10 winning PC games, all for less than $10. How to Respond to Any Situation With an Animated GIF There&#8217;s an animated GIF for every occasion! The blog #WhatShouldWeCallMe brilliantly responds to classic situations. 8 Crazy Gadgets to Buy If You Win Mega Millions What would you buy if you won Friday&#8217;s world-record $640 million Mega Millions jackpot? You can purchase plenty of things with the half-a-billion dollar prize, including these eight gems. Tools to Generate Your Random Mega Millions Numbers Can these random number generators help you win the record-high Mega Millions jackpot? Probably not, but it might be worth a try. Top 10 iPhone Word Games Go pick up a dictionary and fortify the ol&#8217; lexicon &#8212; these iPhone word games demand clever wordplay in order to succeed. For more tech news and resources, you can follow Mashable&#8216;s tech channel on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci. More About: Business, COMMUNICATIONS, Features Week In Review, Social Media, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/digital-media-resources-3-31/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/31/digital-media-resources-3-31/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
