<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Store Refused to Sell to Farsi-Speaking Customers [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Did Apple Store employees in Alpharetta, Ga., refuse to sell an iPhone and an iPad to Farsi-speaking customers because they said they would be sending at least one of the devices to a friend in Iran? That's what Sarah Sabet, a U.S. citizen of Iranian heritage, told WSB-TV, calling the experience "discrimination" and "very hurtful." Sabet, a 19-year old student at the University of Georgia, was reportedly at an Apple Store in a local mall with a friend to buy a pair of new iDevices. After Apple Store employees overheard Sabet and her friend speaking to one another in Farsi, they asked them what language they were speaking, where they were from and where the devices were headed. When Sabet said the devices were a gift for a friend in Iran, the Apple Store denied the sale. "When we said 'Farsi, I'm from Iran,' he said, 'I just can't sell this to you. Our countries have bad relations,'" Sabet told WSB-TV. The station sent a reporter to talk to a manager at the Apple Store, who said the store didn't make the sale because of strict limitations on U.S.-Iranian trade relations. According to Apple's export policy, the "exportation, reexportation, sale or supply" of Apple products "is strictly prohibited without prior authorization by the U.S. Government." Sabet, though, didn't buy that explanation. In her opinion, she was racially profiled. "He didn't have any business asking me what country I was from," Sabet said. "I actually walked out in tears." After the emotional episode, Sabet called an Apple customer service agent, who was apologetic and told Sabet she could buy the equipment through Apple's website. On Tuesday, the Council on American-Islamic Relations called the Apple Store's treatment of Sabet and her friend discriminatory. &#8220;Apple must revise its policies to ensure that customers do not face discriminatory treatment based on their religion, ethnicity or national origin,&#8221; said CAIR National Executive Director Nihad Awad. &#8220;If the actions of these Apple employees reflected company policy, that policy must be changed and all employees retrained.&#8221; Mashable has contacted Apple for comment, but has not yet received a response. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, arakonyunus</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/apple-store-iran/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/apple-store-iran/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter&#8217;s Outage Is Its Biggest in 8 Months</title>
      <description>Twitter suffered its most prolonged outage in eight months on Thursday as the site was down for more than an hour for the first time since October 2011. However, the previous outage took place in a relatively quiet time of day for the service -- midnight to 1 a.m. EST on Oct. 7, according to tracking site Pingdom. Twitter was mostly down for another one-hour period on Nov. 29 from 8 a.m. to 9 a.m. EST, according to Pingdom, and suffered on-off periods for about an hour on Dec. 14, 2011 and Dec. 31 during peak times as well. Still, according to Pingdom's figures, Twitter has enjoyed 99%-plus uptime for every month this year and hit 100% in April. That's a far cry from 2007 and 2008, w&#8230; Continue reading... More About: fail whale, trending, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/twitters-outage-biggest-in-8-months/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/twitters-outage-biggest-in-8-months/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter crashes hard, Internet freaks out</title>
      <description>Cue the collective Internet freakout! Twitter went down for more than an hour on Thursday afternoon, depriving users of a place to complain that Twitter is down.</description>
      <link>http://money.cnn.com//2012/06/21/technology/twitter-down/index.htm?section=money_topstories&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+rss%2Fmoney_topstories+%28Top+Stories%29</link>
      <guid>http://money.cnn.com//2012/06/21/technology/twitter-down/index.htm?section=money_topstories&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+rss%2Fmoney_topstories+%28Top+Stories%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers Take Credit for Twitter Outages</title>
      <description>Twitter has been up and down throughout Thursday -- and now a group of hackers known as UGNazi is taking credit for causing the outages. "We just #TangoDown'd twitter.com for 40 minutes worldwide! #UGnazi," reads a tweet sent from @UG on Thursday afternoon that was directed at accounts associated with the more well-known and widespread Anonymous hacker collective, as well as the media outlet Russia Today. #TangoDown is a term adopted by Anonymous and other hackers and botnet owners referring to a successful attack against a targeted website. Outages are most often caused by some combination of Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attacks and botnets. Both methods overload a target&#8230; Continue reading... More About: anonymous, cybersecurity, hackers, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/twitter-hacked/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/twitter-hacked/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lets Give Karen -The bus monitor- H Klein A Vacation! -- Indiegogo</title>
      <description>I&#8217;m not sure if this has already been brought to everyone&#8217;s attention or not, but here is the deal:http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l93wAqnPQwk&amp;feature=player_embeddedAbove is a video of a 68-year-old bus monitor named Karen Klein being verbally harassed by a group of middle schoolers on their way home from Athena Middle School in Greece, New York. Throughout the ten minute video, you can hear the kids verbally berate the woman, calling her a bitch, fatass, poor, ugly, and various other words of the like. At one point in the video, you can hear one of the kids yell, &#8220;You&#8217;re so fuckin poor you fat ass,&#8221; in which Karen responds, &#8220;I try to live by some of these words, I try and it&#8217;s really hard,&#8221; referring to the words on her purse. Now, I don&#8217;t know about you, but that broke my fucking heart. There&#8217;s even a point in the video where one of the kids touches Karen&#8217;s arm in an attempt to make fun of her. I&#8217;m not sure why these kids would want to bully a senior citizen to tears, but I feel we should do something, or at least try.She doesn't earn nearly enough ($15,506) to deal with some of the trash she is surrounded by. Lets give her something she will never forget, a vacation of a lifetime!Link to the school&#8217;s website: http://www.greece.k12.ny.us/athena-middle.cfmBus number: #784School&#8217;s fax number: (585) 966-4039Principal of the school&#8217;s E-mail address: David.Richardson@greece.k12.ny.usStaff E-mails &amp; Other Links: http://www.greece.k12.ny.us/staff_directory.cfm http://www.greece.k12.ny.us/contact.cfm?school=7 https://maps.google.com/maps?q=Greeced=0CGoQ_AUoAg http://pastebin.com/mMvJ4ZP8Links to the videos: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oipwaZos58E&amp;feature=plcp http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l93wAqnPQwk&amp;feature=plcp http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SBedTlo7BDs&amp;feature=plcpKaren&#8217;s Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/kklein1944</description>
      <link>http://www.indiegogo.com/loveforkarenhklein</link>
      <guid>http://www.indiegogo.com/loveforkarenhklein</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gabi Is a New Way to Visualize and Interact With Facebook</title>
      <description>How you view your Facebook feed just got a little different. Gabi is a new way to visualize and interact with the world's largest social network. Unlike other apps and sites that simply display your feed in different ways, Gabi lets you sort content on Facebook by things that are relevant to you. The app sorts that content by letting you create and ask questions from a Mad-Libs style template of options. You can ask, for instance, &#8220;Which of my videos are the most liked?&#8221; or &#8220;Who are my single male friends?&#8221; You can even get super specific with Gabi and ask exceptionally detailed questions such as &#8220;Who are my married Aquarius guy friends?&#8221; Results are displayed on t&#8230; Continue reading... More About: App, Facebook, iOS, iphone</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/gabi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/gabi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Essential Facebook Marketing Resources</title>
      <description>In our Facebook Marketing Series, Mashable offers tips, insights and a bevy of tools to enhance your marketing on the 900-million strong social network. We know that brands typically reach just 16% of the fan base they have worked so hard to build, but our tips for engagement and explanation of Facebook&#8217;s ad suite should help you broaden your reach and increase engagement. For even more tips, follow our Facebook marketing topic. While Facebook has never officially divulged exactly how to increase reach &#8212; though it did release an ad product, Reach Generator &#8212; there are several tactics known to work. First, let&#8217;s review the EdgeRank trifecta. EdgeRank is the algorithm used by Facebook to determine the most screen-worthy content. Three factors, multiplied together, determine your content&#8217;s value: affinity, weight and time. The affinity score is based on how often a fan has engaged with your brand content in the past, including page visits. Weight, or popularity, is determined by the type and quantity of engagement your post receives (e.g. Likes, comments). Lastly, time and the decay of your post matters; as your content ages and engagement wanes, it becomes less relevant and therefore less likely to appear in a user&#8217;s News Feed. Understanding the EdgeRank algorithm is the first step for brands to improve their content strategy. Last year, Facebook launched a new initiative built around, of all things, verbs. The company&#8217;s Open Graph sought to do something interesting with the way we communicate with each other: Any action expressed on Facebook could become a branding opportunity. Perhaps the best example of Open Graph at work is Spotify. If you listen to Green Day&#8217;s &#8220;Dookie&#8221; on Spotify, then all of your Facebook friends will see that you&#8217;re enjoying the album, and perhaps they&#8217;ll even mark their approval with a Like or comment. You don&#8217;t have to do anything to initiate the action except listen to the album (and don&#8217;t initiate the app&#8217;s &#8220;private listening mode&#8220;). Meanwhile, Spotify gets lots of free exposure simply by having users run its service. Although the appeal for app-makers like Spotify is obvious, Open Graph represents a challenge of sorts for marketers. If you sell soft drinks, for instance, how are you supposed to get people to do anything but &#8220;Like&#8221; your brand? But beyond that obstacle is another, perhaps more daunting one: Marketers are wary of handing over their data to Facebook. Open Graph has now been available for almost nine months and there are just a handful of case studies of brands using it successfully. However, there are a couple of high-profile examples of marketers using it well, including Ford&#8216;s Customizer app and USA Today&#8216;s Ad Meter. At this point, most people know to market their business on Facebook &#8212; there are more than 900 million people on the social platform, constantly &#8220;liking,&#8221; sharing, commenting and posting, after all. It&#8217;s a great audience, but there are a few mistakes you&#8217;ll want to avoid. Mashable spoke with the Facebook team as well as Buddy Media CEO Michael Lazerow to learn about the most common Facebook marketing mistakes. &#8220;There&#8217;s actually a science behind this &#8212; yes, it&#8217;s an art, but we have found some strong conclusions that there are levers that marketers can pull to be more successful,&#8221; says Sean Bruich, head of measurement platform and standards at Facebook. His team recently studied 1,200 posts by 23 brands over a month-long period, using quantitative measurements to determine the unique impact of each post. &#8220;This is not a black box &#8230; there&#8217;s a lot of opportunity to understand how to make your marketing better.&#8221; Timeline, the photo-heavy redesign that Facebook herded brands into in March, has changed the way brands market on Facebook. Although there have been conflicting reports about Timeline&#8217;s effect on brand engagement, marketers are realizing that Timeline may not be more effective &#8212; but it definitely is different. However, Timeline&#8217;s not the only catalyst for the changing marketing ecosystem on Facebook. Another is Facebook&#8217;s financial situation: The company is under huge pressure from Wall Street to figure out a winning formula for advertising on the platform. With about 133 million users in the U.S., the social network has a potential audience bigger than the Super Bowl&#8217;s. Though GM has punctured Facebook&#8217;s air of inevitability, most advertisers haven&#8217;t lost faith enough to drop advertising on the platform wholesale. The combination of these two things has ushered in five new Facebook marketing trends. What&#8217;s the best way to market your brand on Facebook? According to Peter Shankman, an entrepreneur and venture capitalist with a background in marketing and consulting, the answer is actually pretty easy: &#8220;Sharing for the sake of just hearing yourself talk is pointless.&#8221; Yes, the key to doing more is doing it with less. &#8220;You want to engage your audience and make sure that they feel like they&#8217;re apart of something &#8212; not just being marketed to,&#8221; Shankman explains. &#8220;Then they will do your PR for you.&#8221; Mashable spoke with Shankman about the inner workings of Facebook marketing and what users really want to see on your brand page. On Leap Day 2012, Facebook gathered all of its marketing executives in New York City for a coming-out party of sorts for a slew of new ad products. To people outside the industry, the promise of new initiatives might appear a bit on the dull side. But for advertisers, anything that Facebook does for advertising is of interest. Among the products Facebook introduced were Premium on Facebook, Reach Generator, Offers and Logged Out ads. The company also asked brands to embrace a paradigm shift from advertising to &#8220;Stories,&#8221; Facebook&#8217;s preferred term for brand-related messages. Since that time, a few big brands have experimented with the new tools. Over the past few years, Facebook marketing has moved from the domain of early adopters to a mainstream focus for nearly all businesses. During that time, a large number of social media marketing tools have emerged to help companies reach and engage with fans, run promotions and contests, and even integrate Facebook Ad programs with the rest of their social marketing. But while most marketers are currently using the myriad applications that allow them to run their ongoing programs, they may not be as familiar with tools they can use to enhance their day-to-day activities and make their programs more effective. For some companies, one Facebook Brand Page might not be enough. For example, if a restaurant chain prides itself on local ingredients, or a business seeks to cultivate a strong community around each brick-and-mortar outlet, it might make sense to have a Brand Page for each location. But then again, does a brand really want to divvy up its audience and dilute it among several similar pages? While chunking up an audience among numerous Facebook Brand Pages may seem counterintuitive, it does work to the advantage of some brands, such as Lululemon and Sprinkles. But other small businesses, such as Butter Lane and Sweetgreen, find that one Facebook Brand Page does a proper job of cultivating a strong community behind the brand. Customers know that the squeaky wheel gets the grease, and web-savvy customers know that Facebook is the ultimate squeak amplifier. According to Forrester Research, 27% of U.S. online consumers sought customer service support on the web in 2011, and currently three out of four expect a reply to a negative comment posted on Facebook. Unfortunately, many brands still don&#8217;t incorporate customer service into their social strategy, despite the fact that Facebook is one of the best venues in which to turn your customers&#8217; negative comments into brand opportunities. Here are eight tips to help you improve your Facebook customer support initiative and, in turn, raise your brand&#8217;s reputation, decrease your inbound service requests, acquire new customers and turn infrequent customers into brand loyalists. Read the full story and see the video here.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/facebook-marketing-tips-2/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/facebook-marketing-tips-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Euro 2012: How Soccer is Going Digital</title>
      <description>The Euro 2012 European soccer championship begins its elimination phase Thursday after nearly two scintillating weeks of group play in Poland and Ukraine. As the stakes raise on the pitch, Mashable spoke with David Farrelly, the head of UEFA.com, to get a sense of how soccer's second biggest international tournament is playing out in the digital realm. (The Union of European Football Associations is the governing body of European soccer and runs the Continent's once-every-four-years championship.) We were surprised to learn that the United States accounts for a bigger percentage of traffic to UEFA.com than one might think. It consistently places in the top four -- along with the Unite&#8230; Continue reading... More About: sports</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/uefa-euro-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/uefa-euro-2012/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Enhance Your Email Signature</title>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the American Express OPEN Forum, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business. Whether you want to impress a client or score a new job, it's vital that you stand out. But that doesn't always require big thinking -- sometimes the smallest details can be enough to get noticed. One easy way is to jazz up your email signature. You can spice up your sign-off with different colors and fonts, but it's also important to showcase the many facets of your personality and skill set. Don't make email recipients search for your web presence -- provide links to your website and any relevant social media&#8230; Continue reading... More About: email, features, open forum, Small Business</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/enhance-your-email-signature/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/enhance-your-email-signature/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows Phone 8 and Two Other Stories You Need to Know</title>
      <description>Welcome to this morning&#8217;s edition of &#8220;First To Know,&#8221; a series in which we keep you in the know on what&#8217;s happening in the digital world. Today, we&#8217;re looking at three particularly interesting stories. At its Windows Phone Developer Conference in San Francisco, Microsoft has unveiled its next generation mobile platform &#8212; Windows Phone 8. Unfortunately, some bad news came with the announcement: Nokia will not be upgrading current Lumia devices to the new platform. Instead, some of its features will be brought to Lumias in the form of Windows Phone 7.8 &#8212; check out our first look here. Samsung Galaxy S II on AT&amp;T and Sony Xperia S Get Android 4.0 AT&amp;T customers who have a Samsung Galaxy S II will be happy to know that they can finally upgrade their device to Android 4.0.3. The same goes for Sony Xperia S, which got its own Ice Cream Sandwich update. New iPhone to Have a Smaller, 19-Pin Connector The next generation iPhone will have a new dock connector, slimmer than the current one and sporting 19 pins, TechCrunch reports citing unnamed sources. If true, this means that a large number of iPhone accessories will not be compatible with the new device.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/windows-phone-8-brief/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/21/windows-phone-8-brief/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ever Imagined a World Without Internet? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Steve Carrell may be seeking a friend for the end of the world, but here at Mashable, we're more concerned with the end of the Internet. Can you imagine it? Instead of an iPad, you'd be clutching a weighty $1,200 Encyclopedia Brittanica as you rock yourself to sleep. And instead of tweeting with pals halfway around the world, we'd be licking stamps that would total $6.3 trillion in the United States alone. We're cringing at the thought. SEE ALSO: The Internet Is Ruining Your Brain [INFOGRAPHIC] Online Education created this graphic detailing the nightmare that would be the world without Internet. Sure, we're grateful to the World Wide Web for giving us all the joy of narcoleptic ca&#8230; Continue reading... More About: infographics, internet, Social Media, Tech, trending, web</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/world-without-internet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/20/world-without-internet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
