<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>4 Business School Trends to Watch</title>
      <description>Business in the United States has experienced seismic shifts in the last decade, and business schools are no exception. These developments have been fueled by technology, the global financial crisis, cultural shifts, and the introduction of Gen Y into the business world. Traditional MBAs, which have usually focused on accounting and finance, have a hard time producing the type of business leaders companies are currently looking for. Specifically, companies want ethical problem solvers with strong digital and entrepreneurial skills, who are team players and work well in diverse environments. Yet, a 2008 study of top business schools found that curricula lacked valued &#8220;thematic elem&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, contributor, entrepreneurs, features, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/business-school-trends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/business-school-trends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid 17 Internet Scams [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>We've all heard the horror stories: credit card fraud, pyramid schemes, phishing, identity theft -- the list of scams goes on and on. "Oh, that won't happen to me," you think. "I know the signs." No one wants to think he'll be counted among the fooled. But the truth is, you can never be too cautious about scams on the web. [More from Mashable: L.A. Kings Are NHL&#8217;s Twitter Champions Too [INFOGRAPHIC]] After all, according to the Internet Crime Complaint Center, yearly dollars lost grew by about $500 million from 2004 to 2009, and the trend isn't showing signs of slowing. SEE ALSO: How to Check If Your LinkedIn Password Was Stolen [More from Mashable: Is Social Media Destroying Real-World Relationships? [INFOGRAPHIC]] Background Check compiled research on Internet scams from around the world to help you spot the red flags. Among the stats: Nearly 66% of complaints (predominantly phishing) with a known perpetrator location originated in the U.S. Meanwhile, despite having the world's largest online population, China only accounts for 3.1% of those scams. Check out this infographic for information on the types of scams to look out for, and how to make sure you don't wind up a victim. This story originally published on Mashable here.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/avoid-17-internet-scams-infographic-155710298.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/avoid-17-internet-scams-infographic-155710298.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Purported Xbox 720 To Cost $299 With Blu-ray Support, Kinect 2 And Virtual Reality In Time For Holiday 2013</title>
      <description>The current gen Xbox may be a year past its halfway point but a purported &#8220;leaked&#8221; document dating back to August 2010 from a Microsoft presentation details the next gen Xbox 720 in great detail. Features for the next Xbox, according to the document, will include native Blu-ray playback, full support for HD and 3-D, and beefed up hardware (graphics and processor) under the hood. Other bits and pieces from the doc include PVR functionality, a low power mode setting during media playback and what amounts to an always-on mode. Gates did say years ago that the Xbox would eventually become the nerve center for any living room. And based on recent events, it&#8217;s not entirely out of the realm of possibility that Microsoft is making a play to turn the Xbox into a stand-alone set-top box for all things video. After all, they do offer Hulu, Netflix and ESPN. Also, future Microsoft devices will have universal access to content whether you&#8217;re on the Xbox, your smartphone or tablet. Duh, right? The most interesting part of the leaked 56-page document &#8211; which has since been taken down &#8211; is something called Fortaleza, Portuguese for &#8220;Fortress&#8221;. Given the environment of traditional cable providers, the next logical step for the Xbox and others is to create and dictate what content they provide for their respective platforms. At this point, that could be anything but the document details Fortaleza as a way of consuming content through VR. A set of wireless glasses that supposedly won&#8217;t arrive until 2014 will connect to the Xbox 720 over Wi-Fi and give the player/user access to all manner of content in a virtual world. Future versions will apparently connect over a cellular connection for persistent connectivity &#8211; most likely 4G. Whether Microsoft announces the 720 at next year&#8217;s E3 is anyone&#8217;s guess.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/16/purported-xbox-720-to-cost-299-with-blu-ray-support-kinect-2-and-virtual-reality-in-time-for-holiday-2013/</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/16/purported-xbox-720-to-cost-299-with-blu-ray-support-kinect-2-and-virtual-reality-in-time-for-holiday-2013/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rodney King dead at 47</title>
      <description>Rodney King, whose beating by Los Angeles police in 1991 was caught on camera and sparked riots after the acquittal of the four officers involved, was found dead in his swimming pool Sunday, authorities and his fiancee confirmed. He was 47. King's beating after a high-speed car chase and its aftermath forever changed Los Angeles, its police department and the dialogue on race in America. King was 25 and on parole after a robbery conviction in April 1991. In an interview in 2011, he recalled he had been drinking and was headed home from a friend's house when he saw a police car following him and panicked, thinking he would be sent back to prison. So he attempted to flee. "I had a job to go to that Monday, and I knew I was on parole, and I knew I wasn't supposed to be drinking, and I'm like 'Oh, my God,'" he told CNN. He realized he couldn't outrun the police, but looked for a public place to stop. "I saw all those apartments over there, so I said, 'I'm gonna stop right there,'" he said. "'If it goes down, somebody will see it.'" An amateur cameraman caught the scene as four white police officers struck King more than 50 times with their wooden batons and used a stun gun on him. King said as the officers beat him, they yelled, "We are going to kill you, n***er," although the officers denied using racial slurs. The video shows King cowering on the ground and attempting to crawl away as he is surrounded by a crowd of police officers. Four of them used their nightsticks to strike him. King was beaten nearly to death. Three surgeons operated on him for five hours. The video of the beating appeared on national television two days later, focusing attention on the issue of racially-motivated police brutality. "We finally caught the Loch Ness Monster with a camcorder," King attorney Milton Grimes said. Four LAPD officers -- Theodore Briseno, Laurence Powell, Timothy Wind and Sgt. Stacey Koon -- were indicted on charges of assault with a deadly weapon and excessive use of force by a police officer. But following a three-month trial in the predominantly white Los Angeles suburb of Simi Valley, three of the officers were acquitted of all charges. The jury, which had no white members, deadlocked on one charge of excessive force against Powell, and a mistrial was declared on that charge. Powell's attorney, Michael Stone, said earlier this year the unedited video worked against King and helped prove the officers' case. "Most of the nation only saw a few snippets where it's the most violent," Stone said. "They didn't see (King) get up and run at Powell." But African-Americans in Los Angeles exploded in outrage. Rioters ran through the streets -- looting businesses, torching buildings and attacking those who were in the wrong place at the wrong time. The violence was responsible for more than 50 deaths and $1 billion in property damage. On the third day of rioting, King emerged from seclusion to make a plea: "People, I just want to say, can we all get along? Can we get along?" The violence ceased, but the</description>
      <link>http://www.ksat.com/news/Rodney-King-dead-at-47/-/478452/15135268/-/gg6jtxz/-/index.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.ksat.com/news/Rodney-King-dead-at-47/-/478452/15135268/-/gg6jtxz/-/index.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rodney King Dead at 47</title>
      <description>Rodney King -- the man who was at the center of the infamous Los Angeles riots -- was found dead this morning. He was 47.According to our sources, King's fianc&#233;e found him dead at the bottom of a pool.King became famous in 1991 when he was the&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://www.tmz.com/2012/06/17/rodney-king-dead/</link>
      <guid>http://www.tmz.com/2012/06/17/rodney-king-dead/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Apps You Don&#8217;t Want To Miss</title>
      <description>Temple Run Brave Brave, Pixar's newest film, officially hits theaters on June 22, but the mobile game for the movie became available this week. Based on popular endless-runner game Temple Run, Temple Run Brave is a new take on the game, where you play the part of Merida, the lead character in the film. Available for iOS and Android, gameplay involves running through environments that resemble the Scotish landscape from the film and collecting coins. The game also has an archery element &#8211; a huge part of the movie itself &#8211; where you can tap targets along your journey to earn extra points. Click here to view this gallery. It can be tough to keep up with all the new apps released each week. But you&#8217;re in luck: We take care of a lot of that for you, creating a roundup each weekend of some of our own highlights from the week. This week we found a new app to edit photos on your iPhone, as well as another that lets you heavily customize the videos you record with your phone. If you're looking for a deal, a new coupon app will help you make sure you're getting the best discounts possible while you shop. If you're walking, running, or biking to your favorite store, another app will help you donate some cash to charity while working off those pounds. While you're out and about, it's important to stay safe.&#8230; Continue reading... More About: android, App, apps, iphone, mobile app, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/apps-roundup-6-15/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/apps-roundup-6-15/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Tech Concepts Changing the World</title>
      <description>In our social entrepreneurship series, The World at Work, Mashable interviewed the faces behind the startups and projects that are working to make a global impact. These companies are tapping into the public's power to change the world through tech, whether it's encouraging others to take up the challenge of living below the poverty line or helping teens give back to their local communities. While the companies are diverse, they are all on a mission to change our lives for the better and improve society. Here's a final roundup of the series, including exclusive video interviews with the founders of these innovative startups. To read more and watch the videos, click through to the full&#8230; Continue reading... More About: features, mashable, World at Work</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/world-at-work-12/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/world-at-work-12/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Tech Concepts Changing the World</title>
      <description>In our social entrepreneurship series, The World at Work, Mashable interviewed the faces behind the startups and projects that are working to make a global impact. These companies are tapping into the public's power to change the world through tech, whether it's encouraging others to take up the challenge of living below the poverty line or helping teens give back to their local communities. While the companies are diverse, they are all on a mission to change our lives for the better and improve society. Here's a final roundup of the series, including exclusive video interviews with the founders of these innovative startups. To read more and watch the videos, click through to the full&#8230; Continue reading... More About: features, mashable, World at Work</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/world-at-work-12/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/16/world-at-work-12/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Brands Are Becoming Publishers</title>
      <description>According to Deanna Brown, CEO of Federated Media Publishing, &#8220;Content, in the right context, is ultimately king.&#8221; The publishing industry is undergoing a massive disruption, in which storytelling, advertising, and technology are beginning to intersect. By having unhindered access to social and mobile media platforms, brands are experimenting with paid, owned, and earned media to reach connected consumers in their channels of relevance. As brands dabble in publishing, traditional marketing and advertising networks are also evolving. Federated Media is no stranger to the game. On this episode of Revolution, Deanna Brown explores the curre&#8230; Continue reading... More About: brands, content marketing, revoltiontv, storytelling, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/revolution-federated-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/12/revolution-federated-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[from heyjude] Know and show what you got! - TwentyFeet - TwentyFeet Wiki</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; The performance post for twitter is a cool way to recap your last week for your followers and friends. &lt;p&gt; It's for free. You can do that with your "forever free" twitter account. It contains the changes in your key twitter metrics. We will only post positive changes (e.g. a growing number of followers). The "My week on twitter"-post is published at the beginning of the week automatically (only for authorized accounts and if you choose so).</description>
      <link>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</link>
      <guid>http://www.twentyfeet.com/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=6914054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nikola Tesla was the greatest geek who ever lived - The Oatmeal</title>
      <description>An ode to the father of the electric age.View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Takei Airs News Feed Frustrations, Facebook Responds</title>
      <description>Actor George Takei aired his Facebook frustrations on Wednesday about how updates to the social network's news feed were preventing fans from seeing his posts. It didn't take long for a Facebook employee, who is also a big fan of Takei, to explain why it's virtually impossible for members to see everything that happens on Facebook via the news feed. Takei, who is best known for his former role on Star Trek and his highly active social media presence, turned to his Facebook page after learning brand page owners can now pay to get their posts in front of more eyes. "FB used to allow fans to elect to see ALL posts by selecting 'All Updates' from the right hand corner of a post," Takei&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Facebook, George Takei, Promoted Posts, Social Media, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/george-takei-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/14/george-takei-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
