<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft's new Windows 8 Tablet: "Welcome to Microsoft Surface."</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en/us/default.aspx</link>
      <guid>http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en/us/default.aspx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Unveils Its Mystery Device [LIVE BLOG]</title>
      <description>We're live at the Milk studio in Hollywood for Microsoft's big moment. The software giant has tantalized the rest of the tech world with a mysterious, details-free invite to something major; now it has to deliver on that promise. So what's it to be? The smart money -- and most of your bets, apparently -- is on a game-changing tablet. But what exactly? Xbox tablet with SmartGlass technology, as we suggested earlier Monday? iPad killer? A sub-$500 Kindle Fire competitor? Microsoft partner Barnes &amp; Noble has told us they're not involved in this launch, but could it still be some kind of media reader? We'll know soon enough. The live blog starts at 3:30pm Pacific time, 6:30pm Eastern;&#8230; Continue reading... More About: microsoft, tablets, Windows 8, Xbox 360</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/microsoft-live-blog/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/microsoft-live-blog/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ebook Sales Surpass Hardcover for First Time in U.S.</title>
      <description>American publishers are now bringing in more revenue from ebooks than hardcover books, according to a report published by the Association of American Publishers (AAP). The figures, which were posted on GalleyCat on Friday, show that net sales revenue from ebooks exceeded that of hardcover books in the first quarter of the year: a first. The data was compiled from 1,189 publishers and did not include children's books. Collectively, adult ebooks brought in $282.3 million in Q1. That's an impressive 28.4% increase from the same period a year ago. Young adult and children's ebooks performed even better, catapulting 233% to $64.3 million. Sales of adult hardcover books grew too, but more mo&#8230; Continue reading... More About: amazon, barnes&amp;noble, ebooks, Kindle, Media, publishing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/ebook-hardcover-sales/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/ebook-hardcover-sales/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Sick Yo-Yo Tricks You Have to See to Believe [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>1. Little Yo-Yo Man This toddler, who can yo-yo like a dream, is more proof that yo-yoing is an innate skill. Click here to view this gallery. Not a lot about the yo-yo itself has changed over the decades, but its tricks have become a thousand times more complicated. Ever heard of Buddha's Revenge? The Brain Buster? What about the Mach 5, the Spaghetti, the Zipper, the World Tour, the 3-Leaf Clover or the Double Gerbil? Yeah, we didn't think so. Yo-yoing has been around for years. It first gained popularity in the early 1920s and has since reserved a space in our hearts. There's just something magical and mystical about making a yo-yo spin and flip like crazy. SEE ALSO: 15 Developers Help Atari Re-Imagine &#8216;Pong&#8217; [VIDEO] But it's the typical "looks easier than it actually is" sort of thing. We can't prove it but we thi&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Entertainment, features, games, Video, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/yo-yo-videos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/yo-yo-videos/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Integrates With WordPress: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Integrates With WordPress: WordPress publishers can now &#8220;easily integrate Facebook features, such as social publishing and mentions, through the new Facebook for WordPress plugin.&#8221; Publishers can use social plugins as WordPress widgets to share the Facebook Activity Feed, Recommendations, Comments Box and Customizable Like, Subscribe and Send buttons."Once the plugin is installed, you can cross-post content published to WordPress to your Facebook Timeline and the Facebook Pages you manage. You can also mention the names of Pages and friends as you post to further distribute your content."Twitter Rolls Out Tailored Trends: &#8220;In order to show emerging topics that matter more to you,&#8221; Twitter is improving their algorithms to &#8220;tailor Trends based on your location and who you follow on Twitter.&#8221; This new feature will impact how marketers can use Twitter.If you don't wish to see tailored Trends, but instead want to see a more general list of Trends, just change your location on Twitter.com.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:What kind of traffic is Pinterest driving to your site?What do you think of the new Facebook integration for WordPress?What&#8217;s your &#8220;feeling&#8221; about Facebook?Experience More Expanded Tweets: &#8220;When you expand Tweets containing links to partner websites, you can now see content previews, view images, play videos and more.&#8221;More companies like the the New York Times are partnering with Twitter to deliver rich content inside tweets.Facebook Opens the App Center: The App Center is a &#8220;place for people to find great social apps on the web and mobile.&#8221;The App Center helps high-quality apps grow by promoting those that people enjoy most.Bitly Shares Keyboard Shortcuts: Bitly users can &#8220;pick up some speed while performing some of the most common actions&#8221; with these shortcuts.Keyboard shortcuts for Bitly ninjas.Klout&#8217;s iPhone App Gets a Big Update: There are several new features. Users can now enter any Twitter handle and quickly find that user&#8217;s Klout score.With this new upgrade, users can endorse anyone's influence by swiping a finger across one of their Topics.Facebook Announces a New Ad Exchange: &#8220;Facebook announced a new &#8216;real-time bidding&#8217; ad exchange system for buying ads on the network.&#8221;Here are some social media tools worth noting:Konekt.me: An online platform that makes it extremely simple to build and curate a portfolio of your best work online.Konekt.me features include an easy-to-use, content-specific uploader, customizable collections and an interactive CV/resume feature that help you link your content and experience.Likester: A Facebook advertising tool to help Facebook users, companies and advertisers organize and explore over half a billion Facebook Likes.Check out the other pages your Facebook fans also like.Learnist: Essentially Pinterest with a focus on education. All learning boards are created by users and feature educational material.Unlike Pinterest, you are not limited to posting images on Learnist. You can also post articles, websites and videos.Chill: A video sharing site that allows you and your friends to watch videos together on your own computers while interacting in real time through Facebook."Chill is designed to make video sharing beautiful, simple and contextual."LoveIt: A visual sharing space that allows users to share their finished shopping excursion with the public, privately share the deals they got, and collaboratively plan their next shopping trip.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6FAOJXnPW3sAnd don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-integrates-with-wordpress-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-integrates-with-wordpress-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Essential Facebook Marketing Resources</title>
      <description>In our Facebook Marketing Series, Mashable offers tips, insights and a bevy of tools to enhance your marketing on the 900-million strong social network. We know that brands typically reach just 16% of the fan base they have worked so hard to build, but our tips for engagement and explanation of Facebook&#8217;s ad suite should help you broaden your reach and increase engagement. For even more tips, follow our Facebook marketing topic. While Facebook has never officially divulged exactly how to increase reach &#8212; though it did release an ad product, Reach Generator &#8212; there are several tactics known to work. First, let&#8217;s review the EdgeRank trifecta. EdgeRank is the algorithm used by Facebook to determine the most screen-worthy content. Three factors, multiplied together, determine your content&#8217;s value: affinity, weight and time. The affinity score is based on how often a fan has engaged with your brand content in the past, including page visits. Weight, or popularity, is determined by the type and quantity of engagement your post receives (e.g. Likes, comments). Lastly, time and the decay of your post matters; as your content ages and engagement wanes, it becomes less relevant and therefore less likely to appear in a user&#8217;s News Feed. Understanding the EdgeRank algorithm is the first step for brands to improve their content strategy. Last year, Facebook launched a new initiative built around, of all things, verbs. The company&#8217;s Open Graph sought to do something interesting with the way we communicate with each other: Any action expressed on Facebook could become a branding opportunity. Perhaps the best example of Open Graph at work is Spotify. If you listen to Green Day&#8217;s &#8220;Dookie&#8221; on Spotify, then all of your Facebook friends will see that you&#8217;re enjoying the album, and perhaps they&#8217;ll even mark their approval with a Like or comment. You don&#8217;t have to do anything to initiate the action except listen to the album (and don&#8217;t initiate the app&#8217;s &#8220;private listening mode&#8220;). Meanwhile, Spotify gets lots of free exposure simply by having users run its service. Although the appeal for app-makers like Spotify is obvious, Open Graph represents a challenge of sorts for marketers. If you sell soft drinks, for instance, how are you supposed to get people to do anything but &#8220;Like&#8221; your brand? But beyond that obstacle is another, perhaps more daunting one: Marketers are wary of handing over their data to Facebook. Open Graph has now been available for almost nine months and there are just a handful of case studies of brands using it successfully. However, there are a couple of high-profile examples of marketers using it well, including Ford&#8216;s Customizer app and USA Today&#8216;s Ad Meter. At this point, most people know to market their business on Facebook &#8212; there are more than 900 million people on the social platform, constantly &#8220;liking,&#8221; sharing, commenting and posting, after all. It&#8217;s a great audience, but there are a few mistakes you&#8217;ll want to avoid. Mashable spoke with the Facebook team as well as Buddy Media CEO Michael Lazerow to learn about the most common Facebook marketing mistakes. &#8220;There&#8217;s actually a science behind this &#8212; yes, it&#8217;s an art, but we have found some strong conclusions that there are levers that marketers can pull to be more successful,&#8221; says Sean Bruich, head of measurement platform and standards at Facebook. His team recently studied 1,200 posts by 23 brands over a month-long period, using quantitative measurements to determine the unique impact of each post. &#8220;This is not a black box &#8230; there&#8217;s a lot of opportunity to understand how to make your marketing better.&#8221; Timeline, the photo-heavy redesign that Facebook herded brands into in March, has changed the way brands market on Facebook. Although there have been conflicting reports about Timeline&#8217;s effect on brand engagement, marketers are realizing that Timeline may not be more effective &#8212; but it definitely is different. However, Timeline&#8217;s not the only catalyst for the changing marketing ecosystem on Facebook. Another is Facebook&#8217;s financial situation: The company is under huge pressure from Wall Street to figure out a winning formula for advertising on the platform. With about 133 million users in the U.S., the social network has a potential audience bigger than the Super Bowl&#8217;s. Though GM has punctured Facebook&#8217;s air of inevitability, most advertisers haven&#8217;t lost faith enough to drop advertising on the platform wholesale. The combination of these two things has ushered in five new Facebook marketing trends. What&#8217;s the best way to market your brand on Facebook? According to Peter Shankman, an entrepreneur and venture capitalist with a background in marketing and consulting, the answer is actually pretty easy: &#8220;Sharing for the sake of just hearing yourself talk is pointless.&#8221; Yes, the key to doing more is doing it with less. &#8220;You want to engage your audience and make sure that they feel like they&#8217;re apart of something &#8212; not just being marketed to,&#8221; Shankman explains. &#8220;Then they will do your PR for you.&#8221; Mashable spoke with Shankman about the inner workings of Facebook marketing and what users really want to see on your brand page. On Leap Day 2012, Facebook gathered all of its marketing executives in New York City for a coming-out party of sorts for a slew of new ad products. To people outside the industry, the promise of new initiatives might appear a bit on the dull side. But for advertisers, anything that Facebook does for advertising is of interest. Among the products Facebook introduced were Premium on Facebook, Reach Generator, Offers and Logged Out ads. The company also asked brands to embrace a paradigm shift from advertising to &#8220;Stories,&#8221; Facebook&#8217;s preferred term for brand-related messages. Since that time, a few big brands have experimented with the new tools. Over the past few years, Facebook marketing has moved from the domain of early adopters to a mainstream focus for nearly all businesses. During that time, a large number of social media marketing tools have emerged to help companies reach and engage with fans, run promotions and contests, and even integrate Facebook Ad programs with the rest of their social marketing. But while most marketers are currently using the myriad applications that allow them to run their ongoing programs, they may not be as familiar with tools they can use to enhance their day-to-day activities and make their programs more effective. For some companies, one Facebook Brand Page might not be enough. For example, if a restaurant chain prides itself on local ingredients, or a business seeks to cultivate a strong community around each brick-and-mortar outlet, it might make sense to have a Brand Page for each location. But then again, does a brand really want to divvy up its audience and dilute it among several similar pages? While chunking up an audience among numerous Facebook Brand Pages may seem counterintuitive, it does work to the advantage of some brands, such as Lululemon and Sprinkles. But other small businesses, such as Butter Lane and Sweetgreen, find that one Facebook Brand Page does a proper job of cultivating a strong community behind the brand. Customers know that the squeaky wheel gets the grease, and web-savvy customers know that Facebook is the ultimate squeak amplifier. According to Forrester Research, 27% of U.S. online consumers sought customer service support on the web in 2011, and currently three out of four expect a reply to a negative comment posted on Facebook. Unfortunately, many brands still don&#8217;t incorporate customer service into their social strategy, despite the fact that Facebook is one of the best venues in which to turn your customers&#8217; negative comments into brand opportunities. Here are eight tips to help you improve your Facebook customer support initiative and, in turn, raise your brand&#8217;s reputation, decrease your inbound service requests, acquire new customers and turn infrequent customers into brand loyalists. Read the full story and see the video here.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/facebook-marketing-tips-2/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/facebook-marketing-tips-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s the State of Social Media in Asia?</title>
      <description>Asians are the most active social media users in the world: Agree or disagree? A study by Burson-Marsteller showed that social media usage in the Asia-Pacific region went through the roof in the past years, showing growth rates ranging from 107% (South Korea) to 12,305% (Vietnam). More than half of the region's population is active online, with Facebook the most popular social network. Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Japan and South Korea all have larger online populations than Australia. In China, more than half a billion people surf the web. [More from Mashable: Fort Collins and Ottawa Proclaim June 30 Social Media Day] But going beyond statistics, what do those numbers mean? Are Asians really as attuned to social media as the surveys say? How differently do people in Asia use social media as compared to the U.S.? Join us today for a Google+ hangout at 10:00 a.m. ET with Timothy Tiah of Malaysia, Carlo Ople and Rosario Juan of the Philippines, and Aakar Anilof Nepal as we chat about social media trends in Asia in celebration of the upcoming Social Media Day on June 30. Read on to learn more about Social Media Day and find a Meetup near you, and let us know in the comments what social media looks like where you live. [More from Mashable: Celebrate Social Media Day With Mashable in the Bay Area] Whether you've had your event planned for months or are now inspired to get one started, we want to know: What are your plans for Social Media Day 2012? Share with us in the comments how you'll be recognizing the connected generation come June 30th. We look forward to celebrating with you! This story originally published on Mashable here.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/whats-state-social-media-asia-095140499.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/whats-state-social-media-asia-095140499.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Business School Trends to Watch</title>
      <description>Business in the United States has experienced seismic shifts in the last decade, and business schools are no exception. These developments have been fueled by technology, the global financial crisis, cultural shifts, and the introduction of Gen Y into the business world. Traditional MBAs, which have usually focused on accounting and finance, have a hard time producing the type of business leaders companies are currently looking for. Specifically, companies want ethical problem solvers with strong digital and entrepreneurial skills, who are team players and work well in diverse environments. Yet, a 2008 study of top business schools found that curricula lacked valued &#8220;thematic elem&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, contributor, entrepreneurs, features, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/business-school-trends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/business-school-trends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Enhance Your Email Signature</title>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the American Express OPEN Forum, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business. Whether you want to impress a client or score a new job, it's vital that you stand out. But that doesn't always require big thinking -- sometimes the smallest details can be enough to get noticed. One easy way is to jazz up your email signature. You can spice up your sign-off with different colors and fonts, but it's also important to showcase the many facets of your personality and skill set. Don't make email recipients search for your web presence -- provide links to your website and any relevant social media&#8230; Continue reading... More About: email, features, open forum, Small Business</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/enhance-your-email-signature/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/17/enhance-your-email-signature/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pixar&#8217;s &#8216;Brave&#8217;: How One Frame Went from Sketch to Screen [EXCLUSIVE PICS]</title>
      <description>For Pixar fans who've been eager to see a full-length film from the animation studio for more than a year -- or had their appetite whetted by this trailer back in November -- the waiting is almost over. Brave, the story of the trials and tribulations of a medieval Scottish highlands princess called Merida, hits the screens this Friday, June 22. Mashable got an early look at the movie itself -- more on that later -- and an in-depth look behind the scenes at Pixar's magnificent brick headquarters in Emeryville Calif., a former bakery whose redesign was Steve Jobs' pride and joy. We've got a bunch of video and interviews with the Brave team, which we'll be sharing with you in the run up&#8230; Continue reading... More About: animation, Brave, pixar, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/pixar-brave-frame/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/pixar-brave-frame/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid 17 Internet Scams [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>We've all heard the horror stories: credit card fraud, pyramid schemes, phishing, identity theft -- the list of scams goes on and on. "Oh, that won't happen to me," you think. "I know the signs." No one wants to think he'll be counted among the fooled. But the truth is, you can never be too cautious about scams on the web. [More from Mashable: L.A. Kings Are NHL&#8217;s Twitter Champions Too [INFOGRAPHIC]] After all, according to the Internet Crime Complaint Center, yearly dollars lost grew by about $500 million from 2004 to 2009, and the trend isn't showing signs of slowing. SEE ALSO: How to Check If Your LinkedIn Password Was Stolen [More from Mashable: Is Social Media Destroying Real-World Relationships? [INFOGRAPHIC]] Background Check compiled research on Internet scams from around the world to help you spot the red flags. Among the stats: Nearly 66% of complaints (predominantly phishing) with a known perpetrator location originated in the U.S. Meanwhile, despite having the world's largest online population, China only accounts for 3.1% of those scams. Check out this infographic for information on the types of scams to look out for, and how to make sure you don't wind up a victim. This story originally published on Mashable here.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/avoid-17-internet-scams-infographic-155710298.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/avoid-17-internet-scams-infographic-155710298.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Most Annoying Person on Facebook [COMIC]</title>
      <description>From excessive posts about mundane daily tasks to getting too personal in updates, everyone has a few pet-peeves about what they see in their Facebook news feeds. A quirky new infographic called the "Sins of Social Media" -- by digital marketing provider Three Ships Media -- highlights the most annoying habits of Facebook users. SEE ALSO: How to Fill Out Facebook Timeline Without Annoying Your Friends Take a look below and let us know if you are guilty of any of these Facebook behaviors. What annoys you most about certain updates on the site? More About: Facebook, infographics, Social Media, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/most-annoying-person-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/18/most-annoying-person-facebook/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
