<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>55 Breathtaking Examples Of High Speed Photography | Free and ...</title>
      <description>High Speed &lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt; is getting very popular day by day. High speed &lt;b&gt;photography&lt;/b&gt; produces awesome results because of a relatively faster shutter speed. This form of &lt;b&gt;photography&lt;/b&gt; comes into play when we want to capture those scenes which</description>
      <link>http://www.smashingapps.com/2011/02/20/breathtaking-high-speed-photography.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.smashingapps.com/2011/02/20/breathtaking-high-speed-photography.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Free Google Ride is Over for Lazy SEOs &amp; Keyword Domain Names</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a &lt;a href="http://www.seroundtable.com/google-keyword-domains-13125.html"&gt;lot&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="http://www.seobook.com/googles-matt-cutts-talks-down-keyword-domain-names"&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; surrounding a new video from Matt Cutts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title="YouTube video player" width="560" height="349" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rAWFv43qubI?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In it, the prominent Google engineer explains why you should not be swayed into registering a domain name that includes the keywords you are likely to target for your SEO efforts. He provides many examples of successful companies that have a branded domain name&amp;#8211;and not a keyworded one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then he drops somewhat of a bombshell for all those SEOs that have been relying on the keyword in the domain to do all the heavy-lifting:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now if you are still on the fence, let me just give you a bit of color. that we have looked at the rankings and the weights that we give to keyword domains, &amp;amp; some people have complained that we are giving a little too much weight for keywords in domains. So we have been thinking about at adjusting that mix a bit and sort of turning the knob down within the algorithm, so that given 2 different domains it wouldn&amp;#8217;t necessarily help you as much to have a domain name with a bunch of keywords in it. &amp;#8211; Matt Cutts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;So, should you panic? Only if you registered something like &amp;#8220;ringtones.com&amp;#8221; and are sitting at #1 without lifting a finger to optimize it. In other words, the free ride may soon be over for those that managed to secure a keyword-rich domain name and failed to build relevant content or links. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.trackur.com/100-0-1-13.html" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src="http://www.trackur.com/idevaffiliate/banners/trackur60secs300.gif" width="300" height="250"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/O_CNfjkcO-KB4RvThmK-aF7psq8/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/O_CNfjkcO-KB4RvThmK-aF7psq8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/O_CNfjkcO-KB4RvThmK-aF7psq8/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/O_CNfjkcO-KB4RvThmK-aF7psq8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?i=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?i=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?i=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.marketingpilgrim.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?a=kfKvIGlCrNY:sjq7U8pwoTM:YwkR-u9nhCs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/marketing-pilgrim?d=YwkR-u9nhCs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.marketingpilgrim.com/2011/03/the-free-google-ride-is-over-for-lazy-seos-keyword-domain-names.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.marketingpilgrim.com/2011/03/the-free-google-ride-is-over-for-lazy-seos-keyword-domain-names.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Common Questions About Startup Employee Stock Options</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/&amp;title=7 Common Questions About Startup Employee Stock Options&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/stock-options.jpg" alt="" title="stock options" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-751055" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Jim Wulforst is president of &lt;a href="https://us.etrade.com/e/t/corporateservices" target="_blank"&gt;E*TRADE Financial Corporate Services&lt;/a&gt;, which provides employee stock plan administration solutions to both private and public companies, including 22% of the S&amp;#038;P 500.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Perhaps you&#8217;ve heard about the &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-493333/Part-time-Google-masseuse-retires-multimillionaire-share-price-boom.html" target="_blank"&gt;Google millionaires&lt;/a&gt;: 1,000 of the company&#8217;s early employees (including the company masseuse) who earned their wealth through company stock options. A terrific story, but unfortunately, not all stock options have as happy an ending. Pets.com and Webvan, for example, went bankrupt after high-profile Initial Public Offerings left their stock grants worthless. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stock options can be a nice benefit, but the value behind the offer can vary significantly. There are simply no guarantees. So, whether you&#8217;re considering a job offer that includes a stock grant, or you hold stock as part of your current compensation, it&#8217;s crucial to understand the basics. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;What types of stock plans are out there, and how do they work? &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;How do I know when to exercise, hold or sell? &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;What are the tax implications? &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;How should I think about stock or equity compensation relative to my total compensation and any other savings and investments I might have?&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;1. What are the most common types of employee stock offerings?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Two of the most common employee stock offerings are stock options and restricted stock.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employee stock options&lt;/strong&gt; are the most common among startup companies. The options give you the opportunity to purchase shares of your company&#8217;s stock at a specified price, typically referred to as the &#8220;strike&#8221; price. Your right to purchase &#8211; or &#8220;exercise&#8221; &#8211; stock options is subject to a vesting schedule, which defines when you can exercise the options. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s take an example. Say you&#8217;re granted 300 options with a strike price of $10 each that vest equally over a three-year period. At the end of the first year, you would have the right to exercise 100 shares of stock for $10 per share. If, at that time, the company&#8217;s share price had risen to $15 per share, you have the opportunity to purchase the stock for $5 below the market price, which, if you exercise and sell concurrently, represents a $500 pre-tax profit. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the end of the second year, 100 more shares will vest. Now, in our example, let&#8217;s say the company&#8217;s stock price has declined to $8 per share. In this scenario, you would not exercise your options, as you&#8217;d be paying $10 for something you could purchase for $8 in the open market. You may hear this referred to as options being &#8220;out of the money&#8221; or &#8220;under water.&#8221; The good news is that the loss is on paper, as you have not invested actual cash. You retain the right to exercise the shares and can keep an eye on the company&#8217;s stock price. Later, you may choose to take action if the market price goes higher than the strike price &#8211; or when it is back &#8220;in the money.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the end of the third year, the final 100 shares would vest, and you&#8217;d have the right to exercise those shares. Your decision to do so would depend on a number of factors, including, but not limited to, the stock&#8217;s market price. Once you&#8217;ve exercised vested options, you can either sell the shares right away or hold onto them as part of your stock portfolio.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restricted stock grants&lt;/strong&gt; (which may include either Awards or Units) provide employees with a right to receive shares at little or no cost. As with stock options, restricted stock grants are subject to a vesting schedule, typically tied to either passage of time or achievement of a specific goal. This means that you&#8217;ll either have to wait a certain period of time and/or meet certain goals before you earn the right to receive the shares. Keep in mind that the vesting of restricted stock grants is a taxable event. This means that taxes will have to be paid based on the value of the shares at the time they vest. Your employer decides which tax payment options are available to you &#8211; these may include paying cash, selling some of the vested shares, or having your employer withhold some of the shares.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;2. What&#8217;s the difference between &#8220;incentive&#8221; and &#8220;non-qualified&#8221; stock options? &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a fairly complex area related to the current tax code. Therefore, you should consult your tax advisor to better understand your personal situation. The difference primarily lies in how the two are taxed. Incentive stock options qualify for special tax treatment by the IRS, meaning taxes generally don&#8217;t have to be paid when these options are exercised. And resulting gain or loss may qualify as long-term capital gains or loss if held more than a year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Non-qualified options, on the other hand, can result in ordinary taxable income when exercised. Tax is based on the difference between the exercise price and fair market value at the time of exercise. Subsequent sales may result in capital gain or loss &#8211; short or long term, depending on duration held.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;3. What about taxes?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/cat-calculator.jpg" alt="" title="cat calculator" width="640" height="358" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-751079" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tax treatment for each transaction will depend on the type of stock option you own and other variables related to your individual situation. Before you exercise your options and/or sell shares, you&#8217;ll want to carefully consider the consequences of the transaction. For specific advice, you should consult a tax advisor or accountant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;4. How do I know whether to hold or sell after I exercise?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;When it comes to employee stock options and shares, the decision to hold or sell boils down to the basics of long term investing. Ask yourself: how much risk am I willing to take? Is my portfolio well-diversified based on my current needs and goals? How does this investment fit in with my overall financial strategy? Your decision to exercise, hold or sell some or all of your shares should consider these questions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many people choose what is referred to as a same-day sale or cashless exercise in which you exercise your vested options and simultaneously sell the shares. This provides immediate access to your actual proceeds (profit, less associated commissions, fees and taxes). Many firms make tools available that help plan a participant&amp;#8217;s model in advance and estimate proceeds from a particular transaction. In all cases, you should consult a tax advisor or financial planner for advice on your personal financial situation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;5. I believe in my company&#8217;s future. How much of its stock should I own?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is great to have confidence in your employer, but you should consider your total portfolio and overall diversification strategy when thinking about any investment &#8211; including one in company stock. In general, it&#8217;s best &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to have a portfolio that is overly dependent on any one investment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;6. I work for a privately-held startup. If this company never goes public or is purchased by another company before going public, what happens to the stock? &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is no single answer to this. The answer is often defined in the terms of the company&#8217;s stock plan and/or the transaction terms. If a company remains private, there may be limited opportunities to sell vested or unrestricted shares, but it will vary by the plan and the company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For instance, a private company may allow employees to sell their vested option rights on secondary or other marketplaces. In the case of an acquisition, some buyers will accelerate the vesting schedule and pay all options holders the difference between the strike price and the acquisition share price, while other buyers might convert unvested stock to a stock plan in the acquiring company. Again, this will vary by plan and transaction. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;7. I still have a lot of questions. How can I learn more? &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Your manager or someone in your company&#8217;s HR department can likely provide more details about your company&#8217;s plan &#8211; and the benefits you qualify for under the plan. You should also consult your financial planner or tax advisor to ensure you understand how stock grants, vesting events, exercising and selling affect your personal tax situation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images courtesy of iStockphoto, &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/stock-photo-649435-stock-certificate-20.php?st=fe188a5" target="_blank"&gt;DNY59&lt;/a&gt;, Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/vlashton/3324301004/in/photostream/" target="_blank"&gt;Vicki&amp;#8217;s Pics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/investment/"&gt;investment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/startup/"&gt;startup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/stock/"&gt;stock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zba0_pehyo4NUp48kROjIP2P5D0/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zba0_pehyo4NUp48kROjIP2P5D0/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zba0_pehyo4NUp48kROjIP2P5D0/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/zba0_pehyo4NUp48kROjIP2P5D0/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=t-oDb-1we2o:hEVI0A1iPOI:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/t-oDb-1we2o" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/09/30/startup-stock-options/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Art Levinson, Apple&#8217;s New Chairman</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/&amp;title=Meet Art Levinson, Apple&amp;#8217;s New Chairman&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/arthur-levinson-360.jpg" class="alignright" width="275px"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/apple"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; has appointed Arthur Levinson, one of Silicon Valley&amp;#8217;s most respected leaders, as the company&amp;#8217;s new Chairman of the Board. Who exactly is Levinson, and why has Apple chosen him to lead the board?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Levinson has served on Apple&amp;#8217;s board of directors for more than a decade. In 2000, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/steve-jobs"&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt; asked Levinson to join Apple&amp;#8217;s board when Levinson was chairman and CEO of Genentech, the multibillion-dollar biotech company now owned by Roche. Only Intuit&amp;#8217;s Bill Campbell and J.Crew&amp;#8217;s Millard Drexler have served longer on Apple&amp;#8217;s board.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Art is a highly respected CEO and leads one of the most important and successful science-based companies of our time,&amp;#8221; Jobs said when Levinson first joined the board. &amp;#8220;We look forward to his insight and counsel.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Levinson was born in Seattle in March 1950 to Sol and Malvina Levinson. From his childhood he was interested in the sciences. He points to Carl Sagan&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Intelligent Life in the Universe&lt;/em&gt; as one of the most influential books in his early life. That inspiration took him to the University of Washington, where he graduated with a B.Sc. in molecular biology in 1972. He received a PhD in Biochemstry from Princeton in 1977, a year before he got married.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;His career at Genentech began in 1980, when he was recruited as a research scientist by Genentech co-founder Dr. Herbert Boyer. Levinson quickly moved up the ranks, becoming the VP of research technology in 1989 and senior VP of R&amp;#038;D in 1993. In 1995, Levinson was named CEO. In 1999, he was also named chairman of the board.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 2009, Levinson stepped down from his CEO duties at Genentech after the company was &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/03/13/business/worldbusiness/13drugs.html"&gt;acquired by Roche for $46.8 billion&lt;/a&gt;. He remains the company&amp;#8217;s chairman and serves on a variety of boards, including the boards of Roche, Amyris and the Broad Institute. He also joined Google&amp;#8217;s board of directors in 2004, but &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2009/10/12/arthur-levinson-resigns-google/"&gt;left in 2009&lt;/a&gt; not long after the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2009/08/03/eric-schmidt-apple/"&gt;departure of former Google CEO Eric Schmidt from Apple&amp;#8217;s board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What kind of change can we expect from Apple with Levinson in charge of the board? Not much. Levinson has served as co-lead of Apple&amp;#8217;s board since 2005, only relinquishing that title in August when &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/24/breaking-steve-jobs-resigns-from-apple/"&gt;Steve Jobs stepped down as CEO&lt;/a&gt; and became the company&amp;#8217;s chairman. Levinson has been one of the company&amp;#8217;s most visible leaders for a long time. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In other words, don&amp;#8217;t expect Levinson to change Apple&amp;#8217;s magic formula. He helped create it. If you want to get a feel for Levinson and his personality, check out this video of a speech he gave to Genentech employees when Roach bought out the company:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/BWlYRRf8184?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/apple/"&gt;apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/art-levinson/"&gt;Art Levinson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/arthur-levinson/"&gt;Arthur Levinson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/steve-jobs/"&gt;steve jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1qHpeP1J9a93xqButqOm9UPss8o/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1qHpeP1J9a93xqButqOm9UPss8o/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1qHpeP1J9a93xqButqOm9UPss8o/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/1qHpeP1J9a93xqButqOm9UPss8o/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=bdu5KYoPago:wYBWste0z_I:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/bdu5KYoPago" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/15/arthur-levinson-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jobs Was Right: Adobe Abandons Mobile Flash Development, Report Says</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id="attachment_81667" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 670px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2011/11/MG_5442.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-81667" title="MG_5442" src="http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/gadgetlab/2011/11/MG_5442.jpg" alt="" width="660" height="528" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;The BlackBerry PlayBook was famously marketed as a Flash-capable tablet, though ultimately failed to deliver. Photo: Jon Snyder/Wired.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In an abrupt about-face in its mobile software strategy, Adobe will soon cease developing its Flash Player plug-in for mobile browsers, according to an e-mail sent to Adobe partners on Tuesday evening.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And with that e-mail flash, Adobe has signaled that it knows, as Steve Jobs predicted, the end of the Flash era on the web is coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The e-mail, obtained and first reported on by &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/perlow/exclusive-adobe-ceases-development-on-mobile-browser-flash-refocuses-efforts-on-html5/19226"&gt;ZDNet&lt;/a&gt;, says that Adobe will no longer continue to &amp;#8220;adapt Flash Player for mobile devices to new browser, OS version or device configurations,&amp;#8221; instead focusing on alternative application packaging programs and the HTML5 protocol.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Our future work with Flash on mobile devices will be focused on enabling Flash developers to package native apps with Adobe AIR for all the major app stores,&amp;#8221; the quoted e-mail says.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the past, Adobe has released &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/06/adobe-flash-flex/"&gt;software tools for mobile developers&lt;/a&gt; that create a single platform programmers can use to make applications that work across three major mobile platforms: Android, iOS and the BlackBerry OS. While it&amp;#8217;s seemingly easier than learning all of the native languages for each operating system, some developers have claimed a loss in app performance when coding in a non-native language that then gets translated into other languages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The move indicates a massive backpedaling on Adobe&amp;#8217;s part, a company who championed its Flash platform, which is installed on nearly all desktop browsers, in the face of years of naysaying about its use on mobile devices from many in the greater computing industry, including, famously, Apple Computer. Critics of Flash cite its instability and intense drain on batteries as serious drawbacks which makes Flash hurt mobile devices more than it benefits them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Flash became a dominant desktop platform by allowing developers to code interactive games, create animated advertisements and deliver video to any browser that had the plugin installed, without having to take into account the particulars of any given browser. However, with the development of Javascript, CSS, and HTML5, which has native support for video, many web developers are turning away from Flash, which can be a resource hog even on the most advanced browsers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Apple made its biggest waves in the case against Flash in April of last year, when Steve Jobs penned a &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/"&gt;1500-word screed&lt;/a&gt; against the controversial platform, describing it as a technology of the past.. Jobs and Apple disliked the platform so intensely, it has since been barred from use on all iOS devices.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite attempts to breathe life into Flash on other mobile devices &amp;#8212; namely, Android and BlackBerry OS &amp;#8212; Adobe has failed to deliver a consistently stable version of the platform on a smartphone or tablet. In &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/reviews/2011/04/blackberry-playbook/all/1"&gt;WIRED&amp;#8217;s testing of the BlackBerry PlayBook in April&lt;/a&gt;, Flash use caused the browser to crash on a consistent basis. And when Flash was supposed to come to tablets with Motorola&amp;#8217;s Xoom, Adobe was only able to provide an &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/02/motorola-xoom-launches-without-flash/"&gt;highly unstable Beta version of Flash&lt;/a&gt; to ship with the flagship Android device.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Adobe has lost so much credibility with the community that I&#8217;m hoping they are bought by someone else that can bring some stability and eventually some credibility back to the Flash Platform,&amp;#8221; wrote software developer &lt;a href="http://polygeek.com/4838_air-mobile_flash-is-dead-on-mobile-long-live-air"&gt;Dan Florio&lt;/a&gt; in a blog post on Wednesday morning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The drastic reversal in Adobe&amp;#8217;s mobile plans comes in the wake of the company &lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20111108/adobe-eliminates-750-jobs-in-restructuring/"&gt;cutting 750 jobs on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt;, a move prompted by what Adobe labeled &amp;#8220;corporate restructuring.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An Adobe representative did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ll325u1HmRDQwyxAjIRdT5-Ydy0/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ll325u1HmRDQwyxAjIRdT5-Ydy0/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ll325u1HmRDQwyxAjIRdT5-Ydy0/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/Ll325u1HmRDQwyxAjIRdT5-Ydy0/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?a=X8a9DRsshyg:SbCVz-yFVWo:cGdyc7Q-1BI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?d=cGdyc7Q-1BI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?a=X8a9DRsshyg:SbCVz-yFVWo:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?i=X8a9DRsshyg:SbCVz-yFVWo:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?a=X8a9DRsshyg:SbCVz-yFVWo:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?i=X8a9DRsshyg:SbCVz-yFVWo:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?a=X8a9DRsshyg:SbCVz-yFVWo:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GearFactor?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GearFactor/~4/X8a9DRsshyg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/11/adobe-kills-mobile-flash/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GearFactor+%28Blog+-+Gadget+Lab+%28Gear+Factor%29%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/11/adobe-kills-mobile-flash/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+GearFactor+%28Blog+-+Gadget+Lab+%28Gear+Factor%29%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEO Positive Billed As Headline Sponsor For Online Marketing Show - Press Release - Digital Journal</title>
      <description>(PRWEB UK) 26 November 2011 As an SEO agency determined to increase its reach and exposure, SEO Positive Limited has announced its involvement in next year&#8217;s Online Marketing Show, an industry event that&#8217;s run as part of the Marketing Week Live e</description>
      <link>http://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/502599</link>
      <guid>http://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/502599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips for Activating the Entrepreneurial Spirit</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/&amp;title=9 Tips for Activating the Entrepreneurial Spirit&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/business-hero.jpg" alt="" title="business hero" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-776731" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;Kevin O&#8217;Connor, co-founder of &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/doubleclick/" target="_blank"&gt;DoubleClick&lt;/a&gt;, is the CEO of &lt;a href="http://www.findthebest.com/" target="_blank"&gt;FindTheBest&lt;/a&gt;, an unbiased data driven comparison engine, which he established in Santa Barbara, CA.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As an entrepreneur, I&#8217;ve been invited to guest lecture for entrepreneurial programs at colleges from Harvard to the University of Michigan. Each time I stood before a group of aspiring entrepreneurs, I couldn&#8217;t help but wonder whether people could actually &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; the needed skills and qualities to become a successful entrepreneur, or if we&#8217;re born into said skills.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/31/entrepreneur-qualities/"&gt;Do You Have What it Takes to Be an Entrepreneur?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I did some research and, synthesizing my findings with my own experience as an entrepreneur, concluded that people are born with some of the traits and characteristics needed to be a successful, innovative entrepreneur. However, these characteristics can always be improved through education and experience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve been lucky enough to learn about entrepreneurship, leadership and teamwork from supportive family members and forward-thinking mentors. Here are 9 invaluable lessons I&#8217;ve taken away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Become a Budding Entrepreneur&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Believe in yourself and stand behind your convictions.&lt;/strong&gt; If you choose the entrepreneurial path, you must believe in your convictions so strongly that you would stand behind your opinions no matter the discouragements. Although this positive way of thinking may attract a lot of nay-sayers, don&#8217;t lose hope. &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovate and invent constantly.&lt;/strong&gt; Great entrepreneurs rarely invent just one profitable product &#8212; they&#8217;re inventing and innovating constantly. Oftentimes you need to come up with a lot of bad ideas before you come up with the one that sticks. Be persistent and don&#8217;t give up. &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move rapidly.&lt;/strong&gt; Successful innovators get things done quickly because they know time is not on their side. You might have a multi-million dollar idea, but if you don&#8217;t get it out there before someone else, the idea will no longer be profitable. &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Encourage Innovation Within Your Company &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support a meritocracy.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a work environment in which the most talented employees and the best ideas get recognized and promoted, regardless of age, experience or position. Not only does this create healthy competition, but it encourages employees to be vocal and participate in the bigger vision. &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Host weekly brainstorms.&lt;/strong&gt; I brainstorm constantly with my employees; it&#8217;s the quickest way to access the best ideas in the room. I call it The Brainstorm Prioritization Technique: narrow and specifically define your goal, encourage free-flowing brainstorming, then go back to clarify ideas. Finally, allow team members to vote on top ideas. &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead by example.&lt;/strong&gt; If you&#8217;re not moving with a sense of urgency and adding your own ideas to the mix, it will be hard to motivate a potentially innovative team. &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Hire Innovators&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid stock questions.&lt;/strong&gt; I ask a lot of unusual questions when interviewing someone, mainly because stock questions produce equally predictable answers. When trying to gauge if a candidate&#8217;s self-confidence, I&#8217;ll ask him, &#8220;Are you smart?&#8221; Their initial reaction will tell all. &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t write off rebels.&lt;/strong&gt; I also like candidates that have rebelled against authority in the name of a cause or belief. I&#8217;m not automatically prejudice against someone who has been jailed for talking back to a cop or fired for telling his boss to shove it. Innovators have always swum against the stream. &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for a history of thinking big.&lt;/strong&gt; Have they set big goals or innovated in the past? This is a good sign you have the right person. &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do you have any tips for aspiring entrepreneurs? Please share in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/stock-photo-4990516-business-hero.php?st=f80847f" target="_blank"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=550207" target="_blank"&gt;RichVintage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/contributor/"&gt;contributor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/entrepreneurs/"&gt;entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/features/"&gt;features&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/startups/"&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KzBrpUKX7ZMmIWZpTKf7NzL1LGs/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KzBrpUKX7ZMmIWZpTKf7NzL1LGs/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KzBrpUKX7ZMmIWZpTKf7NzL1LGs/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KzBrpUKX7ZMmIWZpTKf7NzL1LGs/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=iX9xSZkNkNU:dGr0NQ0-QBk:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/iX9xSZkNkNU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/entrepreneur-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Luxury Designer Tory Burch Dominates Digital Marketing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/&amp;title=How Luxury Designer Tory Burch Dominates Digital Marketing&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/tory-burch-360.jpg" alt="" title="tory burch 360" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-810273" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;American fashion designer &lt;a href="http://toryburch.com"&gt;Tory Burch&lt;/a&gt; founded her label in February 2004, the same month that Mark Zuckerberg launched &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; from his Harvard dorm room.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the fashion industry, Burch&amp;#8217;s rise has been nearly as striking: the 45-year-old CEO has expanded her line of ready-to-wear clothing and accessories to more than 450 department and specialty stores worldwide, as well as dozens of Tory Burch boutiques in the U.S., Europe and Asia. She opened 20 new shops, including several in international cities (Osaka, Seoul, Hong Kong, Kobe and Taipai), in 2010 alone.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Much of her success can be linked to an aggressive digital strategy, says Miki Berardelli, who has served as chief marketing officer of Tory Burch since 2009. The company launched &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ecommerce"&gt;ecommerce&lt;/a&gt; immediately after opening its first shop in downtown Manhattan, and &lt;a href="http://www.toryburch.com" target="_blank"&gt;toryburch.com&lt;/a&gt; generates more revenue than any physical store. Burch is one of the few designers to maintain a direct, ongoing dialogue with her friends and fans on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, which she does in an easy-going and authentic manner. The company&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.toryburch.com/blog/" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;, which is helmed by former &lt;em&gt;InStyle&lt;/em&gt; editor Honor Brodie, is broadly recognized in the industry as one of the leading manifestations of ongoing, brand-developed content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/Picture-10.png" alt="" title="tory blog logo" width="315" height="100" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-814537" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We spoke with Berardelli about Tory Burch&amp;#8217;s advancements in ecommerce and social media, and how the company is investing in what Berardelli believes is the &amp;#8220;future of ecommerce&amp;#8221;: namely, shopping through Facebook. A transcript of our Q&amp;#038;A is featured below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;#038;A With Miki Berardelli, CMO, Tory Burch&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You joined Tory Burch in 2009. What drew you to the company?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think it was really Tory&amp;#8217;s vision to create a luxury brand that is accessible and has a sense of social responsibility &amp;#8212; those were things that resonated with me both personally and professionally. There was also of course the people and the culture and, from a marketing perspective, the emotional connection that the customer had, and still has, with the brand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you characterize the company&amp;#8217;s marketing strategy at that time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tory always says that in the early years, not having a tremendous budget forced her to really think out of the box and tap into her and her team&amp;#8217;s creativity. It was very much about editorial relationships and personal appearances, which enabled her to connect directly to the customer. Seven and a half years years later, that startup spirit is very much alive. We still have not bought traditional advertisements in U.S. magazines, although we do some display and online advertising.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/Picture-16.png" alt="" title="tory burch website" width="582" height="461" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-814539" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How else have the company&amp;#8217;s marketing efforts changed since you joined?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We continue to focus on all things digital. We redesigned our website earlier this year, which was very much about pulling all of the content [we have developed] into the shopping experience &#8230; [and] supporting mobile commerce. We&amp;#8217;ve also done a lot in the social media space. Lately we&amp;#8217;ve been focusing on the intersection of social, local and mobile, whether that&amp;#8217;s for a new store opening in a specific market, or driving traffic into [our existing] stores. Given the rapid growth of the company, we&amp;#8217;re also focused on analysis of our marketing efforts to ensure that they are effective.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much of your marketing spend is allocated to online versus offline efforts?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s pretty even &amp;#8212; or, I should say, it&amp;#8217;s balanced. But everything we do, whether it&amp;#8217;s our photography or our website, is all serving the marketing message of the company.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what rate is your ecommerce business expanding? What percentage of your sales now occur online? What percentage occur on &lt;a href="http://www.toryburch.com" target="_blank"&gt;toryburch.com&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we are a private company, we can&amp;#8217;t disclose specific numbers. We are however forecasting a growth rate in the high double digits compared to last year. As for your second question, we see a slightly higher penetration of ecommerce sales to total business versus many brands that are distributed through retail or wholesale. What&amp;#8217;s interesting about Tory is that she launched ecommerce immediately after opening [her first] store on Elizabeth Street [in New York]. Ecommerce has always been at the forefront, and &lt;a href="http://www.toryburch.com" target="_blank"&gt;toryburch.com&lt;/a&gt; is our largest store.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mobile sales is currently our fastest-growing segment. The proliferation of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ipad"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt; has definitely impacted our business, seeing a tremendous amount of traffic to our site [from users of those devices] specifically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have been among the biggest marketing and ecommerce challenges as you&amp;#8217;ve expanded into new markets, particularly China?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;China&amp;#8217;s fascinating. The rate at which the Chinese sector is embracing ecommerce is unlike anything I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen. The challenge lies in understanding the landscape and deciding what makes sense for our brand, just as we do here. We launched our first Weibo site in support of the opening of our first store in Bejing. We are currently building ecommerce-enabled sites to support the markets that we&amp;#8217;re in in Europe and in China.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tory Burch has made considerable investments in developing online editorial, largely through its &lt;a href="http://www.toryburch.com/blog/" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. Why have you invested there? Is it paying off &amp;#8212; and if so, how?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="line-height: 26px; width: 290px; border-left-color: #888888; border-left-style: dotted; border-left-width: 1px; margin-bottom: 10px; float: right; color: #888888; margin-left: 15px; padding-left: 15px; font-size: 20px; padding-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&#8220;While the voice is consistent across all platforms, we treat each one differently because they are all unique.&amp;#8221;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tory wanted to tell the brand story in a more editorial way, and that led to hiring Honor Brodie from &lt;em&gt;InStyle&lt;/em&gt;, who is now our creative director. She built a team that focuses on the &lt;a href="http://www.toryburch.com/blog/" target="_blank"&gt;Tory blog&lt;/a&gt;, which is expression of all the things that inspire and entertain Tory, whether it&amp;#8217;s an artist or author or even another designer. The blog doesn&amp;#8217;t talk much about Tory, but about other things, and I think that&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s unique about it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Honor and I [have] worked together to integrate the blog and commerce. We&amp;#8217;ve brought in all the content into the shopping experience so that the customer can explore and connect with the brand while they&amp;#8217;re browsing product. We do look at the analytics of customers who explore content, and have found that they are a more highly engaged customer across the board, not only in how much time they spend on website, but in terms of their purchases and loyalty as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does your current investment in social media look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re currently on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, Flipboard, &lt;a href="http://torypedia.tumblr.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://foursquare.com/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, and Weibo in China. [Those accounts] are run by a small team of two people, except for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, which is run by Tory herself, and Weibo, which is run by our team in Shanghai, in partnership with our editorial team in NYC. [Tory has] always embraced social media, and if it feels right for our brand, we&amp;#8217;ll launch it, test our way into it, learn quickly and make adjustments as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/Picture-17.png" alt="" title="tory burch tweets" width="520" height="423" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-814541" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about video?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The film genre is very important to Tory. We believe it&amp;#8217;s a dynamic way to tell the brand story, we do all different types of films &amp;#8212; behind the scenes during a seasonal photo shoot, or filming Tory on one of her trips where she gets inspiration for her designs. It&amp;#8217;s a pretty varied mix of content, and we&amp;#8217;re continuing to learn what is successful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With so many platforms to choose from, how do you decide where to invest your time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t think that we&amp;#8217;ve ever scaled back any of our efforts anywhere. We do make sure when pooling resources to manage another social platform that we do it well, that we take our time and think through how to do each platform differently. On &lt;a href="http://torypedia.tumblr.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; we do one strong image and a letter, and on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; we do more behind-the-scenes content. With &lt;a href="https://foursquare.com/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;, we focus on the location element. While the voice is consistent across all these platforms, we treat each one differently because they are all unique.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/y6Gmm9YEZys?rel=0&amp;wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sort of return on your investment have you seen? And how do you measure it: sales conversions or engagement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We measure both. Although we have a very strong and growing Facebook and Twitter community, we [also] want to have a truly engaged community. In terms of metrics, we look at &lt;a href="http://www.mashable.com/tag/klout"&gt;Klout&lt;/a&gt; score, amplification and responses. We pay close attention to what types of messages we post and how they are received, and that informs our thinking going forward. It&amp;#8217;s truly a constant learning process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve recently begun experimenting with Fcommerce by offering discounts on certain items through &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/toryburch" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Why have you pursued that strategy in particular?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re testing some concepts now, including exclusives on Facebook. It&amp;#8217;s more of a surprise and delight for our Facebook community, and so far it&amp;#8217;s been successful in driving excitement and sales. Consumers who are fans of a brand on Facebook have a certain appropriate expectation that there should be an exclusive benefit just for them. [Our exclusive discounts] are about tapping into that sensibility. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you think Facebook will ever become a major sales channels for you? If not, what value does it offer you as a company?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We believe that social shopping, or Fcommerce as everyone is calling it now, is the future of ecommerce. The demographic skews younger on Facebook compared to our core customer, so we see it as a really important way to connect with that consumer. We&amp;#8217;re embracing [Fcommerce] with our Facebook shop and our exclusives early on so we can learn quickly. I don&amp;#8217;t think we&amp;#8217;ll import our full catalog to Facebook. My hunch is &amp;#8212; and Honor and I talk about this a lot &amp;#8212; that the experience should be curated in some way, and we&amp;#8217;re testing some ideas and concepts with that in mind. We love &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/16/google-ipad-app-catalogs/"&gt;Google Catalogs&lt;/a&gt;, the idea of taking our traditional printed formats and bringing it into a digital space, but I think &amp;#8212; as we were mentioning earlier about social platforms needing to be slightly differentiated &amp;#8212; that is true of social shopping as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the same potential exist for other platforms?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;re all so different. I think about Flipboard and being able to create your own personalized content, but it&amp;#8217;s hard to say. Facebook is certainly the destination where social shopping is being most closely integrated, both on Facebook Pages and on retail sites.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you planning to set up a Google+ page?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yes, we&amp;#8217;re excited.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice would you give other brands &amp;#8212; fashion or otherwise &amp;#8212; going forward?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#8217;s about being yourself. In the social space it&amp;#8217;s just as important to stay true to your brand and your brand&amp;#8217;s lens just as you would anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/fashion/"&gt;fashion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/marketing/"&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/miki-berardelli/"&gt;Miki Berardelli&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media-marketing/"&gt;social media marketing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/tory-burch/"&gt;tory burch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/business/"&gt;Business&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashbusiness" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Business on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/business" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Business channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/6_sTyhKePQEFKkFEVpw89CnXBkY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/6_sTyhKePQEFKkFEVpw89CnXBkY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/6_sTyhKePQEFKkFEVpw89CnXBkY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/6_sTyhKePQEFKkFEVpw89CnXBkY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=NaClIn6l6fQ:Rf2wvq-zMO8:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/NaClIn6l6fQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/26/tory-burch-cmo-miki-berardelli/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to Mashable&#8217;s Socially Savvy Supporters</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/advertise"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/&amp;title=Thanks to Mashable&#8217;s Socially Savvy Supporters&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Mashable-billboard-360.jpg" alt="" title="Mashable billboard 360" width="360" height="225" class="alignright size-full wp-image-744507" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Thanks to this week&#8217;s advertisers and partners for enabling us to bring you the latest social media news and resources. Mashable&amp;#8217;s sponsors are as social media savvy as our readers!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Advertise with us and get noticed.&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mashable is seeking site sponsors for our large, diverse audience &amp;#8212; social media users, venture capitalists, early adopters, developers, bloggers and many more. You&amp;#8217;ll receive hundreds of thousands of views per day in addition to weekly recognition as part of our &amp;#8220;thank you&amp;#8221; to our premium sponsors. Are you interested? &lt;a href="mailto:advertising@mashable.com"&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt; for more information and to receive our media kit and rate card.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span id="more-811053"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; This week, our valued sponsors are: &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.messagemaker.com/social?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=display&amp;#038;utm_campain=mmslaunch&amp;#038;utm_content=Byline" target="_blank"&gt;MessageMaker Social&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://lenovo.com/us/en/?cid=us|disp|ba|mash|lenovobrand|6572&amp;#038;dfaid=1" target="_blank"&gt;Lenovo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.bmw-i.com" target="_blank"&gt;BMW i&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://sproutsocial.com/?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Weekly+Roundup" target="_blank"&gt;Sprout Social&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.idgknowledgehub.com/blogs/?p=7139&amp;#038;utm_source=MashableSP_3.17.11&amp;#038;utm_medium=MashableSP_3.17.11&amp;#038;utm_campaign=MashableSP_3.17.11" target="_blank"&gt;IDG&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.sps.cuny.edu/onlinems" target="_blank"&gt;CUNY School of Professional Studies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://oneupweb.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Oneupweb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.softlayer.com/" target="_blank"&gt;SoftLayer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.srds.com/trial/mashable.html" target="_blank"&gt;SRDS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/whitepaper-form_review-strategies-for-effective-facebook-wall-posts_retail_campaign.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Banner&amp;#038;utm_content=DataReport2_Whitepaper&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Banner%7CMashable%7CSiteServed%7CPartnerPost%7CText" target="_blank"&gt;Buddy Media&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;243146560;66840934;k" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Clickatell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.microsoftstartupzone.com/BizSpark?WT.mc_id=MSZ_Mashable_weeklythanks" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft BizSpark&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.eventbrite.com/r/mashable" target="_blank"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;246936788;71372949;i;pc=[TPAS_ID]" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/FedEx-logo-100.jpg" alt="" title="FedEx logo 100" width="100" height="65" class="alignright size-full wp-image-768933" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;246936788;71372949;i;pc=[TPAS_ID]" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FedEx&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; does more than shipping. They offer solutions like transporting heart valves to those in need and helping entrepreneurs bring their ideas to life. &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;246936788;71372949;i;pc=[TPAS_ID]" target="_blank"&gt;See how&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fedex supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/commerce-with-a-conscience-series"&gt;Commerce With a Conscience Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-767277" title="Smart_Logo 100" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Smart_Logo-100.jpg" alt="" width="100" height="65" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smart&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; unbig. uncar. Test drive the space saving, eco-friendly, totally unique, smart. Visit &lt;a href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;247593531;61309116;f?http://www.smartusa.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;smartusa.com&lt;/a&gt; to find a new smart center near you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Smart supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/tech-trendsetters-series"&gt;Tech Trendsetters Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.messagemaker.com/social?utm_source=Mashable&amp;amp;utm_medium=display&amp;amp;utm_campain=mmslaunch&amp;amp;utm_content=Byline" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/messagemaker-100.jpg" alt="" title="messagemaker 100" width="100" height="65" class="alignright size-full wp-image-703515" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.messagemaker.com/social?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=display&amp;#038;utm_campain=mmslaunch&amp;#038;utm_content=Byline" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MessageMaker Social&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the social media management system (SMMS) that lets you publish and manage targeted content across a large number of social interaction points while generating actionable intelligence. This smart, simple SaaS solution elevates your company&#8217;s social presence among thousands of social Pages and accounts, helping you meet compliance regulations, maintain brand consistency, maximize engagement and generate actionable intelligence &#8212; without adding additional human resource costs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MessageMaker Social supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-ceo-series"&gt;Social CEO Series&lt;/a&gt;. Follow MessageMaker Social on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/#!/msgmkrsocial" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://lenovo.com/us/en/?cid=us|disp|ba|mash|lenovobrand|6572&amp;amp;dfaid=1" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Lenovo_DO_Logo_100x50.jpg" alt="" title="Lenovo 100" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-655277" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://lenovo.com/us/en/?cid=us|disp|ba|mash|lenovobrand|6572&amp;#038;dfaid=1" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lenovo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; does not just manufacture technology. They make Do machines &#8212; super-powered creation engines designed to help the people who do, do more, do better, do in brand new ways.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lenovo supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/tech-innovators-Series"&gt;Tech Innovators Series&lt;/a&gt;. Follow Lenovo on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/lenovo" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://facebook.com/lenovo" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.bmw-i.com" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/20110412_BMWi_iLogo_RGB_141x61.png" alt="" title="BMW i logo 100" width="100" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-587043" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.bmw-i.com" target="_blank"&gt;BMW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; i is a new concept dedicated to providing mobility solutions for the urban environment. It delivers more than purpose-built electric vehicles &#8212; it delivers smart mobility services. Visit bmw-i.com.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;BMW i supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.mashable.com/global-innovation"&gt;Global Innovation Series&lt;/a&gt;. Follow BMW i on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://twitter.com/#!/bmwi" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/bmwi" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/IDG-logo-1001.jpg" alt="" title="IDG logo 100" width="100" height="65" class="alignright size-full wp-image-594741" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;With the explosion of mobile devices, advertising dollars will begin to shift to mobile for tech marketers this year. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.idgknowledgehub.com/blogs/?p=7139&amp;#038;utm_source=MashableSP_3.17.11&amp;#038;utm_medium=MashableSP_3.17.11&amp;#038;utm_campaign=MashableSP_3.17.11" target="_blank"&gt;IDG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Global Solutions President Matt Yorke talks about the rise of social and how IDG helps marketers create social campaigns. The line is fading between social media and traditional media. Earned media or sharing of information within social networks is becoming mainstream whether on a PC or mobile device. &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.idgknowledgehub.com/blogs/?p=7139&amp;#038;utm_source=MashableSP_3.17.11&amp;#038;utm_medium=MashableSP_3.17.11&amp;#038;utm_campaign=MashableSP_3.17.11" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;IDG supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/modern-media-agency-series/"&gt;Modern Media Agency Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Oneupweb.jpg" alt="" title="Oneupweb" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-502947" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://oneupweb.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Oneupweb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an agency specializing in search marketing, social media and design for mid-to-enterprise level brands. Keep up with Oneupweb through its &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://straightupsearch.com/" target="_blank"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and monthly &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.oneupweb.com/news/newsletter/" target="_blank"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oneupweb supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/behind-the-social-media-campaign-series"&gt;Behind the Social Media Campaign Series&lt;/a&gt;. Follow Oneupweb on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/#!/oneupweb" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/oneupweb" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/SoftLayer.jpg" alt="" title="SoftLayer" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-490239" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.softlayer.com/" target="_blank"&gt;SoftLayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; provides global, on-demand data center and hosting services from facilities across the U.S. it leverages best-in-class connectivity and technology to innovate industry leading, fully automated solutions that empower enterprises with complete access, control, security, and scalability.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow SoftLayer on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/softlayer" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/SoftLayer" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/SRDS.jpg" alt="" title="SRDS" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-447061" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.srds.com/trial/mashable.html" target="_blank"&gt;SRDS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; connects agencies, brands and media through its online database of media planning data. SRDS is committed to making it easier to buy online ad space and build integrated marketing campaigns. Sign up for a free 14-day trial of the SRDS consumer and business database &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.srds.com/trial" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow SRDS on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/srds" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/SRDS/233139127466" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/buddy-media-logo-1001.jpg" alt="" title="buddy media logo 100" width="100" height="60" class="alignright size-full wp-image-591699" /&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/whitepaper-form_review-strategies-for-effective-facebook-wall-posts_retail_campaign.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Banner&amp;#038;utm_content=DataReport2_Whitepaper&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Banner%7CMashable%7CSiteServed%7CPartnerPost%7CText" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buddy Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is Power Tools for Facebook. Have something new to tell 500 million people? Learn the best way to manage multiple brands on Facebook with this &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://forms.buddymedia.com/whitepaper-form_review-strategies-for-effective-facebook-wall-posts_retail_campaign.html?utm_source=Mashable&amp;#038;utm_medium=Banner&amp;#038;utm_content=DataReport2_Whitepaper&amp;#038;utm_campaign=Banner%7CMashable%7CSiteServed%7CPartnerPost%7CText" target="_blank"&gt;webinar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Buddy Media supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook-marketing-series"&gt;Facebook Marketing Series&lt;/a&gt;, which is about how brands can advertise on Facebook. Follow Buddy Media on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/buddymedia" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/buddymedia" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/clickatell-logo.png" alt="" title="clickatell logo" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-777479" /&gt;Reach the world with &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://ad.doubleclick.net/clk;243146560;66840934;k" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clickatell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As the leading SMS gateway we magnify the reach of your mobile communications channel on a truly global scale. Now your social applications can cost-effectively and reliably make contact with over 960 networks in more than 220 countries.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow Clickatell on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/clickatell" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Clickatell/187073743959" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/microsoft_bizspark_logo.jpg" alt="" title="microsoft_bizspark_logo" width="100" height="26" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367130" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.microsoftstartupzone.com/BizSpark?WT.mc_id=MSZ_Mashable_weeklythanks" target="_blank"&gt;BizSpark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a program which offers new software businesses and entrepreneurs access to Microsoft design, development and production tools with no upfront costs for up to three years. Learn more or connect with a Microsoft BizSpark advisor &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.microsoftstartupzone.com/BizSpark?WT.mc_id=MSZ_Mashable_weeklythanks" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;BizSpark supports Mashable&amp;#8217;s weekly &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/bizspark/"&gt;Spark of Genius Series&lt;/a&gt;, which showcases promising startups. Follow Microsoft BizSpark on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/bizspark" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/bizspark?v=app_7146470109" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/eventbrite.jpg" alt="" title="eventbrite" width="100" height="56" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367004" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.eventbrite.com/r/mashable" target="_blank"&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an online events marketplace where tens of thousands of individuals, businesses and organizations of all sizes manage, promote and sell tickets to their events. Make your event a success on Eventbrite. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow Eventbrite on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/eventbrite" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/Eventbrite" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Additionally, thanks to the following partners for making Mashable happen:&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/intridea-logo-green-horiz-simple-100x50.png" alt="" title="intridea-logo-100x50" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-550285" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="intridea.com" target="_blank"&gt;Intridea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an application development consultancy specializing in Ruby on Rails and mobile development, and has worked with many Fortune 500 companies and funded startups. Visit &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="intridea.com" target="_blank"&gt;intridea.com&lt;/a&gt; or call 1-888-968-IDEA (4332).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Intridea has created the official Mashable apps for platforms including Android, iPad, and the Mac App Store. Follow Intridea on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/intridea" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://facebook.com/intridea" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Webtrends_logo_100x50.jpg" alt="" title="Webtrends_logo_100x50" width="100" height="50" class="alignright size-full wp-image-550343" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://webtrends.com" target="_blank"&gt;Webtrends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; founded the web analytics industry in 1993. Today, its leadership extends much further to social media measurement, paid-search optimization and connecting the online and offline data silos scattered throughout organizations. Webtrends helps you analyze the data generated by your web site, blogs, online campaigns and enterprise systems to understand your customers and, ultimately, business opportunities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow Webtrends on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/webtrends" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/webtrends" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/w3edge.jpg" alt="" title="w3edge" width="100" height="27" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367008" /&gt;Since 2007 &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a title="Web Design Company" rel="nofollow" href="http://www.w3-edge.com/" target="_blank"&gt;W3 EDGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has assisted with creative, web development, and search and social media marketing for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/"&gt;Mashable.com&lt;/a&gt; and its other web properties and projects. Day-to-day maintenance and support is handled by Frederick Townes and his W3 EDGE team.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow W3 EDGE on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/w3edge" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/rackspace.jpg" alt="" title="Logo_lockup_version-2 SPOT" width="100" height="39" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367124" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://bs.serving-sys.com/BurstingPipe/adServer.bs?cn=tf&amp;amp;c=20&amp;amp;mc=click&amp;amp;pli=889085&amp;amp;PluID=0&amp;amp;ord=[timestamp]" target="_blank"&gt;Rackspace Hosting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the world&amp;#8217;s leader in the hosting and cloud computing industry. The San Antonio-based company provides Fanatical Support&#174; to its customers across a portfolio of IT services. For more information, visit &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="www.rackspace.com" target="_blank"&gt;rackspace.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mashable.com is hosted on Rackspace, and Rackspace sponsors Mashable&amp;#8217;s Web Development Series. Check it out &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/web-development-series/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and follow Rackspace on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/rackspace" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/istockphoto-img.jpg" alt="" title="istockphoto img" width="100" height="30" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367062" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php" target="_blank"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; offers easy, affordable inspiration with millions of safe, royalty-free photos, illustrations, video, audio and Flash&#174; files. Browse the best stock library of royalty free content at prices anyone can afford. Mashable readers &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php" target="_blank"&gt;save 10%&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mashable sources many of its photos from iStockphoto. Follow iStockphoto on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/istock" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/iStockphoto-Inc/20425620824" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/dyn.png" alt="" title="dyn" width="100" height="46" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367022" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dyn.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;Dyn Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a world leader in managed DNS, powering the best brands on the web including Gowalla, Mashable, Twitter, Wikia and more. For more information about Dyn Inc., visit &lt;a href="http://www.dyn.com" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;www.dyn.com&lt;/a&gt;, e-mail hello@dyn.com or call +1-603-668-4998. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mashable provides exclusive content on Dyn.com. Check it out &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://dyn.com/category/open-dialogue/mashable-exclusive" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and follow Dyn on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/dyninc" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.facebook.com/dns.experts" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/concentric-sky.jpg" alt="" title="concentric sky" width="100" height="24" class="alignright size-full wp-image-367024" /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.concentricsky.com/" target="_blank"&gt;ConcentricSky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; offers web and mobile development with a focus on emerging technologies. With partners ranging from National Geographic and Encyclopedia Britannica to NASA and The World Bank, Concentric Sky is known for delivering innovative, world-class software solutions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Concentric Sky is the only App Developer officially endorsed by Mashable. Learn more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-networking/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and follow ConcentricSky on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://twitter.com/concentricsky" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can get your name out there.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:advertising@mashable.com"&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt; for more information about supporting Mashable&amp;#8217;s growth and development. Alternatively, visit our &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/advertise"&gt;advertise section&lt;/a&gt; for more details about:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Competitive direct ad sales&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Sponsorship opportunities for events and other channels&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Sponsored giveaways and contests&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Custom ad deals and partnerships&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable/"&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/sponsors/"&gt;Sponsors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/RF1rfcEZpLg9OMmXKJ0lYzR1C_s/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/RF1rfcEZpLg9OMmXKJ0lYzR1C_s/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/RF1rfcEZpLg9OMmXKJ0lYzR1C_s/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/RF1rfcEZpLg9OMmXKJ0lYzR1C_s/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=EMOQywJLo4Q:ZvqR-RA1NtI:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/EMOQywJLo4Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/mashable-supporters-11-24/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Y Combinator Experience With the Founders of Codecademy [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;script language="JavaScript" type="text/javascript" src="http://admin.brightcove.com/js/BrightcoveExperiences.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;object id="myExperience$BCpost" class="BrightcoveExperience"&gt;&lt;param name='wmode' value='opaque'&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /&gt;&lt;param name="width" value="608" /&gt;&lt;param name="height" value="342" /&gt;&lt;param name="playerID" value="1265504713001" /&gt;&lt;param name="publisherID" value="1130468786001"/&gt;&lt;param name="isVid" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="linkBaseURL" value="http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/codecademy-video/" /&gt;&lt;param name="isUI" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="@videoPlayer" value="1295411308001" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since Zach Sims and Ryan Bubinsky left Columbia University to join &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/y-combinator/"&gt;Y Combinator&lt;/a&gt;, their startup, &lt;a href="http://codeacademy.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;, has attracted close to 1 million users and $2.5 million in funding from elite tech investors like Fred Wilson&#8217;s Union Square Ventures, Ron Conway&#8217;s SV Angel fund and Yuri Milner. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In our latest episode of Venture Studio, the founders talk about the Y Combinator experience and what it takes to launch a company with the huge vision of teaching the world how to code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/venturestudio" target="_blank"&gt;Venture Studio&lt;/a&gt;, in association with &lt;em&gt;Mashable&lt;/em&gt;, is brought to you by &lt;a href="https://www.square1financial.com/venturestudio" target="_blank"&gt;Square1 Bank&lt;/a&gt;. The show is hosted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/davidblerner"&gt;Dave Lerner&lt;/a&gt;, a 3x entrepreneur and angel investor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/codecademy/"&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/mashable-video/"&gt;mashable video&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/venture-studio/"&gt;venture studio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/y-combinator/"&gt;y combinator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/startups/"&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/MashStartups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Startups on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/startups" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Startups channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/_Ka_yBMwfjQA8p5tIZEgizK6dW0/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/_Ka_yBMwfjQA8p5tIZEgizK6dW0/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/_Ka_yBMwfjQA8p5tIZEgizK6dW0/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/_Ka_yBMwfjQA8p5tIZEgizK6dW0/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?a=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?a=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?i=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?a=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?i=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?a=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?a=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable/Startups?i=Pq_XCjUSZRM:pXLz2G17Rwk:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/Startups/~4/Pq_XCjUSZRM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/codecademy-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/codecademy-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EC to use Facebook, Twitter to woo voters - The Times of India</title>
      <description>The Election Commission of India plans to use the social media for spreading the message.</description>
      <link>http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tech/social-media/EC-to-use-Facebook-Twitter-to-woo-voters/articleshow/10879885.cms</link>
      <guid>http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tech/social-media/EC-to-use-Facebook-Twitter-to-woo-voters/articleshow/10879885.cms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AT&amp;T Wants You to &#8216;Make a Case&#8217; for an AT&amp;T 4G Phone via Facebook</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/&amp;title=AT&amp;#038;T Wants You to &amp;#8216;Make a Case&amp;#8217; for an AT&amp;#038;T 4G Phone via Facebook&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/att-case-face-360.jpg" alt="" title="att case face 360" width="275" class="alignright size-full wp-image-814375" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;AT&amp;#038;T has launched a campaign that lets you advocate for an AT&amp;#038;T 4G smartphone over &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; this holiday season.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;a href="http://www.youvegotacase.com" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;#8220;You&amp;#8217;ve Got a Case&amp;#8221; Facebook app&lt;/a&gt;, you can create a personalized video for one of five AT&amp;#038;T smartphones: the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/02/att-lte-smartphones/"&gt;HTC Vivid&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/02/att-lte-smartphones/"&gt;Samsung Galaxy SII Skyrocket&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/02/05/htc-inspire-4g/"&gt;HTC Inspire 4G&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/10/11/att-five-android-smartphones/"&gt;Samsung Captive Glide 4G&lt;/a&gt; or the the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/03/rim-five-blackberries/"&gt;BlackBerry Torch 4G&lt;/a&gt;. The video, which has been optimized for both the desktop and mobile devices, will let you employ the persuasive powers of actor Will Arnett, who poses as a lawyer to advocate for the phone on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To create a video, you&amp;#8217;ll need to head over to &lt;a href="http://www.youvegotacase.com" target="_blank"&gt;youvegotacase.com&lt;/a&gt; and give the app permission to access your Facebook profile. You can then tell your lawyer what phone you would like and whom you would like to &amp;#8220;serve&amp;#8221; your case to: your mother, your spouse, etc. (If the person you&amp;#8217;d like to serve doesn&amp;#8217;t have a Facebook account, you can opt to send the video via email.) The video, or case, can then be shared to the Facebook wall of both you and your &amp;#8220;defendant,&amp;#8221; where &amp;#8220;a jury of your Facebook peers&amp;#8221; can weigh in.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/att-case-wall.jpg" alt="" title="att case wall" width="456" height="286" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-814373" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the videos are a little contrived, but the application smartly makes public to people you&amp;#8217;re likely to influence (i.e., your Facebook friends) that you&amp;#8217;re shopping for an AT&amp;#038;T phone. It&amp;#8217;s also a more colorful way of hinting what you&amp;#8217;re after than dropping a link to an online order form.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What do you think of the campaign? If you were (or are) planning to ask for an AT&amp;#038;T 4G phone as a present this winter, would you use this Facebook app to do so?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;A Note on AT&amp;#038;T&amp;#8217;s 4G Network&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although all five smartphones in the campaign are labeled as 4G phones, it&amp;#8217;s worth noting that AT&amp;#038;T&amp;#8217;s 4G LTE network has only come to a handful of metropolitan areas so far, including Dallas/Forth Worth, San Antonio, Houston, Atlanta, Chicago, Boston, Washington, D.C., Baltimore, and Athens, GA. AT&amp;#038;T promises the network will come to another six cities, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/04/att-lte-service-new-york-city/"&gt;including New York&lt;/a&gt;, by the end of 2011. 4G-enabled phones will have download speeds of 5-12 Mbps, or about 10 times faster than what&#8217;s offered through AT&amp;#038;T&#8217;s 3G network, the carrier claims.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/att/"&gt;att&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/bbdo/"&gt;BBDO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/marketing/"&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vZztCffOO7L2fv5qeppA7PrbRo4/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vZztCffOO7L2fv5qeppA7PrbRo4/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vZztCffOO7L2fv5qeppA7PrbRo4/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/vZztCffOO7L2fv5qeppA7PrbRo4/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=xObkp4WnLSc:rpJmtuZaRCo:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/tech/~4/xObkp4WnLSc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/25/att-youve-got-a-case-facebook-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
