<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>How Yahoo Killed Flickr and Lost the Internet [Exclusive]</title>
      <description>Web startups are made out of two things: people and code. The people make the code, and the code makes the people rich. Code is like a poem; it has to follow certain structural requirements, and yet out of that structure can come art. But code is art that does something. It is the assembly of something brand new from nothing but an idea. More &#187;</description>
      <link>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</link>
      <guid>http://gizmodo.com/5910223/how-yahoo-killed-flickr-and-lost-the-internet</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GM to Stop Advertising on Facebook (Wall Street Journal)</title>
      <description>GM plans to stop advertising on Facebook after its marketing executives determined their paid ads had little impact on consumers, a disappointing development just days ahead of Facebook's IPO.</description>
      <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304192704577406394017764460.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</link>
      <guid>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052702304192704577406394017764460.html?mod=rss_asia_whats_news</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook and Twitter Ad Spending to Double by 2016 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>This week&#8217;s impending Facebook IPO, which could top $12.7 billion, is sparking questions about the value of Facebook and other social networks. The future of social media ad spending may justify the hype surrounding Facebook, which is geared to being the highest valued U.S. Internet company at IPO. Within four years, global ad spending on social media platforms will reach $9.8 billion from $3.8 billion in 2011, according to BIA/Kelsey&#8217;s U.S Local Media Forecast. Social media ad revenue in the U.S. is predicted to jump from $840 million in 2011 to $3.1 billion in 2016. Companies will drive the ad growth on social networks by incorporating more creative elements like video and pictures. Facebook and Twitter are paving the way for the rise in online ad earnings. Both companies are making crucial changes to their advertising platforms that open doors for companies hoping to reach consumers online instead of offline. &#8220;Facebook opening its ads API to more partners, including those that work with SMBs (small and medium businesses), and Twitter&#8217;s self-serve platform will help to &#8216;democratize&#8217; social ads, which will ultimately lead to more local growth,&#8221; Jed Williams, BIA/Kelsey analyst and program director, states. In its Facebook IPO roadshow video for potential investors, company COO Sheryl Sandberg spoke about Facebook&#8217;s new business model. Sandberg said the end goal is to become the choice online advertising platform for the 70 million businesses worldwide. Facebook is pushing its personalized and targeted ads. Its formula for success being reach, relevance, engagement and social context. Sandberg stated users are adopting the social network faster than ads are incorporated &#8212; an imbalance that needs correcting. Facebook cited successful clients, including Ben &amp; Jerry&#8217;s Ice Cream, American Express and liquor brand Diageo. However, General Motors pulled a huge $10 million advertising campaign from Facebook on Tuesday, citing ineffective ads. SEE ALSO: General Motors Pulls $10 Million Ad Campaign From Facebook [REPORT] Twitter introduced a new way for small business to advertise through the microblogging website in March. The self-serve advertising platform will be available for clients to create promoted tweets and promoted accounts. Twitter, who partnered with American Express for the advertising initiative, opened up the platform to the first 10,000 business to sign up. Do you think social media will see the bulk of online advertising campaigns in the future? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, arakonyunus More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, TwitterFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/facebook-and-twitter-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/facebook-and-twitter-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU</title>
      <description>Tom Murphy: Fenway http://t.co/W5t6XAyU &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgmkkQMCpW/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When it comes to buying local, you can't get much closer than in your "Under Pants." http://t.co/mvDAzrxY</title>
      <description>Doug French: When it comes to buying local, you can't get much closer than in your "Under Pants." http://t.co/mvDAzrxY &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kh7baLix8m/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kh7baLix8m/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX</title>
      <description>Scary Mommy: I want one!!! RT @DarleneMAM: Complimentary massages. Thanks Scary Mommy @scarymommy http://t.co/dIrssWMX &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KgX94Dw9y3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways to Optimize Your iPad for Kids With Special Needs</title>
      <description>When we think about ways the iPad has changed the world, our minds usually shoot to publishing, entertainment, or mobile communication. For the community of people living with disabilities, the iPad may have broken even more ground. The iOS device is not only cool, but provides education, therapy and, of course, entertainment. Last summer, Mashable explored ways iPads are making these changes. Now we&#8217;re following up with Sami Rahman, the father of 4-year-old Noah and co-founder of BridgingApps, the Internet&#8217;s largest database of special needs app and reviews. Noah began using his iPad when he was two and was assessed to be 12 months behind with language and cognition. Within four months, he was on par for his age. Now, two years since he began using the iPad, he is 15 months ahead developmentally, can read English and Arabic, and is learning Mandarin. SEE ALSO: 4 Ways iPads Are Changing the Lives of People With Disabilities Rahman recently released his book Getting Started: iPads for Special Needs. Rahman shared some of his insights for preparing an iPad for people with disabilities. Most of the tricks are tailored for parents or educators working with children. 1. Pick the Right Specs One of the biggest differences between the iPad 2 and the new iPad is retina display, which can create an incredible visual experience. Most special needs iPad users will not appreciate it at all, Rahman says, unlike artists or photographers. The reason to choose the new iPad would be if you want or need 4G connectivity. The iPad 2, however, offers a major advantage over the original iPad &#8212; cameras. A major problem for many people living with learning disabilities is learning to associate an abstract concept with the physical object. In other words, recognizing that an illustration of a tree is related to the tree outside of the window. Taking photos on the iPad can be helpful for learning to associate food as an icon with food as an item, for instance. This can be useful in the classroom environment, where a teacher can create content on the go without going back and forth to the computer. When it comes to choosing the right size, Rahman says most social needs apps are not too large. If your iPad is just going to have one primary user, you won&#8217;t need any larger than 32GB. However, if the device is going to be shared in a classroom, 64GB could be worthwhile. 2. Volume Control Rahman says his wife&#8217;s favorite tip is to cover the speaker with masking tape. His son Noah, who has cerebral palsy, loves to jack up the volume on his iPad to be &#8220;blood curdling loud.&#8221; &#8220;Because the iPad is a platform I can&#8217;t install software on to regulate the overall volume, we literally put cellophane tape over the speaker,&#8221; Rahman says. Another option is to get a big case, which can muffle some of the sound, if you don&#8217;t want to restrict control over the tablet. 3. Explore Accessibility Features The iPad comes with a lot of accessibility features already included, which you should explore. Voice over is one great feature for the visually impaired, which reads what you swipe out loud when it&#8217;s switched on. You can also try &#8220;white on black&#8221; view, zoom (for the visually impaired) and assisted touch (press a button instead of shaking your iPad). Rahman recommends setting the triple click on the home button to turn on the accessibility feature you use most regularly. 4. Try an External Keyboard While some special needs users are great with the touchscreen keyboard, there can be two advantages to attaching an external keyboard to the iPad. First, it&#8217;s easier for people with fine motor issues to get an accurate touch. Second, if you&#8217;re trying to work with multiple languages with different alphabets, you can attach character stickers on to keys rather than flipping between the iPad&#8217;s language options. 5. Make Time for FaceTime For people on the autism spectrum, learning to make eye contact can be incredibly challenging &#8212; it&#8217;s also one of the first warning signs that a child may not be inputting social interactions correctly. Using FaceTime to chat with friends and relatives outside of your home can be a great way to build those skills. The facial close-up forces kids to look into the eyes of the person with whom they&#8217;re chatting. &#8220;For any child that has a hard time with social interactions, FaceTiming with relatives can be fun and incredibly therapeutic,&#8221; Rahman says. 6. DIY Keyguard Keyguards are a very inexpensive way to give a voice to people who are uncommunicative and can be purchased cheaply for $20 or made by hand from foam board and an X-Acto knife. Rahman recalls visiting with a non-verbal student in one school who used a two-button keyguard to communicate yes and no. After answering a sequence of yes or no questions, expressing his preferences for different needs and likes, the boy told a joke. Humor is, of course, a huge indicator of intelligence, Rahman notes. &#8220;Do you have fun in school?&#8221; Rahman asked, expecting a yes, following a series of correctly answered questions. The boy smiled, placed his hand near the yes, and then slid his finger over to the no button. The boy again hit down the no. &#8220;Really?&#8221; Rahman asked a final time. The boy moved his hand over and pressed yes, indicating he in fact enjoyed school. 7. Set Boundaries It should come as no surprise that iPads can be lots of fun for the special needs population, so parents need to set boundaries from the start. &#8220;The iPad is totally useless without a plan,&#8221; Rahman says. &#8220;Everyone owns a hammer but few people can use it to build a building.&#8221; Comparing an iPad to a pacifier, Rahman says parents must draw lines to prevent the iPad from becoming just an entertainer, and to ensure it is used for education and therapy. 8. Make Photo Albums Learning to associate pictures of objects with concepts can take years for some people with special needs, but the iPad can be an important learning tool if you take pictures and organize photo albums. The tablet can become a great communicator when you view 16 icons at once, and allow the user to choose what they want. You can give people who are non-verbal and partially non-verbal the ability to express preference by showing them, for instance, pictures of foods that they can eat for a given meal. You can also show options of activities, clothes or people. 9. Keep Cleaning While iPads can be great babysitters, if you want to use the tablet for therapy or education you&#8217;ll need to frequently mix up the types of apps your child is using. &#8220;If you&#8217;re not removing apps on a regular basis, you&#8217;re focusing on entertainment, not education and therapy,&#8221; Rahman says. Parents almost always tell Rahman that they&#8217;re not removing apps from their children&#8217;s iPads, meaning they&#8217;re not letting their children flex their muscles or learn new skills. 10. Lock Screen The constant rotation of the screen can be incredibly frustrating for some individuals with special needs. You can choose to lock the screen to prevent the display from reorienting as the device moves. This will give the user a greater feeling of control over their experience. Rahman notes that for his own son, after two years with his iPad, it was a big moment when he learned to navigate with an unlocked screen. &#8220;I don&#8217;t want him to just settle, I want a kid that forces the world he wants,&#8221; Rahman says. More About: apple, features, ipad, parenting, Social Good, special needsFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/ipad-special-needs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/11/ipad-special-needs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General Motors Pulls $10 Million Ad Campaign From Facebook [REPORT]</title>
      <description>General Motors has pulled $10 million in ads from Facebook because they just didn't work, according to Wall Street Journal reporter Dennis K. Berman, Berman, the Journal's Marketplace editor, wrote on Twitter: "GM has pulled its $10 million advertising campaign from Facebook. Why? The ads didn't work." GM will continue to use Facebook's free media to promote its brands, the WSJ reported. The report comes awkwardly in front of Facebook IPO, expected Friday. It's part of a drumbeat of background noise to the offering, suggesting that advertising on Facebook is less effective than clients would like it to be. Click-through rates are much lower on Facebook than they are on the internet generally, or on Google, according to WordStream (which manages search ads on Google and thus has a conflict of interest): Facebook: 0.051%Google: 0.4%Average: 0.1% The other issue is whether Facebook is right for all advertisers. Search advertising&#8212;the kind Google provides&#8212;tends to be more effective on customers who are actively doing pre-purchase research. Facebook, on the other hand, is more of an entertainment medium; no one is shopping for cars on Facebook&#8212;a fact GM seems to have now learned. GM had previously invested heavily in Facebook-oriented products and media. In 2011, it allowed customers to customize their vehicles on Facebook and share the designs with friends. GM also integrated Facebook with OnStar, allowing drivers to respond to Facebook messages with voice commands. Facebook has also been a source of stress for GM. In November, Saab lovers virtually occupied a GM Facebook account, flooding it with messages urging the brand be preserved. The social network was also the medium through which environmental groups embarrassed the company into ending its funding of the Heartland Institute, a global warming denialist group. Please follow Advertising on Twitter and Facebook.Join the conversation about this story &#187;</description>
      <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/why-general-motors-pulled-10-million-ad-campaign-from-facebook-2012-5?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+businessinsider+%28Business+Insider%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.businessinsider.com/why-general-motors-pulled-10-million-ad-campaign-from-facebook-2012-5?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+businessinsider+%28Business+Insider%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Facebook for Pseudo A/B Testing</title>
      <description>Brian Honigman is the digital marketing manager at Marc Ecko Enterprises. He is a part of Ecko&#8217;s marketing and ecommerce team, ensuring a polished brand experience across all channels. Follow him on Twitter @Brian_Honigman. A/B testing is a crucial way to compare two versions of your creative, website layout, ads, and other digital assets to understand what best resonates with your audience. That said, it can also be unruly and expensive, even when you only use the tools focused on giving you the best results. One way to get around this is your brand&#8217;s Facebook Page. Your Facebook Page offers a unique opportunity to test your website&#8217;s offerings quickly and with little cost. (Think of it as pseudo A/B testing.) Here are some reasons to consider this option and how to do it. Why Look For Other Ways of A/B Testing? Cost: Typical methods of A/B testing often require major spend to ensure they&#8217;ve performed correctly. The results of the testing are often worth the cost of comparing the two versions of your creative and navigation, but it truly depends on what you&#8217;re testing. For example, a site-wide overlay may be worth this level of testing as opposed to a banner you might only be using on one page of your website. Time: The time it takes to complete A/B testing can vary greatly depending on many factors. Using a test duration calculator can help determine the exact time frame of your testing period. When testing two elements of your website, it&#8217;s better to have the test run for a longer period of time for the most accurate results. But there are exceptions. Traditional A/B testing can take a long time and make deciding upon the creative for large or small campaigns a long process, which can prove problematic when you&#8217;re on a tight schedule. How Is Facebook a Helpful Testing Ground? While I would not recommend this for large-scale initiatives, A/B testing your creative assets on Facebook can be extremely beneficial when it comes to optimizing smaller campaigns. With no cost, a brand could post two versions of a photo or other creative suited for Facebook and ask their audience specifically which photo resonates with them more. The engagement you get on your Facebook content is often instantaneous, and you can quickly see what&#8217;s performing better with your audience within this channel. It&#8217;s quick, free, and effective for gathering feedback from your target demographic. Once you&#8217;ve posted two similar images on Facebook for a period of time, you&#8217;ll want to dive into the data, which will show up in the form of comments, likes, shares, and clicks. In this example from Arby&#8217;s Facebook Page, you can look to see which photo is performing better than the other. Based on the feedback for this post, you can determine if either Arby&#8217;s curly fries or potato cakes are more loved by this Facebook audience. Such information could help Arby&#8217;s make decisions as to where they would place one product on their web properties over the other. Remember to do these tests gracefully. It&#8217;s still important to keep your Facebook audience engaged with quality content that provides value. Would you use Facebook to A/B test your content or stick to more traditional methods? Share in the comments below. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, iPandastudio More About: brands, contributor, Facebook, facebook page, features, Marketing</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/how-to-facebook-page-ab-test/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/15/how-to-facebook-page-ab-test/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Celebrating Mom on the skyline of Springfield, MA http://t.co/4akKIPAW &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kgmf2eFgP7/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yummy catering :) http://t.co/vYGJlLSz</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Yummy catering :) http://t.co/vYGJlLSz &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/KcoPEElgMR/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/KcoPEElgMR/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage neon tote..have to have it #brimfield http://t.co/s0EQ8WDh</title>
      <description>The Land of Nod: Vintage neon tote..have to have it #brimfield http://t.co/s0EQ8WDh &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/Kh-EZZFgMS/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/Kh-EZZFgMS/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
