<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Money and Mobile Commerce [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;re over the age of 20, you&#8217;ve likely used a credit card, counted change and maybe even written a check. But is all that about to change? Mobile payment hasn&#8217;t become the de facto method of financial transactions just yet, but it is projected to overtake those archaic checkbooks and bank notes you&#8217;ve been lugging around. Three types of mobile payments dominate the marketplace today: m-commerce (uses a mobile browser and online wallets), m-payments (uses mobile apps), and m-wallets (replaces your entire wallet). Furthermore, consumers can access several forms of transaction on their mobile devices, including scannable barcodes, mobile coupons and self-checkout. SEE ALSO: How PayPal Here Stacks Up Against Other Mobile Payment Options But are consumers ready to wholeheartedly adopt the latest in mobile payment technology? Adults who are unbanked, for instance, may face a barrier to mobile transactions &#8212; there are currently 17 million unbanked adults in the U.S. But many smartphone users welcome the convenience of mobile payments (87% in the UK), while others worry about the privacy factor (79% in Asia). Still, 49% of consumers in the U.S. found shopping on a smartphone awkward. Then again, many people found paper checks awkward and credit cards confusing the first time around. Where do you fall in the mobile payment debate? What kinds of transactions do you handle on your smartphone? Let us know your thoughts in the comments below. More About: apps, Business, infographics, Mobile, mobile payments</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/future-of-mobile-payments/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/future-of-mobile-payments/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Instagram Photo Could Win You a Trip Across the World</title>
      <description>Do you love Instagram and love to travel? Win a Social Media Week contest and you&#8217;ll go on a trip across the world if you can capture the best shot of your city. Social Media Week is looking for the 14 best shots of this year&#8217;s 14 host cities &#8212; Barcelona, Berlin, Bogota, Chicago, Doha, Glasgow, Hong Kong, Jeddah, London, Los Angeles, Sao Paulo, Seoul, Torino and Vancouver &#8212; taken with smartphones. All you need to do is tag your contest-worthy photo with #InstagramYourCity and the name of the city you&#8217;ve captured by June 29. You can submit photos filtered by other photo apps, such as Hipstamatic, Camera+ and Lightbox. There&#8217;s also no limit to the number of photos you can enter, so feel free to go wild. One photo will be chosen from all applicants from the 14 cities. The winning photographer can chose to spend Social Media Week, which will take place Sept. 24 through 28, in any of the hosting cities. Social Media Week has been hosted by 26 different cities over the last four years. BONUS: 25 Most-Followed Users on Instagram 25. Jason Mraz Username: Jason_Mraz Followers: 363,621 Number of Pictures: 254Click here to view this gallery. Image Courtesy of bridif More About: instagram, social media week, travelFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/instagram-social-media-week/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/instagram-social-media-week/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Lunchtime Photos From the Mashable Community</title>
      <description>For many, lunch is a daily opportunity to break away from one&#8217;s work routine. This week&#8217;s Mashable Photo Challenge asked you to send us a photo that represented your lunch break. This challenge inspired the most diverse collection of photos we&#8217;ve seen so far. We saw photos ranging from desk-side Tupperware to lunchtime excursions. You gave us a glimpse of spectacular noontime locations from California beaches to Paris caf&#233;s. Have a look through these photos from Mashable readers around the world. And be sure to participate in this week&#8217;s upcoming challenge: nostalgia. Appareil Phonatoire "Pause repas devant l'ordi (Lunch break in front of my computer)."Click here to view this gallery. More About: community, Mashable Photo Challenge, photographyFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/photo-challenge-lunch-break-results/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/photo-challenge-lunch-break-results/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roozt Is the Etsy for Social Entrepreneurs</title>
      <description>Ecommerce site Roozt is trying to become the go-to hub for socially conscious consumers. With Roozt, shoppers can browse products based on cause supported, region of the world, or products sold. Brent Freeman founded Roozt about three years ago with the idea of creating an Etsy-style marketplace for social entrepreneurs, providing a distribution platform for mission-oriented brands. In Freeman&#8217;s words, Roozt is &#8220;bringing sexy back to giving back,&#8221; making it easy to look and feel good at the same time. &#8220;Gen Y loves brands that express personality through their purchase,&#8221; Freeman told Mashable. &#8220;You can quickly go into Roozt, discover the coolest brands making a difference, see their products and get into their mission.&#8221; In 2012, Roozt began offering flash deals as well as traditional retail. Unlike Groupon or other big-name flash deal sites, your purchase will send money toward a cause. Recent flash offers include WeWood watches, which plants one tree through American Forests for each purchase; Indosole sandals, which saves one tire from a landmine in Indonesia for every two pairs purchased; and Ssesko sandals, which give money towards women&#8217;s education in Uganda. &#8220;Brands have a greater opportunity because of the marketplace platform,&#8221; Freeman says. &#8220;People need to find out what a company&#8217;s doing in 140 characters or less, to simply be able to discover them.&#8221; Roozt is also gamifying ecommerce by offering rewards and badges. When you sign up, you earn a &#8220;Change Maker&#8221; badge and a $10 credit. As you return to the site, purchase products, and share your purchases on Facebook, Twitter, or invite friends by email, you receive more reward money and more prestigious badges. Are you more likely to make a purchase if it&#8217;s from a brand doing good? Sound off in the comments. More About: ecommerce, Social GoodFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/roozt/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/25/roozt/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr Adds &#8216;Ads&#8217;</title>
      <description>Tumblr finally has its first ads &#8212; except they&#8217;re not &#8220;ads,&#8221; according to Tumblr. This new feature on Tumblr allows the growing social network to use its Radar and Spotlight features on its Dashboard to draw attention to advertisers &#8212; or &#8220;sponsors,&#8221; as Tumblr calls them. Tumblr Radar gets more than 120 million daily impressions, which Tumblr says will offer sponsors &#8220;the opportunity to gain thousands of new followers, likes and reflags.&#8221; Meanwhile, sponsors also have the opportunity to be featured &#8220;front-and-center&#8221; on Tumblr Spotlight. The Spotlight feature, curated by a team of editors, is a sample of some of the more especially creative blogs on Tumblr and is a driver of &#8220;tens of millions of follows each week for new and existing users.&#8221; Tumblr CEO David Karp announced that sponsored posts would be coming to Tumblr at the Ad Age Digital Conference, which took place in New York earlier this month. Though Karp had vehemently been against advertising in the past &#8212; he told the Los Angeles Times in 2010, &#8220;We&#8217;re pretty against advertising. It really turns our stomachs&#8221; &#8212; he later called himself an &#8220;idiot&#8221; for making that comment. The implementation of these sponsored posts comes at the heels of the departure of Tumblr President John Maloney, who resigned this past weekend. According to the Wall Street Journal, &#8220;people familiar with the situation&#8221; said that Maloney&#8217;s skills as a generalist manager were becoming less relevant to Tumblr as it added executives in finance, engineering and human resources &#8212; in other words, as it grows beyond its start-up roots. &#8220;I am a good operator,&#8221; Maloney said. &#8220;Am I one of those big network operators? That is not particularly interesting to me nor does it play to my strengths.&#8221; After explosive growth in 2011, Tumblr hit 20 billion total posts at the end of March. At the announcement of the ads in mid-April, it had reached 21.3 billion total posts. Now &#8212; just two weeks later &#8212; it has added nearly a billion more total posts, according to its About page, which keeps a running list of statistics on the site. Tumblr currently lacks an ad sales force, but Derek Gottfrid, the company&#8217;s vice president of product who currently oversees revenue, said in the Wall Street Journal article that the company plans to build a small ad sales team. &#8220;You should expect a slow build,&#8221; he said. And even though Tumblr doesn&#8217;t like to call its ads &#8220;ads,&#8221; the company does acknowledge that advertising is the game it&#8217;s playing: &#8220;We&#8217;re looking for the world&#8217;s greatest marketers and media companies to help us raise the bar for creative advertising on the web,&#8221; Tumblr states in its Sponsors page. &#8220;If you&#8217;re game, we&#8217;d love to talk!&#8221; Do you think the addition of sponsored posts to Tumblr Spotlight distorts viewers&#8217; understanding of what&#8217;s creative on Tumblr? Can Tumblr maintain its commitment as a &#8220;platform for self-expression&#8221; with these ads? Sound off in the comments. Image courtesy of Ozneo More About: Advertising, Business, tumblr</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/tumblr-adds-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/02/tumblr-adds-ads/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips for Great Content Curation</title>
      <description>Steven Rosenbaum is the CEO of Magnify.net, a real-time video curation engine for publishers, brands, and websites. He&#8217;s also the author of Curation Nation. You&#8217;ve heard the buzz word &#8212; curation &#8212; being thrown around like it&#8217;s a gadget we all know how to work. In reality, good content curation isn&#8217;t as simple as pushing a share button. It&#8217;s actually a combination of finding great content and following some simple best practices on how to successfully share that content. If you&#8217;re a curator looking for some boundaries in what feels like the Wild West, here are five best practices to consider. 1. Be Part of the Content Ecosystem Be part of the content ecosystem, not just a re-packager of it. Often, people think of themselves as either creators or curators as if these two things are mutually exclusive. What a curator really should do is embrace content as both a maker and an organizer. The most successful curators include sites like The Huffington Post, that embrace the three-legged-stool philosophy of creating some content, inviting visitors to contribute some content, and gathering links and articles from the web. Created, contributed, and collected &#8212; the three &#8216;c&#8217;s is a strong content mix that has a measurable impact. Why? Because your visitors don&#8217;t want to hunt around the web for related material. Once they find a quality, curated collection, they&#8217;ll stay for related offerings. 2. Follow a Schedule Audiences expect some regularity, and they&#8217;ll reward you for it. It doesn&#8217;t need to be a schedule that you can&#8217;t keep up with. If you want to curate three new links a day, and write one big post a week, that&#8217;s a schedule. Make sure to post at the same time each week. This is so readers know when to expect new material from you. Consistency and regularity will also bring you new users, and help you grow a loyal base of members who appreciate your work. A good example of someone who gets why a schedule makes a difference is Jason Hirschhorn via his MediaReDEF newsletter. He never misses a publish date. 3. Embrace Multiple Platforms It used to be that your audience came to you. Not anymore. Today content consumers get their information on the platform of their choosing. That means you should consider posting short bursts on Tumblr, images on Pinterest, video on YouTube, and community conversations on Facebook. And don&#8217;t leave out established sites and publishers. If your audience hangs out on a blog, you may want to offer that publication some guest posts or even a regular column. Essentially, you have to bring your content contributions to wherever your readers may be. 4. Engage and Participate Having a voice as a curator means more than creating and curating your own work. Make sure you&#8217;re giving back by reading others and commenting on their posts. A re-tweet is one of the easiest ways to help build relationships with fellow bloggers and curators. And your followers will appreciate that you&#8217;ve pointed them to good content. One word here, I never hit an RT without clicking through to read what I&#8217;m recommending. You can also lose followers if you don&#8217;t put in the effort to recommend material that you really think merits their attention. 5. Share. Don&#8217;t Steal. Take the time to give attribution, link backs, and credit. The sharing economy works because we&#8217;re each sharing our audiences, and providing the value of our endorsements. If you pick up someone&#8217;s work and put it on your blog, or mention a fact without crediting the source, you&#8217;re not building shared credibility. You&#8217;re just abusing someone else&#8217;s effort. The important thing to realize is that we&#8217;re increasingly living in a world of information overload. So when people choose to listen to you it&#8217;s because you&#8217;re able to separate signal from noise. You provide a clear, contextually relevant voice within the topic or topics that you create and curate. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, JamesBrey More About: content curation, contributor, features, online marketing, Web curation</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/tips-great-content-curation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/27/tips-great-content-curation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Is Exploring a Premium Version, CEO Suggests</title>
      <description>Twitter might be developing a premium version of its service, CEO Dick Costolo indicated on stage at Wired&#8216;s business conference in New York City Tuesday afternoon. An audience member asked Costolo whether Twitter would ever introduced a &#8220;pro&#8221; version for individual users. Costolo refused to confirm that Twitter was working to develop one, but did suggest that it was an idea the company was exploring. Costolo said he imagined a product with &#8220;lightweight controls&#8221; for users. &#8220;Our designers and engineers would define how that would work. I don&#8217;t know what it will look like,&#8221; he said. He offered no further details about what the premium product might look like, nor whether Twitter is developing any premium offerings for brands. What would you like to see in a pro version of Twitter? Let us know in the comments. More About: dick costolo, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/twitter-pro-service/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/01/twitter-pro-service/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the 80-Year-Old Grandma on a Quest for 80,000 Twitter Followers</title>
      <description>When the poet Dylan Thomas wrote of growing old, &#8220;do not go gently into that good night,&#8221; it&#8217;s a safe bet he didn&#8217;t have Twitter in mind. But Josephine Lamberti does. The 80-year-old Staten Island grandma is, as her @J_DIMPS Twitter bio puts it, on a quest for &#8220;80K followers (or maybe a million) before I die!&#8221; And she&#8217;s getting close, having already racked up more about 65,000 in less than two years on the network. She&#8217;s become a hit with celebrities, getting retweets and DMs from pop stars and pro athletes alike and becoming something of an online celebrity in her own right. Earlier this year, the NBA player Nate Robinson invited her and her grandson to a game after chatting over Twitter. &#8220;We went and he met us after the game,&#8221; J. Dimps says. &#8220;He wanted to meet me more than I wanted to meet him. It was awesome.&#8221; J. Dimps &#8212; short for dimples &#8212; originally joined Twitter and began her quest for followers with the help of 24-year-old grandson Donny Brandefine. &#8220;Well, it was getting a little boring, so he came over and we tried to figure out something to keep me busy,&#8221; she says. &#8220;We came up with this idea, and it&#8217;s been good.&#8221; Brandefine &#8212; who Dimps calls &#8220;my right arm&#8221; &#8212; says his grandmother has always had a rambunctious personalty and that she&#8217;s taken her online celebrity acquaintances in stride. A list called MyAdoptedGrandchildren contains more than 300 celebrities she&#8217;s interacted with on Twitter or is especially fond of. &#8220;Thats all the big stars she has following her,&#8221; Brandefine says. &#8220;To me its crazy seeing her just sit there like, &#8216;Yeah, Jose Canseco&#8217;s reading me, Rihanna&#8217;s reading me.&#8217; She thinks she&#8217;s a big shot over here!&#8221; Dimps says she remains young at heart, as if her social media presence &#8212; she&#8217;s also on Facebook and YouTube &#8212; wasn&#8217;t proof enough. She Tebows, and she represents the hashtag #OLDladySWAG. What&#8217;s old lady swag mean? &#8220;I&#8217;m really cool, stylish,&#8221; she says. &#8220;Funny. That&#8217;s about it. I really don&#8217;t act my age.&#8221; Dimps says she acts &#8220;maybe 21,&#8221; and her tastes have evolved since she used to ballroom dance at the Palladium concert hall. &#8220;Now I dance to the Rihanna music,&#8221; she says. &#8220;I don&#8217;t do the lindy or things like that no more.&#8221; Despite racking up the Twitter followers, Dimps has managed to keep her followed-by-to-following ratio proper, at about 63,000 to 5,500. So how can you get a follow back from Dimps as she makes her way to 80K? &#8220;If they make me laugh,&#8221; she says, &#8220;I&#8217;ll follow them back.&#8221; Will you help 80-year-old J. Dimps meet her goal of 80,000 followers? Let us know in the comments. More About: TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/grandma-on-a-twitter-quest/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/26/grandma-on-a-twitter-quest/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>House Passes CISPA: Make Sure It Dies In The Senate</title>
      <description>We pushed them to the brink, but House Republicans rammed through CISPA this afternoon, ahead of schedule. Let&amp;#39;s make sure it dies in the Senate: Please add your name at right.</description>
      <link>http://act.demandprogress.org/letter/cispa_passes/?akid=1332.320809.DITcFI&amp;rd=1&amp;t=2</link>
      <guid>http://act.demandprogress.org/letter/cispa_passes/?akid=1332.320809.DITcFI&amp;rd=1&amp;t=2</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
