<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Klout Adds Blogger, Flickr, Instagram, Last.fm &amp; Tumblr - Mashable</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEk-0X4PWfjA5TRBQkf6Jq3mOTK7A&amp;amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/10/klout-adds-blogger-flickr-instagram-last-fm-tumblr/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Klout Adds Blogger, Flickr, Instagram, Last.fm &amp;amp; Tumblr&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Mashable&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;And within the past month, it integrated &lt;b&gt;Foursquare&lt;/b&gt; and YouTube to its algorithm. &#8220;The networks we launched today were chosen to give the Klout Score a more holistic view of influence,&#8221; Klout CEO Joe Fernandez told Mashable. &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHHgdK76aDydtmF47FzJmMqe0f7Bg&amp;amp;url=http://techcrunch.com/2011/08/10/after-foursquare-klout-adds-blogger-tumblr-instagram-flickr-and-last-fm-to-measure-social-influence/"&gt;After &lt;b&gt;Foursquare&lt;/b&gt;, Klout Adds Blogger, Tumblr, Instagram, Flickr And Last.fm To &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;jfkl=true&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dm6kiJ45c0N7njMkiNY2pC1zJ-WUM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;all 2 news articles&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/10/klout-adds-blogger-flickr-instagram-last-fm-tumblr/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/10/klout-adds-blogger-flickr-instagram-last-fm-tumblr/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greg Kot Tweets from SXSW | Follow Kot on his blog</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://twitter.com/#!/gregkot</link>
      <guid>http://twitter.com/#!/gregkot</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TMI.me: when you have too much to say...</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://tmi.me/dyEMy</link>
      <guid>http://tmi.me/dyEMy</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: Watney 'settles the score' with Doral</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502#42063502"&gt;&lt;img align="left" border="0" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/NBCSports/Components/Video/_NEW/s_nbc_glf_wgccadillacwatneyintv_110313_4x3.thumb.jpg" alt="March 13: Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)" style="margin:0 5px 5px 0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Jimmy Roberts interviews Nick Watney after winning the 2011 WGC-Cadillac Championship at Doral in Florida. (NBC Sports)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;</description>
      <link>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</link>
      <guid>http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/21134540/vp/42063502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Can Now Watch "The Big Lebowski" with Your Facebook Friends</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/big-lebowski-facebook/?utm_source=ab2bc&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/big-lebowski-facebook/?utm_source=ab2bc&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German State Bans Facebook&#8217;s &#8220;Like&#8221;</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BERLIN -- A German data protection authority is "unliking" Facebook's "Like" button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The state of Schleswig-Holstein's data protection commissioner, Thilo Weichert, on Friday ordered state institutions to shut down the fan pages on the social networking site and remove the "Like" button from their websites, saying it leads to profiling that violates German and European law.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Facebook insisted Friday that is in full compliance with European data protection laws.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday, Weichert issued a statement saying technical analysis by his office shows Facebook violated German and European data protection laws by passing content data to the social network's servers in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"Whoever visits facebook.com or uses a plug-in must expect that he or she will be tracked by the company for two years," Weichert said. "Facebook builds a broad individual and for members even a personalized profile."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A Facebook spokesman conceded that the company can see "information such as the IP address" of users who visit a site with a "Like" button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;"We delete this technical data within 90 days," said the spokesman, who did not give his name in keeping with company policy. "That is in keeping with normal industry standards."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Weichert's office ordered website owners in Schleswig-Holstein to "immediately stop the passing on of user data to Facebook in the USA by deactivating the respective services" and threatened to take legal action if they fail to comply.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He also urged Internet users in general to "keep their fingers from clicking on social plug-ins" and "not set up a Facebook account" to avoid being profiled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The keepers of Germany's strict privacy laws have repeatedly clashed on issues of privacy with international Internet giants, such as Facebook and Google &amp;ndash; often with success.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Last year Google allowed Germans who opposed its Street View mapping system to blur images of their homes, while Facebook in January granted members more control over their email address books, after a dispute over its "Friend Finder" service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Germany's latest spat with the Palo Alto, California-based Facebook also comes a week after a leading member of Chancellor Angela Merkel's conservative party in Schleswig-Holstein stepped down after admitting to having an affair with a 16-year-old he met over the social networking site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Christian von Boetticher's resignation sparked a debate about the role of social media in politicians' lives, with German newspapers carrying reports from party members, angry that the state legislator spent more time posting personal information to Facebook than focusing on his job. He has since deleted his Facebook profile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/08/19/facebook-like-button-illegal-germany_n_931652.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/08/19/facebook-like-button-illegal-germany_n_931652.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Blocking Social Media During Civil Unrest Is Never the Right Choice [OPINION]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/&amp;title=Why Blocking Social Media During Civil Unrest Is Never the Right Choice [OPINION]&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mashable-op-ed-220-37.jpg" class="alignleft"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This post reflects the opinions of the author and not necessarily those of Mashable as a publication.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/padlock-laptop.jpg" alt="" title="padlock laptop" width="275" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-712081" /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="intro"&gt;David Gorodyansky leads the execution of all business operations at &lt;a href="http://anchorfree.com/" target="_blank"&gt;AnchorFree&lt;/a&gt;, makers of &lt;a href="http://hotspotshield.com/" target="_blank"&gt;HotSpot Shield&lt;/a&gt;, an application that secures a user&amp;#8217;s connection on public networks and allows them to access any website from any location, and was featured as one of &lt;a href="http://www.inc.com/ss/meet-30-under-30-coolest-entrepreneurs#16" target="_blank"&gt;Inc&amp;#8217;s 30 Under 30&lt;/a&gt; in 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When people come together and gather their collective minds, they can accomplish nearly anything. On the other hand, this capacity can apply to situations both great and terrible. For instance, the sheer power of numbers can be dedicated to raising awareness for a worthy cause, or it can be used to fight back against a repressive regime, only to devastate the streets in a violent riot. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thomas Jefferson &lt;a href="http://www.monticello.org/site/jefferson/when-governments-fear-people-there-libertyquotation" target="_blank"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that the government should fear the people. Especially when those people are capable of powerful acts of defiance, it&#8217;s not surprising to see the government act on that fear by attempting to prevent the mobilization of a frustrated collective.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/10/government-riots-social-media/"&gt;Should Governments Monitor Social Media to Prevent Civil Unrest?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lately, these efforts at quashing unrest have targeted the tools people use to communicate and coordinate, specifically the social media that has become indispensable for mass communication. The censorship of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/twitter/"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; during the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/arab-spring/"&gt;Arab Spring&lt;/a&gt; might have seemed tyrannical to Western onlookers, but media communication censorship has occurred elsewhere. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/BBM.jpg" alt="" title="BBM" width="640" height="336" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-712091" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The UK government called for the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/11/uk-riots-social-media/"&gt;suspension of the BlackBerry Messenger&lt;/a&gt; service during this month&#8217;s London riots in an effort to prevent the populace from thwarting police efforts. And San Francisco&#8217;s Bay Area Rapid Transit system &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/12/bart-anonymous/"&gt; (BART) blocked cell service at four of its stations&lt;/a&gt; to circumvent protests. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The problem with such attempts to block social media is that they are reactionary measures made through fear. The actions neglect to address the issues underlying people&#8217;s unrest, potentially harm the innocent, and ultimately fail to accomplish the intended goal of repressing the momentum of an uprising. Shutting down social media is not the right choice, unless the government&#8217;s aim is to reinforce its already Draconian presence.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A modern society is built upon the unification of people from diverse backgrounds, nationalities, genders, races and religions. We have come far to reach a balance of coexistence, based on the ability of different peoples to freely exchange ideas and opinions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As social media is the outlet of choice for today&#8217;s community-minded citizen, silencing it is detrimental to societal growth, no matter how temporary the measure. Censorship defiles the freedoms that benefit civilization. Worse still, it gives the impression that a government is willing to impede the communication of its entire populace in order to hinder the efforts of a select few.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Communication is not inherently good or evil, neither harmful nor benign. However, by manipulating communication tools to indulge one&#8217;s own agenda, or by shutting down the tools themselves, you demonize their inherent potential for good. These actions demonstrate a shortsighted concern with &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; dissidents are coming together, while neglecting to address &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they feel oppressed in the first place. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Furthermore, social media is not the only tool in the arsenal of the malcontent: Dissenters will find ways to dodge online censorship and utilize alternate networks of communication. By blocking the quickest, easiest and most open forms of communication, a government effectively pushes offending communication further underground, where it will be nurtured by the most dedicated members of the opposition &amp;#8212; those most likely to take extreme actions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/01/27/bypass-twitter-facebook-block-egypt/"&gt;How Users in Egypt Are Bypassing Twitter &amp;#038; Facebook Blocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Still, if shutting down social media can stop the spread of dangerous violence, isn&#8217;t that of greater immediate benefit to the general public than free and easy communication? Again, the answer is no. The suspension of communication tools disregards innocent bystanders subsequently impacted by the loss of vital social media. More harm will be done to your unintended targets than to those engaged in protests or rioting. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/riot-fire.jpg" alt="" title="riot fire" width="640" height="314" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-712087" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In times of fear and uncertainty, citizens rely on each other for news and information. People are likely to seek out social networks for news on avoiding unsafe areas, on finding safe havens in the event of injury. By blocking this flow of information, you increase the chance that a commuter blindly stumbles into a looting riot, you incense a panicked bystander trying to reach his cordoned-off street, and you prevent a parent from confirming that her child is safe.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Shutting down social media increases risk, while solving so few of the problems of civil unrest. It is the wrong choice during a time of crisis. While open communication may allow the circulation of dangerous ideas, we cannot allow paranoia to outweigh its positive benefits, namely, our continued growth and survival as a connected society.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/stock-photo-2923331-computer-security-series.php?st=ef5816e" target="_blank"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=743622" target="_blank"&gt;peepo&lt;/a&gt;, Flickr, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/one_schism/5185466489/in/photostream/" target="_blank"&gt;deep_schismic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/xabier-martinez/5646521150/in/photostream/" target="_blank"&gt;Xabier.M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/censorship/"&gt;censorship&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/opinion/"&gt;Opinion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/politics/"&gt;politics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/social-media/"&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/social-media/"&gt;Social Media&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashsocialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Social Media on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/socialmedia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Social Media channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0-0cKs7Ylu9QaIXteJQJT5nYKvg/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0-0cKs7Ylu9QaIXteJQJT5nYKvg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0-0cKs7Ylu9QaIXteJQJT5nYKvg/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/0-0cKs7Ylu9QaIXteJQJT5nYKvg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?a=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=2aiq1U6_FTE:oozHCE3yh8U:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/2aiq1U6_FTE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/19/social-media-block-protests/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind scenes, meticulous preparations under way - Associated Press</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; LONDON (AP) -- Fifty days and counting down. Behind the scenes hundreds are hard at work to make sure the April 29 royal wedding is a day to remember - not just for Prince William and Kate Middleton, but for the country. As the date nears, the machinery that makes a British royal event look, smell</description>
      <link>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</link>
      <guid>http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_ROYAL_WEDDING_THE_COUNTDOWN?SITE=AP&amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;CTIME=2011-03-09-20-37-16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Wells: Time for some meaningful tennis &#8211; Around the Corner - World Tennis Magazine</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGNU9ZGpo-Q-PJOsYBfzOsfGTYkSw&amp;amp;url=http://www.skysports.com/story/0,19528,12110_6801658,00.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://nt3.ggpht.com/news/tbn/k7wmx_mV59mrtM/6.jpg" alt="" border="1" width="80" height="80" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-2"&gt;SkySports&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGBxw2GZXHuzwOEC3wNZCi8KN0C9A&amp;amp;url=http://www.worldtennismagazine.com/archives/4161"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Indian Wells: Time for some meaningful &lt;b&gt;tennis&lt;/b&gt; &#8211; Around the Corner&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;World Tennis Magazine&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;It&amp;#39;s time again for some meaningful &lt;b&gt;tennis&lt;/b&gt;. No disrespect to the ATP World Tour level 250 and 500 tournament&amp;#39;s, but the BNP Paribas Masters in Indian Wells represents a return to top-level &lt;b&gt;tennis&lt;/b&gt; with all the big names in attendance. &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGEnBF-jahL9DnjIv4h8Rjhf7lOIQ&amp;amp;url=http://espn.go.com/sports/tennis/blog/_/name/tennis/id/6197409/win-lose-djoker-swagger-back"&gt;Win or lose, Djoker&amp;#39;s swagger is back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;ESPN (blog)&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEiQN5IiQMF2aWtqX36ak-9wzfrag&amp;amp;url=http://www.livemint.com/2011/03/09212018/Return-of-the-Djoker.html?h%3DB"&gt;Return of the Djoker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;Livemint&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEBTFLE_wi5V9Hbz502gVyZc9HZqQ&amp;amp;url=http://www.current-movie-reviews.com/sports/2011/03/09/indian-wells-draw-out-who-ends-up-at-number-2-is-anyones-guess/"&gt;Indian Wells Draw Out; Who Ends Up At Number 2 Is Anyone&amp;#39;s Guess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="-1" color="#6f6f6f"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;CMR&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF_4mzTJjK_zO6jVMUYPkSM5h16Sw&amp;amp;url=http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5h5s8dfFyzBuhqyL-foDUQeMzptEA?docId%3DCNG.b09b68ea979ffda897db2854fb9c493a.01"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;AFP&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNE87MjCdvBMOEP9RoNEzElpY5OYBg&amp;amp;url=http://www.tennisearth.com/news/tennisNews/Nadals-real-test-in-Indian-Wells--BNP-Paribas-Open-Mens-Preview-177561.htm"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;TennisEarth.com&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;-&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHYTm6LvRSfF0fVHN2NObxqatDZEQ&amp;amp;url=http://nbcsports.msnbc.com/id/41955344/ns/sports-tennis/"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;msnbc.com&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=d3i87imlEWVLVMMk2SqPXT1T_UC2M"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;all 141 news articles&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.worldtennismagazine.com/archives/4161</link>
      <guid>http://www.worldtennismagazine.com/archives/4161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twocation</title>
      <description>NO_SUMMARY</description>
      <link>http://www.twocation.com/</link>
      <guid>http://www.twocation.com/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to School: 15 Essential iOS Apps for Students</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/&amp;title=Back to School: 15 Essential iOS Apps for Students&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/back-to-school.jpg" alt="back to school" title="back to school" width="260" height="" class="alignright size-full wp-image-708723" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Forget Sharpies and highlighters, the new back to school essentials this fall are apps for your &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ipad/"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#8221;http://mashable.com/category/iphone/&#8221;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/ipod/"&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; touch. While cellphones used to be classroom contraband, the burgeoning market of educational apps means iOS devices are as welcome as loose leaf and pencils.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This school year, free iOS apps can replace your pricey graphing calculator and clunky dictionary. Inexpensive planners will organize your homework, grades and finances. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEE ALSO: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/16/back-to-school-student-tech/"&gt;Back to School: 42 Digital Resources for Students &amp;#038; Parents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve rounded up the essentials for the season, so you won&amp;#8217;t go back to school unprepared. These 15 apps will keep your academic and extracurricular life on track.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;1. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/amazon-student/id454603718?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Student&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#234991-Amazon-Student"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="1. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/amazon-student/id454603718?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Amazon Student&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Amazon Student.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes to waste money on textbooks -- especially after putting your John Hancock on an increasingly fat tuition check. Amazon Student is here so you can avoid overpaying for your pile of books. Use the app to scan barcodes in the bookstore and compare your campus hub to Amazon.com's prices. Likewise, at the end of the term, exchange your used books, games, movies or gadgets for credit by scanning their barcodes. The icing on the cake? Free two-day shipping for college students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;2. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aroundme/id290051590?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;AroundMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235012-AroundMe"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="2. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aroundme/id290051590?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;AroundMe&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/AroundMe.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch (with limited functions)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; If you're headed to a new town to study, AroundMe is a great tool to help you get the lay of the land. The app finds the nearest banks, hospitals, bars, gas stations, hotels, coffee shops, restaurants, taxi companies, theaters and supermarkets. With AroundMe on your iOS device, you'll limit the perpetual U-turns and mistaken directions that come standard with learning a new city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;3. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dictionary.com-dictionary/id385756768?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Dictionary &amp; Thesaurus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235033-Dictionary--Thesaurus"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="3. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dictionary.com-dictionary/id385756768?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Dictionary &amp;amp; Thesaurus&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Dictionary &amp; Thesaurus.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $2.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Don't consider buying a dictionary for your dorm room with this app on the market. Without an Internet connection, this mobile dictionary and thesaurus gives you access to nearly 2,000,000 words. Turn on the popular Word of the Day notifications to improve your vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;4. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/documents-to-go-office-suite/id317117961?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Documents To Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235054-Documents-To-Go"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="4. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/documents-to-go-office-suite/id317117961?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Documents To Go&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Documents To Go.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $9.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad and iPhone&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Create, edit and share Word (.doc, .docx), PowerPoint and PDF files from your iOS device with Documents To Go. Add last minute edits to your papers or takes notes on presentations without lugging around your laptop. The mobile app now includes intricate formatting options, so even work done from your iPhone can look polished.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;5. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/free-graphing-calculator/id378009553?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Free Graphing Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235075-Free-Graphing-Calculator"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="5. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/free-graphing-calculator/id378009553?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Free Graphing Calculator&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Free Graphing Calculator.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Don't think about dropping $100 on a ti83 now that this app in on the market. This free calculator includes your standard arithmetic and exponential functions, and can graph up to four color-coded equations at once. An added bonus is a bank of equations stored in its reference section. The only downside is we can't guarantee your professors will let you have your mobile device out during an exam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;6. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/grades-2/id427900301?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Grades 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235096-Grades-2"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="6. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/grades-2/id427900301?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Grades 2&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Grades 2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Are you the type that likes to know exactly where your grade-to-date stands? Grades 2 is designed to compute those pesky calculations for you, assuring you know what scores you'll need on each assignment to achieve your sought after A. You can personalize the app with each of your courses' syllabi. The app also works as a personal organizer, reminding you about deadlines and upcoming exams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;7. &lt;a href="" target="_blank"&gt;iHomework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235237-iHomework"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="7. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;iHomework&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://8.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/iHomework.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $1.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Before you invest in a leather-bound planner, vowing to religiously log all your to-dos, consider iHomework instead. The app will keep your schedule and workflow streamlined, alerting you with all your deadlines and assignments. If a friend sleeps though class (the app alerts you for class so you'll never be the one sleeping late) you can share missed assignments though email. Log your grades so you know what your report card will look like in advance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;8. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ihomework/id302786560?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;iStudiez Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235258-iStudiez-Pro"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="8. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ihomework/id302786560?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;iStudiez Pro&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/iStudiez Pro.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $2.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Organize even the most complicated course schedule with iStudiez. Visualize your classes, activities and assignments on this well designed color-coded calendar. Like many of the other organization apps, you can set reminders for major events and track your grades and GPA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;9. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mint.com-personal-finance/id300238550?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Mint.com Personal Finance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#235119-Mintcom-Personal-Finance"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="9. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mint.com-personal-finance/id300238550?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mint.com Personal Finance&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Mint.com Personal Finance.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Many students are first-timers when it comes to money management. This app helps you establish and stick to a budget, factoring expenses from bar tabs to laundry change. The app can house your checking, credit, savings and retirement account information. Worried about what could happen to your personal finance information should you lose your phone? The app gives you a four-digit pin code to access the Mint.com website and block access to your app should something happen to your device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;10. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/papers/id304655618?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;Papers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#2351310-Papers"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="10. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/papers/id304655618?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Papers&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Papers.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $14.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; You'll never need to do a mass printout again with Papers, the app that digitizes your academic library. The PDF viewer is designed for easy reading, especially on the iPad. Papers comes with eight academic search engines -- ACM, NASA-ADS, arXiv, Google Scholar, IEEE Xplore, JSTOR, Pubmed and Web of Science -- so you have many resources for finding articles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;11. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/penultimate/id354098826?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" target="_blank"&gt;Penultimate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#2351511-Penultimate"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="11. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/penultimate/id354098826?mt=8&amp;amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Penultimate&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Penultimate.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $1.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are a die-hard believer in writing notes by hand, try Penultimate, a notebook simulator allowing you scribble notes into your iPad. This app is great if you're a science or math student, using symbols that are difficult to input into a word processor. Some of Penultimate's fancy features include different colored gel pen style tips, importable paper styles and a true to life eraser. You can organize your notes into different notebooks, making your iPad a seamless replacement to paper note taking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;12. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/snoozerr-recordings/id453389744?ls=1&amp;mt=8#" target="_blank"&gt;Snoozerr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#2351712-Snoozerr"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="12. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/snoozerr-recordings/id453389744?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8#&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Snoozerr&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Snoozerr.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; $0.99&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Even the sharpest students' minds can wander during a lecture. With Snoozerr you can record your lectures to revisit points of a class you missed the first time around. The app includes a time-stamped photo function, so you can take pictures of a graph or diagram on the board which corresponds to class notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;13. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/stanza/id284956128?mt=8# " target="_blank"&gt;Stanza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#2351913-Stanza"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="13. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/stanza/id284956128?mt=8# &amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Stanza&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/Stanza.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Book lovers and literature students alike should make room for Stanza on their iOS devices. The app includes 50,000 free classic titles as well as another 50,000 contemporary titles from partner stores. Add your favorite books to personalize your digital library. If you're someone who rapidly breezes through books, hopefully Stanza's vast collection will satiate your reading bug for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;14. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/usb-disk/id370531520?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;USB Disk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#2352114-USB-Disk"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="14. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/usb-disk/id370531520?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;USB Disk&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://4.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/USB Disk.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone and iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; Eliminate your tiny, easily misplaced USB drive with the USB Disk app. Store and view all your documents and PDFs from your mobile device. USB Disk is also a great way to back up photos and videos from your computer, so you can always have your essential files at your fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;15. &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vocabplus-lite/id402842002?mt=8" target="_blank"&gt;VocabPlus Lite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/#2352715-VocabPlus-Lite"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="15. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vocabplus-lite/id402842002?mt=8&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;VocabPlus Lite&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;" src="http://7.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/ios-apps-for-back-to-school/vocabplus.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Free&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supported devices:&lt;/strong&gt; iPad, iPhone, iPod touch&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you need it:&lt;/strong&gt; If you're preparing for a dreaded standardized test this year, use VocabPlus Lite to integrate new words into your vocabulary. The app teaches 1,500 words through digital flashcards. Once you've mastered a word, the app removes the card from your regular drills, so you an focus on new information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image courtesy of &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/mashableoffer.php"&gt;iStockphoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.istockphoto.com/user_view.php?id=652260"&gt;skodonnell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/education/"&gt;education&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/ios-apps/"&gt;iOS apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/ipad-apps/"&gt;ipad apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/iphone-apps/"&gt;iphone apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashablemobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Mobile on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.mobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/mobile" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Mobile channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/P7ynw9KACl0-i1IRfmt8RABSUfE/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/P7ynw9KACl0-i1IRfmt8RABSUfE/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/P7ynw9KACl0-i1IRfmt8RABSUfE/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/P7ynw9KACl0-i1IRfmt8RABSUfE/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:_e0tkf89iUM"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=_e0tkf89iUM" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:P0ZAIrC63Ok"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=P0ZAIrC63Ok" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:I9og5sOYxJI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=I9og5sOYxJI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:CC-BsrAYo0A"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?d=CC-BsrAYo0A" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/Mashable?a=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:_cyp7NeR2Rw"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Mashable?i=LWK24TovhQw:zpGSq-fWlcM:_cyp7NeR2Rw" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Mashable/~4/LWK24TovhQw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/08/17/iphone-apps-students/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Little Productivity Tip of a Zen Master</title>
      <description>&lt;h6&gt;Post written by &lt;a href="http://leobabauta.com"&gt;Leo Babauta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h6&gt; &lt;p&gt;A little while back I ran into a friend, Susan O&#8217;Connell (Zen Master and Vice President of the &lt;a href="http://www.sfzc.org/"&gt;San Francisco Zen Center&lt;/a&gt;), and she did something old fashioned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I said we should have tea sometime, she immediately went to her bag and got out her paper calendar, and suggested we make a date right then.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I said, &#8220;No, you&#8217;re busy, we can set a date later.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;She said she tries to only deal with something once.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s an old-fashioned piece of productivity advice, and something that I&#8217;ve done in the past, but it works.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Deal with something once. Do it now. Then it&#8217;s off your mind, and you can fully focus on the next matter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do most of us do this? We might read a bunch of emails, and say, &#8220;I&#8217;ll reply to those later. I&#8217;ll decide later.&#8221; We might see a bill or other piece of mail, and put it aside for later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We put off small decisions and tasks for later, and they pile up, weighing on us at the back of our minds, pulling on us until we collapse under the weight of &#8220;later&#8221;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try dealing with it immediately.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you open an email, make a decision on it immediately. Schedule the appointment in your calendar, reply, do a small task it requires, or if it takes too long, then you can put it on a to-do list &#8212; but avoid this if possible. David Allen suggests a two-minute rule: if the task can be done in less than two minutes, do it now. I suggest five minutes, even up to 10, as that means you have one less thing to worry about.&lt;span id="more-8360"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At any rate, archive the email once you&#8217;ve dealt with it, or delete it. You&#8217;re done with that. Move to the next, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This applies to everything else: mail, paperwork, phone calls, requests from others. Deal with them immediately, or schedule a date to deal with it later if necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When your child asks for attention, give it to her now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When your wife starts talking to you, put away the laptop, iPad or mobile device, and talk to her now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What this means is that you deal with each thing in the moment, and then move to the next. Your mind isn&#8217;t pulled in a million directions at once.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s contrary to advice I&#8217;ve given before, because what it sometimes means is that you are often moving at the whim of other people&#8217;s requests &#8212; what they think is important, not you. And this can be a problem. You don&#8217;t want to just be reactive. I prefer to do what I think is important.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But a balance can be struck. When you deal with email or other types of communication, do it now. When you decide to work on something important, clear everything else, shut down communication, and just focus on that one important task. Don&#8217;t bounce around.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve been doing this, mostly, ever since Susan reminded me of this little productivity trick, and it works beautifully. I&#8217;m not perfect &#8212; there are a couple tasks I&#8217;ve been putting off, mostly because I don&#8217;t have the ability to do them immediately, but for the majority of things I&#8217;ve been pretty good at dealing with things now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try it, and practice throughout your day, and &lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/109926473783208635050/posts/escmN4UnKzn"&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; how it works for you.&lt;br /&gt; &amp;#8212;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share" class="twitter-share-button" data-text="Reading: The Little Productivity Tip of a Zen Master" data-count="vertical" data-via="zen_habits"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/zenhabits?a=PI1fhsaV340:89-oGPDYj3A:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/zenhabits?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/zenhabits?a=PI1fhsaV340:89-oGPDYj3A:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/zenhabits?i=PI1fhsaV340:89-oGPDYj3A:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/zenhabits?a=PI1fhsaV340:89-oGPDYj3A:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/zenhabits?i=PI1fhsaV340:89-oGPDYj3A:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://zenhabits.net/once/</link>
      <guid>http://zenhabits.net/once/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
