<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>TNT Ad Becomes the Second Most-Shared of All Time</title>
      <description>An ad for the launch of the cable channel TNT promoting the &#8220;drama&#8221; of its programming had a pretty dramatic debut. TNT&#8217;s ad has become the second most-shared of all time, according to Unruly, a video research firm. The ad, which was released on April 11, has been shared 3 million times. Only &#8220;The Force,&#8221; the 2011 Super Bowl ad from Volkswagen, has been shared more. David Waterhouse, head of content for Unruly, says the TNT ad &#8212; called &#8220;A Dramatic Surprise on a Quiet Street&#8221; &#8212; may well surpass &#8220;The Force&#8221; soon since one in seven people who saw &#8220;Surprise&#8221; shared it vs. one in 12 for &#8220;The Force.&#8221; The TNT ad, featured above, takes place in a &#8220;little town in Belgium&#8221; in a &#8220;square where nothing really happens.&#8221; TNT&#8217;s ad agency, Duval Guillame Modem, placed a large red button there and invited passers-by to &#8220;Push to Add Drama.&#8221; Doing so led to a flurry of activity including a clumsy EMS unit dropping a man on a stretcher, a bicycle accident, a fistfight and the appearance of a woman on a motorcycle clad in lingerie. The ad, which appeared on YouTube on April 11, is now up to 21.5 million views. More About: Advertising, Marketing, social tv, unruly, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/tnt-ad-second-most-shared/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/tnt-ad-second-most-shared/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive detailed: 5 GB for free, launching next week for Mac, Windows, Android and iOS</title>
      <description>Brad McCarty / The Next Web:Google Drive detailed: 5 GB for free, launching next week for Mac, Windows, Android and iOS &#8212; Sometimes we get lucky, and today is one of those days. I got a draft release from a partner of Google's upcoming Google Drive service and it gives away a wealth of information about how Google plans to take on the incumbent Dropbox.</description>
      <link>http://www.techmeme.com/120416/p39</link>
      <guid>http://www.techmeme.com/120416/p39</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Mistrust: Are Texters Cheaters? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Do mobile phones make you suspicious? Do texters have something to hide? That&#8217;s what a couple of recent studies suggest. College students trust text messages less than phone calls, video chats and face-to-face conversation when communicating with their peers. And it may be a case of guilty consciences &#8212; 35% of teens admit to having used their mobile devices to cheat on a test. Nearly one-fifth say they use their phones to take photos of test questions and send them to others, 20% say they search the Internet via cellphone and 26% say they use their devices to store information. This all comes from Online-Education.net, which pulled together separate studies by the University of British Columbia and Common Sense Media to create the below infographic. Check it out to get the full picture of how mobile devices relate to mistrust. Do you feel like texters have something to hide? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy of Flickr, real.tingley More About: infographics, MobileFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/mobile-texters-cheaters/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/mobile-texters-cheaters/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holographic Tupac Spawns Twitter Parody</title>
      <description>5 Funny Tweets From Tupac's Hologram Click here to view this gallery.The late rapper Tupac Shakur returned to the stage as a hologram Sunday night, leaving Coachella attendees and fans worldwide with mixed reviews. Some were amazed by this tech stunt, while others claimed that it was too creepy. Regardless, the event has been a hot topic on social media Monday morning. Naturally, as the people of the Internet tend to do, someone has already created a parody account on Twitter. Everyone, meet @HologramTupac. Check out some of his early tweets in the gallery above, and let us know your thoughts in the comments below. Is this account on the mark? Image Courtesy of MTV Films More About: Coachella, humor, tupac, Twitter, twitter parodies, viral</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/holographic-tupac-parody/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/holographic-tupac-parody/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a Yacht Philippe Starck&#8217;s &#8216;Revolutionary&#8217; Apple Project? [RUMOR]</title>
      <description>World-famous French designer Philippe Starck told a French radio station on Friday that he&#8217;s working on a &#8220;revolutionary&#8221; secret Apple project that will surface in eight months. The designer said that he couldn&#8217;t reveal more details because of Apple&#8217;s &#8220;religious cult of secrecy.&#8221; Apple flatly denied Starck&#8217;s involvement with any of its upcoming products while rumors about the project flew wild. Some speculated Starck could be involved with an Apple TV, others suggested that he&#8217;s working on a new Parisian Apple Store. The answer, it appears, seems to be out to sea: Jobs commissioned Starck to design a &#8220;sleek and minimalist&#8221; yacht with 40-foot-long glass walls. The pair met in Cupertino, California on a monthly basis to talk about the ship, according to Jobs&#8217; official biography. However, neither Apple nor the alleged maker of the yacht, Netherlands-based Feadship, are commenting on the plans. They do, however, match Jobs&#8217; penchant for simple yet beautiful design and engineering. French newspaper Le Figaro reported that Starck is planning on staying in touch with Jobs&#8217; widow Laurene, possibly to finish work on the ship. However, the designer hasn&#8217;t confirmed that the yacht is the &#8220;revolutionary&#8221; project to which he was referring on the radio broadcast. Do you think the ship is the &#8220;revolutionary&#8221; product, or does Starck have something else up his sleeve? Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Bluberries More About: apple, steve jobs, TechFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/philippe-starck-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/14/philippe-starck-apple/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Earth Helps Reunite Man With His Mother After 25 Years [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Saroo Brierly was separated from his older brother in a train station in India in 1986. For most of his life, he thought he would never see his family again. Twenty-five years later, he has reunited with his mother, thanks to the magic of Google Earth. Brierly was illiterate and didn&#8217;t know the name of the village where he was raised. All he knew was that he rode a train for 14 hours to arrive in Kolkata after losing his brother in the train station near his home, the BBC reports. Brierly knew his home should be roughly 1,200 kilometers from Kolkata, because he remembered the approximate length of the train ride. He drew a circle with its radius around Kolkata on a map and began searching Google Earth. After four years of searching &#8212; while living with his adoptive parents in Tasmania, Australia &#8212; Brierly identified a familiar landscape in Khandwa, Madhya Pradesh. It was a waterfall where he played as a boy. Brierly traveled to India this year and found his mother. BONUS: 28 Google Street View Sightings 1. Birdman We're hoping this was for a kid's birthday party... In fact, this scene and others were staged by Street with a View as a prank on Google.Click here to view this gallery. More About: google earth, mashable video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/google-earth-boy-mother/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/google-earth-boy-mother/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Wanted to Buy Instagram [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Facebook snapped up photo-sharing app Instagram last week for $1 billion, but word on the street is that the social network wasn&#8217;t the only one interested in purchasing the filtered wonder. Twitter &#8220;expressed interest&#8221; in purchasing Instagram just a few months ago, according to the New York Times. Twitter co-founder Jack Dorsey was one of the early backers of Instagram, investing in the service in February 2011. Dorsey was also a part of the beta of Instagram and tweeted pictures using the service before it was available to the public, adding buzz around the app&#8217;s release. While Dorsey has posted quite a few Instagram photos over the past year, his Instagram stream has gone silent since the Facebook acquisition of the service. Facebook&#8217;s purchase of Instagram included not only the app but also the Instagram staff. In the Timeline post announcing the acquisition Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg indicated that the company plans to continue to develop Instagram as an independent service and will continue to support sharing Instagram photos on other social networks &#8212; including Twitter. SEE ALSO: Why Instagram Was Worth $1 Billion To Facebook &#8220;For years, we&#8217;ve focused on building the best experience for sharing photos with your friends and family.&#8221; Zuckerberg said in the announcement. &#8220;Now, we&#8217;ll be able to work even more closely with the Instagram team to also offer the best experiences for sharing beautiful mobile photos with people based on your interests.&#8221; What do you think Facebook has planned for Instagram? Do you think the fate of the photo-sharing service would be better or worse in the hands of Twitter. Let us know your thoughts in the comments. BONUS: 20 Witty Reactions to Facebook&#8217;s Acquisition of Instagram Comparing Instagram to Kodak On April 9, Facebook announced plans to acquire popular photo-sharing app Instagram. Earlier this year, 131-year-old film pioneer Kodak filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Facebook, instagram, jack dorsey, mobile apps, photography, TwitterFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/twitter-buy-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/twitter-buy-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Tech-Forward Concepts Reshaping Our Future</title>
      <description>For the Global Innovation Series, presented by BMW, we&#8217;re focused on one simple question: In what ways is technology drastically changing our lives for the better? In a lot of ways, living in a city is challenging &#8212; urban citizens are constantly thinking about mobility, energy, shelter, safety and efficiency as they go about their daily lives. Many projects and startups in cities all around the globe are developing and implementing new technology to ameliorate these daily problems. If these concepts come to fruition, then the future of cities is looking bright. Whether you&#8217;re thinking easier ways to park your car or ideas for the home of the future, studying how we&#8217;ll live in the next 10, 50 or 100 years can reshape the habits and challenges we have today. Take a look at a roundup of 14 of these revolutionary ideas below. Looking for more? Make sure to follow the series &#8212; each week, you&#8217;ll get a new article on the future of urban life. 1. 4 Innovative Solar Tech Projects From Around the World The sun may be our greatest energy resource, but we still rely on fossil fuels in the United States. According to the Energy Department, solar power accounts for just 1% of America&#8217;s alternative energy production. While the industry isn&#8217;t booming just yet, it is growing quickly and there is promise &#8212; Google invested $280 million in solar energy in June and another $94 million in December, and Warren Buffett recently bought a photovoltaic farm for $2 billion. Read the full story here. 2. How One App Empowers Citizens to Take Control of Urban Noise Pollution We live in a loud world. With cars whizzing past, construction sites pounding away, ambulances roaring around and the dull ache of idle chatter constantly bombarding the sound wall, it&#8217;s easy to get overwhelmed in a noisy environment. And there&#8217;s good reason for that: Although it&#8217;s usually pushed into the background, noise is a form of pollution. Read the full story here. 3. Pedestrian Safety: How Innovative Tech Could Save Your Life When it comes to pedestrian traffic, safety should be the number-one concern, but transportation infrastructure in the United States is built to accommodate cars, not people. This focus is putting lives at risk and the data shows it &#8212; in 2010, pedestrian fatalities rose 4.2%, and pedestrian injuries due to motor vehicle crashes increased by 19% from the previous year, according to data from the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. With 4,280 pedestrians killed and 70,000 injured in 2010 in the U.S. alone, cities are installing technologies that will improve pedestrian safety on busy streets. Read the full story here. 4. How Video Chat Is Creating a Global Classroom Tasked with teaching an elementary school class stories, customs, holidays, foods and popular culture of many different cultures, student-teacher Maggie Holmes hopes to squeeze in some first-hand accounts. She&#8217;s asked teachers of global elementary schools to set up an exchange with her class. Until recently, connecting students with those living elsewhere would have likely been a bigger headache than it was worth. But as more teachers look to the Internet to make such global connections, it&#8217;s become a matter of posting a short blog post in the right place. Read the full story here. 5. The Future of Food: 11 Unique Urban Farming Projects Farming has a lot of romance in it. The idea of tilling the land, growing something from scratch and providing for yourself from the gifts of the land is a primal urge that runs through even the most cynical techie. Well, you don&#8217;t have to give up your iPad to get a piece of the farming pie with the growing interest in &#8220;urban farming,&#8221; which is finding ways to bring the farming lifestyle to cities, high-rises and other urban environments. Read the full story here. 6. 8 Amazing Green Buildings That Break Even on Energy Consumption Worldwide revenues from zero-energy buildings are predicted to increase to just under $1.3 trillion by 2035, according to a recent report published by Pike Research. The report also noted that the market for such buildings, including both commercial and residential real estate, currently sits at $225 million. A zero-energy building is one that produces as much energy as it consumes, making it a net-zero energy property and eliminating energy bills for its owners. Although zero-energy homes and buildings are quite rare today, increasing concerns about energy waste have set the stage for a growing market. Read the full story here. 7. 4 Unique Ways to Generate Renewable Energy Finding sources of renewable energy is a growing challenge for the modern world. As we strive for energy efficiency and sustainable resources, avenues are opening up for different and exciting ways to power our lifestyles. Companies across the globe are harnessing the potential of renewable energies, including solar and geothermal methods. Read the full story here. 8. How Mobile Payments Are Revolutionizing Public Transit If modern technology is a universal language, the world is getting schooled in innovation, especially in the public transportation sector. The global transportation industry has become a proving ground for new payment systems, as cutting-edge technologies have been introduced to taxis, buses and trains worldwide to streamline jaunts around town. From reserving and paying for a cab with an app to purchasing train tickets via an iPod, various countries are experimenting with new ways to reach out to travelers and make payment and transport a whole lot easier. Read the full story here. 9. Reimagining City Life: One Startup&#8217;s Vision of the Future &#8220;A lot of people face pretty profound constraints on mobility, enjoy only limited access to opportunity, and face serious difficulty in getting timely, accurate information about services available to them,&#8221; says Adam Greenfield, founder of Urbanscale. &#8220;As far as we&#8217;re concerned, it&#8217;s both a matter of basic morality and in our own long-term best interest, to ensure that everyone living in a society has open and unfettered access to these things.&#8221; And that&#8217;s exactly what his Manhattan-based company is working toward. Read the full story here. 10. Live Greener: 3 Energy-Saving Technologies for Your Home In a perfect world, with perfect circumstances, who wouldn&#8217;t want a self-sustaining smart home? These days, there are so many goals towards home efficiency and sustainability that many are clamoring to &#8220;green&#8221; their homes as best as possible &#8212; with the ultimate achievement of creating a zero-energy home on the horizon. In the real world, building an energy-friendly home is a lot more difficult than it sounds. While you can make a fairly sustainable home simply by employing sensible green building adjustments to insulation, home materials, lighting and heating, that&#8217;s not all that goes into a truly efficient home. Read the full story here. 11. 7 City Parking Apps to Save You Time, Money and Gas Yellow curb, red curb, white curb, blue curb &#8212; figuring out where to park, especially in a big city, can make you feel like you&#8217;re in a zany Dr. Seuss story. And when you do snag a sweet street spot, it can feel like a mini moment of glory. If you live in a crowded metropolis, then finding a parking spot is a task you&#8217;d like to see simplified. Here are seven helpful parking apps to help you find a safe place to park. Read the full story here. 12. 5 Home Technologies That Will Save You Energy and Money Tech manufacturers are making it easier for eco-conscious consumers to welcome a greener lifestyle. But going green doesn&#8217;t mean sacrificing the allure of cutting-edge technology. From controlling lights at home through a mobile app to investing in smart appliances that cut down on energy use and costs, there are myriad high-tech options on the market that make the home more sustainable. Read the full story here. 13. This Is What Your Future Home Might Look Like The urban environment is daunting. In a bustling community of millions and millions of citizens, the mere constraints of having so many people in one place can force innovation to materialize out of sheer need. Over the years, popular culture has tried to mold and shape the way an urban environment will look an act ten, fifty or even a hundred years from now. Will the cities of the future look like The Jetsons or Blade Runner? Well, if current, feasible development is any indication, the answer is actually neither. Read the full story here. 14. High-Tech Threads: Can Your Clothes Do This? Today&#8217;s clothing isn&#8217;t just about fashion &#8212; it&#8217;s about function. We&#8217;re not talking about Scottevest&#8217;s Inspector Gadget-esque trenchcoat to store your iPhone, iPad, iPod and even a few changes of clothes. Sure, that&#8217;s handy, but the jacket itself isn&#8217;t high-tech (though it is well designed). Mashable has explored ways in which tech companies and fashion brands have come together to create prototypes of new kinds of apparel, and we spoke with independent designers who&#8217;ve conceived mind-blowing gear that essentially transforms your body into a generator. Read the full story here. Looking for more great ideas? Take a look at past roundups here and here. Image courtesy of Flickr, frogman2212 More About: features, Global Innovation Series, mashable, roundupFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/urban-future-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/15/urban-future-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Ad Engagement Down 8% in U.S.</title>
      <description>Engagement with Facebook ads in the U.S. dropped eight percent between the final quarter of 2011 and the first quarter of 2012. Meanwhile, the average cost-per-thousand impressions for Facebook ads has increased by 41% worldwide over the past year. Cost-per-click rates have risen as well, and Facebook has become increasingly competitive with Twitter in directing readers to news sites. This all comes from a first-quarter Facebook analysis by the advertising agency TBG Digital, which works with an extensive roster of high-profile clients including jetBlue, Heineken and Coca-Cola. For the study, Facebook measured 372 billion ad impressions in nearly 200 countries for 235 clients over the past year. While click-through rates of ads served in the U.S. dropped over the past three months, TBG Digital CEO Simon Mansell says that&#8217;s not cause for alarm for the social networking giant. &#8220;They&#8217;ve gone from four to seven ads on a lot of pages, so even though click-through is declining, that&#8217;s okay,&#8221; Mansell told Mashable in an interview. &#8220;If you isolate that and point to to you could say it&#8217;s a negative thing, but I think that&#8217;s a bit of a red herring.&#8221; By hosting more ads, and with increased demand boosting the price of buying ads on the site, Mansell says, Facebook&#8217;s revenue stream is in great shape despite the dip in engagement. SEE ALSO: Facebook Marketers Reveal States Where Users Click on Ads Most [EXCLUSIVE] | Want Half-Off Facebook Ads? Keep Users On-Site Another interesting finding of TBG&#8217;s report is that Facebook has managed to become more competitive with Twitter in driving traffic to news sites. TBG found a whopping 196% increase in click-through rates for news sites, driven in part by the successful Facebook social readers of news organizations such as Yahoo, The Washington Post and The Guardian. &#8220;Clients with social readers have started to get some traction,&#8221; Mansell says. &#8220;Before, only Zynga had really made money by building a business on top of a platform. Now the social readers and Spotify are an indication that Facebook can help more industries by plugging into the social graph.&#8221; Do you think Facebook&#8217;s advertising business will continue to grow, or hit a plateau? Let us know in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/facebook-ad-tbg-digital/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/facebook-ad-tbg-digital/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Authorship (and Google+) Will Change Linkbuilding</title>
      <description>Posted by Tom Anthony Google's relationship with links has changed over the last 15 years - it started out as a love affair but nowadays the Facebook status would probably read: "It's Complicated". I think Google are beginning to suffer from trust issues, brought about by well over a decade of the SEO community manipulating the link graph. In this post I'm going to lay out how I think Authorship, and Google+ are one of the ways that Google are trying to remedy this situation. I'll move on to what that means we should be thinking about doing differently in the future, and am sharing a free link-building tool you can all try out to experiment with these ideas. The tool will allow you to see who is linking to you rather than where is linking to you, and will provide you with social profiles for these authors, as well as details of where else they write. To start I want to quickly look at a brief history of Google's view of links. Are links less important than they were? Back in the early days Google treated all links as being equal. A link in the footer was as good as a link in the main content, a link in bad content was as good as a link in good content, and so on. However, then the new generation of SEOs arrived and started 'optimizing' for links. The black hats created all sorts of problems, but the white hats were also manipulating the link graph. What this meant was now Google had to begin scrutinizing links to decide how trust-worthy they were. Every link would be examined for various accompanying signals, and it would be weighted according to these signals. It was no longer a case of all links being equal. Reciprocal links began to have a diminished effect, links in footers were also not as powerful, and so it went for a variety of other signals. Over the last decade Google have begun using a wide range of new signals for determining the answer to the question they have to answer for every single link: How much do we trust this link? They've also introduced an increasing number of signals for evaluating pages beyond the link based signals that made them. If we look at the ranking factors survey results from SEOmoz for 2011 we see that link based factors make up just over 40% of the algorithm. However, in the 2009 survey they were closed to 55% of the algorithm. So in the last 2 years 15% of the algorithm that was links has been replaced by other signals in relative importance. The results are from a survey, but a survey with people who live and breathe this stuff, and it seems to match up well with what the community as a whole believes, and what we observe with the increasing importance of social signals and the like. This reduction in the relative power of links seems to imply that Google aren't able to trust links as much as they once did. Whilst clear they are still the backbone of the algorithm, it is clear Google has been constantly searching for other factors to offset the 'over-optimization' that links have suffered from. Are social signals the answer? The SEO community has been talking a lot about social signals the last couple of years, and whether they are going to replace links. I'd argue that social signals can tell you a lot about trust, timeliness, perhaps authority and other factors, but that they are quite limited in terms of relevancy. Google still need the links - they aren't going anywhere anytime soon. To visualise this point in a different way, if we look at a toy example of the Web Graph. The nodes represent websites (or webpages) and the connections between them as the links between these websites: And a corresponding toy example of the Social Graph: We can now visualise Social 'Votes' (be they likes/tweets/+1s/pins or shares of some other type) for different websites. We can see that nodes on the Social Graph send their votes to nodes on the Web Graph: The Social Graph is sending signals over to the websites. They are basically saying 'Craig likes this site', or 'Rand shared this page'. In other words, the social votes are signals about web sites/pages and not about the links -- they don't operate on the graph in the same manner as links. Whilst social signals do give Google an absolute wealth of information, they don't directly help improve the situation with links and how some links are more trustworthy than others. Putting the trust back into links So Google have needed to find a way to provide people with the ability to improve the quality of a link, to verify that links are trust-worthy. I believe that verifying the author of a link is a fantastic way to achieve this, and it fits neatly into the model. In June last year Google introduced rel author, the method that allows a web page to announce the author of the page by pointing to a Google+ profile page (which has to link back to the site for 2 way verification). We're seeing the graphs merge into a new Web Graph augmented by author data, where some links are explicitly authored links: With this model it isn't: 'Distilled linked to SEOmoz' but it is 'Tom Anthony linked on Distilled to Rand Fishkin on SEOmoz'. It's the first time there has been a robust mechanism for this. This is incredibly powerful for Google as it allows them to do exactly what I mentioned above - they can now verify the author of a web page. This gives 2 advantages: Knowing this is an authored link, by a human who they have data about, they can place far more trust in a link. Its likely that a link authored manually by a human is of higher quality, and that a human is unlikely to claim responsibility for a link if it is spammy. Furthermore it allows them to change the weighting of links according to the AuthorRank of the author who placed the link. The latter point is very important, it could impact how links can pass link juice. I believe this will shift the link juice model towards: I've shown it here as a simple multiplication (and without all the other factors I imagine go into this), but it highlights the main principle: authors with a higher AuthorRank (as determined by both their social standing and by the links coming into their authored pages, I'd imagine): The base strength of the link still comes from the website, but Rand is a verified author who Google know a lot about and as he a strong online presence, so multiplies the power of links that he authors. I'm a less well-known author, so don't give as much of a boost to my links as Rand would give. However, I still give links a boost over anonymous authors, because Google now trust me a bit more. They know where else I write, that I'm active in the niche, and socially etc. Where to Who So what does all this imply that you do? The obvious things are ensuring that you (and your clients) are using authorship markup, and of course you should try to become trustable in the eyes of Google. However, if you're interested in doing that stuff, you probably were already doing it. The big thing is that we need a shift in our mindset from where we are getting links from to who we are getting links from. We need to still do the traditional stuff, sure, but we need to ask start thinking about &#8216;who&#8217; more and more. Of course, we do that some of the time already. Distilled noticed when Seth Godin linked to our Linkbait Guide. I noticed when Bruce Schneier linked to me recently, but we need to begin doing this all in a scalable fashion. With OpenSiteExplorer, Majestic and many other linkbuilding tools we have a wide array of tools that allow us to look at where we are getting links from in a scalable way. I hope I've managed to convince you that we need to begin to examine this from the perspective that Google increasingly will be. We need tools for looking at who is linking to who. Here's the thing - all the information we need for this is out there. Let me show you Authored links - A data goldmine We'll examine an example post from GIanluca Fiorelli that he posted in December. Gianluca is using Google's authorship markup to highlight he is the author of this post. Lets take a look at what information we can pull out from this markup. The rel author attribute in the HTML source of the page points to his Google+ page, from there we can establish a lot of details about Gianluca: We can from his Google+ profile establish where Gianluca lives, his bio, where he works etc. We can also get an indicator of his social popularity from the number of Circles that he is in, but also by following examining the other social profiles that he might link to (for example following the link to his Twitter profile and seeing how many Twitter followers he has). We've talked a lot in the industry in the last couple of years about identifying influencers in a niche, and about building relationships with people. Yet, there is an absolute abundance of information available about authors of links we or our competitors already have -- why are we not using it!?! All of this data can be crawled and gathered automatically, exactly in the way that Google crawls the authorship markup, which allows us to begin thinking about building the scalable sorts of tools I have mentioned. In the absence of any tools, I went right ahead and built one AuthorCrawler - A tool for mining Author Data for Linkbuilding I first unveiled this tool a couple of weeks ago at LinkLove London, but I'm pleased to release it publicly today. (As an aside, if you like getting exclusive access to cool toys like this then you should check out SearchLove San Fran in June or MozCon in July). AuthorCrawler is a free, open-source tool that pulls the backlinks to a URL, crawls the authorship markup on the page, and gives you a report of who is linking to a URL. It is fully functional, but it is a proof-of-concept tool, and isn't intended to be an extensive or robust solution. However, it does allow us to get started experimenting with this sort of data in a scalable way. When you run the report, you'll get something similar to this example report (or take a look at the interactive version) I ran for SEOmoz.org: It pulls the top 1000 backlinks for the homepage, and then crawled each of them looking for authorship markup, which if found is followed to crawl for the authors data (no. Circles, Twitter followers), and very importantly it also pulls the 'Contributes to' field from Google+ so you can see where else this author writes. It might be that you find people linking to your site that also write elsewhere, on maybe more powerful sites, so these are great people to build a relationship with - they are already aware of you, warm to you (they're already linking) and could provide links from other domains. You can sort the report by the PA/DA of where the link was placed, or by the social follower counts of the authors. You can also click through to the authors Google+ and Twitter profiles to quickly see what they're currently up to. I'm pretty excited by this sort of report and I think it opens up some creative ideas for new approaches to building both links and relationships. However, I still felt we could take this a little bit further. I'm sure many of you will know the link intersect tool, in the labs section of SEOmoz. It allows you to enter your URL, and the URLs of other domains in your niche (most likely your competitors, but not necessarily), and it examines the back links to each of these and reports on domains/pages that are linking to multiple domains in your niche. It also reports whether you currently have a link from that page - so you can quickly identify some possible places to target for links. Its a great tool! So, I took the principle from the link intersect tool and I applied the authorship crawling code to create an Author Intersect tool. It will give you a report that looks like this (you can check the interactive example report also): Now what you have is really cool - you have a list of people who are writing about your niche, who are possibly linking to your competitors, whose social presence you can also see at a glance. These are great people to reach out to build relationships with - they are primed to link to you! The tool is pretty simple to use - if you're unsure there is an instructions page on the site to get you started. Wrap Up We are in the early days of authorship, but I think Google are going to keep on pushing Google+ hard, and I think authorship's importance is just going to increase. Correspondingly - I think tools such as this re going to become an increasing part of an SEOs toolkit in the next 12 months, and I'm excited to see where it goes. I've only just begun to dig into the ways we can use tools like these - so I'd love to hear from others what they get up to with it. So go and download the tool and try it out. Have fun! :) Sign up for The Moz Top 10, a semimonthly mailer updating you on the top ten hottest pieces of SEO news, tips, and rad links uncovered by the Moz team. Think of it as your exclusive digest of stuff you don't have time to hunt down but want to read!</description>
      <link>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/authorship-google-plus-link-building?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/authorship-google-plus-link-building?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sergey Brin: I&#8217;m Worried About the Internet</title>
      <description>Google co-founder Sergey Brin is worried about the future of the internet. There are &#8220;very powerful forces that have lined up against the open internet on all sides and around the world,&#8221; he said in an interview with The Guardian. According to Brin, one of the biggest threats to the openness of the internet is pressure from governments, which are trying to control the information flow on the internet. The overzealous entertainment industry, which is trying to end piracy, is another threat, and walled gardens raised by companies such as Facebook and Apple, which control what software can be released on their platforms, is equally dangerous, claims Brin. &#8220;I am more worried than I have been in the past. It&#8217;s scary,&#8221; he said. Brin specifically targets Facebook for its unwillingness to share its users&#8217; data with others, claiming it would be impossible to create a company like Google if the internet was dominated by Facebook. &#8220;You have to play by their rules, which are really restrictive,&#8221; he said. Brin is directly criticizing Google&#8217;s competitors here, but he&#8217;s in a unique position. On one hand, Google famously pulled out most of its operations in China in the name of free speech in January 2010. Furthemore, Google&#8217;s Android mobile platform is open-source, in contrast of Apple&#8217;s closed and proprietary iOS platform. On the other, Google itself has often been criticized due to privacy concerns, which prompted the company to release a new, unified privacy policy in February 2012. Google owns a lot of private data about its users, and has at times been forced to hand it to the U.S. authorities. &#8220;We do everything possible to protect the data. If we could wave a magic wand and not be subject to US law, that would be great. If we could be in some magical jurisdiction that everyone in the world trusted, that would be great &#8230; We&#8217;re doing it as well as can be done,&#8221; claims Brin. What do you think: Is Google one of those &#8220;powerful forces&#8221; lined up against the open internet, or is it one of the good guys? Or is the truth somewhere in between? Share your opinions in the comments. More About: Google, internet, privacy, Sergey Brin, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/sergey-brin-worried-internet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/16/sergey-brin-worried-internet/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
