<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>CEOs Are Finally Warming Up to Social Media [STUDY]</title>
      <description>CEO&#8217;s are finally embracing social media&#8217;s role in engaging business and customers, according to a recent IBM Global CEO Study. For businesses, social media is currently the least-utilized method for connecting with their audiences. The hierarchy of connecting is as follows: face-to-face interactions, websites, channel partners, call centers, traditional media, advisory groups, and then, finally, social media. However, social media is expected to jump to the number two spot within three to five years &#8212; and traditional media will plummet to the bottom of the list &#8212; according to IBM&#8217;s report of their findings. Out of the 1,709 CEOs interviewed for the study &#8212; hailing from 64 countries and 18 industries &#8212; only 16% currently participate in social media. However, that percentage is expected to grow to 57% within the next five years, according to the IBM analysis. As Mashable previously reported, these numbers coincide with the &#8220;conservative optimism&#8221; regarding social media engagement for businesses. More than half of business owners (64%) believe in social media as a useful tactic for marketing &#8212; they just aren&#8217;t willing to jump into it full-force yet. SEE ALSO: Does Social Media Marketing Really Work [INFOGRAPHIC] Despite that hesitation, more and more CEOs are recognizing the potential for social media to change how their companies and organizations can communicate with the world. &#8220;One of the most compelling findings [of the survey] is how in tune CEOs are about the implications and impact of social media,&#8221; stated Bridget van Kralingen, senior vice president of IBM Global Business Services, in the press release of the study. &#8220;Rather than repeating the familiar lament about de-personalizing human relationships, this view leans heavily in favor of deepening them, and using dynamic social networks to harness collective intelligence to unlock new models of collaboration.&#8221; Personalizing these relationships with customers is the top priority for these CEOs. Nearly three-quarters of those polled (73%) are investing significantly in ways to better gain meaningful insights from their customers. Openness and interaction &#8212; not just advertising &#8212; on social media sites like Facebook and Twitter just might be at the heart of this more individualized interaction. As one CEO interviewee put it, the idea is to use social media as a crowd-sourcing mechanism and means of collaboration: &#8220;We use social media less as a marketing or distribution channel and more as a knowledge platform to obtain information about customers,&#8221; said an insurance CEO from Switzerland. The takeaway? With a stronger presence on social media sites and more personalized interactions with customers on these channels, &#8220;control is shifting from institutions to individuals,&#8221; the report stated. If you&#8217;re a CEO or leader in business, do these findings agree with your experience? How else are you looking to engage with customers? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, courtneyk More About: Business, Marketing, Social MediaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/ibm-ceo-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/ibm-ceo-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obama Takes Twitter Questions</title>
      <description>President Barack Obama is no stranger to Twitter; he held his first Town Hall on the microblogging network, at the White House complete with Master of Ceremonies Jack Dorsey, just under a year ago. Thursday, with his reelection campaign getting into gear, Obama decided to take a few questions on Twitter. The Q&amp;A session just ended, so check out what the President had to say in our Storify: [View the story "Barack Obama Hosts Twitter Chat" on Storify] More About: barack obama, Politics, Storify, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/obama-takes-twitter-questions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/obama-takes-twitter-questions/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Releases Instagram Clone</title>
      <description>Less than two months after announcing its plans to acquire photo app company Instagram for $1 billion, Facebook has released an iOS app that looks and functions almost identically to Instagram&#8217;s. Facebook Camera, which is now available in the App Store for free, sincerely improves upon the photo capabilities offered by Facebook&#8217;s primary app for iPhone and iPod touch devices. Like Instagram, your friends&#8217; latest photos are displayed in a single scrolling feed. You can also now simultaneously upload multiple photos to Facebook; Facebook&#8217;s main app only allows you to upload photos one at a time. And like Instagram, the app allows you to crop, rotate and apply filters to your photos. Interestingly, none of the app&#8217;s 15 filters were developed by the Instagram team, Facebook product manager Dirk Stoop told The New York Times. The app, the Times suggests, has been in development for much longer. The Camera App is the second mobile app dedicated to one of Facebook&#8217;s key features. The first, a dedicated messaging app, was released last April. These apps, we feel, are smart ideas: Facebook simply has too many features and tools to bundle into a single mobile app. It&#8217;s likely more such apps will be released this year. In an address to 200 investors leading up to Facebook&#8217;s IPO earlier this month, CEO Mark Zuckerberg said that mobile is Facebook&#8217;s number-one priority. More About: camera app, Facebook, instagram, iphone app, trendingFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/facebook-camera-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/facebook-camera-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FB Launches Facebook Camera &#8211; An Instagram-Style Photo Filtering, Sharing, Viewing iOS App</title>
      <description>Facebook is dead serious about mobile. Today it begins rolling out Facebook Camera for iOS to English-speaking countries, a standalone photos app where you can shoot, filter, and share single or sets of photos and scroll through a feed of photos uploaded to Facebook by your friends. Developed by Facebook&#8217;s photos team without the help of Instagram because the acquisition deal hasn&#8217;t closed yet, Facebook Camera looks a lot like the app TechCrunch leaked images of a year ago, and is designed for quicker publishing than Facebook&#8217;s multi-featured primary mobile app. Facebook Camera lets you rapidly pick one or more photos, apply filters, tag friends and locations, add a description, and post. While its 14 filters, batch uploads, and streamlined interface are a big step up from Facebook for iOS, the design isn&#8217;t as beautiful as Instagram and neither are the photos you&#8217;ll see in it. When asked if Facebook Camera would become a direct competitor to the photo sharing network it bought last month, a spokesman told me &#8220;As Mark asserted, we&#8217;re committed to building and growing Instagram independently, so I anticipate some healthy competition.&#8221; Though for now Facebook Camera is just for iOS in English-speaking countries, it will roll out internationally over the next few weeks as Facebook gets it translated. As for versions for Android, BlackBerry, and Windows Phone, I&#8217;m told &#8220;While we don&#8217;t comment on future products we are carefuly looking at what might make for agood Facebook photos experience across other platforms.&#8221; How It&#8217;s Better Than Instagram The best feature of Facebook Camera and its one real selling point over Instagram is multi-photo uploads. This helps you tell a story or share the best photos from a day&#8217;s outing in a single post. It&#8217;s great for if you can&#8217;t decide which shot is best and don&#8217;t want to go through the sharing flow over and over. Browsing multi-photo stories is smooth too, as they appear as one story in the feed showing the first photo, but you can swipe side to side to view the rest of the set. Rather than having to wait for a photo to load when you browse by like on Instagram, it appears as a blurry placeholder at first and then sharpens up, which is nice. Facebook Camera&#8217;s 14 filters are also more sensibly named with title that describe how they change photos, such as Cool, Light, and Copper, rather than Instagram&#8217;s less indicative Hudson, Sutro, and Brannan, though Instagram does have 17 filters plus light adjustment and tilt-shift that Facebook&#8217;s new app lack. How It&#8217;s Worse Unfortunately, there&#8217;s several flaws in the current version of Facebook Camera that seem especially glaring compared to Instagram. Like and comment icons and counts are overlaid on the photos, disturbing their appearance. When you click to view existing comments on a photo they take a few seconds to load, which can fool you into thinking they aren&#8217;t there. But the first thing you might notice is the photos are decidedly less beautiful than what you&#8217;ll see on Instagram. Most weren&#8217;t uploaded with Facebook Camera but rather through Facebook&#8217;s web interface or primary app, so they&#8217;re unfiltered, and weren&#8217;t necessarily taken with artistry in mind. While Facebook may be late to the standalone photo app scene, you have to remember that while Instagram has hit 50 million downloads, Facebook has over 500 million mobile users, and somewhere around 220 million on iOS and Android. Facebook Camera may not be perfect, but for those who don&#8217;t want to start a whole new social network for photosharing on Instagram, and want an app that sucks in photos shared by their Facebook friends from anywhere, including Instagram and Path, Facebook Camera could find a spot on the homescreen.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/24/facebook-camera/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/24/facebook-camera/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Siri, Y U No Understand Me? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Siri is a loyal mistress, following you wherever you go &#8212; but is she a good listener? Since the iPhone 4S began coming standard with Siri last October, the voice activated personal assistant has become a cultural phenomenon. Samuel L. Jackson and Zooey Deschanel star in Siri-themed ads for the phone. A creepy iPhone case forces you to interact with Siri. A different project enables Siri to destroy your phone if it&#8217;s lost or stolen, and a viral video shows what happens when Siri goes psycho. But everyone&#8217;s not impressed. In March, a man filed suit against Apple, alleging that Siri &#8220;does not perform as advertised.&#8221; Anecdotally, many others have complained that Siri doesn&#8217;t respond to voice commands and questions as hyped. Given the controversy, Internet education portal OnlineDegrees.com rounded up a number of studies and statistics from sources including The Wall Street Journal, ABC News and others over the past several months to produce the infographic below. Among the findings: 87% of iPhone 4S owners use Siri at least once per month, with just over half describing themselves as &#8220;satisfied&#8221; with her performance. 9% say they&#8217;re not satisfied, while 36% say they&#8217;re somewhere between happy and unhappy. Only two-thirds of users, however, employ Siri for anything beyond searching the web, making a phone call or sending a text. At least 30% of users say they would never use Siri to schedule a metting, play music or even send an email, while just a quarter use Siri to send emails on a daily basis. Check out the infographic below for more on how iPhone owners do &#8212; and don&#8217;t &#8212; use Siri. Then let us know in the comments &#8212; do you think Siri really works? More About: apple, infographics, iphone, siri</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/siri-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/21/siri-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo Axis Shines on iPad, an Afterthought on Desktop [REVIEW]</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s been a while, but Yahoo just made some noise again in the search business. With the release of Axis, a new search app and add-on for both iOS and desktop browsers, Yahoo aims to make browsing the Web a more visual and convenient experience. And it succeeds &#8212; at least on the iPad. This is surprising, since on iOS Axis is essentially running a skin over top of Safari &#8212; similar to what the Atomic browser does. In Yahoo&#8217;s case, though, it&#8217;s a powerful skin, filled with features you won&#8217;t find on Apple&#8217;s browser, such as easy toggling between regular and image searches, and instant syncing of bookmarks and tabs between desktop, iPhone and iPad. At the same time, the app isn&#8217;t cluttered. It&#8217;s nice and minimalist, combining the search and address bar into a single field similar to how Chrome works (seriously, why don&#8217;t all browsers do this?). And your bookmarks conveniently appear in every new tab you open, letting you instantly tap to go somewhere familiar. However, it doesn&#8217;t put your most recent bookmarks first, which is a bit annoying. Searching With Gas One of the major thrusts of Axis is that it makes search more visual. It delivers pretty well on this promise, displaying a strip of site preview thumbnail images whenever you input a search term. This is quite handy even if the sites themselves aren&#8217;t particularly visual. For example, for most subjects, a Wikipedia entry is one of the first to appear. While Wikipedia pages tend to be mostly text, they&#8217;re instantly recognizable, even as a thumbnail. The thumbnails tap out after you swipe through the first 20 or so, though, getting replaced with basic text summaries. The most powerful feature of Axis, though, could be its near-flawless device syncing. Open a page on your iPad, and you can pick up right from there on your iPad or any major desktop browser (via an add-on or extension). All your bookmarks are synced, too &#8212; Yahoo even conveniently names one of your folders &#8220;Read Later.&#8221; SEE ALSO: Google Search Just Got 1,000 Times Smarter As I said, though, it&#8217;s only near-flawless. You can only see the last tab you had open on whatever device you&#8217;re picking up from. It also doesn&#8217;t sync your search history (though it will pass along the last search you performed on the other device). Social networkers will appreciate that Axis integrates Pinterest. Whatever page you&#8217;re on, you can tap a virtual button to instantly switch over to the Pinterest iOS app and pin the page, although you&#8217;ll need to switch back to Axis manually. It&#8217;s a convenient addition that Safari doesn&#8217;t have &#8212; although Axis has no &#8220;Print&#8221; or &#8220;Add to Home Screen&#8221; options. Desktop Blues In all, though, the Axis experience on iOS is compelling, which is in contrast to the underwhelming desktop integration. To be fair, it would be expecting too much of Yahoo &#8212; who doesn&#8217;t make any kind of desktop browser &#8212; to come up with something groundbreaking here, and Axis ends up being not much more than an impressive syncing tool. There seemed to be technical difficulties with the pre-release Chrome extension, and I never got it to work. It did better on Firefox, though, but I was disappointed that I had to wait for pages to finish loading completely before I could use Axis. Regaled to a small search box on the bottom of your browser, Axis is more of an unwanted intruder on the desktop, and its abilities didn&#8217;t provide much in functionality that I couldn&#8217;t get from any of the many add-ons in my browser. It&#8217;s also more limited than the iOS version &#8212; your Axis search history, for example, is nowhere to be found. Axis is a worthy experiment, though, and I hope Yahoo quickly iterates its iOS app. It&#8217;s quite simply one of the best browsers you can get for your iPad, and if it keeps improving and adding new abilities, it could help define how we consume the web on tablets. Just as long as Apple doesn&#8217;t kill it. What do you think of Axis? Check it out for yourself at the Axis site, and let us know in the comments. Yahoo Axis, Splash Screen The screen that greets you when you launch Axis on iPad.Click here to view this gallery. More About: Axis, Browsers, search engine, Yahoo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/yahoo-axis-hands-on/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/yahoo-axis-hands-on/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Million E-Readers Headed to Africa With FC Barcelona&#8217;s Help</title>
      <description>Non-profit Worldreader kicked off a campaign Thursday aiming to put 1 million e-books in the hands of children across the planet, with a little help from players on one of the world&#8217;s most popular sports teams. This may sound like a crazy goal, considering the widespread absence of books from African classrooms, but the organization is aleady well on its way. So far, Worldreader has donated 100,000 books to 1,000 students in Ghana, Kenya and Uganda. The non-profit now wants to expand its reach throughout sub-Saharan Africa and has enlisted some capable help &#8212; the world-renowned players on FC Barcelona (Bar&#231;a). &#8220;We&#8217;re trying to get them to do something radically different,&#8221; David Risher, CEO and co-founder of Worldreader, and a former Microsoft and Amazon executive, told Mashable. &#8220;When a student sees the image of a player he idolizes, it brings a whole new culture and habit, associating reading with a hero. Using these tricks we can get kids to read more, making it more fun and a bigger part of their lives.&#8221; The organization believes the popularity of Bar&#231;a will inspire students to keep reading, when they see personalized messages on their e-readers from some of the team&#8217;s biggest stars, including Lionel Messi, Xavi Hernandez, Eric Abidal and Seydou Keita, encouraging them to &#8220;score big&#8221; and continue their education. The donated e-books include classic literature, local African textbooks and story books, and newspapers from around the world. To help reach this distribution goal, Worldreader is seeking donations of $5, which pay for one e-book. In addition to putting books in the hands of students, Worldreader gives local authors and publishers access to a larger market. E-Readers Impact on Students in the Developing World When Worldreader began delivering books to Ghana in November 2010, the non-profit launched a study, funded by USAID, measuring the first implementation of e-readers into classrooms in under-previledged areas. The study found performance on standardized test scores jumping between 12.9% and 15.7%. While Worldreader&#8217;s mission is to put a library of books in the hands of every kid on the planet, distribution isn&#8217;t the only challenge. Half the effort is getting kids excited about doing something new. &#8220;To classroom teachers, e-readers just feel like having more books &#8212; they&#8217;re not significantly new technology to adopt,&#8221; Risher says. &#8220;I&#8217;ve had young boys come and say to me, &#8216;I&#8217;ve always found books kind of intimidating, but this feels like a gadget because it&#8217;s something I can play with.&#8217;&#8221; Another advantage to e-readers, which can be often overlooked, is that the font sizes easily increase, making a big difference for students without proper eyewear. Worldreader mostly distributes books on Amazon Kindles, because they work well outside of the U.S. and because of Risher&#8217;s history with the company. The organization recently began venturing beyond e-readers and onto feature phones, through an e-book app created by developer biNu. Are e-readers a game-changing technology for students in the developing world? Let us know what impact you think technology could have on the developing world. Interested in technology&#8217;s role in sustainable development? Join Mashable and partners in Brazil for Rio+Social. If you can&#8217;t make it to South America, you can join in the discussions on Facebook and Twitter. Click on the image below to learn more. More About: ebooks, education, ereaders, Social Good, WorldFor more Social Good coverage:Follow Mashable Social Good on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Good channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/e-readers-worldreader-fc-barcelona/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/e-readers-worldreader-fc-barcelona/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The History of Facebook&#8217;s Developer Platform [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>The Facebook Platform&#8217;s stated mission is to &#8220;build the social web.&#8221; With help from social app developers, it certainly met its goal. May 24 marks the fifth anniversary of Facebook Platform. The project first launched at the 2007 f8 conference to 70 app developers, like Washington Post and Digg. Fourteen months later, at f8 2008, more than 30,000 apps existed on Facebook Platform. An extension of Facebook Platform, Facebook introduced Connect at the same 2008 conference. Facebook Connect enabled third-party websites to build social integration into their user experiences. As a result of these developments, Facebook hosted an unparalleled social experience both on its site and off. Companies like Zynga introduced hit games like FarmVille on the platform, and the &#8220;like&#8221; button social plugin launched on external websites. (In the first 24 hours, external site &#8220;like&#8221; buttons received 1 billion impressions.) Not to mention, Facebook Platform opened up the opportunity for additional business transactions &#8212; Disney acquired games company Playdom in 2010, and EA acquired Bejeweled Blitz maker PopCap in 2011. By Sept. 2011, Platform was responsible for creating 182,000 American jobs and a $12.19 billion value to the economy. SEE ALSO: Facebook Tests New Timeline Design [PICS] With the launch of Timeline, Facebook has only expanded the possibilities of app development. And somehow we get the feeling it has only just begun. How have Facbeook&#8217;s social apps on-site and off changed your social experience? Where would Facebook be today, had it not launched Facebook Platform? Here&#8217;s your chance to sound off in the comments below. More About: dev, Facebook, facebook platform, infographics, social apps, Social MediaFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/facebook-developer-platform-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/facebook-developer-platform-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nikola Tesla was the greatest geek who ever lived - The Oatmeal</title>
      <description>An ode to the father of the electric age.View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/tesla</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpaceX Tweets Photos of Historic Flight to International Space Station</title>
      <description>1. Watching the Launch "So, what were the ISS astronauts doing during @SpaceX's historic #Dragon launch this week? The same thing we were!" - @NASAClick here to view this gallery.It&#8217;s been two days since private spaceflight company SpaceX launched its Dragon capsule to dock with the International Space Station, and it&#8217;s already captured and tweeted dramatic pictures of its flight. SpaceX and NASA have tweeted a series of photos taken by the unmanned Dragon, which could become on Friday the first ever privately built spacecraft to dock at the habitable artificial satellite. The mission is part of an effort to test Dragon&#8217;s reliability to transfer supplies to the station. By 2015, SpaceX aims to have a certified commercial spacecraft to send passengers to Earth&#8217;s low orbit. SEE ALSO: 7 Things You Need to Know About SpaceX Launch Over the past few days, the Dragon has successfully completed a series of tests to determine if it&#8217;s ready to berth at the station. As of now, it&#8217;s on track to attach to the facility on Friday morning &#8212; a process that SpaceX says will take &#8220;extreme precision.&#8221; SpaceX tweeted on Thursday that the most difficult part of mission is on the horizon. #Dragon has been performing well, but the most difficult aspects of the mission are still ahead. &#8212; SpaceX (@SpaceX) May 24, 2012 Astronauts already on board the International Space Station will activate the space station&#8217;s robotic arm that will reach out and attach the capsule. The following day, they will open Dragon&#8217;s hatch and unload the supplies that the Dragon is carrying. Image courtesy of SpaceX More About: Dragon, elon musk, space, SpaceX</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/spacex-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/24/spacex-twitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Facebook Wreck Marriages?</title>
      <description>Real-Time Advice: Newlywed CEO Mark Zuckerberg may want to watch his status updates, divorce lawyers say. Facebook often gets blamed for breakups.</description>
      <link>http://blogs.smartmoney.com/advice/2012/05/21/does-facebook-wreck-marriages/?mod=1122</link>
      <guid>http://blogs.smartmoney.com/advice/2012/05/21/does-facebook-wreck-marriages/?mod=1122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coda 2</title>
      <description>Comments</description>
      <link>http://panic.com/coda/</link>
      <guid>http://panic.com/coda/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
