<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bud Light Kicks Off Its NFL Deal With Draft-Related Contest</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article.php?article_id=149693"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anheuser-Busch, which is paying an estimated $50 million a year to make Bud Light the new official beer of the NFL, kicks off its sponsorship today by pledging to spend millions more in a contest linked to this month&amp;#039;s NFL Draft. &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/VLEbuN9fiQaFd2oxREUtrE6Lzxo/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/adage/homepage/~4/AUfM7r9A4c0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://adage.com/login.php</link>
      <guid>https://adage.com/login.php</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Emotional Care for Children after a Disaster http://t.co/tbxjQ3Iu #opsafe #thailand #turkey #japan #DT @operationSAFE</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a3.twimg.com/profile_images/472807580/janet-icon_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/janetlansbury"&gt;janet lansbury&lt;/a&gt;: Tips for Emotional Care for Children after a Disaster &lt;a href="http://t.co/tbxjQ3Iu" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/tbxjQ3Iu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=opsafe" target="_blank"&gt;#opsafe&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=thailand" target="_blank"&gt;#thailand&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=turkey" target="_blank"&gt;#turkey&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=japan" target="_blank"&gt;#japan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=DT" target="_blank"&gt;#DT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/operationSAFE" target="_blank"&gt;@operationSAFE&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/janetlansbury/status/129898650636783616"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://opsafeintl.com/emotional-care-for-children-after-disaster/</link>
      <guid>http://opsafeintl.com/emotional-care-for-children-after-disaster/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Stop-Motion Masterpiece With &#8216;Lego Super Hero Movie Maker&#8217;</title>
      <description>Building block giant Lego has released a new iOS app that allows you to create your own stop-motion videos using your iPhone. Called Lego Super Hero Movie Maker, the app lets you bring your blocks to life through a short video and even add tunes to your creation. Designed to be used with Lego&#8217;s DC Universe Super Heroes blocks, the app lets you plan, create, and shoot the next big summer blockbuster on your smartphone. Creating videos simply entails setting up your smartphone and blocks and snapping a shot. After taking one photo, you then move the blocks ever so slightly and snap another photo, repeating the process until your masterpiece is complete. The interface is exceptionally kid-friendly, but adults are also likely to have a good time with the app making their own Lego adventures. While you don&#8217;t technically have to own a tripod to use the app, you&#8217;ll find that having one &#8211;or at least a stationary surface &#8212; will come in handy for creating consistent shots. To help with the storytelling process Lego has included 11 title cards in the mix with images from Batman, Superman, Wonder Woman and more. The app also has five different soundtracks you can add to enhance your crime-fighting tale, and offers the option to add a colored filter to your shot to give a scene a particular look or mood. Finished flicks can be saved to the camera roll on your phone and then shared with friends or uploaded to YouTube. Lego Super Hero Movie Maker is compatible with iPhone 3GS, iPhone 4, iPhone 4S, iPad, and 3rd and 4th generation iPod touch. The free app is available now from the Apple App Store. More About: iOS, iphone, Lego, stop motion, Super Hero</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/lego-super-hero-movie-maker/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/lego-super-hero-movie-maker/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Picnik: 7 Free Alternatives for Quick Photo Edits</title>
      <description>1. PicMonkey This site was created by two former Picnik engineers, Justin Huff and Brian Terry, so you can imagine some similarities.Click here to view this gallery.The day has finally come: April 19 is your last chance to use online photo editor Picnik. In January, Google announced that it would be shuttering its popular web property. While we mourn Picnik&#8217;s demise, we found seven other online photo editors to help you with quick crops, saturations and touch-ups. Some offer easy-to-use basics, while others echo the more advanced edit options of Photoshop. Either way, one of these is bound to replace the Picnik-sized hole in your heart. SEE ALSO: New Site Challenges Instagram Users to Take Their Best Shot Let us know which is your favorite in the comments below. More About: design, features, Google, photo editing, photography, picnik</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/picnik-alternatives/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/picnik-alternatives/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Hot Media Trends You Need to Know</title>
      <description>The Modern Media Agency Series is presented by IDG. CDW added humor to its video marketing campaign and it led to one million video views. In an interview last month, Neal Campbell, CDW&#8217;s Chief Marketing Officer, explained the program and how it led to the Charles Barkley integrated marketing campaign. When a week&#8217;s vacation can leave us behind on social media trends, early adoption becomes more about pattern recognition than bandwagon jumping. Mediaphiles dismissed Foursquare as a toy, until it suddenly owned the geo layer. Internet junkies took afternoon naps and missed Pinterest&#8217;s leap to #3 in social networking. Mom couldn&#8217;t log into Hotmail; now she owns Farmville. All of these trends were forecast well before their big breaks, largely due to the astute eyes of early adopters who are ready to add new and fresh tools to their media-consuming arsenal. Here are eight media trends we&#8217;re tracking right now. Some are right on the cusp of becoming mainstream and others still have a bit to cook before breaking the surface. What patterns are you observing in the media world and what do you think will be the next big thing? Let us know in the comments below. 1. Targeted, Geo-Mobile Coupons When Foursquare started garnering press coverage in 2009, co-founder Dennis Crowley confessed his dream was to one day know users well enough to target smart coupons on the fly. He wanted to send push notifications that essentially said, &#8220;We know you like pizza, and it&#8217;s dinner time right now. Pizza Place X, two blocks away, has a special.&#8221; That day has finally come. With 1.5 billion check-ins, 750 thousand merchants, 20 million users and millions of geo-tagged tips, Foursquare now has the ability to deliver hyper-relevant coupons to its users. I just started getting them and they&#8217;ve been surprisingly accurate. LevelUp and other mobile services are digifying the in-person coupon space as well. We expect this field to mature rapidly now that geodata infrastructure is in place and half of all U.S. mobile phones are smartphones. 2. Audio Watermarking Technology for embedding subliminal signals in audio &#8212; digital sound waves humans cannot consciously detect &#8212; is being used to track data and connect digital devices in increasingly clever ways. New York-based startup Sonic Notify, for example, built technology that allows television shows such as Bravo&#8217;s Top Chef to invisibly activate a viewer&#8217;s smartphone or tablet with related content while watching. As audio watermarking becomes more mainstream (and consumers acclimate to the idea), opportunities for mobile content integration at events and retail stores will arise faster than you can play a Beatles record backwards. 3. Passive Location-Based Networking According to social media data collected by Tracx, the top 3 buzziest startups at SXSW 2012 were all in-person networking apps: Highlight, Glancee, and Sonar. Highlight was the most popular by far, gaining 300% more buzz than any of its peers. Its hook is that it&#8217;s completely passive: Users allow the app to track their locations throughout the day, then when other Highlight users (friends, potential connections) are nearby, it shows both parties the nearby user&#8217;s info. Though buzz was high, the big question around this trend is whether the utility of such apps will outweigh the privacy concerns (and battery drain). There&#8217;s certainly competition in the space, so we&#8217;re likely to see a lot of movement around this concept this year. 4. Motion Tracking and Facial Recognition for Intention Data CBS&#8216;s hit series Person of Interest called this one last September. As facial recognition and motion tracking tech becomes more accurate and less expensive, the ability to digitally divine real-world intent is coming into our grasp. Interpublic Group, for example, has a laboratory in Manhattan where Xbox Kinects, flatscreens and fake grocery aisles come together for some serious spying. When you pick up a box of Pop Tarts, the motion sensors track your face to see if you&#8217;re smiling or frowning about what you see. Screens then output data on how long you&#8217;ve lingered in front of a particular product, and ads trigger based on your gender (which cameras infer) and what objects you&#8217;re touching. All this will help product marketers deliver better experiences. Once we get past the &#8220;creep-out phase,&#8221; consumers will likely start expecting &#8212; and appreciating &#8212; such personalization in their everyday shopping ventures. 5. Automatic Social Media-Activated Discounts Handing a coupon to the waiter after a meal can be embarrassing for customers and time-consuming for employees. American Express has figured out how to bypass both challenges using social media. The credit card company recently launched Twitter and Foursquare integrations that allow cardholders to sync their plastic with a social account, then take advantage of in-store coupons with no more effort than a tweet or check-in. For example, many Foursquare locations have &#8220;$5 Off&#8221; AmEx specials. If a user checks into a location with the special and uses an AmEx card, the store&#8217;s credit card machine pings AmEx, which verifies check-in with Foursquare and then credits $5 to the user&#8217;s card. 6. Brands Building Publications and Entertainment Channels &#8220;We&#8217;re all publishers&#8221; is a trite phrase by now, but big brands are starting to take the mantra seriously. With budgets behind them and no advertising to worry about, companies are building media properties meant to compete with TV stations and magazines. Red Bull&#8217;s homepage, for example, looks like an action-sports news site. The company pumps out professional-grade news articles, feature stories and videos each day, pushing them to social marketing channels such as Facebook and Twitter. This fuels the company&#8217;s social media accounts with content and points followers back to Red Bull&#8217;s site, rather than elsewhere on the Internet. Fashion companies are especially keen on building publications to compete with traditional media. Several have even reported that building entire publications is no more expensive than advertising. A look at the sites of Tory Burch and Kate Spade show where these brands are investing their efforts. 7. TV on the Internet The Thursday Night TV lineup&#8217;s days are numbered. Barry Diller, the media mogul who greenlit The Simpsons while running Fox in the &#8217;80s, thinks broadcast television is the next big disruption in media. As we&#8217;ve seen with music, Internet users want to consume individual pieces of content &#8212; tracks, not albums; episodes, not box sets. They want to pick and choose, and they want their content online, not attached to a cable TV plan. Diller&#8217;s latest project, Aereo, puts live broadcast TV on the Internet. It&#8217;s the next step to cutting the coaxial cable entirely. 8. Mobile, Immersive Reality Digital technology allows us to be in one place while experiencing another. Skype and FaceTime connect people across the world, in person. The next evolution of this is immersive video and augmented reality. Google is developing augmented reality glasses, which would enable wearers to view data layered over real life. A startup called Condition One makes iPad video apps that let the tablet holder move around a faraway scene, like a battlefield. There&#8217;s even R&amp;D happening to create video-enabled contact lenses. Tron, The Terminator and The Matrix, here we come. Series presented by IDG The Modern Media Agency Series is presented by IDG. Humor resulted in CDW&#8217;s video marketing campaign going viral and reaching one million video views! The campaign earned runner-up recognition in BtoB&#8217;s 2012 Social Media Marketing awards. IDG Strategic Marketing Services Director Howard Sholkin interviewed CDW Chief Marketing Officer Neal Campbell last month at the awards ceremony. In an interview last month, Neal Campbell, CDW&#8217;s Chief Marketing Officer, explained the program and how it led to the Charles Barkley integrated marketing campaign. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, scanrail More About: american express, features, Highlight, mashable, Media, Modern Media Agency Series</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/hot-media-trends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/hot-media-trends/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Hopes to Go Public on May 17 [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Facebook is looking at the May 17 date for its initial public offering, TechCrunch reports citing several source familiar with the matter. These sources also claim that Facebook will be valued at around $100 billion or $40 a share &#8211; close to the current valuation of the company based on secondary market trading. The date, however, is not set in stone. Federal regulators might want more time to look at paperwork from Facebook&#8217;s $1 billion acquisition of Instagram, which could push the IPO date back. A change of climate in the market &#8212; perhaps due to mounting problems in the Euro-zone &#8212; could also be a factor. In the meantime, check out everything we know about the Facebook IPO so far in this handy guide. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo, ipoFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/facebook-ipo-may-17/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/facebook-ipo-may-17/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive Interface Leaked in Employee Presentation [EXCLUSIVE]</title>
      <description>Tuesday we heard rumors that Google will soon be launching Google Drive &#8212; its own cloud service &#8212; and now we have an exclusive screen shot of the Google Drive interface that seems to confirm that rumor. A Google employee giving a presentation at a university in Brazil Tuesday appears to have accessed that presentation via Google Drive. Pedro Henrique Moschetta was at the keynote, and sent Mashable a shot of what may be Google&#8217;s cloud service in action. &#8220;Some friends and I were watching a seminar with a Google employee called Jo&#227;o Itaqui (Google Enterprise director in Brazil) here at Universidade Feevale (Feevale University) in Novo Hamburgo, RS &#8212; Brazil when we noticed he had an option called &#8220;Drive&#8221; in his Google toolbar.&#8221; says Moschetta. &#8220;I think he, as a senior employee, has early access to Google Drive before public announcement or release.&#8221; Itaqui was presenting a keynote using Google Docs. The Drive option appeared on the screen on the toolbar between the Calender and Sites options in the same way it did in earlier supposed leaked screenshots of the service. Documents is now absent from the toolbar, seeming to indicate that Google Docs will reside in or be replaced by Google Drive. The URL for Itaqui&#8217;s presentation, however, is still a Google Docs address. A report Tuesday suggested that Google Drive will launch next week. We showed Google the photos from the event, and a Google spokesperson responded by simply saying &#8220;We don&#8217;t comment on rumor or speculation.&#8221; A Google Drive OS X app has already made its way into the Mac App Store, and a leak of a supposed draft release by one of Google&#8217;s launch partners suggests the service will be free to use and offer each user 5GB of storage. Do you think Google Drive will soon debut? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of Ricardo Marzotto More About: Google, Google Drive, Top StoriesFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/google-drive-leaked/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/google-drive-leaked/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn&#8217;s Biggest Competitor Is a Facebook App That Just Hit 25 Million Users</title>
      <description>Two years and 25 million registered users after launching its professional network for Facebook, BranchOut is LinkedIn&#8217;s biggest competitor. &#8220;At this point, it&#8217;s Coke and Pepsi,&#8221; BranchOut CEO Rick Marini says of the company&#8217;s relationship with LinkedIn. BranchOut allows users to see which of their Facebook friends (or friends of friends) work at specific companies. Unlike LinkedIn, it doesn&#8217;t require users to build a professional network one person at a time. Rather, they simply connect to their pre-existing Facebook graphs. The interface works a lot like LinkedIn from there: users can fill in their work histories, send messages to their connections, collect endorsements and request introductions to friends of friends. The 45-employee startup&#8217;s business model also looks similar to that of its giant &#8212; and recently public &#8212; competitor. BranchOut hosts about 3 million job listings and has a product for recruiters called RecruiterConnect that works like LinkedIn Recruiter. The development of this latter product, which helps employers source talent, is what LinkedIn cited as a violation of its terms of service when it blocked BranchOut from accessing its API in July. BranchOut has 13 million monthly unique visitors, which according to AppData.com makes it the 31st most popular app on Facebook &#8212; ahead of Instagram, Skype, Twitter and Pinterest. Marini says much of the growth can be attributed to international adoption and new mobile users. About half of new members are from outside of the U.S., due partly to integrations with European career sites StepStone and totaljobs.com. These partnerships, along with a similar relationship with CareerBuilder in the U.S., allow job searchers to see connections who may help them get a particular job from within that job&#8217;s listing. SEE ALSO: Glassdoor Can Mine Your Facebook Friends to Help You Land a Job [VIDEO] BranchOut launched its first mobile app in November. By January, mobile accounted for 25% of the service&#8217;s traffic. Today, it accounts for 45% of all visits. Although reaching 25 million registered users looks less impressive when compared to LinkedIn&#8217;s 150 million, there are 850 million Facebook users for whom joining BranchOut is just a matter of accepting the app&#8217;s permissions. On Thursday, BranchOut announced a $25 million round of funding, bringing its total venture capital backing to $49 million. While building on Facebook is BranchOut&#8217;s greatest differentiator, it also makes the startup vulnerable to its host&#8217;s whims. When Facebook changes its features, the team of 45 needs to change BranchOut just as quickly. And if Facebook decides to launch a career feature, BranchOut will likely be toast. Marini doesn&#8217;t think that&#8217;s likely, though. &#8220;Facebook is a platform company,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Facebook wants to see companies disrupt multi-billion-dollar markets &#8212; like BranchOut disrupting LinkedIn in the professional networking space. They want to see that happen on their network.&#8221; Image courtesy of iStockphoto, narvikk More About: branchout, Facebook, jobs, linkedin</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/branchout-25-million/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/branchout-25-million/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default Email Signature for New Samsung Phone</title>
      <description>This is a joke, right? Right? &#9733;</description>
      <link>https://twitter.com/thinkofthought/status/192967196413149185/photo/1</link>
      <guid>https://twitter.com/thinkofthought/status/192967196413149185/photo/1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Tony Hawk Always Tweets for Himself [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Tony Hawk is one of the most recognized pro athletes in the world, with a successful video game franchise, premium Youtube channel, apparel line, charitable foundation and more. But it took a lot for him to grow his business to where it is now. Hawk started skating professionally when he was 14, and he started making a business of it right when he got out of high school. He talked to Behind the Brand host Bryan Elliott about getting trapped in a contract to use his likeness and name in the late &#8217;80s that he didn&#8217;t really understand at the time. Hawk said it taught him to guard his assets in later business deals. &#8220;When taking these endorsement deals, I always made sure I had final approval over the way they used my image. But I was also using those dollars to bring attention to skating in general,&#8221; he said. Hawk attributes his success and career longevity on always innovating in business and his skating, a strategy all startups and businesses can learn from. &#8220;The key to success in our sport is &#8216;It doesn&#8217;t matter if you&#8217;re number one. You&#8217;ve got to innovate and try something new or people are going to forget about you,&#8217;&#8221; he said. Part of that success in the past was doing things like creating a successful video game franchise. Now it includes embracing social media, an arena Hawk excels in. &#8220;Social media has given me the best unfiltered feedback of people who are interested in what I&#8217;m doing. It&#8217;s me on Twitter, I want this to be my voice, and I want people to know they are connecting with me.&#8221; Hawk also said he didn&#8217;t want someone running his account, as many other celebrities have opted, saying, &#8220;you just know you are getting the sanitized version of who they are.&#8221; Watch the full Behind the Brand interview above, and tweet your questions to @BryanElliott, or leave them in our comments section below. More Recent Episodes of Behind the Brand: Question: Why Is Rainn Wilson so Awesome at Social Media? [VIDEO] How One Company Helps Sales Teams Leverage Their Social Influence [VIDEO] How to Enchant Your Audience Using Social Media [VIDEO] More About: behind the brand, Business, Social Media, tony hawkFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/tony-hawk-behind-the-brand/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/tony-hawk-behind-the-brand/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Ways to Offer Better Customer Service on Facebook</title>
      <description>The Customer Experience Series is presented by Webtrends, helping brands acquire, engage, nurture and optimize Facebook fans. Get the Social Media Marketing Playbook, a guide for maximizing returns. Download now. Customers know that the squeaky wheel gets the grease, and web-savvy customers know that Facebook is the ultimate squeak amplifier. According to Forrester Research, 27% of U.S. online consumers sought customer service support on the web in 2011, and currently three out of four expect a reply to a negative comment posted on Facebook. Unfortunately, many brands still don&#8217;t incorporate customer service into their social strategy, despite the fact that Facebook is one of the best venues in which to turn your customers&#8217; negative comments into brand opportunities. Here are eight tips to help you improve your Facebook customer support initiative and, in turn, raise your brand&#8217;s reputation, decrease your inbound service requests, acquire new customers and turn infrequent customers into brand loyalists. What are your tips? Let us know in the comments below. 1. Outsource &#8220;Your Facebook wall is not an adequate customer service platform because it is not searchable, and it puts a negative twist on your main page,&#8221; says Jeff Nolan, VP of product at Get Satisfaction. Nolan suggests that brands build an online customer service channel and then funnel the data into their current CRM system. Companies such as Get Satisfaction, Lithium, Moxie Software and Parature enable brands to offer customers a way to connect in multiple online locations, including Facebook. With these products, companies can streamline their customer service processes and track important customer data, no matter where the customer decides to engage. As these features become more commonplace, customers will begin to instinctively seek them out when they visit a brand&#8217;s page, so be prepared. 2. Crowdsource &#8220;Identify and develop relationships with influencers who are knowledgeable about your products,&#8221; recommends Erin Korogodsky, social strategist at Lithium. &#8220;Those superfans are likely to lend a hand when a customer stops by with a question.&#8221; Products like Lithium&#8217;s LevelUp social suite allow for the peer-to-peer customer support Korogodsky suggests. Cultivation, encouragement and rewards for &#8220;superfans&#8221; who engage such solutions provide customer service request deflection, which Korogodsky says is one of the best ways you can save money for your business. 3. Who&#8217;s the Boss? When it comes to social support, it is not always clear who&#8217;s in charge. Your customer service reps are not Facebook experts and vice-versa &#8212; that is why the two groups must team up to provide online customers with the best support experience. Have your social media team field Facebook comments and escalate issues to the appropriate customer service representative. Many social media marketing platforms, such as Buddy Media, Context Optional and Wildfire offer moderation features that allow for customer service reps to be pinged and prompted to respond upon assignment. 4. Transparent Humans Users have faith in the transparency of social media and look to it as a place where they can directly contact their favorite companies &#8212; and be heard. Create a brand voice that is human and approachable. Do not delete posts, but instead take the opportunity to solve your customers&#8217; issues or complaints on your public page. Each problem is most likely a problem for another customer and if the answer is easy to find, customers will be able to answer their own inquiries. At the very least, page visitors and friends of the disgruntled customer will see your brand as attentive and solution-oriented. 5. This is Your Time Elisabeth Diana of Facebook&#8217; communications team suggests brands take advantage of two new Timeline features: messages and pinned posts. First, users can now directly connect with a brand through brand page messages. This feature can serve as a free online customer service support system for your brand until your volume becomes unmanageable. Customers can also exchange private information with your brand, such as phone numbers and email addresses, which may help you solve their problem faster. The downside is that there will be no audience to watch you turn a negative situation into a positive one. Remember however, that this is an optional feature and can be turned off (which many large brands already have done). In addition, &#8220;Pinned&#8221; posts allow brands to highlight certain hot topics by pinning them to the top of the wall. Diana uses TurboTax as an example of a brand that really takes advantage of this feature. As Tax Day approaches every year, TurboTax receives an influx of the same questions. So instead of posting the same answer multiple times, the company can now pin reply posts to the top of the wall, thus reducing the number of incoming inquiries. 6. Know Your Issues As your brand continues to offer effective customer service on Facebook, you will see that the volume of requests will only increase. Take this opportunity to log some of your previously solved issues in order to be more efficient and consistent with future replies (without sounding automated, of course). You may also want to take these most common questions, requests and issues and build a FAQ Facebook tab. Again, if your customers are able to find answers easily, your workload will be lessened, as will negative sentiment on your wall. 7. Set Up Alerts If you have very active Facebook fans and are able to use a social media marketing platform, it&#8217;s important to set up alerts for certain keywords to help filter out high priority initiatives. Single out certain terms such as &#8220;question,&#8221; &#8220;customer service&#8221; or &#8220;frustrated,&#8221; and you will receive notifications when related comments are posted. If you are a toy company currently experiencing an issue with a particular toy, set an alert for the product name. Whether the comments are positive or negative, you will be kept in the loop. 8. Accept Compliments Graciously Your mother always taught you to say &#8220;thank you&#8221; &#8212; your brand should do the same. Don&#8217;t just respond to negative comments, reply to positive ones, too &#8212; you can encourage positivity with politeness and grace. Fans love to know that their favorite brands hear and appreciate their praise, and they will often come back to leave positive comments in the future. These positive comments help shift the overall sentiment of your wall, improve brand reputation and increase Facebook virality &#8230; so remember to say &#8220;thank you.&#8221; Conclusion These are eight tips to get started on your social support effort, but know that this is an intense endeavor that will need constant attention. Ty McMahan, director of communications for customer service rating website STELLAService, says it best: &#8220;We wouldn&#8217;t say that customer service on Facebook is easy. Still, there&#8217;s a fantastic opportunity for a brand to wow customers by being on the cutting edge.&#8221; Series presented by Webtrends The Customer Experience Series is presented by Webtrends. With 850 million fans, Facebook is a marketer&#8217;s dream. Yet many brands are not seeing expected results. With the right tools and a four-step plan, Facebook campaigns can be measured, tested, targeted and optimized with remarkable results. Webtrends shows you how in this step-by-step guide. Get the Social Media Marketing Playbook Now. More About: Customer Experience Series, customer service, Facebook, Facebook brand pages, features, mashable</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/facebook-customer-service-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/facebook-customer-service-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
