<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Poker: One Year After the Biggest Bust in Gaming History</title>
      <description>On the anniversary of the biggest shakeup in the online gaming world, poker in the digital age is a far cry from what it was just one year ago. But according to industry experts, poker may be back online in the next few years. This Sunday, April 15 &#8212; called the &#8220;Black Friday&#8221; of the online gaming industry &#8212; marks the one-year anniversary of the biggest scandal of the poker world. On this day in 2011, three of the largest gaming sites were shut down by the Department of Justice. Popular poker sites such as Full Tilt Poker, PokerStars and Absolute Poker were charged with illegal online gambling, as well as money laundering and bank fraud. &#8220;Right now, if you want to play poker online for money, you can&#8217;t,&#8221; Douglas Tirola, writer and director of the documentary All In &#8211; The Poker Movie, told Mashable. &#8220;There was a community of thousands of people that made a daily living playing poker. After the industry was wiped out, those players had to find new jobs or many moved to other countries, such as Canada, the Caribbean or parts of Europe, where online poker is still booming.&#8221; All In &#8211; The Poker Movie is in theaters now, and will be available for download via iTunes starting April 24, 2012. The film follows the worldwide poker boom that started in the underground clubs of New York City and went on to be played beyond homes and casinos worldwide, thanks to the growing online gaming world. All In features actor Matt Damon, who starred in the 1998 poker film Rounders, which introduced the allure of poker to mainstream audiences. It also featured professional and hall of fame poker players, and discussed the growth and fate of online poker in the U.S. After online poker player Chris Moneymaker qualified on the Internet to play in the 2003 World Series of Poker and later won, more flocked to the sites to try their hands in online poker. Online poker revenues grew from $82.7 million in 2001 to $2.4 billion in 2005. SEE ALSO: How the DOJ Forced an Online Poker Savant Into Fantasy Sports However, after the crackdown on April 15, 2011, players who had money in accounts in sites such as Full Tilt Poker were never reimbursed. (PokerStars reimbursed all of its players.) In addition to losing their money, they had nowhere to play. Long before the crackdown, politicians who wanted to make gambling illegal targeted the game. In 2006 President George W. Bush signed into law The Unlawful Internet Gambling Enforcement Act (UIGEA), which threatened to put an end to the online poker world. But it wasn&#8217;t until 2011 that the Department of Justice stepped in and overtook the sites. PokerStars still has a statement up on its homepage from the government about the matter: &#8220;On 15 April 2011, PokerStars ceased providing real-money poker to residents of the United States and related territories. Real money play and deposits by US residents are strictly prohibited.&#8221; The news hit the poker industry hard, as many weren&#8217;t expecting a complete shutdown, especially under President Obama&#8217;s leadership. During his state senator days, Obama was known to play poker with his buddies, so when his administration shut down the online sites, it left many people perplexed and disappointed. It also affected a lot of people surrounding the poker industry, not just the players themselves. For now, poker players are getting their fill by visiting casinos when they can. &#8220;There are people more going to casinos because they have no other place to play,&#8221; says Tirola. &#8220;But there is a misnomer that casinos didn&#8217;t like the rise of online poker because it took people away from their properties, and that&#8217;s not true. It just provided people another way to get good at poker.&#8221; However, many people in the industry hope and believe that online poker will return in the future. &#8220;The general belief is that poker will come back online in the next few years, and that it will be regulated and taxed,&#8221; says Tirola. &#8220;People used to go to certain sites because professional players would be affiliated with those brands, but we&#8217;re expecting online card rooms to now be run by reputable casinos such as Caesars, Wynn or Mohegan Sun.&#8221; Not only does the industry think poker will come back online; many believe it could be even bigger than the first boom. &#8220;A lot of people stayed out of that space because they thought they were doing something illegal,&#8221; adds Tirola. &#8220;The next wave could attract more people than ever. You will also have bigger choices for online consumers from different casinos. It may not be as romantic and sexy as the first poker boom, but it has the potential to be even bigger.&#8221; Online card rooms run by casinos would make the experience more about the casino itself than the professional card players behind it. For example, it would be like going to see the Yankees play because you support the Yankees &#8212; not necessarily because you love Derek Jeter. &#8220;Before, everyone went to certain poker sites just for the poker stars that played on them,&#8221; says Tirola. &#8220;If and when poker comes back online, it will be a lot different.&#8221; Image courtesy of iStockphoto, nicolas_ More About: Entertainment, games, online gambling, online gaming, pokerFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/online-poker-black-friday/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/online-poker-black-friday/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Great Uses For Google+&#8217;s New White Space [PICS]</title>
      <description>Betty #WhiteSpace Posted by E! Entertainment NewsClick here to view this gallery. The Internet quickly seized on a perceived design flaw in the Google+ redesign Wednesday suggested several uses for the site&#8217;s new field of white space. Ideas ranged from portraits of Barry White to a slab of bacon hurled at the computer monitor screen. Though Google Social Head Vic Gundotra said &#8220;We have plans for the column,&#8221; on the new G+, at the moment, it appears to be a fairly liberal amount of pointless white space. Many users appeared thrill to point out Google&#8217;s apparent faux pas. A few hours after the new look took hold #whitespace was trending on Google+ and many users had come up with suggestions on how to fill the void. Above are a few creative suggestions. With additional reporting by Stephanie Haberman More About: Google, whitespace</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/google-plus-white-space/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/google-plus-white-space/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funding Frenzy! Another $1 Million for iPhone-Friendly Watch on Kickstarter</title>
      <description>Remember when the Pebble, the watch that talks to your iPhone or Android device via an array of open-source apps, was asking for a mere $100,000 on crowdfunding site Kickstarter? Well, actually, the Pebble is officially still only asking for $100,000 on Kickstarter. But the Internet has responded with a loud chorus of &#8220;shut up and take my money!&#8221; The Pebble&#8217;s funding hit $500,000 Wednesday evening. It reached $1 million in investment, just 28 hours after the Kickstarter launched. By midnight Friday ET, the hot little e-paper wristwatch had blasted past the $1.5 million mark. There are 35 days remaining in the Kickstarter. Not bad for a device nobody has actually tested in the wild yet. (Though some own its predecessor, the Android-only InPulse watch.) SEE ALSO: iPhone-Friendly Watch Gets $500,000 Kickstarter Funding in a Day Each early investor gets a Pebble at a slight discount ($115 versus $150). But what the funding frenzy really suggests is a burning need that has so far not been met &#8212; to extend the capability of your smartphone, especially your iPhone, to other wearable devices. But only in a way that makes sense. Part of the Pebble&#8217;s appeal is this: it&#8217;s a relatively simple, dumb device that lets the phone do the heavy lifting. It communicates with your apps, rather than trying to replicate them. Perhaps most importantly, the information is displayed using a technology &#8212; Kindle-like e-paper &#8212; that isn&#8217;t likely to drain the watch&#8217;s battery. (What the constant Bluetooth communication does to it remains to be seen.) Meanwhile, the celebration is only beginning at Pebble Technology in Palo Alto. &#8220;We popped a bottle of champagne at $200k, because we missed the $100k milestone,&#8221; founder Eric Migicovsky told Mashable. At this rate, he&#8217;ll be on caviar and oysters by day 35. How much funding will the Pebble get? Place your bets in the comments. More About: android, inPulse, iphone, kickstarter, pebble</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/pebble-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/pebble-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Angelina and Brad&#8217;s Engagement: The Toast of Twitter</title>
      <description>News of Angelina Jolie and Brad Pitt&#8217;s engagement rocked the interwebs Friday &#8212; and briefly nabbed the top trending spot on Twitter. The fact that &#8220;Brangelina&#8221; are finally making it official was confirmed by Pitt&#8217;s manager Cynthia Pett-Dante. She told the Associated Press: &#8220;Yes, it&#8217;s confirmed. It is a promise for the future and their kids are very happy.&#8221; No date has been set for the nuptials at this time. Photos of Jolie rocking a big diamond ring on her wedding finger fueled the public&#8217;s curiosity about the jet-setting superstars&#8217; engagement. Pitt&#8217;s manager also confirmed that Brad designed Angie&#8217;s ring. SEE ALSO: Angelina Jolie Hilariously Legbombs the Internet &#8220;Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie&#8221; was the top trending topic in the Twitterverse, but eventually fell below &#8220;Beliebers Are Beautiful.&#8221; The most common responses to the news on Twitter: users who thought the couple was married already. We grabbed some of the tweets that captured the moment the news was released. Take a look at the gallery below and tell us which one is your favorite. Twitter Responds To Angelina and Brad's Engagement Us Weekly was the first to tweet about the engagement news. Click here to view this gallery. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, EdStock&#8236; More About: Angelina Jolie, Brad Pitt, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/angelina-brads-engagement-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/angelina-brads-engagement-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix&#8217;s Unlimited Employee Vacation Policy: Why It Works</title>
      <description>Netflix employees have one less things to keep track of: the amount of vacation days they take. Co-founder Reed Hastings recently told Bloomberg Businessweek that Netflix has an unlimited vacation policy. In an effort to separate itself from bureaucratic corporations, Netflix, with its 900 employees, abandoned the typical vacation allotment to opt for a sky&#8217;s-the-limit plan. Keeping vacation unlimited, said Hastings, requires mature, responsible employees who care about high-quality work. Netflix has a &#8220;freedom and responsibility culture,&#8221; Hastings told the publication in an article entitled, &#8220;How To Set Your Employees Free.&#8221; Hastings said Netflix gauges success by focusing on what employees get done, not on how many days they worked. The CEO does make sure to be a good role model and takes vacations, where he can do some creative thinking. Hasting explained how the idea evolved: &#8220;My first company, Pure Software, was exciting and innovative in the first few years and bureaucratic and painful in the last few before it got acquired. The problem was we tried to systemize everything and set up perfect procedures. We thought that was a good thing, but it killed freedom and responsibility. After the company was acquired, I reflected on what went wrong.&#8221; The pressure to hang onto one&#8217;s job in a bad economy, and smaller staffs at some organizations, have caused many workers to push themselves to burnout mode. Now, it seems, there may be a growing focus on employees regaining a work-life balance. SEE ALSO: Sheryl Sandberg Leaves Work at 5:30 Every Day &#8212; And You Should Too Netflix isn&#8217;t the only company that has jumped on the all-you-want vacation bandwagon. IBM has a famously flexible time-off policy &#8212; letting employees leave early and take a day off on short notice, just so long as they have a handle on their workloads. Numerous startups and innovative companies working in the tech space are beginning to see the benefits of ditching vacation limits and promoting personal responsibility. What do you think about unlimited vacation policies? Does your employer offer a flexible or unlimited vacation policy? Tell us in the comments. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, Crisma&#8236; More About: IBM, netflix, reed hastings, trending, vacationFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/netflix-unlimited-vacation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/netflix-unlimited-vacation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DRAMATIC SURPRISE ON A QUIET SQUARE</title>
      <description>(18 votes - 1 comment - 127 views)YT: "To launch the high quality TV channel TNT in Belgium we placed a big red push button on an average Flemish square of an average Flemish town. A sign with the text "Push to add drama" invited people to use the button. And then we waited"</description>
      <link>http://music.videosift.com/video/So-they-installed-a-Push-to-add-drama-button-in-Belgium</link>
      <guid>http://music.videosift.com/video/So-they-installed-a-Push-to-add-drama-button-in-Belgium</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why CEOs Should Allow Facebook in the Workplace [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Many CEOs forbid use of social media at work, but recent research shows that web surfing leads to increased productivity. This Keas infographic explores the benefits of social media in the workplace, showing that social connections make people happier and a brief recess involving Internet-browsing increases productivity. An Academy of Management experiment gave three groups of people &#8212; a control group bundling sticks, a group taking an Internet-free break and a group browsing the Internet for 10 minutes &#8212; the simple task of highlighting as many letter A&#8217;s as they could among 2,000 words of text. The three groups then had their mental exhaustion measured. Those browsing the Internet were 16% more productive than the Internet-free break group and 39% more productive than the control group. SEE ALSO: 37 Productivity Tips for Working From Anywhere The study concludes that taking a break, particularly one spent browsing the Internet, should be encouraged by employers hoping to increase productivity. Do you use Facebook at work? Does it negatively or positively affect your concentration? Sound off in the comments. More About: Facebook, workplaceFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/facebook-workplace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/11/facebook-workplace/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life on Mars? NASA Wants Your Help Finding It</title>
      <description>Right now, the Curiosity Rover is sailing through space en route to the Red Planet. The one-ton, car-sized beast should hopefully land intact on the surface of Mars in early August, and we can&#8217;t wait to see what it finds. Neither can NASA. But after the robot rover has combed, poked at and rolled over the rocky surface: what then? What&#8217;s the next step in finding life on Mars, and putting human life on the Martian surface in the next few decades &#8212; especially given the space agency&#8217;s unfortunate budget constraints? Well, NASA announced its plans to draw up a Red Planet road map Friday &#8212; and you&#8217;re invited to contribute. &#8220;Receiving input from our community is vital to energize the planning process,&#8221; Doug McCuistion, director of the Mars Exploration Program at NASA Headquarters, told reporters on a conference call. &#8220;We&#8217;ll integrate inputs to ensure the next steps for the Mars Exploration Program will support science, as well as longer-term human exploration and technology goals.&#8221; As McCuistion spoke, five-time astronaut and NASA associate administrator John Grunsfeld tweeted this: Have a good idea about Mars exploration?we&#8217;d like to hear about it: lpi.usra.edu/meetings/marsc&#8230; &#8212; John Grunsfeld (@SciAstro) April 13, 2012 The input process isn&#8217;t yet as public-friendly as it could be. That link takes you to the homepage of the &#8220;Concepts and Approaches for Mars Exploration&#8221; conference, to take place at the Lunar and Planetary Institute in Houston in July. You can sign up to attend and to submit a paper. But McCuistion promises there will be more web tools for public input, and that the conference will be broadcast live online. The resulting Martian road map will be released in August &#8212; around the same time Curiosity lands. Grunsfeld and the rest of the NASA team seem to be taking a lemons-to-lemonade approach to the Obama administration&#8217;s budget cuts. &#8220;We&#8217;re forced into different strategies,&#8221; he said, &#8220;but that can help you find different solutions.&#8221; In any case, finding some kind of life on Mars may boost NASA&#8217;s bottom line. &#8220;Based on observations in the last six months, it&#8217;s reasonable to think there may be life on Mars today,&#8221; Grunsfeld added. SEE ALSO: Elon Musk: Why I&#8217;m a Space Junkie [VIDEO] &#8220;If there&#8217;s life already there, we have to understand the effect on humans. It&#8217;s not just the question of are we alone, it&#8217;s a question of safety &#8230; we want to enable a path to putting more life on Mars, ie. us.&#8221; How do you think we should approach the Red Planet? Tell us &#8212; and NASA &#8212; in the comments. More About: Curiosity, Mars, NASA</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/nasa-mars-mission/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/nasa-mars-mission/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retro Digital Cinema Camera Is a Hit on Kickstarter [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Meet the Digital Bolex D16, a small hand-held video camera inspired by the cinema-quality Bolex cameras popular in the 1960s and &#8217;70s. The Digital Bolex mimics 16mm film, which essentially provides independent filmmakers an affordable alternative to shoot high-quality, raw images that aren&#8217;t compressed. The project has raised more than $262,000 on Kickstarter.com. The first 100 backers will receive the Bolex D16 for $2,500 &#8212; a $800 discount, says inventors Elle Schneider and Joe Rubinstein. The Kickstarter fund will help the creators develop the cutting-edge camera technology further. &#8220;Think of the difference between a blocky, low-res JPEG image you find online, and a smooth high-res photographic print in a gallery,&#8221; Rubinstein said on the Kickstarter page. &#8220;That&#8217;s the difference between compressed, normal video footage and raw. It&#8217;s a big difference.&#8221; The Digital Bolex D16 prototype shoots completely in raw format files. The filmmaker can then adjust color balance, contrast, white balance and more without diminishing the quality of images. The camera has a side crank that is easily programmable to control frame rates or other camera functions. The D16 offers high-quality resolution (comparable to the HD-quality of the new iPad). Its creators claim the D16 is the first truly cinema camera featuring RAW, uncompressed video recordings. The camera stores data on dual CF cards. &#8220;There is no camera on the market that offers affordable RAW quality to consumers and independent filmmakers,&#8221; Rubinstein said. Would you back or purchase a Digital Bolex D16? Tell us in the comments. Image courtesy of Kickstarter, Joe Rubinstein More About: camera, kickstarter, Raw, VideoFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/digital-bolex/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/digital-bolex/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google&#8217;s Amazing Growth, By The Numbers [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Google may not be the new kid on the block anymore, but it&#8217;s still growing like one. As this infographic from Statista shows, the company continues its upward trajectory, at least if you go by revenues, stock price, net income and market share. As of the first-quarter of 2012, Google seems set to once again have its biggest year ever. Though Google+ has dropped some impressive stats lately, the company has a track record of social media failures and a federal antitrust probe could also derail Google&#8217;s growth. But as a snapshot of this moment in time, Google appears to be at the height of its powers. Do you think Google can keep the momentum going? Let us know in the comments. For the full-size version of this infographic, click here More About: Google, SearchFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/googles-growth-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/googles-growth-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get more likes on Facebook</title>
      <description>More tanks. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
