<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Band to Take Requests via Text During Upcoming Concert</title>
      <description>Music acts nationwide are getting more creative with technology during live performances when they roll into town for concerts. Case in point: Rock jam band Umphrey&#8217;s Mcgee, which is gearing up for a digitally interactive concert event next week that allows audience members to engage with the band in real time via text messages. Fans will be able to directly text the band song requests during the show, as well as answer questions posed by the group and even recommend when it&#8217;s time to switch up the instruments. Called the UMBowl &#8212; &#8220;UM&#8221; for the band names&#8217; initials &#8212; it&#8217;s modeled off of the Super Bowl with the inclusion of four quarters. But each quarter has its own interactive theme. Held in the band&#8217;s hometown of Chicago, the third-annual event will take place on Friday, April 27 at the Park West concert venue. &#8220;We wanted to create an event that is collaborative, interactive and unlike any other concert people have been to before,&#8221; Umphrey&#8217;s McGee keyboardist Joel Cummins told Mashable. &#8220;People are always using their phones, so we wanted to include that as a part of the concert experience to facilitate voting for songs and interaction while we are playing.&#8221; A screen on stage will display texts from fans, so Umphrey&#8217;s McGee can reference them to the audience or adjust the set list accordingly. The first quarter is dubbed the &#8220;All Request Quarter,&#8221; where fans choose the set list and dictate instrument switches and solos. The band will also ask questions and fans can text in their responses. The second quarter is devoted to different themes, scenes and concepts that fans can request through texts. Quarter number three &#8212; which comes after a brief intermission &#8212; is the &#8220;Choose Your Own Adventure&#8221; round, where the band will poll fans on what they should do next and the final act is dedicated to improvisational songs that can be swayed by text requests, such as &#8220;let&#8217;s hear more drums.&#8221; There is a 15 to 20 minute intermission between each quarter. The band prides itself as staying tech-savvy on and off the stage. &#8220;We are also very active on social media sites, especially Twitter,&#8221; Cummins said. &#8220;About 20 years ago, musicians were up on a pedestal and in a fortress somewhere else, but now artists can interact with fans on a personal level anytime, anywhere. We love that. Technology can help create a more intimate experience and also make for more dedicated fans.&#8221; Umphrey&#8217;s McGee also hopes to stream its live shows online in the future. &#8220;You are only reaching a small portion of the population when doing a concert,&#8221; Cummins said. &#8220;When a concert is online and you&#8217;re going into people&#8217;s homes, you increase your audience tenfold.&#8221; Although Umphrey&#8217;s McGee has been touring to promote their latest album &#8220;Death By Stereo&#8221; &#8212; and will be also appear at upcoming festivals including Bonnaroo in Tennessee and the Catalpa Music Festival in New York City alongside Black Keys and Snoop Dogg &#8212; the band will be holding a five-day summer music camp in the Catskill Mountains to instruct and jam with 150 fans. Do you think more artists should incorporate technology into live performances? Is this the future of seeing your favorite band in concert? Let us know in the comments. More About: Entertainment, Music, smartphones, Social MediaFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/umphreys-mcgee-umbowl/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/umphreys-mcgee-umbowl/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Charles Darwin Created Foursquare, It Might Look Like This</title>
      <description>The World at Work is powered by GE. This new series highlights the people, projects and startups that are driving innovation and making the world a better place. Name: Project Noah Big Idea: Project Noah harnesses the power of mobile to let users contribute to real scientific data and research. Why It&#8217;s Working: Project Noah calls itself a &#8220;butterfly net for the 21st century,&#8221; giving members of the connected generation a way to reconnect with nature on the platform their most comfortable &#8212; their smartphones. Its catalog of nature images aims to one day capture every living species on the planet. Nature Deficit Disorder, the idea that children&#8217;s behavioral patterns are changing because they are spending less time outside, was introduced in Richard Louv&#8217;s 2005 book Last Child in the Woods. In short, screens replace the wonders of the natural world that used to provide children with hours of entertainment, leaving kids to wither indoors. The team at Project Noah (short for &#8220;Networked Organisms and Habitats&#8221;) thinks that spending time exploring nature and time attached to screens don&#8217;t need to be mutually exclusive. The startup hopes to mobilize a new generation of nature lovers with a modern digital experience. &#8220;Project Noah is what would have happened if Charles Darwin had created Foursquare,&#8221; co-founder Yasser Ansari tells Mashable. &#8220;Anyone can be a citizen scientist and participate in real world scientific inquiry. We&#8217;re measuring the pulse of mother nature.&#8221; Project Noah primarily comes to life as a mobile app, available for iOS and Android. The app is a tool for anyone &#8212; from an amateur nature lover to a professional scientist &#8212; to document the wildlife and plants around them. You can take photos, called &#8220;Spottings,&#8221; add observations and tag your location. If you don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;ve found, you can ask the Project Noah community for help identifying what you&#8217;ve Spotted. Project Noah contains a map of all Spottings made, so you can explore what other people have seen in your area &#8212; or across the globe. The database hosts about 200,000 Spottings and almost half a million photos, shot in 215 countries and all seven continents. The Android and iOS apps together have been downloaded about 250,000 times. Within the app, you can create and accept missions, such as photographing different varieties of orchids or &#8220;animal architecture,&#8221; like beehives or beaver dams. Similar to badges found within other social check-in apps, you can earn &#8220;Patches&#8221; for completing different tasks. Project Noah recently launched a digital classroom for teachers, including special missions for the school environment. One middle school biology teacher is using the tool to challenge his students to document every living organism on their campus. For students or other users who are not smartphone owners, you can access the tool via a web browser. Some noteworthy discoveries have already been made through Project Noah, such as the first known photograph of the Impatiens plant, spotted by Dipanshu Mitra, in Sikkim, India. The flower had previously only been captured through illustrations. As the startup, which has seed funding from National Geographic, continues to gain traction, Ansari sees potential to print books of Spottings and Missions, create a presence in biology classes across the world and build the largest known database of nature observations. &#8220;Tech has leveled the playing field, but we need to go beyond inspiring people. We need to give you tools,&#8221; Ansari says. &#8220;Parents say, &#8221;I forgot how much I loved this,&#8217; and kids say, &#8216;I didn&#8217;t even know this existed.&#8217;&#8221; Series presented by GE The World at Work is powered by GE. GE Works focuses on the people who make the things that move, power, build and help to cure the world. Image via Project Noah user Gerardo Aizpuru More About: apps, features, mashable, Mobile, nature, World at Work</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/project-noah/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/project-noah/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Nokia Ad Has 41 MegaPixels of PureView Awesomeness</title>
      <description>Remember that monster 41-megapixel camera on Nokia 808, revealed at this year&#8217;s Mobile World Congress in Barcelona? Well, Nokia now shot a video ad entirely with that camera, and &#8212; needless to say &#8212; it looks really good. The video highlights some of the phone&#8217;s capabilities &#8211; besides taking really good photos and HD video, it enables you to easily share them with another Nokia device or via social networks such as Twitter. Perhaps the most interesting feature of the camera is its pixel-perfect zooming capability. You can take photos up to three times as close, as well as shoot Full HD video clips at 30 fps and 4x zoom with no loss of detail, Nokia says. Of course, the phone itself is a Symbian device, which will pause many wanna-be buyers, but Nokia said the camera technology will be carried over to other products, so one can always hope the next-gen Lumia will have a 41-megapixel camera as well as Apollo. Check out the video below and tell us what you think in the comments. More About: 41-megapixel camera, Nokia, PureViewFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/nokias-ad-41-megapixel-cam/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/nokias-ad-41-megapixel-cam/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Media Will Change the Olympics [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>This year&#8217;s Olympics are being branded by organizers as the world&#8217;s &#8220;first social Games,&#8221; and it&#8217;s not hard to see why. Social media has narrowed the divide between athlete and fan over the past few years, with new and unexpected connections happening every day. That&#8217;s why the International Olympic Committee (IOC) launched an online hub this week. Sixteen years after the Olympics first launched a dedicated website, the portal will offer a directory of verified accounts, gamification rewards for active fans and exclusive content. It may not seem like a huge step for the organization, but consider these stats. When the last Summer Olympics began in 2008, Facebook was a relative baby, at just 100 million users. When the 2012 Games kick off in London this summer, Mark Zuckerberg&#8217;s empire will boast more than 845 million members. Likewise, Twitter had 6 million users in 2008; today the network is more than 20 times larger, at 140 million users. Of course, it&#8217;s not all positive news &#8212; the Olympic organization has also seen branding-related troubles that have been denounced by some observers. Still, that controversy will only increase the level of social media chatter around the games. Check out this IOC-produced infographic illustrates how social media has contributed to the changes in the Summer Olympics experience for fans and athletes. Check it out to see how coverage has evolved since the first modern Games in 1896, and find out the most popular athletes on Facebook and Twitter. What role will social media play in your Olympics experience this summer? Let us know in the comments. More About: Facebook, olympics, sports, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/social-media-olympics-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/social-media-olympics-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Food Brands Building Social Buzz on a Budget</title>
      <description>Bob Marshall is a social media strategist for SociaLogic Marketing. SociaLogic provides social media strategy, community management, and content development for clients in the food, CPG, and automotive categories. Follow him @Bob_SociaLogic. By now, most brands are rightly viewing social media as an integral piece of their overall marketing strategy. However, many still hold the incorrect notion that injecting more money into social media is the only way to build and nurture an online fan base. In reality, there are several standout social media marketing tactics that can mobilize an enthusiastic audience while remaining cost effective, and the food industry has consistently been a leader worth emulating in this department. SEE ALSO: 8 Best Practices for Food Brands on Pinterest The most successful brands are discovering three inherent truths about social media marketing. First, food brand marketers know that in order for a fan base to talk, it needs something to talk about. Second, they understand the need for conversations to go beyond company products and services. They get that without appealing to consumers&#8217; broader interests, a brand&#8217;s social media presence tends to intrude, rather than engage. Third, they know they don&#8217;t need millions of dollars to succeed online. Here are five food brands that prove a company can build social media buzz without draining the marketing budget. 1. Chobani Chobani Greek Yogurt is an innovator among health food brands. While many competitors in the industry were utilizing social media to blather about the benefits of their products, Chobani employed a different strategy, tapping into the lifestyle of its consumer base and joining conversations that were already happening on social media. Knowing their target&#8217;s social media habits led to insight on what interests the target and elicits engagement. These insights led Chobani to provide specific content to its consumers, which included recipes, snack ideas, and tips on staying fit. Chobani also wasn&#8217;t afraid to follow consumers to niche social platforms, being the first yogurt brand to join the young, predominantly female target on Pinterest, as well as the photo-sharing phenomenon, Instagram. This move established Chobani as a thought leader on these networks, staking claim before competing brands with bigger budgets followed. On places like Facebook, Chobani openly aligned itself with other, non-competing brands that were popular with its target demographic. Take a look at Chobani&#8217;s likes, and you&#8217;ll find companies like NPR, SELF Magazine, and Oreo. Lessons: Look to your target consumers&#8217; social media conversations to lead strategy and know that letting consumers take the reigns on content development is a cost-effective way to keep them engaged. 2. Whole Foods Whole Foods shines when it comes to giving users something to talk about. It does so by not talking down to consumers, realizing that many of the grocery store chain&#8217;s shoppers are already quite knowledgeable about the wide array of products the company offers. Instead of focusing on a product&#8217;s features and benefits, Whole Foods shares content that encourages consumers to talk about what they can accomplish with a product. For example, instead of using Twitter to mention a type of wine&#8217;s characteristics, Whole Foods designates a separate wine-focused Twitter account to suggest what dishes the wine would be best paired with. This strategy addresses and responds to consumers as peers, connecting with them on an emotional level while offering value-added advice. Whole Foods also willingly decentralizes its social media presence, encouraging individual stores around the world to begin Twitter and Facebook accounts to let customers know about promotions happening at the local level. Lessons: Respect your consumers&#8217; intelligence and conversations over social media, and when appropriate, take an extra step with your content development to offer tips and advice where appropriate. This will help your brand get more bang for its buck with community management. Also, if your brand has multiple locations, creating individual social media accounts is a cheap way to speak more directly to consumers. 3. Chipotle Chipotle employs a highly responsive social media strategy by using multiple community managers. Although they attribute all Tweets and Facebook posts to a specific community manager, they have managed to maintain a consistent, helpful, and jocular voice. This strategy is a great way to establish a brand as customer-service oriented. It&#8217;s also a great way to emphasize the individual personalities of its employees. In addition, it can be a thrill for consumers to be directly mentioned over social media by a brand with 80,000-plus followers on Twitter and 1.7 million Facebook likes. This responsive social media strategy has helped Chipotle to forge genuine relationships with consumers online, turning casual social media fans into brand evangelists. This has helped Chipotle harness social media&#8217;s power as an effective channel for digital word-of-mouth marketing. Lessons: Consumers appreciate the opportunity to connect with the community managers behind a brand, and adding attribution to posts and responses is an easy and free way to foster these connections. Don&#8217;t be afraid to engage with consumers directly. As you get to know them, you&#8217;ll find consumers will want others to get to know you, spreading your brand messaging and, in a sense, doing your work for you. 4. Kraft Macaroni &amp; Cheese Last year, Kraft Macaroni &amp; Cheese made headlines for hiring Ted &#8220;Golden Voice&#8221; Williams as the product&#8217;s new TV spokesperson. A social media celebrity, Williams rode a wave of fame when a YouTube video exhibiting the then homeless man&#8217;s incredible pipes went viral. By hiring Williams over a more costly Hollywood celebrity, Kraft tied itself to someone with existing social media equity, and then used the online buzz around Williams to support the brand&#8217;s traditional marketing. Kraft Macaroni &amp; Cheese continued to use Williams in their digital marketing efforts, employing his talents in the brand&#8217;s &#8220;Golden Voice of Love&#8221; Twitter and YouTube campaign this past Valentine&#8217;s Day. Kraft Macaroni &amp; Cheese also used social media to support its TV advertising in another way, taking Twitter users&#8217; tweets about the product and turning them into ads. Using this user-generated content, Kraft produced three 30-second TV ads, one of which ran during the prime-time broadcast of Conan on TBS. In doing so, Kraft used social media content to generate traditional media content, using consumers&#8217; ideas to direct the brand&#8217;s own. The television spot may have not been free, but the tweet that influenced it was. Lessons: You don&#8217;t need a big budget to hire someone with existing social media clout. Aligning your brand with a person or thing that has already built social media equity can be an effective tactic for boosting your marketing on social and traditional media. Social media conversations and user-generated content also can be utilized as a content farm for developing marketing concepts that connect with consumers who are already talking about your brand. And, no, you don&#8217;t need the kind of cash a prime-time TV media buy requires to do so. 5. Domino&#8217;s Like Kraft Macaroni &amp; Cheese, Domino&#8217;s Pizza used user-generated content to make a big statement. As part of its &#8220;Our Pizza Sucks&#8221; campaign, the company looked to social media to listen to the advice, ideas, and even complaints of customers unhappy with the company&#8217;s products. Social media guided Domino&#8217;s marketing tactics, culminating in the company&#8217;s pizza tracker, which allowed customers to review their ordering experience. In doing so, the company created its own social media channel, which continues to guide its marketing efforts and solidify its dedication to customer service. Though not directly affiliated with Domino&#8217;s corporate marketing efforts, a former Chicago delivery driver, and now marketing manager of six franchises in the city, has been innovating local stores&#8217; social media tactics. In 2009, Ramon De Leon responded to a customer complaint by recording a YouTube video of himself apologizing. The video now has more than one million views. By going the extra mile to converse with customers on social media, De Leon is a great example of one person making a big impact.Those who have seen him talk social media strategy at speaking engagements throughout the country agree. Lessons: Providing a platform that welcomes and asks for consumer response is an easy way to get consumers talking about your brand. Also, as Ramon De Leon proves, you don&#8217;t need a company-wide policy to motivate employees to take the initiative when it comes to using social media for customer service. Embrace your employees&#8217; ideas, and don&#8217;t hesitate to follow their lead if they find success marketing your brand over social channels. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, nicolebranan More About: brands, contributor, features, Food, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/food-brands-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/20/food-brands-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Stop-Motion Masterpiece With &#8216;Lego Super Hero Movie Maker&#8217;</title>
      <description>Building block giant Lego has released a new iOS app that allows you to create your own stop-motion videos using your iPhone. Called Lego Super Hero Movie Maker, the app lets you bring your blocks to life through a short video and even add tunes to your creation. Designed to be used with Lego&#8217;s DC Universe Super Heroes blocks, the app lets you plan, create, and shoot the next big summer blockbuster on your smartphone. Creating videos simply entails setting up your smartphone and blocks and snapping a shot. After taking one photo, you then move the blocks ever so slightly and snap another photo, repeating the process until your masterpiece is complete. The interface is exceptionally kid-friendly, but adults are also likely to have a good time with the app making their own Lego adventures. While you don&#8217;t technically have to own a tripod to use the app, you&#8217;ll find that having one &#8211;or at least a stationary surface &#8212; will come in handy for creating consistent shots. To help with the storytelling process Lego has included 11 title cards in the mix with images from Batman, Superman, Wonder Woman and more. The app also has five different soundtracks you can add to enhance your crime-fighting tale, and offers the option to add a colored filter to your shot to give a scene a particular look or mood. Finished flicks can be saved to the camera roll on your phone and then shared with friends or uploaded to YouTube. Lego Super Hero Movie Maker is compatible with iPhone 3GS, iPhone 4, iPhone 4S, iPad, and 3rd and 4th generation iPod touch. The free app is available now from the Apple App Store. More About: iOS, iphone, Lego, stop motion, Super Hero</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/lego-super-hero-movie-maker/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/lego-super-hero-movie-maker/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive Interface Leaked in Employee Presentation [EXCLUSIVE]</title>
      <description>Tuesday we heard rumors that Google will soon be launching Google Drive &#8212; its own cloud service &#8212; and now we have an exclusive screen shot of the Google Drive interface that seems to confirm that rumor. A Google employee giving a presentation at a university in Brazil Tuesday appears to have accessed that presentation via Google Drive. Pedro Henrique Moschetta was at the keynote, and sent Mashable a shot of what may be Google&#8217;s cloud service in action. &#8220;Some friends and I were watching a seminar with a Google employee called Jo&#227;o Itaqui (Google Enterprise director in Brazil) here at Universidade Feevale (Feevale University) in Novo Hamburgo, RS &#8212; Brazil when we noticed he had an option called &#8220;Drive&#8221; in his Google toolbar.&#8221; says Moschetta. &#8220;I think he, as a senior employee, has early access to Google Drive before public announcement or release.&#8221; Itaqui was presenting a keynote using Google Docs. The Drive option appeared on the screen on the toolbar between the Calender and Sites options in the same way it did in earlier supposed leaked screenshots of the service. Documents is now absent from the toolbar, seeming to indicate that Google Docs will reside in or be replaced by Google Drive. The URL for Itaqui&#8217;s presentation, however, is still a Google Docs address. A report Tuesday suggested that Google Drive will launch next week. We showed Google the photos from the event, and a Google spokesperson responded by simply saying &#8220;We don&#8217;t comment on rumor or speculation.&#8221; A Google Drive OS X app has already made its way into the Mac App Store, and a leak of a supposed draft release by one of Google&#8217;s launch partners suggests the service will be free to use and offer each user 5GB of storage. Do you think Google Drive will soon debut? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of Ricardo Marzotto More About: Google, Google Drive, Top StoriesFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/google-drive-leaked/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/google-drive-leaked/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 3.3.2 (and WordPress 3.4 Beta 3)</title>
      <description>WordPress 3.3.2 is available now and is a security update for all previous versions. Three external libraries included in WordPress received security updates: Plupload (version 1.5.4), which WordPress uses for uploading media. SWFUpload, which WordPress previously used for uploading media, and may still be in use by plugins. SWFObject, which WordPress previously used to embed Flash content, and may still be in use by plugins and themes. Thanks to Neal Poole and Nathan Partlan for responsibly disclosing the bugs in Plupload and SWFUpload, and Szymon Gruszecki for a separate bug in SWFUpload. WordPress 3.3.2 also addresses: Limited privilege escalation where a site administrator could deactivate network-wide plugins when running a WordPress network under particular circumstances, disclosed by Jon Cave of our WordPress core security team, and Adam Backstrom. Cross-site scripting vulnerability when making URLs clickable, by Jon Cave. Cross-site scripting vulnerabilities in redirects after posting comments in older browsers, and when filtering URLs. Thanks to Mauro Gentile for responsibly disclosing these issues to the security team. These issues were fixed by the WordPress core security team. Five other bugs were also fixed in version 3.3.2. Consult the change log for more details. Download WordPress 3.3.2 or update now from the Dashboard &#8594; Updates menu in your site&#8217;s admin area. WordPress 3.4 Beta 3 also available Our development of WordPress 3.4 development continues. Today we are proud to release Beta 3 for testing. Nearly 90 changes have been made since Beta 2, released 9 days ago. (We are aiming for a beta every week.) This is still beta software, so we don&#8217;t recommend that you use it on production sites. But if you&#8217;re a plugin developer, a theme developer, or a site administrator, you should be running this on your test environments and reporting any bugs you find. (See the known issues here.) If you&#8217;re a WordPress user who wants to open your presents early, take advantage of WordPress&#8217;s famous 5-minute install and spin up a secondary test site. Let us know what you think! Version 3.4 Beta 3 includes all of the fixes included in version 3.3.2. Download WordPress 3.4 Beta 3 or use the WordPress Beta Tester plugin.</description>
      <link>http://wordpress.org/news/2012/04/wordpress-3-3-2/</link>
      <guid>http://wordpress.org/news/2012/04/wordpress-3-3-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Surprising Facts About Mobile Shoppers</title>
      <description>Jinal Shah is a digital strategist at JWT in New York. Before joining JWT, Jinal worked at Advanta, where she created ideablob.com, the very first social network launched by a financial services company. As we all know, the spike in smartphone adoption is changing the way users interact with their mobile devices. For instance, phone calls are no longer the point of phones for many of us. Instead, we expect our phones to perform more complicated tasks in shorter amounts of time, and we take them with us wherever we go. People also treat the smartphone as a first screen, rather than a second screen, because it&#8217;s the go-to device to instantly source real-time information like directions, prices, and reviews. In fact, most people look at their phone about 150 times a day, (that&#8217;s roughly once every 6.5 minutes), according to Qualcomm CEO, Paul Jacobs. Those glances are to check incoming e-mail and text messages, but mobile web browsing is exploding as well. This begs the question: what about mobile shopping? These days, consumers are indeed using their smartphones to bridge the gap between brick-and-mortar stores and ecommerce. IBM reported that Black Friday sales were up 24.3% in 2011 and attributed some of these gains to mobile device purchases, which &#8220;surged to 9.8% from 3.2%,&#8221; compared to the same time last year. In an effort to learn more about who these mobile shoppers are, we conducted a quantitative study, zeroing in on adults (we define adults as anyone 18 years old and above) who used a smartphone or tablet to shop during the holiday season. What we found is that consumers are constantly integrating their smartphones into their shopping routines all year round. Below, are seven other interesting facts about how this plays out. 1. Mobile Shopping Doesn&#8217;t Equal Mobile Purchasing While browsing is up, mobile shoppers aren&#8217;t necessarily using their phones to complete the purchase cycle. In fact, of all the activities for which shoppers use their phones, purchasing is one of the least popular, with price comparison ranking the highest. Mobile shoppers overwhelmingly cite security concerns as the top reason for not completing purchases with their phones. 2. Men Are More Likely To Consult Their Phone One thing is clear, men are more likely to use mobile devices as in-store companions for all types of shopping activities, from price comparisons to gathering information for a purchase. Men are also more apt to use their mobile phones for shopping outside of traditional retail settings. 3. Mobile Devices Often Trump Computers The majority of mobile shopping is done in locations where computers are more readily accessible, such as at home and work. Part of this may be because some employees prefer to do personal browsing and web shopping on a mobile device rather than a computer attached to a corporate network. 4. Mobile Phones Hardly Impact Shopping Habits Most mobile purchasers say they would buy all or some of the same items, whether or not they were shopping on a mobile device. So while mobile purchasing trends don&#8217;t have a huge impact on goods, bought or sold, they do establish a new commerce channel with a potentially different purchase funnel. 5. The Mobile Experience is Good Of those who shop on their mobile device, 69% believe the experience is either &#8220;excellent&#8221; or &#8220;very good.&#8221; Most consider it a convenience to use a mobile device rather than wait in line. 6. But It Still Needs Some Work Despite the convenience factor of mobile phones, there is plenty of room for improvement, particularly in the user experience of the commerce sites themselves. Most mobile users were dissatisfied with the difficulty of navigating mobile shopping sites, lack of product information on those sites, and the need for better mobile shopping apps. It appears that one of the biggest consumer obstacles &#8212; perception of mobile web security &#8212; also needs to be addressed more fully before a broader swath of consumers feels comfortable entering credit card info via their smartphones. 7. Touchscreens Are Preferred We are witnessing a new user behavior that is being driven largely by adoption of tablets and touchscreen phones. These offer an easier web-browsing experience that turns an Amazon.com purchase into what it should be: a natural, no-fuss, alternative that allows for greater convenience. Kyle Monson, JWT&#8217;s content strategy director, contributed to this article. Image courtesy of iStock, _bilge More About: contributor, features, mobile shopping, mobile technologyFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/mobile-shoppers-trends-facts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/mobile-shoppers-trends-facts/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter Project Wants You to Drink 999 Bottles [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Leading a sustainable life is a matter of choice, but it can be hard to visualize what effect your choices are actually making on the world &#8212; and prove to others how important sustainability is. That&#8217;s why the new green water bottle 999Bottles is set to launch on Kickstarter, just in time for Earth Day. What sets it apart from Nalgene, Klean Kanteen and other reusable bottle makers is that each 24 oz. bottle includes three numbered dials around its base. Every time you refill the bottle, you advance the dial up a notch. In short, it&#8217;s an effortless way to add up the number of plastic bottles you save &#8212; up to 999 bottles. 999Bottles also has an iPhone app that tells you what these numbers actually mean. Designed by the Artefact group, the app visualizes your consumption with graphs so that you can share the impact of your efforts with your friends as well. And that&#8217;s exactly the point of 999bottles. Anybody can use re-usable bottles, but as stated on its website, &#8220;With 999Bottles you can share and amplify the impact of your behavior to influence others in helping reduce consumption of disposable water bottles.&#8221; The campaign also points out that there are no health benefits to drinking bottled water over regular tap water. According to the Centers for Disease Control, not drinking tap water can be detrimental to your health: &#8220;If you mainly drink bottled water with no or low flouride, and you are not getting enough flouride from other sources, you may get more cavities than you would if fluoridated tap water were your main water source.&#8221; With Earth Day coming up on April 22, look out for the 999Bottles&#8217; Kickstarter campaign later this week. More About: earth day, green, Social Good, sustainabilityFor more Social Good coverage:Follow Mashable Social Good on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Good channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/kickstarter-water-999-bottles/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/kickstarter-water-999-bottles/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if Environmentalism Was as Big as Social Media? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>What if everyone across the globe used his or her social media influence to help the planet? The impact would be huge, according to a recent infographic from Recyclebank, a company that rewards green consumers with discounts and deals from local and national businesses. The data encourages the connected generation to use social networks and technology for a positive effect on the earth. For example, if each Pinterest user shared one green idea per month, there would be 12 million more environmentally-conscious tips being passed around. The efforts can be carried offline, too. According to Recyclebank, if everyone on Facebook shortened his or her shower by one minute, we would save enough water to fill 1,136,364 Olympic-sized swimming pools. What relationship do you see between social media and helping the planet? What can you do to make an impact? Let us know in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Olena_T. More About: earth day, infographics, Social Good, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/social-media-environmentalism/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/19/social-media-environmentalism/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
