<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taylor Swift Makes Time For Fans In Paris - Clevver TV</title>
      <description>&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align:top;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td width="80" align="center" valign="top"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td valign="top" class="j"&gt;&lt;font style="font-size:85%;font-family:arial,sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="padding-top:0.8em;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" width="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="lh"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;fd=R&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEaSOx9QETLe_64jLdQSkusugaumw&amp;amp;url=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3D_mnfXb0UQwI"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; Makes Time For Fans In Paris&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#6f6f6f"&gt;Clevver TV&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; makes time for her fans even when she&amp;#39;s in Paris! We&amp;#39;ve got the 411 on Tay&amp;#39;s latest trip to France. Hey ClevverTV peeps, I&amp;#39;m Joslyn Davis, coming to you from our Hollywood HQ. &lt;b&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/b&gt; posed for pics outside her hotel in Paris, &lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font size="-1" class="p"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;font class="p" size="-1"&gt;&lt;a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?pz=1&amp;amp;ned=us&amp;amp;ncl=dqgtZ-P9QDDUAFM"&gt;&lt;nobr&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/nobr&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v%25253D_mnfXb0UQwI</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tom Carden: Time Travel Tube Map</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://www.creativity-online.com/work/tom-carden-time-travel-tube-map/22661"&gt;&lt;img src="http://assets.adage.com/images/work/rightrail/t/o/m/TomCarden_TimeTravelTubeMap11.jpg" width="255" alt="Tom Carden: Time Travel Tube Map" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Subway maps continue to inspire a wealth of creativity. First. Google&amp;#039;s Alexander Chen turned the MTA subway map into an interactive instrument with his Conductor project . Now, UK developer Tom Carden has put together this isochronic London Undergound map, based around travel times. When you click on your chosen station, the illustration will reogranize itself to reflect the times taken to reach different destinations. This is also marked by concentric circles around the station that you&amp;#039;ve chosen. Carden says he was inspired by Oskar Karlin&amp;#039;s reworking of the tube map around the time to travel from Elephant and Castle and Rod McLaren&amp;#039;s subsequent sketch 10 Minutes tube travel from Oxford Circus .</description>
      <link>http://creativity-online.com/login</link>
      <guid>http://creativity-online.com/login</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Limits TweetDeck Access After Security Fears</title>
      <description>Twitter has shut down access to TweetDeck after a bug appeared to give users access to accounts that are not their own. The TweetDeck web app is currently offline. If you&#8217;re currently logged in to the latest software version, Mashable tests show, you will not be able to get back in after logging out. A Twitter user named Geoff Evason discovered the bug on Friday, and tweeted a message to TweetDeck and Twitter suggesting they look into the issue. Hey @Tweetdeck A bug in your software has given me access to hundreds of accounts. #YouShouldLookIntoThat /cc @Twitter twitter.com/gevason/status&#8230; &#8212; Geoff Evason (@gevason) March 30, 2012 According to Evason the bug gave him access to &#8220;hundreds&#8221; of Twitter and Facebook accounts by simply logging into the service using his own account. In order to prove he wasn&#8217;t lying he also sent out a test message from one of those accounts. test &#8212; Tackleberry Showroom (@gotackleberry) March 30, 2012 TweetDeck has confirmed that the service is down via a Twitter post &#8212; however, the company has not indicated when the service will be back up and running or the reason behind the outage. TweetDeck is currently down while we look into an issue. Apologies for the inconvenience. &#8212; TweetDeck (@TweetDeck) March 30, 2012 We reached out to Twitter for more information on the outage, and a representative indicated the company had nothing more to say at this time other than the tweet acknowledging the outage itself. Twitter recently updated TweetDeck to add better list management, inline media support and improved retweeting support. More About: tweetdeck, TwitterFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/tweetdeck-outage/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/tweetdeck-outage/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Charlie Bit My Finger&#8217; Has Earned $500,000 in 5 Years [VIDEOS]</title>
      <description>That precocious Charlie is more than a finger-biter &#8212; he&#8217;s a moneymaker. The family that created the most viewed amateur YouTube video ever &#8212; featuring a biting baby and his talkative older brother &#8212; has made a half-million dollars from ads surrounding that video. Speaking to ABC&#8217;s Nightline, the boy&#8217;s father said the whole thing started when he posted the video in 2007 for his son&#8217;s godfather in Colorado. The video captured a few million views within its few months. Howard Davies-Carr, the boy&#8217;s dad, said he considered taking the video down at that point &#8212; but didn&#8217;t, because there were already many parody videos and copies on other websites. Once the video reached 50 million views, the family began raking in cash from YouTube ads and television spots. SEE ALSO: Charlie Bit My Finger Reimagined as a Zombie Film [VIDEO] With more than 436 million views, the video has become a pop culture phenomenon. The only video watched more on YouTube is the official theme of the 2010 World Cup. Playing off the popularity of the video and their adorable boys, the family started a blog in 2009 to document the kids&#8217; lives. They also have a Twitter account, @harryandcharlie, a YouTube channel with other videos of their boys (there are four), and a Facebook page. There are dozens of &#8220;Charlie Bit Me&#8221; parodies, songs and various auto-tuned remixes &#8212; take a look at some in the gallery below. Charlie bit my finger - again ! The original video posted in 2007. Click here to view this gallery. More About: viral videos, YouTubeFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/charlie-bit-my-finger/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/charlie-bit-my-finger/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Angry Birds Space: How the Physics Works</title>
      <description>The Angry Birds franchise owes a lot to Isaac Newton. The legendary 17th-century scientist defined the classical laws of gravity, after all, and without them, the game&#8217;s designers would have had nothing to go on in crafting how things move in its virtual world. Consequently, the game&#8217;s heroic-yet-furious birds wouldn&#8217;t be able to exact their high-impact revenge on those smug, green pigs. Without the laws of gravity to guide them, the pigs&#8217; Rube Goldberg-esque structures simply wouldn&#8217;t come crashing down. The thing is, the game doesn&#8217;t use real physics to model how things move. That&#8217;s according to Rhett Allain, an associate professor of physics at Southeastern Louisiana University. The latest version, Angry Birds Space, which escalates the avian-porcine conflict to the final frontier, uses science that&#8217;s even further from reality, he says. Allain says he took on figuring out the game&#8217;s physics because it was a challenge. Without ever contacting the game publisher, Rovio, he wrote an extensive analysis of the physics of Angry Birds Space for Wired. The question remains: Why spend so much time analyzing a silly game? &#8220;My goal is to use this as an educational tool,&#8221; Allain told Mashable. &#8220;I love doing analysis for Angry Birds because it&#8217;s a lot like real physics but it doesn&#8217;t have the same answers. Obviously in this case the gravitational force is not the same as what you could look up in a textbook. I want to to try to find the answer, just like we do in science.&#8221; SEE ALSO: &#8216;Angry Birds Space&#8217; Downloaded 10M Times in 3 Days It&#8217;s clear Angry Birds Space doesn&#8217;t use real physics (for starters, the gravity of each &#8220;planet&#8221; is limited to an arbitrarily-sized bubble). It instead uses some kind of rule structure that determines the motion of the birds and their targets. In his analysis, Allain had to make a lot of assumptions, such as the typical mass of a bird, the bird&#8217;s velocity when it hits a gravity well, and the size of the planets. After working out the math and plotting how he thought the birds probably move, he compared his work with some video captures of the game (he quickly got good at launching birds so they would &#8220;orbit&#8221; the little planets). The results were pretty close (see the excerpted chart below). He also found a few surprises. &#8220;For Angry Birds Space, it looks like gravity on the birds is just a constant value,&#8221; he says. &#8220;One of the things that&#8217;s important for orbital motion is that the further away you get the less that force is. In this case, it looks like that&#8217;s not true.&#8221; As for how the accuracy of the game&#8217;s physics compares with the &#8220;terrestrial&#8221; version of Angry Birds, Allain says it&#8217;s not even close. Although the regular game takes some liberties with science (momentum isn&#8217;t conserved when the white birds drop their eggs, for example), the outer-space version is off-the-charts ludicrous. &#8220;In space,&#8221; he explains, &#8220;if this were actual gravity, the mass of the planets would have to be so large in order to get these kinds of orbits &#8212; bordering black hole density. At least neutron stars.&#8221; Of course, those departures from reality are what makes the game fun to play. Allain says every game that has things happening in real time has its own laws of physics. &#8220;When you make a game, there&#8217;s two things you could do: You could say this object is constrained to move in this way, or I could make up some rules. In Fruit Ninja, do i say that the fruit moves up or moves down and I tell the game how the fruit should move. Games that deal with things that can change in unpredictable ways all have some type of model. &#8220;Some are more interesting to look at than others.&#8221; What are some of your favorite games with with either real or imagined physics? Share your experiences in the comments. BONUS: A Tour of Angry Birds Space Angry Birds Intro The Angry Birds, with all new characters, are blasting off in pursuit of their piggy foe.Click here to view this gallery. More About: angry birds, angry birds space, games, Gaming, physics, rovio, Science</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/physics-angry-birds-space/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/physics-angry-birds-space/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Employees Like Tim Cook a Little Better than Steve Jobs</title>
      <description>The late Steve Jobs may be as venerated within the company he founded as he is outside it. But that doesn&#8217;t mean his successor is suffering by comparison. In fact, according to anonymous employee posts on the employer reviews website Glassdoor, Cook has the highest approval rating of any CEO in tech &#8212; indeed, any CEO in the U.S. &#8212; a whopping 97%. That&#8217;s a small but significant step above Jobs, who garnered 95% approval during his final year in the CEO role. (Cook&#8217;s year includes the months he was officially filling in for Jobs while the founder was on medical leave.) But for that extra 2%, Cook would not be the sole winner of Glassdoor&#8217;s list of tech CEOs. He&#8217;d be level-pegging with Qualcomm CEO Paul Jacobs, who has had a stunning year as far as his employees are concerned, rising from 87% approval to 95%. SEE ALSO: Top Tech Companies to Work for in 2012: Facebook Beats Google, Apple Meanwhile, Google CEO Larry Page isn&#8217;t faring so well &#8212; he&#8217;s seen a 2% decline in employee satisfaction compared to his predecessor, Eric Schmidt. Given that Page has been on a tear killing projects in order to focus on a few core products, it&#8217;s perhaps surprising that his number is still as high as 94%. As for Cook, there are any number of reasons why his popularity is so high. Apple shares are soaring past $600, a 50% premium since Jobs&#8217; departure. He&#8217;s set up a matching program for charitable donations, something Jobs famously refused to do. And he&#8217;s dealt expertly with threats to the Apple image &#8212; most recently making an impromptu visit to the Foxconn factories in China. &#8220;The products speak for themselves and the company,&#8221; writes one anonymous Apple engineer on Glassdoor. &#8220;We have the best management team anywhere,&#8221; says another Cupertino reviewer. Perhaps the real question should be: What&#8217;s the deal with the 3% of Apple employees who don&#8217;t like Tim Cook? More About: apple, Foxconn, glassdoor, Google, tim cookFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/apple-employees-tim-cook-steve-jobs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/apple-employees-tim-cook-steve-jobs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Wonders of the Universe&#8217; Lets You Explore Space On Your iPad</title>
      <description>HarperCollins released a new iPad app Thursday that will set you off on a 3D exploration through space using high-resolution visuals specifically optimized for the new iPad's Retina display.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/wonders-universe-lets-explore-space-ipad-224054718.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/wonders-universe-lets-explore-space-ipad-224054718.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Easy PC Pranks to Trick Your Friends</title>
      <description>1. Make Desktop Icons Disappear This prank is so easy, you can do it in just a few seconds. When you have access to your victim's computer, right-click on the desktop background, hit the first option -- "View" -- then uncheck the "Show desktop icons" option. Now, sit back and wait for utter confuzzlement.Click here to view this gallery.With April Fools&#8217; Day on the horizon, it&#8217;s the perfect time to play some epic pranks on your PC-using co-workers, friends, family and frenemies. These classic suggestions will utterly confuse your hapless victims. Some devilishly simple pranks will only take a matter of seconds to pull off, whereas more advanced trickery will require a couple of minutes to access your victims&#8217; PC control panels. SEE ALSO: 10 Office Pranks Perfect for April Fools&#8217; Day Take a look through our gallery of geeky April Fool&#8217;s Day tricks to play on your nearest and dearest. Go forth and be epic, then, come back here and let us know which ones they fell for! Thumbnail image courtesy of iStockphoto, EricHood More About: april fools, features, Holiday, How-To, Windows 7</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/pc-pranks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/pc-pranks/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media</title>
      <description>The Customer Experience Series is supported by Webtrends. Get insider tips and a step-by-step guide to acquiring, engaging and nurturing fans. Download the Playbook. We all know social media is an important tool for brand awareness and customer acquisition &#8212; but how exactly are you supposed to convert random Twitter and Facebook users into real-life customers? Well, that depends. Different brands have different challenges when it comes to customer acquisition: &#8220;If you&#8217;re our customer, you&#8217;ve signed up for a year-long service, unlike the Starbucks of the world, where you can be a customer by coming in for a cup of coffee one day,&#8221; says Lisa D&#8217;Aromando, social media community manager at Equinox. Whether you&#8217;re a clothing shop, a restaurant or a subscription service, you must tailor your strategy so that it makes sense for your brand. That said, there are a few universal ways to help your company attract new faces on the social web. &#8220;I&#8217;m a big believer in creating and sharing meaningful content,&#8221; says Danni Snyder, co-founder and creative director at jewelry brand Dannijo. &#8220;Over time, that is every brand&#8217;s best bet for creating and sustaining a following that will grow their business.&#8221; But what does it all entail? Mashable spoke with some super-social brands about how they find new customers and lock in their existing ones they have as repeat buyers. 1. Get Your Search On There are 340 million tweets sent per day &#8212; odds are that a few of them are referencing your brand, though you may not realize it. &#8220;Just because chatter on social media channels isn&#8217;t mentioning your brand by handle or hashtag doesn&#8217;t mean it isn&#8217;t happening,&#8221; says McKee Floyd, director of brand development at Sweetgreen. The key is to be proactive. For the company&#8217;s upcoming Sweetlife Festival, Floyd set up Twitter searches for &#8220;sweetlife&#8221; and &#8220;sweetlife festival&#8221; on TweetDeck, which pulls the tweets even if users didn&#8217;t include the hashtag. &#8220;As groups of friends have conversations back and forth on Twitter about whether or not they should buy tickets, we monitor and chime in with helpful info, answering logistical questions about the festival and hopefully swaying them towards choosing to attend.&#8221; Geoff Alexander, managing partner at Chicago&#8217;s Wow Bao, says his team also uses TweetDeck to search for certain keywords &#8212; such as &#8220;wow bao,&#8221; &#8220;baomouth&#8221; and &#8220;hot Asian buns&#8221; &#8212; and they reply to any and all posts they find. Wow Bao initially got into social media because there wasn&#8217;t a budget for advertising, so the brand opted to spread the word by giving away buns. &#8220;@BaoMouth searches the Internet for ways to reward people &#8212; giving away bao, full meals or mobile money [for the food truck],&#8221; says Alexander. But the search tactic works for more than just food concepts. Danni Snyder says she monitor mentions of Dannijo religiously and also searches Twitter for &#8220;jewelry.&#8221; Consuming social media buzz about jewelry &#8212; and not just Dannijo&#8217;s wares &#8212; helps the brand be &#8220;aware of what people are talking about, what they like and don&#8217;t like, etc.&#8221; says Snyder, which can help Dannijo cultivate a new audience with their next collection. One tip for finding new customers is to see who&#8217;s engaging with your competitors &#8212; if someone just started following or tweeted at or checked in at another bakery in the neighborhood, you could tweet at the person to come check out your cupcakes. They customer will appreciate the shout-out and the fact that you handpicked them to be your customer. Get clever with searches that are relevant to your business and offerings to help you target potential customers &#8212; then reel them in by being charming and human, not salesy. 2. Use Images to Engage Who would have thought Mr Dannijo would be back in such a good way?! #EVERYBODY #eyespy #MRDANNIJO @manrepeller @danielleasnyder @jodielynns #putaneyeonit A picture is worth a thousand words &#8212; photos drive twice as much engagement as text posts do on Facebook. So if you&#8217;re looking to attract some new fans, start snapping pics. Snyder says Instagram is her favorite medium for connecting with fans. &#8220;You can subliminally market without annoying your customers because each post is capable of accomplishing a number of things,&#8221; she says. &#8220;In one post, we can showcase a new design available at Dannijo.com, thus driving traffic to our ecommerce site; show how we&#8217;d style the jewelry; mention a tastemaker friend like Questlove or ManRepeller and promote them while they&#8217;re wearing Dannijo; inspire discussion and engagement, gaining valuable customer feedback; and provide followers some visual inspiration and insight into your creative process.&#8221; But the pics need not be product-focused. Dannijo posts photos of food and musicians that embody the Dannijo vibe. Similarly, Rent the Runway posts pictures of various style trends. &#8220;On Facebook, we try to use as much imagery as possible &#8212; not just promotional imagery of our dresses, but images that relate to pop-culture,&#8221; says Jenny Fleiss, president and co-founder of Rent the Runway. For example, in anticipation of the upcoming Great Gatsby movie, the RTR blog posted about Gatsby-inspired fashion trends. 3. Host a Competition Nothing gets customers going like some swag, so contests are a great way to boost your followers and engagement. But be strategic about what you&#8217;re offering, or else you could attract the wrong followers. ModCloth hosts monthly photo contests that garner hundreds of entries and thousands of votes. &#8220;Our most recent contest, Thrifted Treasures, asked our fans to share their favorite vintage finds, and our community could vote up their favorites,&#8221; explains Natasha Khan, ModCloth&#8217;s social media manager. &#8220;The social actions surrounding that event brought in thousands of new fans, which we otherwise would not have gained.&#8221; Khan says contests and offers have been the most high impact customer generation events for ModCloth. But if you&#8217;re planning on hosting a contest, Khan has a few suggestions. First, build in actions that allow the fan to share to their social networks, as this will increase virality. Second, stay true to your brand. Third, tweak the contest to fit the platform on which you&#8217;re running it &#8212; &#8220;On Facebook that means sharing photography, on Twitter it means wordplay hashtags, and for Polyvore it means styling outfits,&#8221; says Khan. &#8220;Quality is more important than quantity when it comes to Facebook fan growth. If your company product is clothing and your prize is free iPads, then you will gain followers that might not belong to your core demographic. Make sure the reward is something your customer will value, such as a gift card or grab bag of your products,&#8221; says Khan. 4. Spice Up The Platforms With so many platforms to manage, be sure to have a distinct M.O. on each channel &#8212; and cross-pollinate sparingly. If a customer sees the same information and pictures on Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Instagram and Pinterest, she need only follow you on one of these platforms. Also, be wary of overpromotion. Nothing is more of a turnoff than a constant sales messaging &#8212; people easily can unfollow, and they will. Interestingly, many of Wow Bao&#8217;s posts have nothing to do with bao &#8212; @BaoMouth tweets during award shows and keeps a lively conversation going on a number of topics, winning people over with its spunky personality. Of course, a big reason why you use various social media channels is to promote your product, so there are some things to keep in mind for the messaging when you are pushing your goods. &#8220;Prove the value of being a Facebook fan. If you can find the same content and offers on other channels, there is no incentive to also follow the brand on Facebook,&#8221; Khan says. &#8220;Exclusive Facebook-only offers and original content reinforces our investment in the channel.&#8221; The same goes for every other social platform. For Equinox, Facebook is for broadcasting of events and initiatives, like Cycle For Survival, Twitter is more conversation and geared toward responding to questions about membership, fitness routines and healthy eating, and Foursquare is the platform on which to find offers for Equinox&#8217;s spa and shop, which are open to the public. &#8220;Every Monday in March, we posted a different Foursquare check-in special for The Shop at all of our locations,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;Since you don&#8217;t have to necessarily be a member to go to The Shop or The Spa, these specials are accessible to everyone,&#8221; and can lure in potential customers into becoming Equinox members. The company&#8217;s Q blog is another digital project where you&#8217;ll find awe-inspiring videos and original lifestyle content &#8212; a great way to add value for potential customers. &#8220;Q was launched to extend our brand and increase this word-of-mouth among our target audience. It gives people &#8212; members and nonmembers &#8212; topics and material from our Equinox experts to share with others,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;In lieu of promos, we create a different sort of currency: highly produced, branded content on Q with exclusives for our social media communities.&#8221; 5. Make It Personal No one like a mass message &#8212; consumers like to feel as if they&#8217;re the only ones being spoken to. You should know your customers and speak to them in personal ways to establish touchpoints that build relationships and create loyalty. &#8220;I like to make it very personable &#8212; if someone tweets a question I make sure to answer immediately,&#8221; says Steven Rojas, social media director at GrandLife Hotels. &#8220;Often I go as far as Googling that person to make sure I know as much as I can about them before reaching out. I want to humanize the brand so people don&#8217;t feel like they are speaking to a computer but to an actual person who cares about what they are saying. My obsession for all things digital never sleeps, so I make sure everyone gets what they need, when they need it.&#8221; Live chats are another effective way to offer intimate interaction and engagement with fans. &#8220;It&#8217;s about having a conversation with your community, so we often do live chats with our stylists on Facebook to answer any styling questions customers may have,&#8221; says Fleiss. &#8220;These posts tend to elicit the most &#8216;Likes&#8217; and comments.&#8221; While you&#8217;re browsing sites for comments to respond to, don&#8217;t ignore negative feedback &#8212; addressing the complaint is an opportunity to convert an unhappy customer into an impressed brand ambassador. &#8220;We&#8217;re very appreciative when someone takes the time to let us know about a bad experience or an issue because then we can help fix it,&#8221; says Jenny Danzi, a Mountain Dew brand manager. &#8220;Reply to every complaint to turn those consumers into advocates &#8212; even if you can not offer an instant fix, people appreciate getting a human response,&#8221; she adds. And don&#8217;t forget that even the littlest gesture can make a big difference. &#8220;Sometimes for us it can be as simple as letting consumers know where they can find our products,&#8221; says Danzi. Wow Bao takes it to the next level, proactively finding ways to create touchpoints with consumers. &#8220;We comment on any and all posts mentioning people&#8217;s birthdays and pop culture,&#8221; says Alexander. &#8220;We even schedule posts for people&#8217;s birthdays, when people post something like, &#8216;My birthday is in 12 days&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; a very personalized tactic that can go a long way. 6. Let Your Customers Shine Nothing makes a customer feel better than being acknowledged &#8212; or better yet, honored &#8212; by their favorite brand. Is there a way to offer kudos to your loyal fans? If so, make it happen. Because women love to talk about what they&#8217;re wearing &#8212; and often wear RTR to social events such as weddings and cocktail parties &#8212; Rent the Runway strives to move these conversations online. &#8220;We have weekly style award contests on our blog and Facebook Page, and a section of our site called RTR Moments where women can share photos of themselves in RTR dresses,&#8221; says Fleiss. For Mountain Dew, whose fan base is extremely young and active on social media, the &#8220;Diet Mountain Dew Supernova Spotter&#8221; is a great way to celebrate the return of the fan-chosen flavor in addition to highlighting the passion of the fans. &#8220;Dew drinkers can upload their photo of Diet Supernova, and on Friday we&#8217;ll open the entries up to public voting. Fifteen winners will each get a Diet Dew hoodie, and everyone who enters can easily share their Diet Supernova passion with friends,&#8221; Danzi says. For Equinox, whose social media fan base is largely comprised of members, the goal isn&#8217;t as much to incentivize people to join (they already have), but to make them feel special for being members. &#8220;We have a Facebook app where members can refer friends directly, and if the friend joins, the member gets a referral bonus,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;We also just launched a program on Twitter where we&#8217;re rewarding our advocates by offering them private group fitness classes for them and their friends. This gives us a way to say &#8216;thanks&#8217; to those who always post about us, and it gives them something to talk about with their friends &#8212; online and off.&#8221; Brands, how does your company acquire new customers on social media? Consumers, what makes you want to become a customer? Let us know in the comments. Series supported by Webtrends The Customer Experience Series is supported by Webtrends. Create campaigns that lead to greater click-throughs, conversions and revenue. Want to get started? Download the Playbook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci More About: Customer Experience Series, features, instagram, mashable, rent the runway, Social Media, Sweetgreen, tweetdeck</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/customer-acquisition-social/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/customer-acquisition-social/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Likes: How Google and Adobe Aim to Measure Your True Social ROI</title>
      <description>Measuring marketing spending used to be pretty easy, at least in theory: You&#8217;d run a big ad campaign and then see if your sales rose. If they did, great. If not, then you wasted your money. Social media has muddied the waters. A campaign may not do much for sales, but it might add a million Facebook fans or garner an impressive number of retweets. Does that mean you spent your money effectively? Over the past month, Google and Adobe have attempted to answer that question. Both companies have released tools that let marketers track their marketing spend through social media. Such data aims to provide some concrete ROI behind the touchy-feely world of Likes, retweets and +1s &#8212; data that, on its own, amount to what Phil Mui, group product manager for Google Analytics, dubs &#8220;vanity metrics.&#8221; Adobe Social Adobe, best known for design software such as Photoshop, is attempting to boost its credibility as a marketing services provider with Adobe Social. The tool, which is part of the Adobe Online Digital Suite, offers data from Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Google+. The latest version of Social, which was introduced earlier this month at a conference in Salt Lake City (see picture above, featuring director Jeff Jordan, senior product manager or social media), is an update of Adobe SocialAnalytics, which was launched in March 2011. Since that time, Adobe has purchased Efficient Frontier, a firm best known as a buyer and seller of ads on Facebook. The company has tapped that expertise for the latest version. Aseem Chandra, VP of marketing for the Adobe Digital Marketing Business, says SocialAnalytics lets you track activity on those social media platforms and then take note of users who wind up on your website. If you sell something on your site, it can connect that activity to sales. The product was just released to the public on March 9, but Adobe has been working with a handful of brands for the past few months in a pilot program. Among those brands is Expedia, the online travel firm, which ran a promotion in April 2011 called FriendTrips. The promo dangled $1 million in prizes. Participants entered to win one of 13 luxury vacations. However, you were required to RSVP five friends for each entry. Chandra says the effort netted Expedia 1 million new Facebook fans. By calculating the money spent on the promotion, $1 million, and the 750% increase in fans, SocialAnalytics reckoned that the cost-per-fan fell 4.5 times compared to previous campaigns. Users can also get data like fan demographics, likes and shares via SocialAnalytics. Such information will cost you. Chandra declined to get specific, but said access costs &#8220;tens of thousands&#8221; of dollars, meaning it&#8217;s an option for some small- to medium-size businesses, but not mom-and-pops. Google Analytics A little more than a week after Adobe released SocialAnalytics, Google announced Social reports, an addition to Google Analytics that attempts to show a causal relationship between social media activity and sales. There are three major differences between Adobe&#8217;s and Google&#8217;s solution: 1. Google&#8217;s is free. 2. Facebook and Twitter do not provide data. 3. The data completely revolves around your website. If you&#8217;ve used Google Analytics, you know that you can already see if recent traffic has been referred from one of the social networks. Google has expanded on that. Now, you can also see if someone interacted with your site days, weeks or months ago and then returned &#8212; a conversion that Google calls &#8220;assisted.&#8221; Google also lets you place a monetary value on such interactions, though that&#8217;s somewhat subjective. If your site allows for direct sales, then figuring out that figure is easy enough. Otherwise, Google suggests you quantify each conversion. That can get tricky if you sell, for instance, cars, since merely visiting your site doesn&#8217;t necessarily equal a sale. The assisted conversions are also subjective. Chandra lets marketers set their time frame. If someone on Facebook clicked on a link six months ago and then went back and bought something today, is that old interaction valuable? Google says it is if you think it is. The lack of Facebook and Twitter metrics may also be an issue, but maybe not as much as you think. Perhaps you don&#8217;t want to dive into all the Likes and People Talking About metrics and just see in broad brush strokes how many people came from your site via Facebook. However, Google&#8217;s wealth of data for participating networks (the company claims about 20, including, of course, Google+), may make you wish Facebook and Twitter were cooperating. For instance, if you see a bump in traffic from Google+, now you can call up actual conversations behind it. You can dig even deeper and identify your most influential users as well. Is This Helpful? Such data is attractive to marketers. If nothing else, it provides an answer to company bean counters&#8217; questions about social media ROI. But are they useful for creating new social media marketing campaigns? Brian Solis, principal of Altimeter Group, says better metrics don&#8217;t address the fact that most marketers launch social media campaigns without a clear goal in mind. &#8220;If you want to optimize Facebook&#8217;s contribution to sales, you have to design that at the front end,&#8221; says Solis, who recently completed a study looking at how influencers actually spread social media messages. He recommends creating programs that provide some value to such influencers and people connected to them. He also suggests defining what success looks like before you launch your program. Since social media is still relatively new, that may be a tough task for marketers. One alternative is to try various things in social media and then track the results. Given the dynamic nature of social media and the mind-boggling number of variables involved with each campaign, isolating the elements that made a campaign successful might be tough. All of which is why Google&#8217;s and Adobe&#8217;s new metrics might provide greater visibility into marketing done via social media, yet still can&#8217;t offer straightforward results. When it comes to the question of social media marketing ROI, the answer is still that old Facebook standard: It&#8217;s complicated. Adobe Social: Set Up This slide shows how it might look at the beginning of a campaign, with various stated goals. Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, michellegibson More About: adobe, Business, features, Google, google analytics, Social Media, social media marketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/google-adobe-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/google-adobe-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creepy iPhone Case Forces You to Interact with Siri</title>
      <description>Your iPhone 4S has a beautiful touchscreen retina display. But who cares about that when Siri can do everything for you by voice command? This reverse iPhone case covers the smartphone&#8217;s screen, revealing only the home button. That way, Siri leaves you no choice but to interact with her. Muahahahahaha! Designed and sold by 3D printing company Shapeways, the Siri case retails for $90. More About: Gadgets, iphone, iphone accessories, Mobile, shapeways, siri, viralFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/siri-iphone-case/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/30/siri-iphone-case/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
