<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>6 Ways to Acquire New Customers via Social Media</title>
      <description>The Customer Experience Series is supported by Webtrends. Get insider tips and a step-by-step guide to acquiring, engaging and nurturing fans. Download the Playbook. We all know social media is an important tool for brand awareness and customer acquisition &#8212; but how exactly are you supposed to convert random Twitter and Facebook users into real-life customers? Well, that depends. Different brands have different challenges when it comes to customer acquisition: &#8220;If you&#8217;re our customer, you&#8217;ve signed up for a year-long service, unlike the Starbucks of the world, where you can be a customer by coming in for a cup of coffee one day,&#8221; says Lisa D&#8217;Aromando, social media community manager at Equinox. Whether you&#8217;re a clothing shop, a restaurant or a subscription service, you must tailor your strategy so that it makes sense for your brand. That said, there are a few universal ways to help your company attract new faces on the social web. &#8220;I&#8217;m a big believer in creating and sharing meaningful content,&#8221; says Danni Snyder, co-founder and creative director at jewelry brand Dannijo. &#8220;Over time, that is every brand&#8217;s best bet for creating and sustaining a following that will grow their business.&#8221; But what does it all entail? Mashable spoke with some super-social brands about how they find new customers and lock in their existing ones they have as repeat buyers. 1. Get Your Search On There are 340 million tweets sent per day &#8212; odds are that a few of them are referencing your brand, though you may not realize it. &#8220;Just because chatter on social media channels isn&#8217;t mentioning your brand by handle or hashtag doesn&#8217;t mean it isn&#8217;t happening,&#8221; says McKee Floyd, director of brand development at Sweetgreen. The key is to be proactive. For the company&#8217;s upcoming Sweetlife Festival, Floyd set up Twitter searches for &#8220;sweetlife&#8221; and &#8220;sweetlife festival&#8221; on TweetDeck, which pulls the tweets even if users didn&#8217;t include the hashtag. &#8220;As groups of friends have conversations back and forth on Twitter about whether or not they should buy tickets, we monitor and chime in with helpful info, answering logistical questions about the festival and hopefully swaying them towards choosing to attend.&#8221; Geoff Alexander, managing partner at Chicago&#8217;s Wow Bao, says his team also uses TweetDeck to search for certain keywords &#8212; such as &#8220;wow bao,&#8221; &#8220;baomouth&#8221; and &#8220;hot Asian buns&#8221; &#8212; and they reply to any and all posts they find. Wow Bao initially got into social media because there wasn&#8217;t a budget for advertising, so the brand opted to spread the word by giving away buns. &#8220;@BaoMouth searches the Internet for ways to reward people &#8212; giving away bao, full meals or mobile money [for the food truck],&#8221; says Alexander. But the search tactic works for more than just food concepts. Danni Snyder says she monitor mentions of Dannijo religiously and also searches Twitter for &#8220;jewelry.&#8221; Consuming social media buzz about jewelry &#8212; and not just Dannijo&#8217;s wares &#8212; helps the brand be &#8220;aware of what people are talking about, what they like and don&#8217;t like, etc.&#8221; says Snyder, which can help Dannijo cultivate a new audience with their next collection. One tip for finding new customers is to see who&#8217;s engaging with your competitors &#8212; if someone just started following or tweeted at or checked in at another bakery in the neighborhood, you could tweet at the person to come check out your cupcakes. They customer will appreciate the shout-out and the fact that you handpicked them to be your customer. Get clever with searches that are relevant to your business and offerings to help you target potential customers &#8212; then reel them in by being charming and human, not salesy. 2. Use Images to Engage Who would have thought Mr Dannijo would be back in such a good way?! #EVERYBODY #eyespy #MRDANNIJO @manrepeller @danielleasnyder @jodielynns #putaneyeonit A picture is worth a thousand words &#8212; photos drive twice as much engagement as text posts do on Facebook. So if you&#8217;re looking to attract some new fans, start snapping pics. Snyder says Instagram is her favorite medium for connecting with fans. &#8220;You can subliminally market without annoying your customers because each post is capable of accomplishing a number of things,&#8221; she says. &#8220;In one post, we can showcase a new design available at Dannijo.com, thus driving traffic to our ecommerce site; show how we&#8217;d style the jewelry; mention a tastemaker friend like Questlove or ManRepeller and promote them while they&#8217;re wearing Dannijo; inspire discussion and engagement, gaining valuable customer feedback; and provide followers some visual inspiration and insight into your creative process.&#8221; But the pics need not be product-focused. Dannijo posts photos of food and musicians that embody the Dannijo vibe. Similarly, Rent the Runway posts pictures of various style trends. &#8220;On Facebook, we try to use as much imagery as possible &#8212; not just promotional imagery of our dresses, but images that relate to pop-culture,&#8221; says Jenny Fleiss, president and co-founder of Rent the Runway. For example, in anticipation of the upcoming Great Gatsby movie, the RTR blog posted about Gatsby-inspired fashion trends. 3. Host a Competition Nothing gets customers going like some swag, so contests are a great way to boost your followers and engagement. But be strategic about what you&#8217;re offering, or else you could attract the wrong followers. ModCloth hosts monthly photo contests that garner hundreds of entries and thousands of votes. &#8220;Our most recent contest, Thrifted Treasures, asked our fans to share their favorite vintage finds, and our community could vote up their favorites,&#8221; explains Natasha Khan, ModCloth&#8217;s social media manager. &#8220;The social actions surrounding that event brought in thousands of new fans, which we otherwise would not have gained.&#8221; Khan says contests and offers have been the most high impact customer generation events for ModCloth. But if you&#8217;re planning on hosting a contest, Khan has a few suggestions. First, build in actions that allow the fan to share to their social networks, as this will increase virality. Second, stay true to your brand. Third, tweak the contest to fit the platform on which you&#8217;re running it &#8212; &#8220;On Facebook that means sharing photography, on Twitter it means wordplay hashtags, and for Polyvore it means styling outfits,&#8221; says Khan. &#8220;Quality is more important than quantity when it comes to Facebook fan growth. If your company product is clothing and your prize is free iPads, then you will gain followers that might not belong to your core demographic. Make sure the reward is something your customer will value, such as a gift card or grab bag of your products,&#8221; says Khan. 4. Spice Up The Platforms With so many platforms to manage, be sure to have a distinct M.O. on each channel &#8212; and cross-pollinate sparingly. If a customer sees the same information and pictures on Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Instagram and Pinterest, she need only follow you on one of these platforms. Also, be wary of overpromotion. Nothing is more of a turnoff than a constant sales messaging &#8212; people easily can unfollow, and they will. Interestingly, many of Wow Bao&#8217;s posts have nothing to do with bao &#8212; @BaoMouth tweets during award shows and keeps a lively conversation going on a number of topics, winning people over with its spunky personality. Of course, a big reason why you use various social media channels is to promote your product, so there are some things to keep in mind for the messaging when you are pushing your goods. &#8220;Prove the value of being a Facebook fan. If you can find the same content and offers on other channels, there is no incentive to also follow the brand on Facebook,&#8221; Khan says. &#8220;Exclusive Facebook-only offers and original content reinforces our investment in the channel.&#8221; The same goes for every other social platform. For Equinox, Facebook is for broadcasting of events and initiatives, like Cycle For Survival, Twitter is more conversation and geared toward responding to questions about membership, fitness routines and healthy eating, and Foursquare is the platform on which to find offers for Equinox&#8217;s spa and shop, which are open to the public. &#8220;Every Monday in March, we posted a different Foursquare check-in special for The Shop at all of our locations,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;Since you don&#8217;t have to necessarily be a member to go to The Shop or The Spa, these specials are accessible to everyone,&#8221; and can lure in potential customers into becoming Equinox members. The company&#8217;s Q blog is another digital project where you&#8217;ll find awe-inspiring videos and original lifestyle content &#8212; a great way to add value for potential customers. &#8220;Q was launched to extend our brand and increase this word-of-mouth among our target audience. It gives people &#8212; members and nonmembers &#8212; topics and material from our Equinox experts to share with others,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;In lieu of promos, we create a different sort of currency: highly produced, branded content on Q with exclusives for our social media communities.&#8221; 5. Make It Personal No one like a mass message &#8212; consumers like to feel as if they&#8217;re the only ones being spoken to. You should know your customers and speak to them in personal ways to establish touchpoints that build relationships and create loyalty. &#8220;I like to make it very personable &#8212; if someone tweets a question I make sure to answer immediately,&#8221; says Steven Rojas, social media director at GrandLife Hotels. &#8220;Often I go as far as Googling that person to make sure I know as much as I can about them before reaching out. I want to humanize the brand so people don&#8217;t feel like they are speaking to a computer but to an actual person who cares about what they are saying. My obsession for all things digital never sleeps, so I make sure everyone gets what they need, when they need it.&#8221; Live chats are another effective way to offer intimate interaction and engagement with fans. &#8220;It&#8217;s about having a conversation with your community, so we often do live chats with our stylists on Facebook to answer any styling questions customers may have,&#8221; says Fleiss. &#8220;These posts tend to elicit the most &#8216;Likes&#8217; and comments.&#8221; While you&#8217;re browsing sites for comments to respond to, don&#8217;t ignore negative feedback &#8212; addressing the complaint is an opportunity to convert an unhappy customer into an impressed brand ambassador. &#8220;We&#8217;re very appreciative when someone takes the time to let us know about a bad experience or an issue because then we can help fix it,&#8221; says Jenny Danzi, a Mountain Dew brand manager. &#8220;Reply to every complaint to turn those consumers into advocates &#8212; even if you can not offer an instant fix, people appreciate getting a human response,&#8221; she adds. And don&#8217;t forget that even the littlest gesture can make a big difference. &#8220;Sometimes for us it can be as simple as letting consumers know where they can find our products,&#8221; says Danzi. Wow Bao takes it to the next level, proactively finding ways to create touchpoints with consumers. &#8220;We comment on any and all posts mentioning people&#8217;s birthdays and pop culture,&#8221; says Alexander. &#8220;We even schedule posts for people&#8217;s birthdays, when people post something like, &#8216;My birthday is in 12 days&#8217;&#8221; &#8212; a very personalized tactic that can go a long way. 6. Let Your Customers Shine Nothing makes a customer feel better than being acknowledged &#8212; or better yet, honored &#8212; by their favorite brand. Is there a way to offer kudos to your loyal fans? If so, make it happen. Because women love to talk about what they&#8217;re wearing &#8212; and often wear RTR to social events such as weddings and cocktail parties &#8212; Rent the Runway strives to move these conversations online. &#8220;We have weekly style award contests on our blog and Facebook Page, and a section of our site called RTR Moments where women can share photos of themselves in RTR dresses,&#8221; says Fleiss. For Mountain Dew, whose fan base is extremely young and active on social media, the &#8220;Diet Mountain Dew Supernova Spotter&#8221; is a great way to celebrate the return of the fan-chosen flavor in addition to highlighting the passion of the fans. &#8220;Dew drinkers can upload their photo of Diet Supernova, and on Friday we&#8217;ll open the entries up to public voting. Fifteen winners will each get a Diet Dew hoodie, and everyone who enters can easily share their Diet Supernova passion with friends,&#8221; Danzi says. For Equinox, whose social media fan base is largely comprised of members, the goal isn&#8217;t as much to incentivize people to join (they already have), but to make them feel special for being members. &#8220;We have a Facebook app where members can refer friends directly, and if the friend joins, the member gets a referral bonus,&#8221; says D&#8217;Aromando. &#8220;We also just launched a program on Twitter where we&#8217;re rewarding our advocates by offering them private group fitness classes for them and their friends. This gives us a way to say &#8216;thanks&#8217; to those who always post about us, and it gives them something to talk about with their friends &#8212; online and off.&#8221; Brands, how does your company acquire new customers on social media? Consumers, what makes you want to become a customer? Let us know in the comments. Series supported by Webtrends The Customer Experience Series is supported by Webtrends. Create campaigns that lead to greater click-throughs, conversions and revenue. Want to get started? Download the Playbook. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, akinbostanci More About: Customer Experience Series, features, instagram, mashable, rent the runway, Social Media, Sweetgreen, tweetdeck</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/customer-acquisition-social/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/customer-acquisition-social/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LG&#8217;s Flexible E-Paper Is Coming to Europe in April</title>
      <description>LG has announced it has started mass production of its electronic paper display (EPD) product, with a planned launch in Europe next month. LG&#8217;s EPD is a 6-inch, 1024&#215;768 e-ink plastic screen. It&#8217;s 0.7mm thick, it weighs 14g, and LG claims it&#8217;s resistant to scratches and drops from a 1.5 meter height. Of course, its biggest claim to fame is its flexibility: LG claims the screen allows bending at a range of 40 degrees from its center. &#8220;With the world&#8217;s first plastic EPD, LG Display has once again proven its reputation for leadership and innovation with a product we believe will help greatly popularize the E-Book market,&#8221; said Sang Duck Yeo, Head of Operations for LG Display&#8217;s Mobile/OLED division. There is no word on a US release, but LG says the EPD will first be supplied to ODM companies in China, with completed products hitting European shores at the beginning of April. More About: e-paper, LGFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/lg-e-paper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/lg-e-paper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LG&#8217;s Flexible E-Paper Is Coming to Europe in April</title>
      <description>LG has announced it has started mass production of its electronic paper display (EPD) product, with a planned launch in Europe next month. LG&#8217;s EPD is a 6-inch, 1024&#215;768 e-ink plastic screen. It&#8217;s 0.7mm thick, it weighs 14g, and LG claims it&#8217;s resistant to scratches and drops from a 1.5 meter height. Of course, its biggest claim to fame is its flexibility: LG claims the screen allows bending at a range of 40 degrees from its center. &#8220;With the world&#8217;s first plastic EPD, LG Display has once again proven its reputation for leadership and innovation with a product we believe will help greatly popularize the E-Book market,&#8221; said Sang Duck Yeo, Head of Operations for LG Display&#8217;s Mobile/OLED division. There is no word on a US release, but LG says the EPD will first be supplied to ODM companies in China, with completed products hitting European shores at the beginning of April. More About: e-paper, LGFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/lg-e-paper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/lg-e-paper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes of the World&#8217;s First Live-Tweeted Open-Heart Surgery</title>
      <description>Doctors at Houston&#8217;s Memorial Hermann Northwest Hospital made medical and social media history last month by live-tweeting an open heart surgery for the first time ever. Dr. Michael Macris performed a double-coronary artery bypass on a 57-year-old patient. Meanwhile, colleague Dr. Paresh Patel provided 140-character updates throughout the procedure, and answered questions submitted by followers of the hospital&#8217;s @houstonhospital Twitter account. Dr. Macris also wore a video camera attached to his head. Dr. Patel snapped additional photos, and posted some of the pictures and videos to Twitter. The procedure lasted two and a half hours, and the patient made it through fine. More than anything, though, the feat is a powerful example of social media&#8217;s ability to connect people and shed light on even the most unexpected activities. Its success is a lesson in using creativity and digital innovation to educate mass audiences. &#8220;We&#8217;re always becoming more connected as a society,&#8221; says Gary Kerr, CEO of the non-profit Memorial Hermann Healthcare System, which includes Northwest Hospital. &#8220;Information can&#8217;t be contained anymore, and that&#8217;s the most positive thing about the Internet.&#8221; Hospital staff expected a modest amount of attention, but were surprised to see the event blow up online. Natalie Camarata, Memorial Hermann Healthcare System&#8217;s digital marketing manager, told Mashable the event delivered an estimated 125 million impressions through Twitter, Storify and media coverage in the weeks following the operation. Since the surgery, Mashable interviewed several of the people involved in the groundbreaking idea, asking them what it means that social media can be leveraged in new, effective ways. We spoke with Dr. Macris, Dr. Patel, Kerr, Camarata and Beth Sartori, a Memorial Hermann marketing and communications executive. What follows is their inside story. Pulling Back a Curtain Memorial Hermann has embraced digital technology for the past several years. It has also hosted more than 50 webinars over the past year, and this week hosted a live social media-broadcasted Q&amp;A about colonoscopies for Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month. The live-tweeted open-heart surgery was born from that spirit of using technology to educate. Camarata: We were talking about what we could do for Heart Month. Last year we did something where you could share a glass of red wine with someone online, but we wanted to take it farther. So we came up with the Twitter-cast idea to pull back the curtain on something that happens every day in all of our hospitals. Sartori: We already had a social media policy in place, but this wasn&#8217;t exactly addressed specifically because it had never been done before. We got risk management and hospital executives [to approve] it. It&#8217;s a little bit different from just getting a news camera in the operating room. But it didn&#8217;t take a lot of arm twisting with Dr. Macris. Dr. Macris: When Natalie told us all about the Twitter idea, we all thought it would be a pretty straightforward thing, not a big deal in terms of the attention it got. I said, &#8220;How many people are we talking about following along?&#8221; They said, &#8220;Oh, maybe 50 or 100.&#8221; Kerr: Once they told me that had a process in place for the 1% chance something got more complicated in the procedure, I felt comfortable for it to go forward. Preparing for a Social Media First Once hospital executives signed off on the plan, the team had to find a willing patient and figure out how exactly they would pull the thing off. Turns out, it wasn&#8217;t as complicated as they predicted: A patient of cardiologist Dr. Patel agreed to have his operation broadcast for the world to see. Camarata: People on Twitter expects things to be instantaneous, in the moment. Twitter is now, so it&#8217;s the perfect medium to use, and you can add Twitpics and videos. So that&#8217;s why we chose that vehicle. Dr. Patel was the patient&#8217;s cardiologist and works directly with Dr. Macris, so it was a natural fit. He was very interested and excited about the opportunity and more than happy to take some online questions. Dr. Patel: I&#8217;ve done lectures and sessions for the public for Heart Month, but that was a much more limited number of people to reach. This way, you&#8217;re able to reach a lot more people. Kerr: People don&#8217;t just show up to the hospital and ask for treatment these days. They want to ask a lot of questions and know more about what&#8217;s happening with their bodies. This medium starts to address that. It&#8217;s a different thing, but it&#8217;s the right thing. Camarata: There was no dry run. We tested Dr. Macris&#8217;s helmet camera a few times but there was no dry run. Dr. Macris: This was an operation we perform so commonly that we know statistically we have a 99.9% confidence level it&#8217;s going to be fine. We didn&#8217;t want to do a high risk, complex case with any chance of the patient being compromised. It was the basketball equivalent of a slam dunk. But at the same time, you couldn&#8217;t take someone off the street and say, &#8220;Hey, go do this operation.&#8221; Anytime we do a heart surgery, it&#8217;s true that if we make a mistake someone could die as a direct consequence. Under the Knife Once the operation and social media broadcast began, it quickly became apparent the Memorial Hermann team had hit a home run. Dr. Macris: I have to be honest, I had no clue what was going on. I was just doing my regular operations. At the time I had no idea what was going on beyond that. Sartori: I was surprised at how much interest in generated from moment it started. That was the best part, generating so much awareness and interest right away. Dr. Patel: I was surprised how many questions were coming in, and how much people already knew. Keeping the answers short was a little bit hard. There were restraints, but it wasn&#8217;t too bad. Kerr: The patient&#8217;s sister was sitting right there while Dr. Patel answered questions. I asked if she was nervous. She said, &#8220;Yeah, but this is great. Normally I&#8217;d be sitting in a room by myself wondering what&#8217;s happening with my brother. Now I&#8217;m watching what&#8217;s happening and following along, so in some ways it&#8217;s much better.&#8221; Aftermath The event attracted media attention from around the world. Dr. Patel&#8217;s tweets were translated for readers as far away as Azerbaijan, India and China. Kerr: Dr. Macris is Greek, and he&#8217;s been telling me about all these people in Greece watching it and all the comments he&#8217;s gotten from the other side of the world. Dr. Macris: A lot of people were asking me if I was actually doing the tweeting. I always laugh &#8212; no, was just doing the operation. But I believe it was a resounding success. The only downside is I know a lot of people were kind of kicking themselves later. How did some solo practitioner in a community hospital garner all this attention? As opposed to really big hospitals, major medical centers, things like that. Sartori: The biggest goal was to educate and raise awareness. That definitely happened, so from that standpoint it was a huge success. Camarata: A few hospital systems have tweeted us back congratulations and things like that. A few have reached out to us for more on the mechanics of how it worked. Dr. Macris: I would predict that similar things start happening more and more. Social media will be taken much more seriously by academia. It&#8217;s an incredibly powerful way to communicate with people. So to say that I think we&#8217;ll see more and more things like this would be a very easy prediction to make. More About: features, medicine, Social Good, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/live-tweeted-open-heart-surgery/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/live-tweeted-open-heart-surgery/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turn Your Tweets Into Toilet Paper &#8212; for $35 a Pack</title>
      <description>Last year Bill Gates announced plans to revolutionize the toilet. Now one startup is attempting to revolutionize toilet paper -&#8211; by putting tweets on it. The service, called Shitter, will take one or more feeds from your Twitter account and print those tweets on toilet paper you can then display and use proudly in your favorite restroom. The company&#8217;s tagline: &#8220;Social Media has never been so disposable.&#8221; Shitter allows you to have a roll printed with your own personal tweets, your timeline, favorites, or tweets from a specific list you&#8217;ve created or follow on Twitter. If there&#8217;s someone on Twitter you think has particularly crappy things to say, you can opt to have his or her feed printed on a few rolls. Priced for use in high-end powder rooms, Shitter rolls are priced at $35 for a pack of four. That, you may reasonably surmise, is money down the drain. Mashable did the math, and if Shitter&#8217;s rolls of TP have the standard 75 sheets you&#8217;d be shelling out about 8.5 cents a sheet to drop your latest tweets off at the pool. Shitter isn&#8217;t the first company out there to make custom toilet paper, although they are the first to focus on taking Twitter to the toilet. Another company, simply called Custom Printed Toilet Paper also offers the ability to gift the &#8220;world&#8217;s crappiest&#8221; gift by having a toilet paper printed up with a favorite logo, picture, or phrase. What do you think about tweeting on TP? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. Please, no typing in the bathroom. More About: startup, Toilet, TwitterFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/shitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/shitter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Photos Slip Through Great Firewall, Arrive in China</title>
      <description>China notoriously blocks access to social networking sites Facebook, Twitter and YouTube. Now a startup, FamilyLeaf, has found a break in the Great Firewall &#8212; allowing Chinese families to get a glimpse at the Facebook photos of their loved ones. FamilyLeaf co-founder Wesley Zhao says he can feel how censorship affects his family in China. Virtual Private Networks provide access for some privileged Chinese Internet users, though the majority are restricted. &#8220;Lots of Chinese American families have been disconnected by the Great Firewall of China,&#8221; Zhao told Mashable. &#8220;FamilyLeaf isn&#8217;t something the government would worry about, as it&#8217;s just for family. It&#8217;s a perfect way for people to connect, even if some of their family&#8217;s content is on Facebook or other blocked sites. &#8221; While the Chinese government blocks Facebook&#8217;s main domain, user photos are stored on a separate content delivery network (CDN). Because of these separate CDNs, FamilyLeaf users can share photos directly from their Facebook albums, without an addition upload. Zhao&#8217;s family loves the hundreds of his photos they can now see and he enjoys seeing their photos he has missed because he&#8217;s not active on Chinese social networks. SEE ALSO: Beyond the Great Firewall: How China Does Social Networking [INFOGRAPHIC] &#8220;We don&#8217;t think the Chinese government did this by accident,&#8221; Zhao says. &#8220;The Facebook photos CDN is still available because the government is concerned about people organizing protests. Photos are not going to rile up protests.&#8221; The site, which launched Tuesday, functions as a private directory for families, much like a mini-social network. You can share Facebook, Flickr, Picasa and Instagram photos, write on a family message board, and store contact information in the closed forum. FamilyLeaf wasn&#8217;t started with the intention of connecting Chinese families specifically. Co-founder Ajay Mehta&#8217;s father keeps lists of relatives&#8217; contact information strewn around his house. The startup&#8217;s primary goal is to connect families separated by distance. &#8220;Most kids don&#8217;t want to friend their parents and lots of parents go on Facebook exclusively to share baby photos,&#8221; Zhao says. &#8220;The general purpose of FamilyLeaf is to help families connect in a very private way.&#8221; Once they discovered Facebook photos could be shared with Chinese Internet users, the site has taken on a new life. Zhao&#8217;s father quickly translated the site into Chinese, to optimize its utility for users in China. Before officially launching, FamilyLeaf has received significant international attention, receiving press in China, France and Italy, and active users in India, Israel, and Greece. FamilyLeaf has no immediate plans to become profitable. Zhao says it won&#8217;t take advertising, which he feels would detract from the site&#8217;s authenticity. The company would look into services that will add value within the context of the family, such as planning family reunions or sending cards. Would you try FamilyLeaf to keep in touch with your family? Do you think the Chinese government will continue to allow Facebook photos to come through the Great Firewall? Image of Wesley Zhao&#8217;s niece Mumu, courtesy of the Zhao family More About: china, Great Firewall of China, Startups, World</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/china-firewall-family-leaf/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/29/china-firewall-family-leaf/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Likes: How Google and Adobe Aim to Measure Your True Social ROI</title>
      <description>Measuring marketing spending used to be pretty easy, at least in theory: You&#8217;d run a big ad campaign and then see if your sales rose. If they did, great. If not, then you wasted your money. Social media has muddied the waters. A campaign may not do much for sales, but it might add a million Facebook fans or garner an impressive number of retweets. Does that mean you spent your money effectively? Over the past month, Google and Adobe have attempted to answer that question. Both companies have released tools that let marketers track their marketing spend through social media. Such data aims to provide some concrete ROI behind the touchy-feely world of Likes, retweets and +1s &#8212; data that, on its own, amount to what Phil Mui, group product manager for Google Analytics, dubs &#8220;vanity metrics.&#8221; Adobe Social Adobe, best known for design software such as Photoshop, is attempting to boost its credibility as a marketing services provider with Adobe Social. The tool, which is part of the Adobe Online Digital Suite, offers data from Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Google+. The latest version of Social, which was introduced earlier this month at a conference in Salt Lake City (see picture above, featuring director Jeff Jordan, senior product manager or social media), is an update of Adobe SocialAnalytics, which was launched in March 2011. Since that time, Adobe has purchased Efficient Frontier, a firm best known as a buyer and seller of ads on Facebook. The company has tapped that expertise for the latest version. Aseem Chandra, VP of marketing for the Adobe Digital Marketing Business, says SocialAnalytics lets you track activity on those social media platforms and then take note of users who wind up on your website. If you sell something on your site, it can connect that activity to sales. The product was just released to the public on March 9, but Adobe has been working with a handful of brands for the past few months in a pilot program. Among those brands is Expedia, the online travel firm, which ran a promotion in April 2011 called FriendTrips. The promo dangled $1 million in prizes. Participants entered to win one of 13 luxury vacations. However, you were required to RSVP five friends for each entry. Chandra says the effort netted Expedia 1 million new Facebook fans. By calculating the money spent on the promotion, $1 million, and the 750% increase in fans, SocialAnalytics reckoned that the cost-per-fan fell 4.5 times compared to previous campaigns. Users can also get data like fan demographics, likes and shares via SocialAnalytics. Such information will cost you. Chandra declined to get specific, but said access costs &#8220;tens of thousands&#8221; of dollars, meaning it&#8217;s an option for some small- to medium-size businesses, but not mom-and-pops. Google Analytics A little more than a week after Adobe released SocialAnalytics, Google announced Social reports, an addition to Google Analytics that attempts to show a causal relationship between social media activity and sales. There are three major differences between Adobe&#8217;s and Google&#8217;s solution: 1. Google&#8217;s is free. 2. Facebook and Twitter do not provide data. 3. The data completely revolves around your website. If you&#8217;ve used Google Analytics, you know that you can already see if recent traffic has been referred from one of the social networks. Google has expanded on that. Now, you can also see if someone interacted with your site days, weeks or months ago and then returned &#8212; a conversion that Google calls &#8220;assisted.&#8221; Google also lets you place a monetary value on such interactions, though that&#8217;s somewhat subjective. If your site allows for direct sales, then figuring out that figure is easy enough. Otherwise, Google suggests you quantify each conversion. That can get tricky if you sell, for instance, cars, since merely visiting your site doesn&#8217;t necessarily equal a sale. The assisted conversions are also subjective. Chandra lets marketers set their time frame. If someone on Facebook clicked on a link six months ago and then went back and bought something today, is that old interaction valuable? Google says it is if you think it is. The lack of Facebook and Twitter metrics may also be an issue, but maybe not as much as you think. Perhaps you don&#8217;t want to dive into all the Likes and People Talking About metrics and just see in broad brush strokes how many people came from your site via Facebook. However, Google&#8217;s wealth of data for participating networks (the company claims about 20, including, of course, Google+), may make you wish Facebook and Twitter were cooperating. For instance, if you see a bump in traffic from Google+, now you can call up actual conversations behind it. You can dig even deeper and identify your most influential users as well. Is This Helpful? Such data is attractive to marketers. If nothing else, it provides an answer to company bean counters&#8217; questions about social media ROI. But are they useful for creating new social media marketing campaigns? Brian Solis, principal of Altimeter Group, says better metrics don&#8217;t address the fact that most marketers launch social media campaigns without a clear goal in mind. &#8220;If you want to optimize Facebook&#8217;s contribution to sales, you have to design that at the front end,&#8221; says Solis, who recently completed a study looking at how influencers actually spread social media messages. He recommends creating programs that provide some value to such influencers and people connected to them. He also suggests defining what success looks like before you launch your program. Since social media is still relatively new, that may be a tough task for marketers. One alternative is to try various things in social media and then track the results. Given the dynamic nature of social media and the mind-boggling number of variables involved with each campaign, isolating the elements that made a campaign successful might be tough. All of which is why Google&#8217;s and Adobe&#8217;s new metrics might provide greater visibility into marketing done via social media, yet still can&#8217;t offer straightforward results. When it comes to the question of social media marketing ROI, the answer is still that old Facebook standard: It&#8217;s complicated. Adobe Social: Set Up This slide shows how it might look at the beginning of a campaign, with various stated goals. Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, michellegibson More About: adobe, Business, features, Google, google analytics, Social Media, social media marketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/google-adobe-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/google-adobe-social-media/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest Spammer Makes $30,000 in a Month</title>
      <description>A 24-year-old man who calls himself &#8220;Steve&#8221; makes more than $1,000 per day pinning Amazon product links on Pinterest, one of 2012&#8242;s hottest social networks. Taking advantage of the startup&#8217;s fast growth and optimal user demographics &#8212; consisting mostly of brand-savvy women with an annual household income of more than $100,000 and a love of shopping &#8212; spammers are making huge amounts of money just by pinning items to Pinterest and directing consumers to make purchases on Amazon. The Daily Dot published an interview with Pinterest spammer Steve after exposing an underground community of spammers targeting the hot site. On Amazon, he uses various accounts including the name &#8220;final-fantas07.&#8221; At one time, thousands of his spambots are sharing posts on Pinterest. He showcases products to the Pinterest community, appealing especially to women, who repin posts and buy items linked to Steve&#8217;s Amazon accounts. &#8220;Pinterest is by FAR the easiest social network to spam right now,&#8221; Steve told The Daily Dot. &#8220;Quite possibly the easiest ever to spam. It requires almost no work to get started and no money to invest. You just have to know how the system works and how you can fix it to your advantage.&#8221; He&#8217;s made up to $1,900 a day since he started spamming Feb. 20. The above image was Pinned with a link to Steve&#8217;s Amazon account, through which fake user &#8220;Nancy Nelon&#8221; only pins items from Amazon.com. The Pinterest account is also linked to a Twitter feed that bears no activity and a different first name. &#8220;I fully expect next week&#8217;s earnings to be $2,000 to $2,500 a day. There are no guarantees in this business and it could all come crashing down soon,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Not a matter of if, but when will it happen.&#8221; Out of Steve&#8217;s collection of fake accounts, he says, Pinterest has only deleted one. Pinterest acknowledges it is working on minimizing the spam users see. In a statement sent to Mashable on behalf of the company, the company said: As a growing service, Pinterest is not immune to challenges faced by sites across the web, including spam. However, it is a tremendous priority for us to quickly address them. Our engineers are actively working to manage issues as they arise and are revisiting the nature of public feeds on the site to make it harder for fake or harmful content to get into them. SEE ALSO: Pinterest Scams on the Rise: Protect Yourself [PICS] 4 Tips for Avoiding Pinterest Spam: Avoid repinning or clicking on pins that use logos of big brands, but aren&#8217;t affiliated with any official accounts: These links open up to windows that ask you to repin to win unofficial contests, like this: If a pin is advertises a free gift card and the source looks fishy, avoid clicking. Avoid pins that aren&#8217;t sourced and link to suspicious websites. And, don&#8217;t repin items from Pinterest users with extraordinarily weird user names and Pinterest accounts with no description or picture. Will spam prevent you from using Pinterest or making purchases through pins? Tell us in the comments. Image courtesy of Flickr, Cayusa More About: pinterest, scam</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/pinterest-amazon-spam/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/pinterest-amazon-spam/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook to Halt Trading of Shares in Secondary Market This Week [REPORT]</title>
      <description>Facebook will halt trading of its shares on secondary markets this week, Bloomberg reports. We're told that bankers close to the deal are expecting the public offering to come in May. Click here for updates to this post....</description>
      <link>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2012/03/28/businessinsiderthe-ipo-is-comingfac.DTL</link>
      <guid>http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/g/a/2012/03/28/businessinsiderthe-ipo-is-comingfac.DTL</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wind Map of the U.S. Will Blow You Away</title>
      <description>Ever wondered what the wind would look like if you could see it in action from above? You&#8217;re about to find out. A new project posted online Wednesday by a pair of Google computer scientists, called simply Wind Map, has to be clicked on to be believed. The wind information, updated hourly from the National Weather Service&#8217;s forecast database, is portrayed as white and grey strands, almost like sand or rivulets of mercury. It can be quite hypnotizing to watch the gusty trails blast across the American continent, skitter over the Sierras, get roughed up by the Rockies, and whoosh over the great plains on its way to Canada. (Which seems to give as good as it gets, sending most of its wind towards New York.) Wind patterns are constantly changing, of course, which is why the Wind Map designers have also given us a moving-image gallery of previous blustery days. Wind Map is the brainchild of Fernanda Vi&#233;gas and Martin Wattenberg, the co-leaders of Google&#8217;s &#8220;Big Picture&#8221; visualization research group in Cambridge, Mass. The pair have previously visualized Wikipedia and Google searches. No word on whether we&#8217;ll see the Wind Map in Google Earth any time soon, but the pair do say they want to expand it to the planet &#8212; and are looking for any source of global wind information. What do you make of the Wind Map? Is this something you&#8217;d like to see more of? Does it change how you think of the potential for wind energy, as its creators hope? Let us know you thoughts in the comments. More About: data visualization, GoogleFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/wind-map/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/wind-map/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips for Raising Money on Kickstarter</title>
      <description>Rusel DeMaria is the author of more than 60 books, and currently runs the High Score 3 Kickstarter project. Follow him on Twitter @DeMaria. Double Fine, the game developer, raised $3.3 million for its adventure game, Double Fine Adventures. InXile, a game development company, made $500,000 in 17 hours for its role-playing game, Wasteland 2. Both did it on Kickstarter, the world&#8217;s largest funding platform for creative projects. Naturally, it would be easy to think of Kickstarter as a virtual Gold Rush. That would be a mistake. SEE ALSO: How to Crowdfund Your Next Big Idea Kickstarter has its challenges. Even as a successful participant, I&#8217;ve hit some bumps along the way. The lessons I&#8217;ve learned from this experience are worth observing. If you&#8217;re looking to get funded on Kickstarter, here are ten tips to help you succeed. 1. Do Your Research Not every project will work on Kickstarter, and even fewer will create a feeding frenzy. So do your research. Observe, for example, what has worked and what hasn&#8217;t for other project creators. To find successful examples, look at sections of the site such as &#8220;Staff Picks&#8221; or &#8220;Popular.&#8221; To find projects that have not hit their goals, look at some of those under &#8220;Ending Soon.&#8221; Obviously, projects succeed and fail for different reasons, but researching examples of each will help you get a feel for what to do and what to avoid. 2. Define Your Goal Decide exactly what you want to accomplish and how much money you need to do that. Remember, if you don&#8217;t meet your goal, you get nothing. Better to ask a reasonable amount and then work hard to exceed that goal. Double Fine initially asked for $400,000, but blew that out of the water. If possible, have at least a group of friends who will support you with pledges from the get-go. That will help you build momentum. And remember, you cannot change the amount after you launch. Also, think about how long your project should run. Kickstarter recommends a maximum of 30 days, but some people have succeeded with longer cycles. Consider your audience and how long it will take to get the word out when making this decision. As with the funding amount, you can&#8217;t change your project length once it&#8217;s set. 3. Consider Your Rewards and Costs You&#8217;ll quickly learn that people want something in exchange for their pledges. Create rewards, gifts to backers based on the amount they pledge, starting at low values, like $5. That way you can reward even small-time backers. Double Fine is a good example of a project that created great rewards tailored to their audience. Their lowest reward was a digital copy of the game for $15. The highest was a private party with the developers for $10,000. Another critical factor to consider when creating rewards are related costs. For example, if you&#8217;re going to send your backers something by mail, calculate the postage and packaging you&#8217;ll need. Don&#8217;t get blindsided and discover that your costs will cancel out a part of your funding. 4. Prepare Your Pitch How you introduce your project can make a huge difference. On your project page you&#8217;ll describe your project, goals, and rewards. Be specific and include engaging images of your work. Kickstarter recommends that you also create a video. Make it fun, natural, and compelling by including key elements like people talking about how great or important the project is. Remember, your pitch should pump people up about your project and show both your enthusiasm and your ability to follow through. 5. Market the Hell Out of It Once you&#8217;ve pulled the trigger and published your project, it&#8217;s time to promote via social media, friends, family, even strangers. Any updates you post will automatically be sent to your current backers, but urge them to re-post and re-tweet. If you can find a way to make your work newsworthy, pitch popular websites and newspapers. 6. Keep It Alive Your initial marketing may bring you some early success, but you need to keep feeding the fire. Find ways to update the project. Add new and fun rewards as you go. Keep people informed about your progress, and definitely share any good news or milestones like &#8220;We&#8217;re halfway there!&#8221; 7. Listen to Your Backers Many of your backers will offer advice. Listen. Some of them have backed many projects and know what works. Others just have an opinion, and even if you don&#8217;t agree, consider how many other people &#8212; potential investors &#8212; may think the same way. 8. Be Patient There will be times when pledges seem to flow in steadily, and times when it seems that nobody cares. When this happens, you&#8217;ll need to stay positive and re-engage those who got you this far. Start by letting your biggest supporters know it&#8217;s time to step up and spread the word. If they&#8217;ve backed the project, then they also want it to succeed. 9. Be Flexible and Creative Be prepared to do things you never anticipated doing. You hadn&#8217;t considered a special T-shirt as a reward? Maybe you should. A supporter offers to create limited-edition rewards to help your project? Why not? Bottom line: Be open and flexible. 10. Have Fun This is going to be a crazy ride so enjoy it. And remember, if at first you don&#8217;t succeed&#8230;. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, Draco77 More About: contributor, crowd-funding, features, kickstarter, StartupsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/raising-money-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/03/28/raising-money-kickstarter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
