<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>55 Digital Media Resources You May Have Missed</title>
      <description>Maybe you were too busy hunting down celebrities on the new video chat service, Airtime. Better yet, maybe you were using it to land a job. For whatever reason, you missed out on some of Mashable's features coverage this week, and that simply won't do. Thankfully, we've rounded up the top resources in social media, business and tech to catch you back up to speed. We've continued our series of beginners' guides with cheat sheets on Twitter and Reddit. And in a week of password-hacking mania, we've got tips for ensuring that your LinkedIn and eHarmony profiles stay safe and secure. Be sure to check out our Google search tips and keyboard shortcuts, the latest episodes of our web ser&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Business, COMMUNICATIONS, Features Week In Review, Social Media, Tech</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/digital-media-resources-43/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/digital-media-resources-43/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FSocialMedia+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Social+Media+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now There Are More Internet Addresses Than Stars in the Universe</title>
      <description>Long story short: After this week's switchover to a new protocol called IPv6, there are a whole lot of IP addresses on the Internet now. How many more? Just one day after the world wide web made a permanent and forever change on Wednesday, CNN reported the Internet now has 340 trillion trillion trillion unique addresses. That's 340 undecillion. We knew the switch from IPv4 to IPv6 would make a bunch of new addresses available. But this is a growth of 79 octillion (billion billion billion), according to the report. But we have no frames of reference for a number that large, so let's put it into context for a moment. 340 trillion trillion trillion is: More than the numb&#8230; Continue reading... More About: internet, IP addresses, IPv4, IPv6</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/now-there-are-more-internet-addresses-than-stars-in-the-universe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/07/now-there-are-more-internet-addresses-than-stars-in-the-universe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silencing the bell doesn't put out the fire</title>
      <description>Many big organizations have full-time employees who scan the social media, looking for people with a complaint. They swoop in and grease the squeaky wheel, solving the problem of the person who spoke up. The theory is that these loud complainers are a problem, and the easiest solution is to give them something to make them happy. Of course, that doesn't do anything for the 95% of the population that has the very same problem but isn't speaking up, right? When Jeff Jarvis blogged about Dell Hell, he hurt the company very badly. Mollifying Jeff (and those like him) did the company no good in the long run, though, because they didn't deal with the underlying cause, they merely gave the loud ones an excuse to be quiet. The purpose of the bell is to point to a fire somewhere else. Worry about that instead.</description>
      <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/silencing-the-bell-doesnt-put-out-the-fire.html</link>
      <guid>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/06/silencing-the-bell-doesnt-put-out-the-fire.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Lead Nurturing Debuts, And Other Marketing Stories of the Week</title>
      <description>Gather round, inbound marketers. I have a story for you. Actually, I have like 5 stories for you. But I didn't write any of them -- these are the best stories from around the interwebs this week that you may have missed. Which is totally understandable, because holy cow do people pump out a lot of content these days (that's good though; keep doing that inbound marketers). Without further ado, here are the inbound marketing stories that tickled my fancy this week, and I think will help us all be better inbound marketers. And as always, share your own favorite industry stories with us in the comments! HootSuite Partners With HubSpot to Offer Social Media Lead Nurturing I had to start with this one, because it is so cool! We all use social media to generate traffic and leads; we spend time and effort nurturing those leads to become customers; then we rely on closed-loop reporting to tell us how we did. Wouldn't it be great if all those activities were more integrated though, and you could actually monitor your very own leads' activity in social media so you can nurture them right then and there? You bet your buttons it would be -- which is why we at HubSpot partnered with HootSuite to make that possible. Read more about the partnership in this blog post! LinkedIn's Security Woes Pour Salt on Social Media's Exposed Wounds From MarketingPilgrim By now you probably know about LinkedIn's security breach in which 65 million passwords were leaked. If not, well, go change your password and then come back. Everything good? Awesome. Frank Reed at MarketingPilgrim took the coverage a step further with an insightful assessment of the state of the social media security union. He believes security is at the crux of social media's success and you can read the post to learn why some current social media giants should invest in it lest they meet an eventual demise. Google Finally Takes a Clear Stance on Mobile SEO Practices From Search Engine Land We've talked a lot about the importance of investing in mobile marketing; and I think most inbound marketers are already sold on how critical a strong organic search presence is. This article from Barry Schwartz helps us bridge the gap between the two with his report on Google's official stance on mobile SEO. It's not that the topic of mobile SEO hasn't been covered before -- but this time, it comes straight from the horse's mouth. The 2012 Shopping Behavior Insights Study From Parago Marketers waffle back and forth on what really motivates shoppers to buy. If you have a great brand experience, will that trump cheaper prices from a competitor? Just how much of a role do coupons and discounts play in the buyer's decision-making process? Their importance may be bigger than you think (they were bigger than I anticipated, at least). Take a look at that and other insights in Parago's newly published study with data-backed insights on shoppers' behaviors. Don't Like Snake Oil? Stop Buying It From SEOmoz To be clear, SEOmoz isn't selling snake oil. That header is a tad misleading. (On a side note, maybe we should start adding commas into these headings well, next week is another week.) Now that that's cleared up, Dr. Pete at SEOmoz comes to the defense of SEOs everywhere who have been given a bad name, usually by people who don't really know what SEO is. Or, by all those grey- and black-hat people who call themselves legitimate SEOs (tsk, tsk). This post tells everyone who practices SEO how to stop feeding into the stereotype by being well-informed and learning how to work well with clients and bosses who are demanding results in the SERPs. What else happened in marketing this week that we should know about? Image credit: BiblioArchives / LibraryArchives</description>
      <link>http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/33191/Social-Media-Lead-Nurturing-Debuts-And-Other-Marketing-Stories-of-the-Week.aspx?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+HubSpot+%28HubSpot%29</link>
      <guid>http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/33191/Social-Media-Lead-Nurturing-Debuts-And-Other-Marketing-Stories-of-the-Week.aspx?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+HubSpot+%28HubSpot%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Marketing Company Helps Clients Come Up First in Search Engine Searches</title>
      <description>Internet Marketing Company, one of the most trusted search engine marketing firms, polled people on the question "If Not For Google, Which Search Engine Would You Prefer Using?" on the Facebook&#174; Platform. The possible choices were Yahoo!, Bing, and Ask.com. The number one answer was Bing. The internet marketing agency, which provides internet marketing services, has allowed people interested in SEO services to visit the page, read about the company and then to click "Like" on the Facebook Platform page to be able to follow the company's news or mention the company in one of their posts. Users who have logged onto the page to check out what the search engine marketing company is all about have seen that they provide internet search engine marketing services, link building services along with reputation management and other services. Pinterest's goal is to connect everyone in the world through the 'things' they find interesting. They think that a favorite book, toy or recipe can reveal a common link between two people. With millions of new pins added every week, Pinterest is connecting people all over the world based on shared tastes and interests. Facebook gives everyone the power to share with the people they care about, making the world more open and transparent. Facebook users communicate and share information through the social graph, the network of connections and relationships between people. Facebook gives companies and the developer community access to the social graph through Facebook Platform. Using a rich set of tools and online services, developers can build applications that are deeply integrated into the Facebook website. Millions of Facebook users return to the site each day, providing unparalleled distribution potential for applications and the opportunity to build a business that is highly relevant to people's lives. In 2007, Facebook launched Facebook Platform to empower developers and entrepreneurs around the world make the Web more social for users. Millions of Facebook users return to the site each day, providing unparalleled distribution potential for applications and the opportunity to build a business that is highly relevant to people's lives. Internet Marketing Company delivers effective and cost-effective SEO services that help companies compete and attract new customers driven by listings among the top search engine results. Professionals at the Internet Marketing Company have the expertise and experience to enhance exposure of a business on major search engines. And the better a brand&#8217;s exposure, the better a company can reach the customers and prospects who rely on search engines every day to research, find, and buy new products and services. With SEO from Internet Marketing Company, everyone can see results&#8212;fast, easy, and guaranteed. Facebook&#174; is a registered trademark of Facebook Inc.</description>
      <link>http://www.prweb.com/releases/searchengineoptimization/internetmarketingagency/prweb9569423.htm</link>
      <guid>http://www.prweb.com/releases/searchengineoptimization/internetmarketingagency/prweb9569423.htm</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Mobile Payments: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Simplifies Mobile Payments: Facebook has made it easier for developers to add payment options on mobile web apps. And marketers also now have the option of buying mobile-only Facebook ads.The new Facebook flow for mobile payments requires no typing and looks like this.HootSuite Partners With HubSpot to Offer Social Media Lead Nurturing #ClosedLoopSocial: &#8220;The HubSpot/HootSuite integration, available for any HubSpot customer who also uses HootSuite&#8217;s professional or enterprise software, will make it easier for customers to use social media to better work their leads and make the close.&#8221;HootSuite users can now join the HubSpot app beta program to access their HubSpot data inside the HootSuite dashboard.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:What&#8217;s your favorite Google Analytics how-to resource?How do you structure pricing for a social media consulting business?How participating in the Networking Clubs is bringing traffic to one member&#8217;s blogTwitter Logo Takes Flight: Twitter simplified its bluebird logo. Check out the updated guidelines and new image downloads on the Twitter brand resources page.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fh20pdCrCAUThe All-New Foursquare App Is Here: &#8220;This isn&#8217;t just a fresh coat of paint, it&#8217;s a whole new app.&#8221; Foursquare&#8217;s new app focuses on recommending places for you to go. .Try the New Disqus 2012: Current Disqus users can request an invite. &#8220;Disqus 2012 makes it easier than ever for commenters to find interesting conversations and communities all over the web.&#8221; .Pinterest Is Now Also Available in Spanish: Spanish-speaking users can now use Pinterest in Spanish. There&#8217;s a tab to change language preferences on the top right corner of the site.You can also change language preferences when you edit your profile.LinkedIn Advises Users to Change Passwords: Following last week&#8217;s reports of stolen LinkedIn passwords, it&#8217;s recommended all LinkedIn users change their passwords.LinkedIn Updates Privacy Policy: LinkedIn&#8217;s latest update shortens the time LinkedIn keeps personally identifiable information obtained through plugins to 24 hours. And users now have enhanced controls over what information can be accessed outside LinkedIn by search engines and third parties.Here&#8217;s a social media tool worth noting:Amara: A tool to put captions on your videos and translate them too. .And don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-mobile-payments-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-mobile-payments-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the UFC Ran the Most Successful Spotify Campaign in History</title>
      <description>Long since a knockout on social media, the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) landed another social haymaker recently by running the most successful branded Spotify campaign to date. In fact, no other contest even comes close to matching the UFC's results -- according to Spotify representatives this week, the UFC promotion attracted about four time as many votes as any previous campaign on the platform. (Both UFC and Spotify declined to specify how many votes that totaled.) So what was the contest? The UFC has a reality show and mixed martial arts competition called The Ultimate Fighter, in which a field of combatants compete for a pro contract with the league. For the season final&#8230; Continue reading... More About: sports, spotify, ufc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/ufc-spotify/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/ufc-spotify/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the UFC Ran the Most Successful Spotify Campaign in History</title>
      <description>Long since a knockout on social media, the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) landed another social haymaker recently by running the most successful branded Spotify campaign to date. In fact, no other contest even comes close to matching the UFC's results -- according to Spotify representatives this week, the UFC promotion attracted about four time as many votes as any previous campaign on the platform. (Both UFC and Spotify declined to specify how many votes that totaled.) So what was the contest? The UFC has a reality show and mixed martial arts competition called The Ultimate Fighter, in which a field of combatants compete for a pro contract with the league. For the season final&#8230; Continue reading... More About: sports, spotify, ufc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/ufc-spotify/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/ufc-spotify/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Amazon Saves a Ton of Money [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>With $48.1 billion in net sales last year, Amazon is certainly the leading Internet retailer. But how does the company fare in other areas, such as employee satisfaction and corporate social responsibility? Not so well, according to an infographic from MBAOnline, a website that curates business information from the top minds in the blogosphere. In fact, Amazon seems to put saving money ahead of many other priorities. For example, on a 102-degree day in June 2011, 15 workers in an Amazon warehouse collapsed from the lack of air conditioning, six of whom needed to be rushed to the emergency room. And despite a $5 billion cash reserve, Amazon donates nothing to charities -- if an employe&#8230; Continue reading... More About: amazon, Business, ecommerce, infographics</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/amazon-money-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/09/amazon-money-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Kickstarter Champs Share the Secrets of Their Success</title>
      <description>This post originally appeared on the American Express OPEN Forum, where Mashable regularly contributes articles about leveraging social media and technology in small business. Watching your product come to life through public support after pouring blood, sweat and tears into it is every entrepreneur's biggest dream. Kickstarter has become famous for making that a reality, serving as the birthplace of many now-thriving small businesses. [More from Mashable: 5 Things to Consider Before Self-Publishing Your Book] But just because Kickstarter has made it easier for you to raise awareness about a product doesn't mean that your campaign will be successfully funded. In fact, just assuming your product will be a hit with consumers and not taking intiatives before, during and after the project launch is a sure-fire way to fail. We spoke with some online entrepreneurs who found success on Kickstarter about what small businesses need to know before launching a campaign -- and what they wish they would've known before launching their own. [More from Mashable: Revolutionary Paper Scanner Folds Flat, Costs $15 on Kickstarter] Whether it's music, film, product design or other areas of entrepreneurship, these success stories could prove valuable for anyone thinking about launching a Kickstarter. Filmmaker Shaun Seneviratne found success on Kickstarter just two weeks before he started shooting How Will We Cross the Seas?, his short film project. Seneviratne set a small goal of $1,300 based on his budget and the $1,500 he'd be putting in himself. The project received $2,330 in funding. Musician Simon Joyner set a goal of $6,000 for his double album, Ghosts, to cover recording, mixing and manufacturing expenses. The funding nearly doubled his goal, garnering $11,862 from backers. Dave Petrillo asked for $9,500 for his product Coffee Joulies, a stone-shaped object that helps maintain your drink's temperature. The project was well-received, resulting in $306,944 from backers. Petrillo is now president of the Coffee Joulies company and is currently teaching classes on Skillshare. Jared Brickman pledged a $5,000 goal for his music project, One Hello World, a series of anonymous voicemails set to personal composition. He received $5,405 in funding and the website expanded, featuring some of the hundreds of voicemails received daily. Game designer Jason Rohrer created two-player strategy game Diamond Trust of London for Nintendo DS. The game was finished and approved by Nintendo, but Rohrer faced a manufacturing minimum with the company. Roher decided to put the game on Kickstarter to see how many would respond, asking for $78,715; the project was fully funded. "When I say, 'Know what your getting yourself into,' I'm actually urging you to take a real unemotional look at your ability to enjoy and run a project at a range of different scales. Start with the smallest the project could be to get you off the couch (this is how you set your goal) and then imagine at what point the project would take over your life, and what you would do about it. Try to break that up into more of a continuous spectrum and understand what that means to you personally." "I researched successful projects on Kickstarter to see what they had in common before designing my project -- that's really important. What I found was that having many options for rewards at many contribution levels was key. So, I went wild with the options, and it really paid off." "If you expect people to donate money to your project, especially if it's a film project, you should show them a film. It's important to make this connection with your prospective backers and show them either a video sample of what the project could be or a taste of your personality. Half the film's story is the filmmaker's story, and backers want to be a part of that story." -- Shaun Seneviratne, How Will We Cross the Seas? "Study the data! One of the most interesting aspects of Kickstarter is how transparent the whole thing is. They've obviously been gathering tons of data over the past three years, but unlike the other web-based spooks out there, they're not keeping the resulting insights a secret. Are you planning for "the trough" in the middle of your campaign? Should you make your campaign longer than 30 days? Which reward tiers should you focus the most effort on? The answers to all these questions are there in the data." "Detail out the budget for your project to determine what you'll need to raise in order to fulfill your needs. When you've established that figure, try to determine if you can realistically reach that fundraising goal with your online audience. If your need outstretches your expectations of what you can raise, consider lowering your Kickstarter goal and supplementing your budget through other means." "In my video game campaign, I planned up-front for only 1,000 Limited Edition versions to make them more special, but after those sold out, the remaining Kickstarter supporters felt left out. I had to scramble, mid-campaign, to devise some additional special rewards so that pledging felt worth it to people. Otherwise, why not just wait until the game comes out post-campaign and buy it then?" "I wish I had more content to share with my audience to drive buzz during my fundraising period. If I had my letter-pressed album covers and postcards during my campaign (rather than after), I think it would've made the project more tangible and driven more donations overall -- it certainly drove actual sales when I posted about it recently." "With respect to manufacturing, one of the best things we did was test early, often and in small batches. We scaled up production very steadily from a handful of units a week to more than 7,000 units per week over the course of 10 months. Since this was such an attention-suck, we didn't have the same approach to the marketing side of our business during the same period. We ultimately had another big learning curve when we transitioned from a Kickstarter project to a month-over-month business that has to go out and find its customers and sell to them just like every other company." "Despite raising more than my goal, I was still short. Given the amount we raised, I would've set the goal amount higher and hoped that we went above and beyond that amount. I would also reach out to websites and blogs that reflect the issues in the film. I also wish that I didn't start this two weeks before production. The day the Kickstarter ended was the first day of production -- and all the money was still with Kickstarter. It takes about two weeks for that money to get into your hands. I had to pay for everything out of pocket until the money came in." "Kickstarter's great, but don't let your project live or die by it! Find other sources of funds that will help you realize your dream. For many cases, there will always be the buzz and subsequent sales that follow a successful Kickstarter campaign." "Rewards are also really important. Not just what you choose as rewards, but the levels you set them at. I get so mad when I see people offering a DVD or download of the film at a very high level. Why should backers contributing $75 or more be the only ones that get to see your film? That seems really unfair to backers who can't afford to contribute more. It's annoyingly proprietary. Also, everyone with a project on Kickstarter is a creative person -- the rewards should reflect that creativity! Have it be in line with the theme of your project. Don't just offer a DVD and a t-shirt." "Kickstarter has helpful information on the site about what to consider before creating a project. All I really did beyond following Kickstarter's advice tips was to look at successful campaigns in my field, and build on the strengths of those projects. The great thing about Kickstarter is that past projects do not disappear after they are funded. You can search through a history of successful campaigns." "Using Kickstarter gives you two extremely useful things that you don't usually get elsewhere. First, your project gives you early and 100% real customer feedback. If your project went viral, you've got a hot idea on your hands. If your project raised $10 from mom, then you need to go back to the drawing board. Second, you get to use funds raised from customers in order to finance your growth. No debt, no equity. Having explained this starting point to investors and other startups for the past year has taught me just how exceptional and revolutionary it is. There is no better method out there." This story originally published on Mashable here.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/5-kickstarter-champs-share-secrets-success-160217107.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/5-kickstarter-champs-share-secrets-success-160217107.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Need a Quick Opinion? There&#8217;s An App For That</title>
      <description>Does this shirt go with these pants? Is the Galaxy S III a great phone? If you're looking for a quick opinion on something, there's now an app for that. Appropriately named "Thumb," the app lets you ask yes or no questions and get a thumbs up or down from the community. The app has been around since July 2010 and just launched version 3.0, which revamps the experience and adds a number of new features into the mix. "Anything you can potentially ask for an opinion of people did it, and that kind of blew us away," Thumb CEO Dan Kurani told Mashable about the app's early days. "We thought we were building a utility and we found out when we launched it that it's very much a social tool th&#8230; Continue reading... More About: App, Thumb</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/thumb-version-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/08/thumb-version-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>President Barack Obama &#8220;Sings&#8221; Call Me Maybe</title>
      <description>It&#8217;s the endlessly viral song that won&#8217;t seem to die. President Obama is the latest to join in on the &#8220;Call Me Maybe&#8221; trend. The President (presumably unknowingly) performs the song via a clever mashup from YouTube channel baracksdubs. Carly Rae Jepsen&#8217;s &#8220;Call Me Maybe&#8221; has taken on a life of its own and inspired multiple re-imaginings and spin-offs. The trend of college sports teams performing the crazy catchy song started with the Harvard baseball team. Soon, sports teams all over were joining in. SEE ALSO: Watch 11 Sports Teams Rock Out to &#8216;Call Me Maybe&#8217; [VIDEOS] Other memorable renditions included the quirky video from the Miss USA contestants and Donald Trump. There seems to be no end in sight for &#8220;Call Me Maybe.&#8221; How do you want to see the catchy pop song re-incarnated next? More About: barack obama, Call Me Maybe, Entertainment, Music, obamaFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/president-barack-obama-sings-call-me-maybe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/president-barack-obama-sings-call-me-maybe/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
