<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>20 Minimalist Backgrounds for a Simpler Desktop</title>
      <description>1. Vivid 2 A shock of color on a metallic gradient. Magnifique. By Alexander234.Click here to view this gallery.Allergic to desktop clutter? Minimalism is the cure. These 20 hand-selected illustrations will breathe some fresh color and life into your workflow, and will provide a clean space on which to pile your projects until you sweep them into the &#8220;done&#8221; folder. SEE ALSO: Top 10 Beautiful Minimalist Icon Sets What&#8217;s on your desktop screen right now? Share your favorite wallpapers in the comments below. More About: art, design, desktop wallpaper, features, wallpaperFor more Dev &amp; Design coverage:Follow Mashable Dev &amp; Design on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Dev &amp; Design channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/minimalist-desktop-wallpaper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/minimalist-desktop-wallpaper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Friday! Reuters Malaysia article on rapper 50 Cent automatically converts him into ringgit. http://t.co/ghwJW2vX via @ajaym14</title>
      <description>Michael Clemens: Happy Friday! Reuters Malaysia article on rapper 50 Cent automatically converts him into ringgit. http://t.co/ghwJW2vX via @ajaym14 &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://twitpic.com/9bwydd</link>
      <guid>http://twitpic.com/9bwydd</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips for Women in the Tech Industry</title>
      <description>Being a female entrepreneur in the male-dominated tech industry is challenging, and comes with a distinct set of barriers. Thankfully, there are several female-led organizations that are working to bring more women into the tech fold. I asked a panel of successful young female entrepreneurs from the Young Entrepreneur Council (YEC), an invite-only nonprofit organization comprised of the world&#8217;s most promising young entrepreneurs, what challenges women in tech face, and what could help eliminate some of those barriers? Here&#8217;s what they shared. 1. Women&#8217;s Organizations Help While women tend to be more relationship-oriented in general, I&#8217;ve found that networking our way into the inner circle of the tech world is not as easy for us. There are probably a number of reasons for this, but I believe organizations like Women 2.0 and Women in Technology will be instrumental in bridging that gap in the coming years. - Lisa Nicole Bell, Inspired Life Media Group 2. Sharing is Key Whether a woman is contemplating launching her first startup or simply considering registering for a course that will teach her to code, it&#8217;s so important that she share this with friends and colleagues. When these conversations between women don&#8217;t take place, the circle of women in tech grows at a much slower rate. Outside the tech world, there&#8217;s this perception that &#8220;only men are doing it.&#8221; But if we all talked about it more, I think that would give more women permission to dive in. - Amanda Aitken, The Girl&#8217;s Guide to Web Design 3. See the Glass as Half Full Despite the fact that we tell girls and women that any path is possible, there are still strong gender roles that reinforce the idea that women aren&#8217;t as good at STEM skills. The most important step we can take is to integrate these skills in the classroom as early as possible by showcasing successful female tech entrepreneurs. We also need to quit treating women in tech as a rarity, when numbers have grown dramatically. We&#8217;re creating something of a self-fulfilling prophecy, and we need to step back from that. - Thursday Bram, Hyper Modern Consulting 4. Develop Access to Capital Women founders can find it more difficult to raise funding for their businesses. The statistics show that less than 20 percent of female-led ventures get funding, which is much lower than the statistics for men. That said, there are several great organizations trying to help women reach their funding goals, including Women 2.0, Astia, and others. We need to support such groups. - Doreen Bloch, Poshly Inc. 5. Be Yourself When I was starting TalentEgg, not only was I a woman in the tech industry, but I was also very young &#8212; a 24-year-old who looked like I was only 15. Thankfully, I learned early on that my biggest strength was my ability to be myself. I didn&#8217;t pretend to be older than I was, or have more experience than I had. I also didn&#8217;t try to emulate men in my industry. I was just me, and I never listened to any commentary regarding the barriers that I was supposedly facing by being a young woman in technology. - Lauren Friese, TalentEgg Inc. 6. Having Some Chutzpah When it comes to women in tech, we need more of them, and a little chutzpah, too. I say that because once women start getting their hands dirty in the tech world, there&#8217;s no stopping them. That&#8217;s what&#8217;s important to remember. Also, there&#8217;s a huge shift happening right now as more women show an interest in this space. Those actions needs to be rewarded at a much earlier age for girls. - Nathalie Lussier, Nathalie Lussier Media 7. Find Mentors I recently read that only one in five professional women have had a mentor. Yet, most women believe having a mentor is important for career advancement. Sheryl Sandberg, Facebook&#8217;s COO, often discusses how important mentors have been in her career. When looking for a mentor, I think it&#8217;s good to seek out males and females. Women are more likely to choose a female mentor, and while I think it&#8217;s critical for women to support other women, it&#8217;s also good to have a male perspective. Personally, my male and female mentors push me and challenge me in different ways, and I really appreciate that. - Natalie MacNeil, She Takes on the World Image courtesy of iStockphoto, courtneyk More About: contributor, entrepreneurs, features, ment, women in technology</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/women-entrepreneurs-barriers-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/women-entrepreneurs-barriers-tech/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is the web right now - The Oatmeal</title>
      <description>The State of the Web - Spring 2012View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/state_web_spring</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/state_web_spring</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OperationSAFE is going back to China this summer to work with abandoned children. You can help! http://t.co/U6t67lkm #DT @operationSAFE</title>
      <description>CathPrisk: OperationSAFE is going back to China this summer to work with abandoned children. You can help! http://t.co/U6t67lkm #DT @operationSAFE &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.firstgiving.com/fundraiser/jonathan-wilson-1/opsafe</link>
      <guid>http://www.firstgiving.com/fundraiser/jonathan-wilson-1/opsafe</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Buys $550 Million in Patents from Microsoft</title>
      <description>Facebook has signed an agreement to acquire $550 million in patents from Microsoft, the companies announced jointly Monday. The patents were part of the $1.065 billion in patents Microsoft purchased from AOL earlier this month. In the initial agreement, Microsoft took ownership of approximately 925 U.S. patents and patent applications, in addition to a license to AOL&#8217;s remaining patent portfolio of about 300 patents. Facebook has now taken possession of 650 of those patents, &#8220;plus a license to the AOL patents and applications that Microsoft will purchase and own,&#8221; Facebook said in a release. That leaves Microsoft with 275 of the original patents and applications it purchased from AOL. Microsoft will also retain a license to 650 of the patents and applications now owned by Facebook, in addition to the ~300 AOL patents it gained a license to earlier. &#8220;Today&#8217;s agreement with Facebook enables us to recoup over half of our costs while achieving our goals from the AOL auction,&#8221; Brad Smith, executive vice president and general counsel of Microsoft, said in the release. More About: aol, Facebook, microsoft, patentsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/facebook-buys-microsoft-aol-patents/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/facebook-buys-microsoft-aol-patents/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get more likes on Facebook</title>
      <description>More tanks. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/comics/facebook_likes</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Video Tips for Businesses on Pinterest</title>
      <description>Grant Crowell is a multimedia writer and marketing analyst who&#8217;s been covering the online video space since 2006. Connect with him on LinkedIn or follow him at @grantcrowell. Since Pinterest was founded in 2008, it&#8217;s proven one thing: People love their visuals. And it looks like the site is becoming a hot space for online video marketing opportunities as well, with its recent integration of the Vimeo platform. SEE ALSO: Need More YouTube Views? Try Pinterest The video platform addition makes sense, given how video continues to grow on the network. For example, despite Pinterest&#8217;s &#8220;no-follow&#8221; links rule to third-party sites, videos on the site are being indexed by Google at a rapid rate. In late March, Google had indexed 1,170 Pinterest videos. By mid-April, that figure jumped to 5,870 video results &#8212; an increase of more than 500% in just three weeks. What that should tell brands and marketers is that now is the time to start looking at Pinterest as a video marketing vertical. Here are ten tips on how to get the most out of using video on this site. 1. Customize the Thumbnail Images Video thumbnails that are nicely photographed and appear to be art directed will blend in much better on Pinterest, and typically draw more attention than a video still frame. However, if you&#8217;re not a YouTube Partner, the images you get won&#8217;t always look great. Vimeo offers a far better solution where you can upload your own custom thumbnail. This leaves quality control in your hands. When selecting a thumbnail, find or create an eye-catching image that properly represents your video. If it&#8217;s a company product, consider setting it against a white background. If it&#8217;s more of an idea, then find a visual that provides a unique way of showcasing your theme. Whatever you do, make sure that your primary visual can clearly be seen at thumbnail size, and is not obscured by the default &#8220;play&#8221; button. 2. Have Descriptive Video Pins and Pinboards Pinterest recommends you create at least a few boards that cover a broad range of interests, rather than maintaining a single board devoted to one topic. Yet, some brands make the mistake of placing all of their videos on a single pinboard and non-descriptively titling it, &#8220;videos.&#8221; Don&#8217;t do that. You wouldn&#8217;t think of titling a pinboard, &#8220;images.&#8221; Instead, look for ways to combine your originally-produced videos with curated videos into pinboards around keyword-rich themes, and place them next to related static images you&#8217;ve pinned. For example, a product pin can be strategically placed next to an interesting video showing a lifestyle experience or demo of that product. Merchandising images and video together can prove to be more influential with viewers. 3. Keep Your Videos Short, When Possible Pinterest is designed for quick browsing and pinning, so you don&#8217;t want to make people feel like they&#8217;re going to be stuck watching a long video. Naturally, there will be exceptions, as some video themes, like DIYs or demos, may require more time. In either case, make sure to list the length of the video right in the description since viewers are becoming conditioned to seeing that in YouTube and search engine results. 4. Clearly Describe Video Content Don&#8217;t ever leave your description field blank. Describe to people what they can expect to see before they click on the video. Even with an eye-catching thumbnail image, and a relevant subject, people still read the description field of a video to make sure it&#8217;s worth their time. 5. Curate Fresh Videos with Fresh Descriptions Always consider taking the most popular and freshest videos that relate to whatever product, solution, lifestyle, or event you are a part of, and curating them. I recommend creating your own unique title and description instead of duplicating what appears on the original video page, so as not to appear &#8220;spammy.&#8221; 6. Include &#8220;Pin This&#8221; Annotations When you are using your own YouTube videos, Brian Honigman, the digital marketing manager at Marc Ecko Enterprises, suggests including annotations with a call-to-action for your audience. Basically, tell your visitors to &#8220;pin this video to Pinterest&#8221; or provide a link to your Pinterest profile as a way to connect. 7. Add &#8220;Pin Me&#8221; Notices in Video Outtros Of course, you can always feature your own call-to-action in the video content you create. Simply include something like &#8220;Follow me at pinterest.com/[pinterest name]&#8221; in your video outtros, like the example above. It makes for a great reminder for users to engage with you in another way and in a different community. 8. Put a &#8220;Pin It&#8221; Button Next to Your Video Player You likely already know that you can add the Pinterest follow button to your website or blog. You should also have it embedded right under the embedded video player on your website and blog pages. It&#8217;s just one more way your visitors can get to key content. 9. Create a Pinterest-Specific Video Campaign Some brands are now developing video campaigns to encourage users to follow them on Pinterest and pin their items. Take this Pinterest video campaign from a U.K. insurance comparison website. Their Driving in Heels video was part of a contest where users submitted the craziest shoes they have ever worn while operating a car. This turned out to be an effective cross-marketing strategy. It created awareness about a public safety issue (unsafe driving habits), while also generating increased brand awareness through theme-based pinning. 10. Repin Videos by Others Pinterest&#8217;s best brand practices page says &#8220;repinning is one of the most social activities on Pinterest and it&#8217;s how any user really builds his/her network of followers.&#8221; One way to do this with videos is to find influencers in your industry who already have Pinterest profiles, follow them, and include their videos on your own pinboard. Make sure to notify them about it on the comments section of their original pins. Better yet, you can create a custom video that comments on some of the more interesting &#8220;Pin-fluencers&#8221; in your community. Both of these are acceptable ways of reaching out to thought leaders and brand leaders. What other online video marketing opportunities are you seeing with Pinterest? Have you used video on Pinterest with a business strategy or an interesting business outcome? Let us know in the comments. 1. Perfect Palette 244,163 Followers 113 Boards 6,925 Pins Looking for a color theme for your upcoming wedding? Well, you've come to the right place. Click here to view this gallery. More About: contributor, features, ONLINE VIDEO, pinterest, social media marketing, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/pinterest-video-marketing-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/23/pinterest-video-marketing-tips/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest is Now the No. 3 Social Network in the U.S. [STUDY]</title>
      <description>Pinterest is now the number three most-popular social network in the U.S., behind Facebook and Twitter, according to Experian Hitwise. A new report from the researcher shows Pinterest got 21.5 million visits during the week ending Jan. 28, a nearly 30-fold increase over a comparable week in July. Not surprisingly, the site skews female with a 60/40 ration of women to men visitors. Experian rep Matt Tatham says Pinterest beat its next-closest competitor, LinkedIn, in total visits in February. Tatham says the rankings by total visits for March is as follows: 1. Facebook: 7 billion 2. Twitter: 182 million 3. Pinterest: 104 million 4. LinkedIn: 86 million 5. Tagged: 72 million 6. Google+: 61 million The report, which tracks visits rather than unique visitors, is based on web traffic and doesn&#8217;t factor in visits from mobile sites. According to Experian&#8217;s reckoning, Foursquare only got 2.9 million visits in March and Instagram got 10.2 million. ComScore, which doesn&#8217;t measure mobile traffic either, but ranks sites by uniques rather than total visits, did not include Pinterest in its list of the top 50 web properties in February. However, LinkedIn made number 27 with 36 million visitors. ComScore listed Pinterest as its number three &#8220;top-gaining&#8221; properties, however, with 17.8 million total visitors that month. ComScore&#8217;s March figures were not available at press time. More About: Experian Hitwise, Facebook, Google, pinterest, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/06/pinterest-number-3-social-network/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Social Media Is Taking Over the News Industry [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>More than ever, people are using Twitter, Facebook and other social media sources to learn about what&#8217;s happening in the world as traditional news outlets become increasingly less relevant to the digital generation. American forces&#8217; raid on Osama Bin Laden, Whitney Houston&#8216;s death, the Hudson River plane landing &#8212; these are just a few of many major news stories ordinary citizens broke on Twitter first. Professional journalists, meanwhile, use Twitter all the time to break news quickly before writing up full articles. And the business side is going digital too. Online news now generates more revenue than print newspapers. But the trend toward Internet and social media-based news &#8212; and the accompanying rush to be first to report a story &#8212; also comes with pitfalls. Some 50% of news consumers have received &#8220;breaking news&#8221; via social media, only to find out later it was erroneously reported. All this and more comes from the online education portal Schools.com, which pulled research from sources including the Washington Post, Pew Research Center and Reuters to put together the infographic below. Check it out to see the fuller picture of how social media is coming to dominate the news industry. How much do you rely on social media for news compared to more traditional sources? Has that balance changed for you recently? Let us know in the comments. Thumbnail image courtesy iStockphoto, DNY59 More About: Facebook, infographics, News, Social Media, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/social-media-and-the-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/18/social-media-and-the-news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix&#8217;s Unlimited Employee Vacation Policy: Why It Works</title>
      <description>Netflix employees have one less things to keep track of: the amount of vacation days they take. Co-founder Reed Hastings recently told Bloomberg Businessweek that Netflix has an unlimited vacation policy. In an effort to separate itself from bureaucratic corporations, Netflix, with its 900 employees, abandoned the typical vacation allotment to opt for a sky&#8217;s-the-limit plan. Keeping vacation unlimited, said Hastings, requires mature, responsible employees who care about high-quality work. Netflix has a &#8220;freedom and responsibility culture,&#8221; Hastings told the publication in an article entitled, &#8220;How To Set Your Employees Free.&#8221; Hastings said Netflix gauges success by focusing on what employees get done, not on how many days they worked. The CEO does make sure to be a good role model and takes vacations, where he can do some creative thinking. Hasting explained how the idea evolved: &#8220;My first company, Pure Software, was exciting and innovative in the first few years and bureaucratic and painful in the last few before it got acquired. The problem was we tried to systemize everything and set up perfect procedures. We thought that was a good thing, but it killed freedom and responsibility. After the company was acquired, I reflected on what went wrong.&#8221; The pressure to hang onto one&#8217;s job in a bad economy, and smaller staffs at some organizations, have caused many workers to push themselves to burnout mode. Now, it seems, there may be a growing focus on employees regaining a work-life balance. SEE ALSO: Sheryl Sandberg Leaves Work at 5:30 Every Day &#8212; And You Should Too Netflix isn&#8217;t the only company that has jumped on the all-you-want vacation bandwagon. IBM has a famously flexible time-off policy &#8212; letting employees leave early and take a day off on short notice, just so long as they have a handle on their workloads. Numerous startups and innovative companies working in the tech space are beginning to see the benefits of ditching vacation limits and promoting personal responsibility. What do you think about unlimited vacation policies? Does your employer offer a flexible or unlimited vacation policy? Tell us in the comments. &#8234;Photo courtesy of iStockphoto, Crisma&#8236; More About: IBM, netflix, reed hastings, trending, vacationFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/netflix-unlimited-vacation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/04/13/netflix-unlimited-vacation/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
