<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Gap Between PC and Mac Sales Narrowing [CHART]</title>
      <description>There's no questioning the dominance of Microsoft Windows among the world's computers. Recent statistics show Windows is the OS on more than 78% of all personal computers sold, while Apple's Macs have to settle for 3.7%. However, Microsoft's perch isn't as high as it used to be. According to data from Asymco, the ratio of PCs sold to Macs sold has been declining for most of the past decade, and it's now at a level that hasn't been seen since the mid '90s (summarized in this chart). The gap was at its widest in 2004, when there were more than 50x as many Windows machines sold than Macs, but in 2011 the ratio was down to about 20x. That's obviously still a huge difference, but it not&#8230; Continue reading... More About: apple, ipad, microsoft, pc, PCs, Windows, Windows 8</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/mac-vs-pc-sales/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/mac-vs-pc-sales/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Shutdowns Continue: iGoogle, Google Video, Google Mini &amp; Others Are Killed</title>
      <description>Google is continuing to shut down services which aren&#8217;t core to its business &#8211; something it has been actively doing ever since Google co-founder Larry Page took over as CEO. Today, the tradition continues as Google is announcing the shuttering of five more services, the most notable of which are Google Video and iGoogle, its personalized homepage offering. Clearly iGoogle has outlived its usefulness. The service dates back to a time when homepage portals were people&#8217;s entry points to the Internet. These days, we just never close our browser tabs, it seems. iGoogle is getting the ax on November 1st, 2013, which is far enough away for users to export their data, says Google. Another big-name closure is Google Video, a service which has long been overshadowed by Google-owned YouTube. It&#8217;s actually surprising that Google Video is still up-and-running, given that it stopped accepting uploads in May 2009. Google Video&#8217;s shutdown is arriving much sooner, however, so if you&#8217;ve dragged your feet in moving videos over to YouTube, now is the time. Google Video is no more as of August 20th. Other services fading to black today include Google&#8217;s Symbian Search App (bookmark Google.com, Google advises), Google Talk Chatback (a Google Talk widget for websites &#8211; Google says try its new acquisition Meebo instead) and Google Mini, an enterprise appliance that&#8217;s been around since 2005. Note that Google isn&#8217;t exiting the enterprise by any means, it&#8217;s just that Mini&#8217;s functionality is now offered by other products like Google Search Appliance, Google Site Search and Google Commerce Search, the company blog post reminds us. Google will honor its existing contracts for Mini customers, though. You can read more about the closures here. If you&#8217;re starting to lose track of the services Google&#8217;s has killed off in recent months, here&#8217;s a brief refresher: Google Bookmarks Lists, Google Friend Connect, Google Gears, Google Search Timeline, Google Wave, Knol, Renewable Energy Cheaper than Coal (RE&lt;C), Aardvark, Desktop, Fast Flip, Google Maps API for Flash, Google Pack, Google Web Security, Image Labeler, Notebook, Sidewiki, Subscribed Links,Google Flu Vaccine Finder, Google Related, Google Sync for BlackBerry, mobile web app for Google Talk, One Pass, Patent Search, Picasa for Linux, Picasa Web Albums Uploader for Mac and Picasa Web Albums Plugin for iPhoto, and all Slide products.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/03/google-shutdowns-continue-igoogle-google-video-google-mini-others-are-killed/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/03/google-shutdowns-continue-igoogle-google-video-google-mini-others-are-killed/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Clinton Jams Out Sax Solo in M83&#8242;s &#8216;Midnight City&#8217;</title>
      <description>Bill Clinton's well known for his prowess on the tenor saxophone, but it's been a while since the former president dusted the musical cobwebs off. Fans of Slick Willie's music can rejoice -- he's back, jamming out the sax solo on the hit Midnight City by indie electronica band M83. Okay, so it's not really Clinton playing the solo in the above video, but we're big fans of this overdubbed track that uses the president's famous 1992 appearance on The Arsenio Hall Show. We've already got Texts From Hillary, so why not Ringtones From Bill? Rock on, prez! SEE ALSO: Yes, Secretary Clinton Submitted Her Own &#8216;Text From Hillary&#8217; Image courtesy of iStockphoto, EdStock More About: Bill Clinton, m83, Music, Politics, US, Video, viral, watercooler, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/bill-clinton-midnight-city/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/bill-clinton-midnight-city/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Beauty Tutorial Is a Powerful Anti-Domestic Violence Campaign</title>
      <description>YouTube makeup star Lauren Luke, a UK personality with almost half a million subscribers and more than 125 million video views, took a break from her regular tips on covering up in her latest video. The self-taught makeup artist encourages teen girls and women not to hide evidence of domestic abuse in her latest post, "How to look your best the morning after," which is packaged like any of her other tutorials. The powerful PSA is packaged just like any other of Luke's tutorials, and surely attracted eyeballs due to its provocative headline. Since being posted Sunday, it has already received more than 100,000 views. Luke says she was moved to start the campaign because she was "gob&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Social Good, YouTube</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/youtube-lauren-luke-domestic-violence/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/youtube-lauren-luke-domestic-violence/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Drops LinkedIn Partnership</title>
      <description>LinkedIn announced via a blog post on Friday that Twitter would no longer be partnering with the business-networking site to sync updates from one site to the other. This ends a partnership that began in 2009. LinkedIn users can still create updates on the site and click a button to share to Twitter as well, but the the reverse is no longer possible. The LinkedIn post by Ryan Roslansky, head of content products at LinkedIn, pointed to Twitter's own Friday blog post about "delivering a consistent experience on Twitter." Perhaps Twitter wants to separate itself from the business networking company after the recent password breach in which 6 million LinkedIn passwords were stolen. Li&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Drops LinkedIn Partnership</title>
      <description>LinkedIn announced via a blog post on Friday that Twitter would no longer be partnering with the business-networking site to sync updates from one site to the other. This ends a partnership that began in 2009. LinkedIn users can still create updates on the site and click a button to share to Twitter as well, but the the reverse is no longer possible. The LinkedIn post by Ryan Roslansky, head of content products at LinkedIn, pointed to Twitter's own Friday blog post about "delivering a consistent experience on Twitter." Perhaps Twitter wants to separate itself from the business networking company after the recent password breach in which 6 million LinkedIn passwords were stolen. Li&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dress Your iPhone for Summer With These New Cases [PICS]</title>
      <description>1. Case-Mate rPET Fun, green and eco-friendly. The Case-Mate rPET is made of 100% recycled material. $30Click here to view this gallery. Your smartphone cover does so much more than protect the precious phone inside. It's an accessory, a statement about who you are. Some people prefer the tough, rugged styles, while others prefer the simple touch. You can show your true colors by sporting your favorite team's logo on your case or even a QR code for a quick scan of your contact info. Whatever the case, we rounded up a few of the newest ones for you check out. More About: case, casemate, iphone, iphone cases, Speck</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/summer-iphone-cases/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/summer-iphone-cases/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why You're Probably Working an Extra Two Months This Year</title>
      <description>Looking forward to that July 4 holiday? Of course you are. But be honest: what are the chances you&#8217;re going to sneak a look at your work email at some point during the day, just in case? A new survey from mobile security firm Good Technology confirms what we already knew &#8212; that Americans&#8217; work-life balance is going from bad to worse. The stats read like a depressingly familiar roll call of what&#8217;s wrong with our hectic connected existence. Some 68% of us check work email before 8 a.m., with half of us doing so before our heads leave the pillow. (The average check-in time of the 1,000 randomly-selected respondents: 7:09 a.m.) At the other end of the day, 69% of us can&#8217;t slip into slumber unless we&#8217;ve checked that old work email one last time. But perhaps the most eye-popping part of the survey is how much all that extra time adds up to. Simply by answering work-related calls and emails when we&#8217;ve left the office, the average respondent is working an extra seven hours a week. That adds up to 365 hours a year. Assuming eight-hour days and five-day weeks, that&#8217;s around two months per year of unpaid overtime &#8212; and you&#8217;re putting it in voluntarily. Bad news for you, good news for your manager, right? Not so much. Another lesson these workplace studies teach us is the law of diminishing returns. The more you&#8217;re &#8220;on,&#8221; the faster you burn out, and the greater the likelihood that you&#8217;ll make a mistake. SEE ALSO: Tell-Tale Signs an Employee is Overworked [INFOGRAPHIC] Deep down, it seems, we all know this. That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re drawn to stories about Facebook&#8217;s COO leaving work at 5:30pm, for example, or a New York Times op-ed this weekend, which encouraged greater awareness of what it called &#8220;the busy trap.&#8221; Is your work life bleeding into your home life? What, if anything, can we do about it? Let us know in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/overtime-at-home/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/02/overtime-at-home/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ad Agency Uses &#8216;Diablo 3&#8242; to Screen Job Candidates</title>
      <description>Are you a fearless digital warrior? Can you contribute real-time teamwork? Exhibit creative thinking under fire? More importantly, are you good at Diablo 3? If you are and if you're a programmer who's interested in working for an Israeli ad agency, then you might want to check in on Wednesdays at 8 p.m. Israeli time this month to square off with Yossi Lubaton, CEO of BBR Saatchi, a.k.a. "Yossilubaton#2572." If you fare well against the level 60 Barbarian, he will invite you into his office for a job interview and will give you Warmonger, the legendary sword, one million gold coins "and maybe manager's insurance." Lubaton's strategy makes sense: Likely candidates will be on D3&#8230; Continue reading...</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/diablo-3-job-interview/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/diablo-3-job-interview/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Questions to Ask During Your Next Interview</title>
      <description>Jayne Mattson is Senior Vice President at Keystone Associates, a leading career management and transition services consulting firm in Boston. Mattson specializes in helping mid-to-senior level individuals in new career exploration, networking strategies and career decisions based on corporate culture fit. As you look for a new job, will you take any job offer or are you looking for the right one? What does the right job mean? Too often job seekers do not take enough time to reflect on where they have been in their careers before they actively begin their new job search. And when they receive an offer, they do not have any criteria that help them determine the right fit. To help you identify what the right role would look like, think back on times during your career when you were the most satisfied. What role did you love doing, what type of manager were you working for and what was the culture like during this time? Finding a perfect fit comes down to three main questions that your potential employer must answer: Now you know your criteria for the right role, you need to ask courageous questions in your interview &#8212; not safe ones &#8212; to stand out from your competition. Safe questions include: A response from an interviewer will give you some answers, but will you find out what you really need to know to take the job with confidence? Here are more courageous questions to ask. 1. How receptive are you to feedback from your employees when do you do something they disagree with? If one of your values is being able to speak up (diplomatically, of course) when you disagree with a certain decision or behavior of your manager or peers, then this is for you. This question will help you understand how receptive your manager and others would be to constructive feedback without fear of retribution. 2. As a manager, what frustrates you about the people that work for you? As often as you can during the interview, ask questions where the manager would be able to tell you about a specific situation and provide concrete anecdotes. In this case, you want to know what frustrates him or her, so if you get the job, you will know what behaviors to watch out for in yourself. 3. Is there a project your department is working on now? If so, how are you interacting with your staff on it? You certainly want direction from your new manager, but not one that micro-manages your work. If you ask the safe question, &#8220;Do see yourself as a micro-manager?&#8221; they might answer, &#8220;No, I am not at all.&#8221; However, if you ask the riskier question, you may hear he is involved in the project every step of the way &#8212; a potential red flag for you about his style. 4. Can you give me an example of how you work collaboratively with other departments? Your idea of how people collaborate can be completely different than others, so this question helps you assess if the environment is compatible with the way you work best. 5. Does the company welcome celebrating special occasions in employees&#8217; lives? What was the last occasion your department celebrated? This question is a must if your idea of a fun workplace culture includes celebrating special occasions. Now, if the person mentions, &#8220;We don&#8217;t tend to celebrate,&#8221; you could follow up and get a sense whether they would be receptive to it the future. 6. What would be the three things that your peers would say you do extremely well? This question is often asked about you &#8212; the interviewer is listening carefully to what you will say. In some cases, they might follow up with people you are referring to in your answer to verify what you said. You could ask this question to the manager, potential peer or even HR to get a better idea of how the company operates. Since working in teams is much more prevalent in today&#8217;s businesses, you&#8217;ll want to know more about your colleagues. 7. I understand the company has a formal recognition program; however, what type of recognition have you recently given to one of your staff? If recognition or praise is one of your values, then this is a good question. It not only tells you about the company culture, but also if the manager is generous with recognizing the great work of his team. Nearly everyone wants recognition for the work they do, but in very different ways. Find out whether the methods of the company you&#8217;re considering work for you. 8. Has anyone on your staff been promoted over the last couple of years? If so, what was the reason why this person was promoted? If you are looking for development opportunities, you will want to know what those would look like. You&#8217;ll also want to know if the person was promoted because they pushed the subject or if the manager led the process. 9. What type of work do you delegate to your staff? You want to work for a manager who delegates, so you can develop beyond your role. If a manager is not a good delegator, then he might be insecure about his role and not want you to know what they are doing. This could potentially hold you back from promotions or development. 10. What are the three main factors you will be using to determine the right person for this job? This question is best asked toward the end of the interview, so the interviewer might use some of what you have to offer as some of the factors. You should find out how you fit in with the manager and job criteria, so if you could address the concerns in the post-interview correspondence and next round of interviews. 11. What have been the main characteristics of your favorite employees? When someone is talking about a favorite employee, watch for their body language, tone of voice and their word usage. These factors will help you determine if you have some of their same qualities and if not, it will give you more to think about after the interview. 12. What was the company&#8217;s most strategic decision made in the last year? Could you describe how they came to this decision? You want to work for a company that is planning for the future. By asking this question, it will demonstrate to the interviewer that you are thinking ahead. It will also help you understand what you might need to do to keep yourself current in your field and continue to add value to the company. 13. Can you give me an example of how and why one of your staff made a major mistake, and what was your response to it? You want to be able to take risks, but you also want to know your manager will support you in resolving it &#8212; not reprimand you. Asking this question will give you a sense of the level of risk-taking that would be acceptable. Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting!</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/questions-job-interview/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/01/questions-job-interview/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8216;Steve Jobs: The Lost Interview&#8217; Now Available on iTunes</title>
      <description>Steve Jobs: The Lost Interview documentary is now available on iTunes for customers in the U.S. The 1 hour and 15 minute-long interview with Steve Jobs was conducted in 1995 by tech journalist and former Apple employee Robert X. Cringely. The interview, which dates from Jobs's NeXT Computer and Pixar days, is unedited, and it's described on iTunes as "candid, controversial and funny." The name of the documentary stems from the fact that it was conducted for use in the TV show Triumph of the Nerds, but only 10 minutes of the footage was actually used. The rest of the footage was presumed lost, but it was rediscovered shortly after Steve Jobs died in October 2011. You can&#8230; Continue reading... More About: interview, itunes, steve jobs, The Lost Interview</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/steve-jobs-the-lost-interview-itunes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/07/03/steve-jobs-the-lost-interview-itunes/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple 'settles China iPad case'</title>
      <description>BEIJING (AP) &#8212; A Chinese court says Apple has agreed to pay a local company $60 million to settle a dispute over ownership of the iPad name. The Guangdong High People&#8217;s Court said Monday that Apple and Proview Technology reached the settlement through mediation. The court said that ended the legal case. Apple says it bought global rights to the iPad name from Proview in 2009 but Chinese authorities say ownership in China was never transferred. The settlement ends a potential legal complication to selling the popular iPad in China, one of Apple&#8217;s most important markets.</description>
      <link>http://www.boston.com/news/world/asia/2012/07/01/china-court-apple-pays-settle-ipad-case/n08G3zAu9XPZYc3Vu3GdBL/story.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.boston.com/news/world/asia/2012/07/01/china-court-apple-pays-settle-ipad-case/n08G3zAu9XPZYc3Vu3GdBL/story.html</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
