<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Who Is an Average Facebook User? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; What does it mean to be average on Facebook? On a given day, 26% of users "Like" a friend's status, 22% comment on a friend's status and 15% update their own status.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/average-facebook-user-infographic-031307748.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/average-facebook-user-infographic-031307748.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Is an Average Facebook User? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>What does it mean to be average on &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/facebook/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;? On a given day, 26% of users &amp;#8220;Like&amp;#8221; a friend&amp;#8217;s status, 22% comment on a friend&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8230;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/18/facebook-stats/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/18/facebook-stats/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Is A Secure Vault For All Of Your Private, Digital Data</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/personal.png?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="personal" title="personal" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wrote about stealthy startup &lt;a href="http://www.personal.com/"&gt;Personal&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year when the company announced &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/06/personal-raises-7m-from-steve-case-and-others-to-help-consumers-protect-their-digital-data/"&gt;$7.6 million&lt;/a&gt; in funding from Steve Case&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/revolution-llc"&gt;Revolution LLC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/allen-and-company"&gt;Allen&amp;amp;Company&lt;/a&gt;, and others. This week, Personal finally launched its service, which aims to give consumers control over their digital data, to the public.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Personal is a free web and mobile service that helps you take control of all the digital information about yourself and your life, decide who gets access to it, and use it for your benefit. This information ranges from your passwords, your kids allergies, emergency contacts, credit card info, and more. Basically, any information you may not want to store in email but want to be able to share with your loved ones or friends.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With Personal you can store various information in &amp;#8216;data vaults&amp;#8217; where you can selectively share certain vaults with people. Of course, all accounts on Personal include a legal guarantee that you own your data in the system.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, one way to use Personal is via its Form Killer app. You simply enter personal data once (that you would typically enter into forms such as address, social security numbers, birth data and more and then you can gill out forms with a single click using the startup&amp;#8217;s Form Killer app&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the very heart of Personal, are what the startup calls &amp;#8216;gems.&amp;#8217; Gems are nuggets of reusable information that represent the details of your life &#8211; your family, pets, car, home, office, food and travel preferences, and more. You can decide which gems to add to your vault and which to share with others using our grant and request features. And you can download existing data from LinkedIn and Facebook. Personal also has a Gem Gallery, which is where you browse for the gems you need to use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Your Personal data vault is a secure and convenient place for your gems. All sensitive data that you put in gems must be locked and unlocked with an owner-chosen password that Personal does not store and therefore, cannot access. Personal uses a 256-bit SSL encryption and HTTPS to ensure that there is no eavesdropping whenever data is transferred back-and-forth from your computer to Personal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Personal is available on the mobile web and will be launching native Android and iPhone apps will be released soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are number of services similar to Personal (such as &lt;a href="https://singly.com/"&gt;Singly&lt;/a&gt;) but one thing the service has in its favor is its relatively clean and easy to use UI. It makes understanding which data is being shared very easy. Considering some of the hesitations we have sharing certain types of confidential information over email, or even Facebook; there is a need for a private (and highly secure) data organization service. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For background, Personal was founded by the same management team that built business mapping application&lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/the-map-network"&gt; The Map Network&lt;/a&gt; (which was acquired by NAVTEQ in 2006).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/454707/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ITHfwZwMVUBSF5OwoKlRnJ1VncY/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ITHfwZwMVUBSF5OwoKlRnJ1VncY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ITHfwZwMVUBSF5OwoKlRnJ1VncY/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ITHfwZwMVUBSF5OwoKlRnJ1VncY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XhyCOGa1Khk:kS_OVDdC4zA:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/XhyCOGa1Khk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/17/personal-is-a-secure-vault-for-all-of-your-private-digital-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/17/personal-is-a-secure-vault-for-all-of-your-private-digital-data/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For When You Have Too Much to Say</title>
      <description></description>
      <link>http://tmi.me/hO5bJ</link>
      <guid>http://tmi.me/hO5bJ</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instagram</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width= "73" height="73" src="http://a2.twimg.com/profile_images/1552800378/pirate_twitter_avatar2_normal.jpg" /&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks"&gt;Sarah McIntyre&lt;/a&gt;: Good afternoon, guardian studio troll &lt;a href="http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj" target="_blank"&gt;http://t.co/X6RVf0Zj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/jabberworks/status/131361371802705920"&gt;&amp;#9733;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Like Siftlinks.com? &lt;a href="http://pledgie.com/campaigns/15159"&gt;Donate now&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</link>
      <guid>http://instagr.am/p/SRQse/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter to Chancellor Linda P.B. Katehi (Chancellor of UC Davis)</title>
      <description>Join University of California at Davis, Assistant Professor Nathan Brown in calling for the resignation of UC Davis Chancellor Linda P.B. Kathei for...</description>
      <link>http://www.change.org/petitions/uc-davis-chancellor-linda-pb-katehi-resign</link>
      <guid>http://www.change.org/petitions/uc-davis-chancellor-linda-pb-katehi-resign</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racism And Meritocracy</title>
      <description>&lt;img width="100" height="70" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/gummy-bears.jpg?w=100&amp;amp;h=70&amp;amp;crop=1" class="attachment-tc-carousel-river-thumb wp-post-image" alt="Gummy bears" title="Gummy bears" style="float: left; margin: 0 10px 7px 0;" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor&#8217;s note: &lt;/strong&gt;Guest contributor &lt;a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/eric-ries"&gt;Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt; is a consultant and the author of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous-Innovation/dp/0307887898"&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;. Follow him &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/ericries"&gt;@ericries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unless you&#8217;ve been living under a rock, you can&#8217;t have missed the recent dust-up over race and Silicon Valley. Like almost every discussion of diversity and meritocracy in this town, it turned &lt;a href="http://uncrunched.com/2011/11/02/racism-the-game/"&gt;ugly&lt;/a&gt; fast. One side says: &#8220;All I see is white men. Therefore, people like Michael Arrington must be racist.&#8221; The other responds, &#8220;Silicon Valley is a colorblind meritocracy. If there were qualified women or minority candidates, we&#8217;d welcome them.&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;d like to say a few words about this, but I want to do so under special ground rules.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I want to make an argument, step by step, that I hope will convince you to care about this issue, but that doesn&#8217;t presuppose that you already agree that diversity is important. And it will explain how it is possible for both sides to be mostly correct &#8211; and that we still have a problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So the rules are:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;No political correctness. Let&#8217;s speak the truth no matter where it leads.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;You don&#8217;t have to believe that diversity is an end in itself. In fact, I will argue that is important as a means to an end.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Meritocracy is a good thing. Whenever possibly, people should be judged based on their work and results, not superficial qualities.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We should use science, whenever possible, rather than anecdotal evidence.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;No hand-wringing. There&#8217;s no point discussing this problem if we can&#8217;t do anything about it.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;So &#8211; no hippies, no whiners, no name-calling, and no BS. If you want to make Silicon Valley &#8211; and startup hubs like it &#8211; as awesome as possible, pay attention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What accounts for the decidedly non-diverse results in places like Silicon Valley? We have two competing theories. One is that deliberate racisms keeps people out. Another is that white men are simply the ones that show up, because of some combination of aptitude and effort (which it is depends on who you ask), and that admissions to, say Y Combinator, simply reflect the lack of diversity of the applicant pool, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The problem with both of these theories is that the math just doesn&#8217;t work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s a fact that the applicant pool to most Silicon Valley startup schools and VCs is skewed. Could this be the result of innate differences between white men and other groups? The math simply doesn&#8217;t hold up to support this view. Think about two overlapping populations of people, like men and women. They would naturally be normally distributed in a bell curve around a mean aptitude. So picture those two bell curves. Here in Silicon Valley, we&#8217;re looking for the absolute best and brightest, the people far out on the tail end of aptitude. So imagine that region of the curve. How far apart would the two populations have to be to explain YC&#8217;s historical &lt;a href="http://www.foundersatwork.com/1/post/2011/1/what-stops-female-founders.html"&gt;admission rate of 4% women&lt;/a&gt;? It would have to be really extreme.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/2138794"&gt;some research&lt;/a&gt; on the differences between men and women, and it has shown some differences in both average aptitude and the standard deviation of aptitude (i.e. that men have more extreme outcomes in both the positive and negative direction). But these differences are extremely small, nowhere near large enough to suggest a region on this curve with all men and no women on it. If you&#8217;d like to examine the math involved, check out this excellent slide deck courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/terriko"&gt;Terri Oda&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;iframe src='http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/2252025' width='640' height='525'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;What is true for aptitude is also true for interest. Some populations are more interested in science, in math, in business, and in taking risks than others. But all of the research I am aware of suggests that these differences are extremely small &#8211; not nearly big enough to explain what we&#8217;re observing in places like Y Combinator.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is why I personally care about diversity: it&#8217;s the &lt;a href="http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2010/02/why-diversity-matter-meritocracy.html"&gt;canary in the coal mine&lt;/a&gt; for meritocracy. When we see extremely skewed demographics, we have very good reason to suspect that something is wrong with our selection process, that it&#8217;s not actually as meritocratic as it could be. And I believe that is exactly what is happening in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There&#8217;s plenty of good research on the subject of team performance that shows that &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/01/08/science/08conv.html"&gt;diverse teams outperform homogeneous teams&lt;/a&gt; on many different kinds of tasks. The problem is that this research doesn&#8217;t argue for demographic diversity, but rather for a diversity of perspectives. So, again, racial or gender diversity is not an end in itself. But we have to ask ourselves: if teams are consistently being put together with homogeneous demographics, what are the odds that they also will contain a diversity of perspectives? Shouldn&#8217;t we be worried that the same selection process that produces homogenous results in one area might be accidentally doing the same in the area that we care about (but that is harder to measure)? &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Does that mean that the racism theory is necessarily correct? I don&#8217;t think so. I&#8217;ve certainly heard my share of sexist and racist jokes in Silicon Valley, but hardly enough to believe that people like Michael Arrington or Paul Graham are lying when they say that they are colorblind. I think that &#8211; in the absence of any counterevidence &#8211; we should take them at their word. Besides, we don&#8217;t need racism to explain these results. Now that we&#8217;ve clarified the question to be &#8220;how do we build a meritocratic selection process?&#8221; we can look at a wealth of research that has been done in this area.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And there&#8217;s good news here. Wherever selection processes have been studied scientifically, errors have been found. These errors are called &#8220;&lt;a href="https://implicit.harvard.edu/implicit/demo/"&gt;implicit bias&lt;/a&gt;&#8221; in the research literature, which causes a lot of confusion, because the word &#8220;bias&#8221; connotes malevolence. But let&#8217;s leave that connotation behind &#8211; we&#8217;re entrepreneurs, scientists and engineers, for goodness&#8217; sake. We can talk about bias like grownups.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And what the grownups have discovered, through painstaking research, is that it is extremely easy for &lt;em&gt;systems &lt;/em&gt;to become biased, even if none of the individual people in those systems intends to be biased. This is partly a cognitive problem, that people harbor unconscious bias, and partly an organizational problem, that even a collection of unbiased actors can work together to accidentally create a biased system. And when those systems are examined scientifically, they can be reformed to reduce their bias.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most famous example of this comes from the world of musical orchestras. Until the 1970s, almost every professional orchestra in the world was all-male. All experts in the musical world agreed on the reason: male performers had superior aptitude to female performers. They gave all kinds of explanations for why, that had to do with men&#8217;s allegedly superior skill, hand-eye coordination, interest in music, and their willingness to sacrifice so much to become a professional musician. And yet, by the 1990s, these ratios had &lt;a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w5903"&gt;changed dramatically&lt;/a&gt;. No conductors went to political correctness anti-bias training camps. No hand-wringing was needed. They hit upon a solution &#8211; by accident &#8211; that practically changed orchestra selection overnight: they had performers audition behind a physical screen, so that the judges could not see their race or gender while they played. When rating performers anonymously, it turned out that men and women &lt;a href="http://www.princeton.edu/pr/pwb/01/0212/7b.shtml"&gt;played equally well&lt;/a&gt;, on average.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&#8217;ve seen the movie &lt;em&gt;Moneyball&lt;/em&gt; recently (or read the book), this should sound familiar. The whole premise of &lt;em&gt;Moneyball&lt;/em&gt; was the triumph of science, data, and reason over the gut feelings and beauty contests of baseball scouts. Think of the famous scene in which the scouts are sitting around a table debating which prospects had &#8220;the right look&#8221; &#8211; and Brad Pitt and Jonah Hill are calling BS. Which side of the table sounds more like the admissions process to a Silicon Valley startup school, where they are often &#8220;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/24/y-combinators-paul-graham-were-looking-for-people-like-us/"&gt;looking for people like us&lt;/a&gt;?&#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to the research on implicit bias, our selection processes are making some huge, obvious mistakes. The Y Combinator partners conduct short ten-minute interviews where they make snap decisions about candidates on the spot &#8211; &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/magazine/2011/05/ff_ycombinator/all/1"&gt;sometimes in as little as sixty seconds&lt;/a&gt;. This process, while efficient, is the exact opposite of musical performances happening behind a screen. They are even moving towards &lt;a href="http://ycombinator.com/video.html"&gt;video interviews&lt;/a&gt; &#8211; which would bring this visual bias even earlier into the process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now think about the countless VC pitch meetings and &#8220;get to know you&#8221; mixers and coffees and lunches. These are all opportunities for VC&#8217;s to use their vaunted pattern recognition to try and spot promising entrepreneurs and companies early. But pattern recognition is just a fancy word for bias. And if you look at the research on implicit bias, you will find that bias is a necessary consequence of using pattern recognition, it&#8217;s part of how the brain works. We literally think faster when we see something that matches the pattern, and have to slow down to process something that doesn&#8217;t match. I think Michael Arrington provided a fascinating first-hand account of this cognitive process in action, when he described his experience &lt;a href="http://uncrunched.com/2011/10/28/oh-shit-im-a-racist/"&gt;struggling to name a single African-American entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt;. He couldn&#8217;t come up with one on the spot, but not because he&#8217;s a racist.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;None of this is meant as a criticism of Y Combinator, VCs, or anyone else. It&#8217;s meant to point out that even though our current selection process is pretty good, and pretty meritocratic, it still contains bias. We can do better. And, if we do, we will make all of Silicon Valley more successful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So how can we do better? I believe there are several relatively simple changes we could make right away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I previously &lt;a href="http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2010/02/why-diversity-matter-meritocracy.html"&gt;described on my blog&lt;/a&gt; one simple change I made to the hiring process at my last company. I asked all of our recruiters to give me all resumes of prospective employees with their name, gender, place of origin, and age blacked out. This simple change shocked me, because I found myself interviewing different-looking candidates &#8211; even though I was 100% convinced that I was not being biased in my resume selection process. If you&#8217;re screening resumes, or evaluating applicants to a startup school, I challenge you to adopt this procedure immediately, and report on the results.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Startup schools are an exceptionally good laboratory for testing these ideas. In fact, if anyone out there wants to put this idea to the test, I suggest the following experiment: for your next batch of admissions, have half of your reviewers use a blind screening technique and the other half use your standard technique, on your first screen (before you&#8217;ve met any applicants). Compare the outputs of both selection processes. I predict they will show different demographics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, this doesn&#8217;t address the whole problem. Remember, part of the defense against the racism theory is that the applicants are already skewed before any selection is done. Once again, this sounds like something you can only throw your hands up about: if it&#8217;s not a problem with innate differences, it must be a problem with our education system or some other &#8220;pipeline&#8221; problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So let&#8217;s take a look at this problem, too.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I once spent time with a promising entrepreneur who was not a white man. Because their startup sold a product that a lot of tech entrepreneurs buy, many of their customers were graduates of Y Combinator. So I asked if they were planning to apply. Their response: &#8220;oh, no, it&#8217;s a waste of time. Y Combinator doesn&#8217;t accept people like me.&#8221; Where did they get that idea? Surely not from YC&#8217;s partners, who as far as I can tell are scrupulously fair in their dealings with entrepreneurs. Rather, they got that impression by inferring that there is probably implicit bias in YC&#8217;s admissions process, and that they&#8217;d be better off spending their time doing something else other than applying to YC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We all know there is a huge gender gap in computer science. But that gap means that women receive &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/04/17/science/17comp.html?_r=2&amp;amp;8dpc=&amp;amp;oref=slogin&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&amp;amp;oref=slogin"&gt;only about 30% of degrees in CS&lt;/a&gt;. But 30% is a lot larger than 4% &amp;#8211; and that&#8217;s a big math problem for advocates of the pipeline theory.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Imagine that you were a professional musician thinking about which orchestra to audition for. You have a choice between an all-male orchestra that conducts interviews out in the open, and a mixed-gender orchestra that conducts auditions behind a screen. Which would you choose to apply to? Wouldn&#8217;t your answer be different if you were a man or a woman?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think thought experiments like this are helpful for suggesting an alternate hypothesis to the pipeline problem: that there are qualified minority applicants who are choosing &#8211; rationally &#8211; to invest their time and energy elsewhere. I am not aware of any scientific study that proves this hypothesis is correct. But I have seen enough existence proofs to believe it is likely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, I have been a mentor for several years in the &lt;a href="http://founderlabs.org/"&gt;Founder Labs&lt;/a&gt; program, which was originally created by Women 2.0. It&#8217;s a pre-incubator program, that helps potential founders figure out if they should become entrepreneurs. They created it as a way of encouraging women to apply to startup schools and create companies. But they took a novel approach to this problem. They did not advertise the program as being about diversity. Instead, they adopted a minimal rule: each founding team had to have at least one woman, and they privately reached out to talented women in their networks and encouraged them to join.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I spoke to the Founder Labs teams. I kept asking: who are you and where have you been? It was unlike any other audience I&#8217;ve seen at any other startup school: 50/50 men and women, with a surprising amount of diversity. The participants included chip designers and hard-core engineers, the kind of people that have the aptitude but don&#8217;t apply to most startup school programs or pitch most VCs. I believe the reason they came to this program was that they believed its selection process would be more meritocratic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Groups that make a conscious effort to become more meritocratic are able to make meaningful changes in the diversity of their participants. One of my favorite examples is the San Francisco Ruby Meetup, which spent a year making the effort to improve the number of women who participate. The steps they took required effort, but not rocket science. They didn&#8217;t have to get sixth grade girls interested in programming. You can read more about it &lt;a href="http://www.sarahmei.com/blog/2010/02/20/scale-8x-slides-posted/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There&#8217;s one last piece to this puzzle that science can help us with. It goes by the rather unfortunate academic name of &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/1999/08/thin-ice-stereotype-threat-and-black-college-students/4663/?single_page=true"&gt;&lt;em&gt;stereotype threat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But a confusing name doesn&#8217;t make it any less real. It turns out that when people are in a situation that defies stereotypes, reminding them of the stereotype diminishes their performance. In one study from NYU, students were given a math test. Asking men and women questions about their gender beforehand increased the performance gap substantially. &#8220;Priming&#8221; students with questions about other aspects of their identity, did not. This result has been replicated in &lt;a href="http://scienceblogs.com/mixingmemory/2007/12/combating_stereotype_threat_in.php#stereowild6"&gt;many, many studies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think this helps explain why asking more minorities to apply to these programs doesn&#8217;t work. Consciously thinking about proving a stereotype wrong impairs performance. So it&#8217;s entirely possible that a completely objective assessment of the performance of candidates in an application process will show minority candidates doing worse, because they are literally cognitively impaired.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And this brings me back to the no hand-wringing rule. Most people interpret this finding as bad news, but I think they have it backwards. It&#8217;s actually really good news. If you look at the studies, what they show is that the performance gap between groups can be mostly erased, if candidates are primed in a merit-focused way. Explicit diversity programs have the solution exactly backwards. What we need to do is to build meritocratic selection processes, and then go our of our way to tell people about them. We should emphasize the objectivity of the selection process and our efforts to weed out all forms of bias. I believe this is why certain programs, like Founder Labs and 500 Startups, that boast of their meritocratic &#8220;moneyball&#8221; approach to admissions have more diverse applicants &#8211; and participants.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When it comes to meritocracy and diversity, the symbolic is real. And that means that simple actions that reduce bias, such as blind resume or application screening, are a double win: they reduce implicit bias and they help communicate our commitment to meritocracy. As a startup ecosystem we are in the &lt;a href="http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2010/02/why-diversity-matter-meritocracy.html"&gt;meritocracy business&lt;/a&gt;. This is the path towards making Silicon Valley &#8211; and every other startup hub &#8211; even more awesome.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/daviniodus/5933485031/"&gt;Daviniodus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/tctechcrunch2011.wordpress.com/455376/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kCefIYebUcjZBQJ-ymq7ZOpfqaA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kCefIYebUcjZBQJ-ymq7ZOpfqaA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kCefIYebUcjZBQJ-ymq7ZOpfqaA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/kCefIYebUcjZBQJ-ymq7ZOpfqaA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:2mJPEYqXBVI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:-BTjWOF_DHI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rlnEEtEEDpM:CsX5v1rBSPs:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/rlnEEtEEDpM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/19/racism-and-meritocracy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/19/racism-and-meritocracy/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung Galaxy Nexus: the Best Android Phone We&#8217;ve Seen Yet</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="float:right;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/submit?text=sdasdasd&amp;url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/stumbleupon.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://digg.com/tools/diggthis/login?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/&amp;title=Samsung Galaxy Nexus: the Best Android Phone We&amp;#8217;ve Seen Yet&amp;related=true&amp;style=true"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/diggme.png" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" type="box_count" name="fb_share" href="http://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/&amp;src=sp" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" src="http://6.mshcdn.com/wp-content/themes/v7/img/share-buttons/fb.jpg" align="right" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://api.tweetmeme.com/share?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/&amp;service=bit.ly&amp;source=mashable"&gt;&lt;img style="border:none;margin-right:5px;" width="51" height="61" src="http://api.tweetmeme.com/imagebutton.gif?url=http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/" align="right"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="float:left;margin-bottom:10px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://9.mshcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/top640_CTW0664.jpg" alt="" title="Samsung Galaxy Nexus pic" width="640" height="428" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-806175" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Samsung Galaxy Nexus is the first smartphone with the latest Android 4.0 (Ice Cream Sandwich) operating system. We have one in our hands, and it&amp;#8217;s the best Android phone yet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A new era in the impressive story of &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/category/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/follow/topics/android/"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; operating system has just begun with the release of the Nexus. Gone are those antiquated buttons at the bottom. Now when you look at the front of this relatively large smartphone, all you see is an enormous screen &amp;#8212; an impressive 4.65 inches diagonally &amp;#8212; that looks even bigger without those clunky buttons that until now have always resided at the bottom of Android phones. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The result? Except for the tiny amount of bezel on the top and bottom and a slender sliver on either side, the front of this phone is almost all screen.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;The Hardware&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a lightweight phone at 4.8 ounces, with a HSPA+ radio inside (this test model sent to us by Google is using the T-Mobile network &amp;#8212; a Verizon model using that company&amp;#8217;s faster 4G LTE network will be slightly heavier). The phone has a cheap plastic feel to it, but once I spent some time with it, I didn&amp;#8217;t mind its light weight, especially given its large size, which is about an inch shorter than an average-sized hand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With that large size comes a gorgeous screen. If the term &amp;#8220;1280 x 720-pixel Super AMOLED high-definition display&amp;#8221; doesn&amp;#8217;t mean much to you, suffice to say that even when a screen measures a huge 4.65 inches diagonally, that high number of pixels is still tightly packed onto the screen, resulting in an exquisitely sharp view. If a screen were any sharper than this, it would be hard to tell the difference unless you had super-human eyesight. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Looking at the phone from the side, I realize this is not the thinnest smartphone I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen &amp;#8212; that honor goes to the &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/11/motorola-droid-razr-review/"&gt;Motorola Droid Razr&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; but at 8.94mm, it&amp;#8217;s slim enough. And, it&amp;#8217;s the first smartphone I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen with a gentle curve to its body, accompanied by a remarkable &amp;#8220;Contour Display&amp;#8221; whose glass is also gently curved. It&amp;#8217;s a subtle effect, but I think it&amp;#8217;s downright beautiful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The back of the Galaxy Nexus is plastic, but it&amp;#8217;s an attractive and practical design that gives you a good grip on the phone. At the bottom of the back, there&amp;#8217;s a slight chin, but it&amp;#8217;s not obnoxious like that of too many other Android phones, and this one gives you a slight rise it makes it easier to hold onto the phone, especially when you have it oriented in a horizontal position.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The entire rear panel is easy to remove, facilitating battery removal, and with a few rehearsals, I learned how to quickly snap it back into place. Who says you can&amp;#8217;t have a removable battery and still enjoy clean, minimalist lines on a smartphone? Whoever made that arbitrary proclamation hadn&amp;#8217;t seen the Galaxy Nexus. Even though the Galaxy Nexus is still a plastic phone with a glass screen, in my view, its form factor is a spectacular success.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That clean design on the outside gives you a hint of the highly capable hardware inside, with a 1.2GHz dual-core processor from Texas Instruments (the first time Samsung&amp;#8217;s used such a processor), 1GB of RAM and 16GB of internal storage. The result of that processing power is snappy performance and quick startup. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What we don&amp;#8217;t know yet is how all this hardware and that huge screen will affect battery life &amp;#8212; we&amp;#8217;ve only had the phone for a short while, not long enough to do longer-term battery testing, which is an inexact science at best. However, to give you an idea, when we started testing today, the battery was at 63% and six hours later, it was almost depleted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Those who are obsessed with specs (&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/nexus/#/tech-specs" target="_blank"&gt;Galaxy Nexus specs are all here&lt;/a&gt;) would at first be disappointed with its 5-megapixel camera on the back (with a 1.3 megapixel front-facing camera for videoconferencing), but when I compared identical shots between the Galaxy Nexus and the iPhone 4S, I realized that even though the iPhone 4S&amp;#8217;s 8-megapixel camera looks slightly sharper in brightly-lit situations, the quality of this Samsung Nexus camera in low light matches it nicely. Take a look at our gallery for comparison shots. And, the camera started up quickly, takes multiple pictures in rapid succession, and even has a handy ability to grab panoramic shots. Topping it off is a 1080p video camera which did an admirable job of grabbing acceptable HD footage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Ice Cream Sandwich is Delectable&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;All that hardware is brought to bear on the centerpiece of this new phone, the first smartphone shipping with Google&amp;#8217;s Android 4.0 &amp;#8220;Ice Cream Sandwich&amp;#8221; (ICS) operating system. It represents a giant leap in usability for this popular operating system. The first thing I noticed was its ability to smoothly scroll down long lists, the complaint I&amp;#8217;ve had against Android-packing phones from the beginning. Finally, you can scroll up and down a Google+ stream and slide down lists of emails with smoother response, although not all apps I tried enjoy that butter-smooth scrolling yet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Besides the user interface that&amp;#8217;s cleaned up considerably and much more intuitive, there are unusual new features I was eager to try. One feature I consider to be more demo-ware than useable is its facial recognition to unlock the screen, which worked well as long as I was in the same lighting as the first shot it took to learn how to recognize me. However, when I was outside with a hat and earmuffs on on a blustery Midwestern day, the phone didn&amp;#8217;t have any idea who I was. Nor did it recognize me in slightly different lighting conditions. For now, this facial recognition failed more than it succeeded, and in my experience is not practical to use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because there aren&amp;#8217;t physical buttons any more (except for a volume control on the left and an on-off switch on the right), the apps must give users a way to navigate from one place to another, and there are some apps that aren&amp;#8217;t quite ready for this yet. However, you can still find your way around, and instead of physical buttons you can now use three icons that take you Home, let you go Back, and access recently used apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beyond that, everything on Android 4.0 just looks a lot better, and it&amp;#8217;s more than just window dressing. Among its many improvements, my favorites were the way you can toss off notifications by swiping to the left or right, more easily switch between apps that are running with Android&amp;#8217;s true multitasking, the way there&amp;#8217;s a new center button that immediately takes you to screens full of icons, the way those icons show apps separately from widgets, and the subtle way the app icon screen seems to slightly tilt sideways when you try to slide beyond the last one. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s another new feature called Voice Actions that uses speech recognition to let you send text, dictate emails, navigate to different places and call up web pages. Although Google puts on a pretty good demo of this capability, in the real world it falls short. It&amp;#8217;s no Siri, but if Google can make its Voice Actions easier to use and more accurate, and give it some basic smarts, it might someday become useful. For now, I&amp;#8217;m not going to be depending on Google&amp;#8217;s speech recognition anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2&gt;We Have a Winner&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beyond those gimmicks that don&amp;#8217;t work as well in the real world as they do on television commercials, Ice Cream Sandwich&amp;#8217;s main claim to fame is that it&amp;#8217;s a more-polished version of Android &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s easier to use and more aesthetically pleasing than any of its predecessors. Bravo, Google &amp;#8212; I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to further refinements of Android, and if this leap forward is any indication, the world&amp;#8217;s most popular smartphone operating system has even brighter days ahead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Couple that with this gorgeous and subtly curved handset, and you have yourself a winner. The Samsung Galaxy Nexus is by far the best Android phone I&amp;#8217;ve seen yet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Check out those clean lines&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/#34947Check-out-those-clean-lines"&gt;&lt;img width="400" style="border:none;" title="Check out those clean lines" src="http://5.mshcdn.com/wp-content/gallery/samsung-galaxy-nexus/_CTW0667.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;p&gt;I like its minimalist design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/#34947Check-out-those-clean-lines'&gt;Click here to view this gallery.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More About: &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/android/"&gt;android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/google/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/ice-cream-sandwich/"&gt;ice cream sandwich&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/review/"&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/samsung-galaxy-nexus/"&gt;samsung galaxy nexus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tag/smartphones/"&gt;smartphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For more &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/tech/"&gt;Tech&lt;/a&gt; coverage:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;ul style="margin-top:0;" class="xoxo"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mashabletech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Follow Mashable Tech on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mashable.tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Become a Fan on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/mashable/tech" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;Subscribe to the Tech channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Download our free apps for &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2010/08/02/mashable-android-app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-mac/id412390413?mt=12" rel="nofollow"&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable/id356202138?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mashable-for-ipad/id370097986?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/DhBIN0005y-hjBv5C731fjJiIxA/0/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/DhBIN0005y-hjBv5C731fjJiIxA/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/DhBIN0005y-hjBv5C731fjJiIxA/1/da"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~a/DhBIN0005y-hjBv5C731fjJiIxA/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:D7DqB2pKExk"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:7Q72WNTAKBA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.mashable.com/~ff/mashable/tech?a=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/mashable/tech?i=ukXWMhgSYx0:zXv2VLIkiOw:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/mashable/tech/~4/ukXWMhgSYx0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2011/11/17/samsung-galaxy-nexus-review/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Twitter Marketing Tips From the Pros</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/how-to/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="social media how to" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/how-to-pose.png" alt="social media how to" width="190" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Are you looking for fresh ideas to improve your Twitter marketing?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We sought out hot Twitter tips from the pros. Keep reading for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ow&amp;#8217;s not the time to let your Twitter marketing go stale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter has already &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/twitter-expects-incredible-growth-with-ios-5-integration/59073" target="_blank"&gt;grown more in the last 9 months&lt;/a&gt; than in the last 5 years and &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1783467/fresh-crispy-apple-twitters-could-deep-fry-facebooks-future" target="_blank"&gt;this trend is expected to continue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;How does Twitter fit into your social media marketing? Here are &lt;strong&gt;17 Twitter marketing tips shared by Social Media Examiner&amp;#8217;s writers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;span id="more-12149"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improve Your Tweets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/mari-smith/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-mari-smith.png" alt="Mari Smith" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Mari Smith @marismith&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#1: Share valuable content in your own voice&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do your best to &lt;strong&gt;craft your content tweets, @replies and promotional tweets all with a seamless style that matches your personality and/or brand&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ideally, you want people to read your tweets and feel naturally compelled to click on your links and retweet you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You just want to &lt;strong&gt;add value and have no agenda&lt;/strong&gt; or attachment to &amp;#8220;making the sale,&amp;#8221; yet you&amp;#8217;re strategic and mindful about how you tweet. Then you&amp;#8217;ll see a marked improvement in your retweet and click-through rates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 370px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-smith-1-content-tweet.jpg" alt="content tweet" width="360" height="288" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;A content tweet from Mari with a link to an informative blog post, and an upbeat comment in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://marismith.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Mari Smith&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;/em&gt;Facebook Marketing: An Hour a Day&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/debbie-hemley/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-debbie-hemley.png" alt="Debbie Hemley" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Debbie Hemley @dhemley&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#2: Use keywords in your tweets&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keywords have been and continue to be a relevant and driving force for web content (whether we&amp;#8217;re talking about a website, blog post, Facebook update or a tweet). Keywords are the backbone of content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;d have to say hands-down, my best &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/26-twitter-tips-for-enhancing-your-tweets/"&gt;Twitter marketing tip&lt;/a&gt; for business is to &lt;strong&gt;make a list of keywords that best describe your business and industry. Use these words as you compose your 140-character posts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Think quality over quantity. Make every character and tweet count!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://debbiehemley.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Debbie Hemley&lt;/a&gt;, social media consultant and blogger. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/shane-snow/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-shane-snow.png" alt="shane snow" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Shane Snow @shanesnow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#3: Share links to useful content&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sharing links to useful content is, statistically speaking, more effective at growing and retaining followers than &amp;#8220;engaging&amp;#8221; with them in conversation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s not to say that conversations aren&amp;#8217;t useful in helping people to like you, but if you want to grow your fan base, you need to &lt;strong&gt;share more links than you do @replies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://contently.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Shane Snow&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of Contently.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/nichole-kelly/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-nichole-kelly.png" alt="nichole kelly" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Nichole Kelly @Nichole_Kelly&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#4: Use search features to discover what your clients want&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use the search feature in a Twitter tool like &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank"&gt;HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;watch for conversations about a problem your business can solve&lt;/strong&gt;. It will give you insight into what is on your prospects&amp;#8217; minds and provide an open door for you to help them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try providing a link to a great article or video that answers their question. This one action could lead to an ongoing dialogue that in turn may lead to a customer relationship later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://fullfrontalroi.com/social-media-measurement-bootcamp" target="_blank"&gt;Nichole Kelly&lt;/a&gt;, publisher of FullFrontalROI.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improve Your Networking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/kristi-hines/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-kristi-hines.png" alt="kristi hines" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Kristi Hines @kikolani&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#5: Connect with the right people and tweet with them&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are two crucial things businesses should focus on when implementing their Twitter strategy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first is not finding just anyone to follow in hopes that they follow you back, but finding relevant people to follow who are more likely to follow you back. You can bloat your account to 100,000+ followers, but if they are not interested in your content, it gets you nowhere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You need to be using tools such as &lt;a href="http://followerwonk.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Follower Wonk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.twellow.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Twellow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://wefollow.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Wefollow&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;find people who are in your region (if you&amp;#8217;re a local business) and interested in your industry&lt;/strong&gt;. Then start following them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The second is after you find your targeted audience, don&amp;#8217;t just tweet &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; them&#8212;&lt;strong&gt;tweet &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; them. Follow their conversations; add in your two cents from time to time&lt;/strong&gt;. Follow anyone who talks about your brand and thank them for their compliments or help them with their concerns. Follow anyone who talks about your industry and show why you are an authority.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Doing these things will help you run a successful Twitter campaign that will give your brand exposure as a leader in your industry!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://kikolani.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Kristi Hines&lt;/a&gt;, Internet marketing specialist with Vertical Measures and author of Kikolani.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/carla-dewing/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-carla-dewing.png" alt="Carla Dewing" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Carla Dewing @CarlaDewing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#6: Use a classic icebreaker&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most followers become nameless, faceless numbers on a follower list. Remember when networking used to be about meeting people face to face? Icebreakers were important then, and they&amp;#8217;re just as important now in the virtual world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Icebreakers help you &lt;strong&gt;share a common connection with a stranger&#8212;and make you memorable enough to begin and sustain a long-term relationship&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you find relevant tweets from among your followers, retweet their blog link&#8212;and follow the author&amp;#8217;s feed. Then &lt;strong&gt;send them an @message, detailing something insightful about their blog post&lt;/strong&gt;. At the end of the tweet, link to a similar post you&amp;#8217;ve written.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This should result in more blog comments, retweets and followers, all from 10 minutes of effort. Twitter is all about icebreakers, and collecting followers who instantly recognize you in a sea of faces. Invest time in your introductions and they&amp;#8217;ll make all the difference to your feed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.contrastmedia.co.za/" target="_blank"&gt;Carla Dewing&lt;/a&gt;, content marketing expert and part-owner of Contrast Media. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/charlene-kingston/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-charlene-kingston.png" alt="Charlene Kingston" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Charlene Kingston @SocialMediaDIY&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#7: Cultivate relationships&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pay attention when someone tweets about your blog posts or retweets something you&amp;#8217;ve shared. When you are building a business, never take it for granted when people help you spread the word. Start by thanking them for the tweet. And &lt;strong&gt;take it a step further: add them to a private list for tweeters and retweeters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At least once every day for five minutes, &lt;strong&gt;review the tweets in that list. Look for great content&lt;/strong&gt; that you might have missed, information from smart people you need to follow and conversation trends you might have missed. &lt;strong&gt;Jump into conversations, retweet items&lt;/strong&gt; your community would appreciate and thank people for sharing great things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But most of all, &lt;strong&gt;get to know more about these people&lt;/strong&gt; who volunteered to become part of your team by sharing your content. It&amp;#8217;s all about relationships, and Twitter helps you build relationships with these important members of your community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://socialmediadiyworkshop.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Charlene Kingston&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Social Media DIY Workshop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/jim-lodico/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-jim-lodico.png" alt="Jim Lodico" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Jim Lodico @jlcommunication&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#8: Engage your audience&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Find ways to &lt;strong&gt;reach out and engage your audience&lt;/strong&gt;. Too many businesses want to just set their Twitter feed on autopilot or constantly push promotional content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although there is a place for the promotional tweet, your feed will receive much more attention if you make it a resource for your followers. Sharing articles of interest, leading discussions on topics important to your industry, answering questions and sometimes just being there can do this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s about creating relationships and building trust and those relationships. Although they may not be clients now, when the time comes, you&amp;#8217;ve already cleared the first hurdle for your followers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jalcommunication.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Jim Lodico&lt;/a&gt;, copywriter and marketing consultant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/sara-hawkins/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-sara-hawkins.png" alt="sara hawkins" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Sara Hawkins @saving4someday&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#9: Be helpful&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Plenty of people are filling up Twitter streams with the tech-equivalent of screaming infomercials to buy things. Effective marketing on Twitter takes time. But it also takes more than just selling or pushing your message.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Engaging and interacting with your consumers in a consistent and helpful way will keep your product or service at top of mind. &lt;strong&gt;Not everyone needs your offering right now. You want to provide information and solutions that keep them reading&lt;/strong&gt;, so when they need what you have, they know you&amp;#8217;re there for them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.savingforsomeday.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Sara Hawkins&lt;/a&gt;, lawyer and blogger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/stephanie-gehman/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-stephanie-gehman.png" alt="Stephanie Gehman" width="85" height="84" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Stephanie Gehman @airport_girl&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#10: Transparency lends credibility&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you mess up, admit it&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don&amp;#8217;t know the answer to a question, admit it. If you&amp;#8217;re inexperienced, admit it. If you&amp;#8217;re willing to admit that your business is not perfect and is a work-in-progress or open to suggestion, your audience is more likely to take you seriously. You &lt;strong&gt;build your company&amp;#8217;s credibility and trustworthiness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The quickest way to lose credibility? If, as a business, you attempt to cover-up, lie or over-promise and under-deliver.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be honest, be real and be transparent&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flyhia.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Stephanie Gehman&lt;/a&gt;, marketing manager for Harrisburg International Airport in Pennsylvania. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bring Twitter Followers Back to Your Website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/tim-ware/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-tim-ware.png" alt="tim ware" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Tim Ware @HyperArts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#11: Use hashtags to create and curate conversations around your brand&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;reward your followers when they participate&lt;/strong&gt; by retweeting them or displaying their tweets on your site or blog.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bergdorf Goodman is a high-end clothing and shoe retailer that is using the Instagram photo app as well as a Twitter hashtag (#BGShoes) to &lt;strong&gt;encourage fans to tweet pictures&lt;/strong&gt; of their shoes (purchased at BG of course) around the city of New York.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 538px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.bergdorfgoodman.com/bg-shoes/"&gt;&lt;img class=" " src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-tim-bergdorf-goodman.png" alt="bergdorf goodman" width="528" height="428" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Bergdorf Goodman is capturing all of the photos and tweets on this interactive map, which gives users an incentive to participate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s another example, the San Francisco Food Bank (@SFFoodBank) gave followers a challenge: Try to spend less than $5/day on food. And tweet about it along the way, using the #hungerchallenge hashtag.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Participants are listed on the &lt;a href="http://hungerchallenge.blogspot.com/"&gt;Hunger Challenge website&lt;/a&gt; (and you can pity them in real time as they tweet about their barely full bellies, all captured in the hashtag stream: http://twitter.com/#!/search/hungerchallenge).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 529px"&gt;&lt;img class=" " src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-tim-carinaost.png" alt="carina ost" width="519" height="197" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Food blogger @CarinaOst is one of the participants able to help increase awareness of hunger in SF and promote the Food Bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 545px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-tim-hunger-challenge.png" alt="hunger challenge" width="535" height="535" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;These tweets were not just blank advertisements; they were an entertaining journal of the struggle of trying to eat on a budget each day!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hyperarts.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Tim Ware&lt;/a&gt;, owner of HyperArts Web Design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/christine-gallagher/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-christine-gallagher.png" alt="christine gallagher" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Christine Gallagher @ChristineG&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#12: Share links back to your website for list-building&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In most cases, people aren&amp;#8217;t going to buy from you right off of a site like Twitter. You need to&lt;strong&gt; shift your thinking&lt;/strong&gt; from &amp;#8220;How can I get this person to buy from me or hire me now?&amp;#8221; to &amp;#8221;How can I bring this person into my community and strengthen the relationship with him/her on an ongoing basis?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to do this is to &lt;strong&gt;encourage visits to your blog or website by providing something of value for free in exchange for email addresses&lt;/strong&gt;. (Make sure what you&amp;#8217;re giving them is extra-juicy and useful!) That way, you have permission to keep in touch and build an ongoing relationship with prospects.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This shouldn&amp;#8217;t be thought of as list-building just for the sake of boosting your subscriber numbers; rather, it&amp;#8217;s a natural continuation of the solid foundation you&amp;#8217;ve begun building with a potential client or customer within the Twitterverse.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://communicatevalue.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Christine Gallagher&lt;/a&gt;, relationship marketing speaker, trainer and coach. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/janet-aronica/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-janet-aronica.png" alt="Janet Aronica" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Janet Aronica @janetaronica&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#13: Tweet links to your blog more often&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#8217;re thinking about using social media for &lt;a href="http://www.hubspot.com/lead-generation-marketing-hub/" target="_blank"&gt;lead generation&lt;/a&gt;, you want to use Twitter as not only a conversation channel, but also as a way to &lt;strong&gt;drive traffic to your content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found a significant increase in traffic from Twitter and engagement with our account when I posted &lt;strong&gt;several tweets of a blog post rather than one the morning. It gives your followers a chance to catch that link&lt;/strong&gt; if they missed it the first time and also targets people in different time zones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t be spammy and go overboard, but sharing your content several times (if it&amp;#8217;s valuable) will give you the extra edge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://janetaronica.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Janet Aronica&lt;/a&gt;, director of marketing and community for oneforty.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fit Twitter Into Your Social Media Marketing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/stephanie-sammons/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-stephanie-sammons.png" alt="stephanie sammons" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Stephanie Sammons @StephSammons&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#14: Connect your LinkedIn account with your Twitter account&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Syncing your LinkedIn account with your Twitter account can make your Twitter activities much more relevant to business. Not only can you share content across both networks simultaneously, but also you can &lt;strong&gt;keep track of your professional connections from LinkedIn and follow their tweets&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are three tips:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to add your Twitter account to your LinkedIn profile&lt;/strong&gt;. Visitors to your profile will be able to follow you on Twitter right there from your profile page! Have more than one Twitter account (perhaps personal and business)? Add them both to your LinkedIn profile and designate your primary account.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the LinkedIn &amp;#8220;Tweets&amp;#8221; application on your LinkedIn profile&lt;/strong&gt; and immediately go through and follow each of your LinkedIn connections who have Twitter profiles. In most cases, your professional connections are going to follow you back!&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Twitter list of your LinkedIn connections automatically&lt;/strong&gt; with the click of a button using the Twitter application in LinkedIn. This makes it easy to follow the stream of updates on Twitter coming from your professional connections.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter is a firehose of information, data and resources. I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of making sense out of that data and making it more relevant to your professional network! Integrating your Twitter account with LinkedIn is a great way to do this. To learn more, catch this article from Social Media Examiner: &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com//how-to-use-linkedin-with-twitter-for-better-networking/" target="_blank"&gt;How to Use LinkedIn With Twitter for Better Networking&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stephaniesammons.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Stephanie Sammons&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO of Wired Advisor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make Twitter Tools Work for You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/ben-pickering/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-ben-pickering.png" alt="Ben Pickering" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Ben Pickering @bpicks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#15: Take advantage of tools to help curate and share relevant content&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sending out 140-character messages every so often may not seem like a task that requires marketing automation software but, to the contrary, these tools can greatly &lt;strong&gt;improve the effectiveness of your Twitter marketing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a slew of services available, some free and some paid, to help manage your Twitter account. At Strutta, we use the &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank"&gt;HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; dashboard to &lt;strong&gt;track Twitter activity&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be easily categorized into multiple streams that we follow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We also use &lt;a href="http://summify.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Summify&lt;/a&gt; to help &lt;strong&gt;filter through the noise&lt;/strong&gt; and surface news that is most relevant to our industry. This enables us to find content that is both useful to consume and valuable to share with our followers via retweeting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sharing relevant content from other trusted sources helps establish your credibility, especially when mixed with your own original content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-pickering-schedule-messages.jpg" alt="schedule messages" width="480" height="360" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;When it comes to sharing, having a platform like HootSuite where you can schedule tweets is extremely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Given the short shelf-life of a tweet, you can easily &lt;strong&gt;schedule content to be pushed out at pre-set intervals to maximize visibility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.strutta.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Ben Pickering&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Strutta. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/andrea-vahl/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-andrea-vahl.png" alt="Andrea Vahl" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Andrea Vahl @AndreaVahl&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#16: Add columns of searches in HootSuite&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;have a separate tab in HootSuite set up only for searches&lt;/strong&gt; that I want to monitor throughout the day. I have several columns of searches on this tab so I can see in one glance what people are talking about with respect to those searches at any given moment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I use a combination of searching on hashtags and searching on just keywords.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 489px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-vahl-add-searches-in-hootsuite.png" alt="searches in hootsuite" width="479" height="242" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;In this screenshot, I show one search I have with the hashtag #Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then &lt;strong&gt;I also have a search where I put the words &amp;#8220;how do I&amp;#8221; which will give me an exact match on that phrase, and the word &amp;#8220;Facebook&amp;#8221; which will show both of those key phrases anywhere within the tweet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking for people asking questions about Facebook that I can help with. I can then answer the person&amp;#8217;s question and perhaps follow them. When you help people who have questions about your niche on Twitter, you stand out as a leader and authority in your field.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you are authentically helping people out&lt;/strong&gt; and not giving a sales pitch. So if you want to watch for people asking questions about your niche&#8212;which is yoga, for example&#8212;you would put the keywords &amp;#8220;how do I&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;yoga.&amp;#8221; Or you may find that a better search question could be &amp;#8220;where do I.&amp;#8221; Test out different keyword phrases to see what works best for your business.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.andreavahl.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Andrea Vahl&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;/em&gt;Facebook Marketing All-in-One for Dummies&lt;em&gt; and Facebook community manager for Social Media Examiner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Still Need Help?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/jamie-turner/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-jamie-turner.png" alt="jamie turner" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Jamie Turner @60Second Tweets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#17: Get a Twitter tutorial from your teenager&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was at a conference last week where a professor who specializes in new and emerging media made this confession&#8212;he frequently asks his students to teach him how to use Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and other social media tools.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He went on to explain that at one point, during one of his tutorials, a student turned to him and said, &amp;#8220;Aren&amp;#8217;t I paying YOU to teach me this stuff?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The truth is, if you&amp;#8217;re like most businesspeople, it&amp;#8217;s very hard to keep up with all of the changes taking place. One way to get more efficient about using Twitter and other tools is to &lt;strong&gt;sit down with someone younger than you and ask him or her for a front-lines tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oh sure, we all understand the CONCEPT of Twitter, but when it comes to the practical application or the unwritten rules, it&amp;#8217;s hard to keep up. The solution, I&amp;#8217;ve found, is to not be shy about asking someone younger for a brief, in-the-trenches tutorial. In the long run, it&amp;#8217;ll save you hours and hours of anguish.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.60secondmarketer.com/KeynoteSpeaker" target="_blank"&gt;Jamie Turner&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;/em&gt;How to Make Money with Social Media&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think? What&amp;#8217;s your favorite Twitter marketing tip?&lt;/strong&gt; What works best for your business? Please share your comments in the box below. &lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2F17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="17 Twitter Marketing Tips From the Pros &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div name="googleone_share_1" style="position:relative;z-index:5;float: left; margin-right: 10px;"&gt;&lt;g:plusone size="medium" count="1" href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/"&gt;&lt;/g:plusone&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Twitter Marketing Tips From the Pros</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/category/how-to/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img class="alignright" style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;" title="social media how to" src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/how-to-pose.png" alt="social media how to" width="190" height="166" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Are you looking for fresh ideas to improve your Twitter marketing?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We sought out hot Twitter tips from the pros. Keep reading for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ow&amp;#8217;s not the time to let your Twitter marketing go stale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter has already &lt;a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/twitter-expects-incredible-growth-with-ios-5-integration/59073" target="_blank"&gt;grown more in the last 9 months&lt;/a&gt; than in the last 5 years and &lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1783467/fresh-crispy-apple-twitters-could-deep-fry-facebooks-future" target="_blank"&gt;this trend is expected to continue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;How does Twitter fit into your social media marketing? Here are &lt;strong&gt;17 Twitter marketing tips shared by Social Media Examiner&amp;#8217;s writers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;span id="more-12149"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improve Your Tweets&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/mari-smith/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-mari-smith.png" alt="Mari Smith" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Mari Smith @marismith&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#1: Share valuable content in your own voice&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do your best to &lt;strong&gt;craft your content tweets, @replies and promotional tweets all with a seamless style that matches your personality and/or brand&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ideally, you want people to read your tweets and feel naturally compelled to click on your links and retweet you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You just want to &lt;strong&gt;add value and have no agenda&lt;/strong&gt; or attachment to &amp;#8220;making the sale,&amp;#8221; yet you&amp;#8217;re strategic and mindful about how you tweet. Then you&amp;#8217;ll see a marked improvement in your retweet and click-through rates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 370px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-smith-1-content-tweet.jpg" alt="content tweet" width="360" height="288" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;A content tweet from Mari with a link to an informative blog post, and an upbeat comment in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://marismith.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Mari Smith&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;/em&gt;Facebook Marketing: An Hour a Day&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/debbie-hemley/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-debbie-hemley.png" alt="Debbie Hemley" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Debbie Hemley @dhemley&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#2: Use keywords in your tweets&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keywords have been and continue to be a relevant and driving force for web content (whether we&amp;#8217;re talking about a website, blog post, Facebook update or a tweet). Keywords are the backbone of content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;d have to say hands-down, my best &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/26-twitter-tips-for-enhancing-your-tweets/"&gt;Twitter marketing tip&lt;/a&gt; for business is to &lt;strong&gt;make a list of keywords that best describe your business and industry. Use these words as you compose your 140-character posts&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Think quality over quantity. Make every character and tweet count!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://debbiehemley.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Debbie Hemley&lt;/a&gt;, social media consultant and blogger. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/shane-snow/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-shane-snow.png" alt="shane snow" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Shane Snow @shanesnow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#3: Share links to useful content&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sharing links to useful content is, statistically speaking, more effective at growing and retaining followers than &amp;#8220;engaging&amp;#8221; with them in conversation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s not to say that conversations aren&amp;#8217;t useful in helping people to like you, but if you want to grow your fan base, you need to &lt;strong&gt;share more links than you do @replies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://contently.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Shane Snow&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of Contently.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/nichole-kelly/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-nichole-kelly.png" alt="nichole kelly" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Nichole Kelly @Nichole_Kelly&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#4: Use search features to discover what your clients want&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use the search feature in a Twitter tool like &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank"&gt;HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;watch for conversations about a problem your business can solve&lt;/strong&gt;. It will give you insight into what is on your prospects&amp;#8217; minds and provide an open door for you to help them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try providing a link to a great article or video that answers their question. This one action could lead to an ongoing dialogue that in turn may lead to a customer relationship later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://fullfrontalroi.com/social-media-measurement-bootcamp" target="_blank"&gt;Nichole Kelly&lt;/a&gt;, publisher of FullFrontalROI.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improve Your Networking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/kristi-hines/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-kristi-hines.png" alt="kristi hines" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Kristi Hines @kikolani&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#5: Connect with the right people and tweet with them&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are two crucial things businesses should focus on when implementing their Twitter strategy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first is not finding just anyone to follow in hopes that they follow you back, but finding relevant people to follow who are more likely to follow you back. You can bloat your account to 100,000+ followers, but if they are not interested in your content, it gets you nowhere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You need to be using tools such as &lt;a href="http://followerwonk.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Follower Wonk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.twellow.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Twellow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://wefollow.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Wefollow&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;find people who are in your region (if you&amp;#8217;re a local business) and interested in your industry&lt;/strong&gt;. Then start following them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The second is after you find your targeted audience, don&amp;#8217;t just tweet &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; them&#8212;&lt;strong&gt;tweet &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; them. Follow their conversations; add in your two cents from time to time&lt;/strong&gt;. Follow anyone who talks about your brand and thank them for their compliments or help them with their concerns. Follow anyone who talks about your industry and show why you are an authority.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Doing these things will help you run a successful Twitter campaign that will give your brand exposure as a leader in your industry!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://kikolani.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Kristi Hines&lt;/a&gt;, Internet marketing specialist with Vertical Measures and author of Kikolani.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/carla-dewing/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-carla-dewing.png" alt="Carla Dewing" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Carla Dewing @CarlaDewing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#6: Use a classic icebreaker&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most followers become nameless, faceless numbers on a follower list. Remember when networking used to be about meeting people face to face? Icebreakers were important then, and they&amp;#8217;re just as important now in the virtual world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Icebreakers help you &lt;strong&gt;share a common connection with a stranger&#8212;and make you memorable enough to begin and sustain a long-term relationship&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you find relevant tweets from among your followers, retweet their blog link&#8212;and follow the author&amp;#8217;s feed. Then &lt;strong&gt;send them an @message, detailing something insightful about their blog post&lt;/strong&gt;. At the end of the tweet, link to a similar post you&amp;#8217;ve written.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This should result in more blog comments, retweets and followers, all from 10 minutes of effort. Twitter is all about icebreakers, and collecting followers who instantly recognize you in a sea of faces. Invest time in your introductions and they&amp;#8217;ll make all the difference to your feed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.contrastmedia.co.za/" target="_blank"&gt;Carla Dewing&lt;/a&gt;, content marketing expert and part-owner of Contrast Media. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/charlene-kingston/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-charlene-kingston.png" alt="Charlene Kingston" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Charlene Kingston @SocialMediaDIY&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#7: Cultivate relationships&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pay attention when someone tweets about your blog posts or retweets something you&amp;#8217;ve shared. When you are building a business, never take it for granted when people help you spread the word. Start by thanking them for the tweet. And &lt;strong&gt;take it a step further: add them to a private list for tweeters and retweeters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At least once every day for five minutes, &lt;strong&gt;review the tweets in that list. Look for great content&lt;/strong&gt; that you might have missed, information from smart people you need to follow and conversation trends you might have missed. &lt;strong&gt;Jump into conversations, retweet items&lt;/strong&gt; your community would appreciate and thank people for sharing great things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But most of all, &lt;strong&gt;get to know more about these people&lt;/strong&gt; who volunteered to become part of your team by sharing your content. It&amp;#8217;s all about relationships, and Twitter helps you build relationships with these important members of your community.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://socialmediadiyworkshop.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Charlene Kingston&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Social Media DIY Workshop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/jim-lodico/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-jim-lodico.png" alt="Jim Lodico" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Jim Lodico @jlcommunication&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#8: Engage your audience&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Find ways to &lt;strong&gt;reach out and engage your audience&lt;/strong&gt;. Too many businesses want to just set their Twitter feed on autopilot or constantly push promotional content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although there is a place for the promotional tweet, your feed will receive much more attention if you make it a resource for your followers. Sharing articles of interest, leading discussions on topics important to your industry, answering questions and sometimes just being there can do this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s about creating relationships and building trust and those relationships. Although they may not be clients now, when the time comes, you&amp;#8217;ve already cleared the first hurdle for your followers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jalcommunication.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Jim Lodico&lt;/a&gt;, copywriter and marketing consultant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/sara-hawkins/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-sara-hawkins.png" alt="sara hawkins" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Sara Hawkins @saving4someday&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#9: Be helpful&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Plenty of people are filling up Twitter streams with the tech-equivalent of screaming infomercials to buy things. Effective marketing on Twitter takes time. But it also takes more than just selling or pushing your message.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Engaging and interacting with your consumers in a consistent and helpful way will keep your product or service at top of mind. &lt;strong&gt;Not everyone needs your offering right now. You want to provide information and solutions that keep them reading&lt;/strong&gt;, so when they need what you have, they know you&amp;#8217;re there for them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.savingforsomeday.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Sara Hawkins&lt;/a&gt;, lawyer and blogger.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/stephanie-gehman/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-stephanie-gehman.png" alt="Stephanie Gehman" width="85" height="84" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Stephanie Gehman @airport_girl&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#10: Transparency lends credibility&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you mess up, admit it&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don&amp;#8217;t know the answer to a question, admit it. If you&amp;#8217;re inexperienced, admit it. If you&amp;#8217;re willing to admit that your business is not perfect and is a work-in-progress or open to suggestion, your audience is more likely to take you seriously. You &lt;strong&gt;build your company&amp;#8217;s credibility and trustworthiness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The quickest way to lose credibility? If, as a business, you attempt to cover-up, lie or over-promise and under-deliver.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be honest, be real and be transparent&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flyhia.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Stephanie Gehman&lt;/a&gt;, marketing manager for Harrisburg International Airport in Pennsylvania. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bring Twitter Followers Back to Your Website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/tim-ware/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-tim-ware.png" alt="tim ware" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Tim Ware @HyperArts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#11: Use hashtags to create and curate conversations around your brand&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;reward your followers when they participate&lt;/strong&gt; by retweeting them or displaying their tweets on your site or blog.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bergdorf Goodman is a high-end clothing and shoe retailer that is using the Instagram photo app as well as a Twitter hashtag (#BGShoes) to &lt;strong&gt;encourage fans to tweet pictures&lt;/strong&gt; of their shoes (purchased at BG of course) around the city of New York.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 538px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.bergdorfgoodman.com/bg-shoes/"&gt;&lt;img class=" " src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-tim-bergdorf-goodman.png" alt="bergdorf goodman" width="528" height="428" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Bergdorf Goodman is capturing all of the photos and tweets on this interactive map, which gives users an incentive to participate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s another example, the San Francisco Food Bank (@SFFoodBank) gave followers a challenge: Try to spend less than $5/day on food. And tweet about it along the way, using the #hungerchallenge hashtag.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Participants are listed on the &lt;a href="http://hungerchallenge.blogspot.com/"&gt;Hunger Challenge website&lt;/a&gt; (and you can pity them in real time as they tweet about their barely full bellies, all captured in the hashtag stream: http://twitter.com/#!/search/hungerchallenge).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 529px"&gt;&lt;img class=" " src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-tim-carinaost.png" alt="carina ost" width="519" height="197" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Food blogger @CarinaOst is one of the participants able to help increase awareness of hunger in SF and promote the Food Bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 545px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-tim-hunger-challenge.png" alt="hunger challenge" width="535" height="535" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;These tweets were not just blank advertisements; they were an entertaining journal of the struggle of trying to eat on a budget each day!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hyperarts.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Tim Ware&lt;/a&gt;, owner of HyperArts Web Design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/christine-gallagher/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-christine-gallagher.png" alt="christine gallagher" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Christine Gallagher @ChristineG&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#12: Share links back to your website for list-building&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In most cases, people aren&amp;#8217;t going to buy from you right off of a site like Twitter. You need to&lt;strong&gt; shift your thinking&lt;/strong&gt; from &amp;#8220;How can I get this person to buy from me or hire me now?&amp;#8221; to &amp;#8221;How can I bring this person into my community and strengthen the relationship with him/her on an ongoing basis?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to do this is to &lt;strong&gt;encourage visits to your blog or website by providing something of value for free in exchange for email addresses&lt;/strong&gt;. (Make sure what you&amp;#8217;re giving them is extra-juicy and useful!) That way, you have permission to keep in touch and build an ongoing relationship with prospects.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This shouldn&amp;#8217;t be thought of as list-building just for the sake of boosting your subscriber numbers; rather, it&amp;#8217;s a natural continuation of the solid foundation you&amp;#8217;ve begun building with a potential client or customer within the Twitterverse.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://communicatevalue.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Christine Gallagher&lt;/a&gt;, relationship marketing speaker, trainer and coach. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/janet-aronica/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-janet-aronica.png" alt="Janet Aronica" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Janet Aronica @janetaronica&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#13: Tweet links to your blog more often&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#8217;re thinking about using social media for &lt;a href="http://www.hubspot.com/lead-generation-marketing-hub/" target="_blank"&gt;lead generation&lt;/a&gt;, you want to use Twitter as not only a conversation channel, but also as a way to &lt;strong&gt;drive traffic to your content&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found a significant increase in traffic from Twitter and engagement with our account when I posted &lt;strong&gt;several tweets of a blog post rather than one the morning. It gives your followers a chance to catch that link&lt;/strong&gt; if they missed it the first time and also targets people in different time zones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t be spammy and go overboard, but sharing your content several times (if it&amp;#8217;s valuable) will give you the extra edge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://janetaronica.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Janet Aronica&lt;/a&gt;, director of marketing and community for oneforty.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fit Twitter Into Your Social Media Marketing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/stephanie-sammons/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-stephanie-sammons.png" alt="stephanie sammons" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Stephanie Sammons @StephSammons&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#14: Connect your LinkedIn account with your Twitter account&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Syncing your LinkedIn account with your Twitter account can make your Twitter activities much more relevant to business. Not only can you share content across both networks simultaneously, but also you can &lt;strong&gt;keep track of your professional connections from LinkedIn and follow their tweets&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here are three tips:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to add your Twitter account to your LinkedIn profile&lt;/strong&gt;. Visitors to your profile will be able to follow you on Twitter right there from your profile page! Have more than one Twitter account (perhaps personal and business)? Add them both to your LinkedIn profile and designate your primary account.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install the LinkedIn &amp;#8220;Tweets&amp;#8221; application on your LinkedIn profile&lt;/strong&gt; and immediately go through and follow each of your LinkedIn connections who have Twitter profiles. In most cases, your professional connections are going to follow you back!&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Twitter list of your LinkedIn connections automatically&lt;/strong&gt; with the click of a button using the Twitter application in LinkedIn. This makes it easy to follow the stream of updates on Twitter coming from your professional connections.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Twitter is a firehose of information, data and resources. I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of making sense out of that data and making it more relevant to your professional network! Integrating your Twitter account with LinkedIn is a great way to do this. To learn more, catch this article from Social Media Examiner: &lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com//how-to-use-linkedin-with-twitter-for-better-networking/" target="_blank"&gt;How to Use LinkedIn With Twitter for Better Networking&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stephaniesammons.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Stephanie Sammons&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CEO of Wired Advisor.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Make Twitter Tools Work for You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/ben-pickering/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-ben-pickering.png" alt="Ben Pickering" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Ben Pickering @bpicks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#15: Take advantage of tools to help curate and share relevant content&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sending out 140-character messages every so often may not seem like a task that requires marketing automation software but, to the contrary, these tools can greatly &lt;strong&gt;improve the effectiveness of your Twitter marketing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a slew of services available, some free and some paid, to help manage your Twitter account. At Strutta, we use the &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank"&gt;HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; dashboard to &lt;strong&gt;track Twitter activity&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be easily categorized into multiple streams that we follow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We also use &lt;a href="http://summify.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Summify&lt;/a&gt; to help &lt;strong&gt;filter through the noise&lt;/strong&gt; and surface news that is most relevant to our industry. This enables us to find content that is both useful to consume and valuable to share with our followers via retweeting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sharing relevant content from other trusted sources helps establish your credibility, especially when mixed with your own original content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 490px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-pickering-schedule-messages.jpg" alt="schedule messages" width="480" height="360" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;When it comes to sharing, having a platform like HootSuite where you can schedule tweets is extremely helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Given the short shelf-life of a tweet, you can easily &lt;strong&gt;schedule content to be pushed out at pre-set intervals to maximize visibility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.strutta.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Ben Pickering&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of Strutta. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/andrea-vahl/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-andrea-vahl.png" alt="Andrea Vahl" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Andrea Vahl @AndreaVahl&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#16: Add columns of searches in HootSuite&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;have a separate tab in HootSuite set up only for searches&lt;/strong&gt; that I want to monitor throughout the day. I have several columns of searches on this tab so I can see in one glance what people are talking about with respect to those searches at any given moment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I use a combination of searching on hashtags and searching on just keywords.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 489px"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/1011ck-vahl-add-searches-in-hootsuite.png" alt="searches in hootsuite" width="479" height="242" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;In this screenshot, I show one search I have with the hashtag #Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then &lt;strong&gt;I also have a search where I put the words &amp;#8220;how do I&amp;#8221; which will give me an exact match on that phrase, and the word &amp;#8220;Facebook&amp;#8221; which will show both of those key phrases anywhere within the tweet&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking for people asking questions about Facebook that I can help with. I can then answer the person&amp;#8217;s question and perhaps follow them. When you help people who have questions about your niche on Twitter, you stand out as a leader and authority in your field.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you are authentically helping people out&lt;/strong&gt; and not giving a sales pitch. So if you want to watch for people asking questions about your niche&#8212;which is yoga, for example&#8212;you would put the keywords &amp;#8220;how do I&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;yoga.&amp;#8221; Or you may find that a better search question could be &amp;#8220;where do I.&amp;#8221; Test out different keyword phrases to see what works best for your business.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.andreavahl.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Andrea Vahl&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;/em&gt;Facebook Marketing All-in-One for Dummies&lt;em&gt; and Facebook community manager for Social Media Examiner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Still Need Help?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 95px"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/author/jamie-turner/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/images/sme-contributor-jamie-turner.png" alt="jamie turner" width="85" height="85" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;Jamie Turner @60Second Tweets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3&gt;#17: Get a Twitter tutorial from your teenager&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was at a conference last week where a professor who specializes in new and emerging media made this confession&#8212;he frequently asks his students to teach him how to use Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and other social media tools.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He went on to explain that at one point, during one of his tutorials, a student turned to him and said, &amp;#8220;Aren&amp;#8217;t I paying YOU to teach me this stuff?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The truth is, if you&amp;#8217;re like most businesspeople, it&amp;#8217;s very hard to keep up with all of the changes taking place. One way to get more efficient about using Twitter and other tools is to &lt;strong&gt;sit down with someone younger than you and ask him or her for a front-lines tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oh sure, we all understand the CONCEPT of Twitter, but when it comes to the practical application or the unwritten rules, it&amp;#8217;s hard to keep up. The solution, I&amp;#8217;ve found, is to not be shy about asking someone younger for a brief, in-the-trenches tutorial. In the long run, it&amp;#8217;ll save you hours and hours of anguish.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.60secondmarketer.com/KeynoteSpeaker" target="_blank"&gt;Jamie Turner&lt;/a&gt;, co-author of &lt;/em&gt;How to Make Money with Social Media&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think? What&amp;#8217;s your favorite Twitter marketing tip?&lt;/strong&gt; What works best for your business? Please share your comments in the box below. &lt;div class="wp_twitter_button" style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;"&gt; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/share?counturl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.socialmediaexaminer.com%2F17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros%2F" class="twitter-share-button" data-url="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/" data-count="vertical" data-via="smexaminer" data-lang="" data-text="17 Twitter Marketing Tips From the Pros &amp;raquo; Social Media Examiner"&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div name="googleone_share_1" style="position:relative;z-index:5;float: left; margin-right: 10px;"&gt;&lt;g:plusone size="medium" count="1" href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/"&gt;&lt;/g:plusone&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/17-twitter-marketing-tips-from-the-pros/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Is Quietly Building A Huge Business (ERTS, CMCSA)</title>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://ads.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=8578e22ddc5819af75d455bbd60976b3&amp;p=2"&gt;&lt;img alt="" style="border: 0;" border="0" src="http://ads.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=8578e22ddc5819af75d455bbd60976b3&amp;p=2"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br clear="both" style="clear: both;"/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This note is from BI Research, a new tech-industry intelligence service. The service is currently in beta and free. To learn more and sign up, please&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/sign-up-for-business-insider-research" target="_blank" title="Business Insider Research Sign-Up"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;click here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float:right;" src="http://static7.businessinsider.com/image/4e7b509369bedd242f000019-400-/twitter-ad-revenue-per-user-per-year-demand-media-facebook-microsoft-yahoo.png" border="0" alt="twitter ad revenue per user per year demand media facebook microsoft yahoo" width="400" /&gt;The conventional wisdom about &lt;a class="hidden_link" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/blackboard/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; is that it may be a very nice product, but it doesn't have much of a business. And up until recently, that was true. And the fact that Twitter has been mostly dodging questions about its business metrics helps perpetuate the idea.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But we think it's not true anymore.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a bit of fumbling, which is normal for a company exploring a new medium, Twitter has been quietly but steadily rolling out its ad units. And evidence thus far suggests that they have been performing really well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yesterday &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-promoted-tweets-2011-11"&gt;SAI reporter Ellis Hamburger&lt;/a&gt; "spoke with&amp;nbsp;Hilary Smith, SVP of Communications for Digital content at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/blackboard/nbc" class="hidden_link"&gt;NBC&lt;/a&gt;. She informed me that Promoted Tweets NBC has purchased have been shockingly successful, and have received a ton of engagement from Twitter users." Hamburger wrote that when he first saw Twitter ads they were actually useful and relevant, and this has been this analyst's experience as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago &lt;a class="hidden_link" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/blackboard/electronic-arts"&gt;Electronic Arts&lt;/a&gt; said its Promoted Trend also &lt;a href="http://www.marketingmagazine.co.uk/News/MostRead/1102858/Electronic-Arts-claims-Twitter-ads-exceeded-expectations/"&gt;exceeded expectations&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In our conversations with ad industry insiders as part of our special report on Twitter's business, they said Twitter's ads showed lots of promise. They said Twitter still needs to work on some aspects, but Twitter seems to be improving every day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Therefore, this is what we're prepared to say about Twitter's business:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's still early days&amp;mdash;and that's the point.&lt;/strong&gt; Right now, Twitter's "promoted tweets" (ad tweets that show up in a user's Twitter stream) only show up on Twitter.com. Soon they will show up in Twitter's broader application ecosystem. And the ad system keeps getting refined: for example, ads can only be targeted on a handful of metrics. What we're seeing right now is very impressive&amp;mdash;and yet it's just an inkling of the future.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter ads have the potential of being a drug for marketers.&lt;/strong&gt; Twitter charges ads by "engagement" (clicks, replies, retweets or follows), and ads can generate social media conversations around a brand. In other words, Twitter may have cracked the code on allowing advertisers to create genuine social media conversations around a brand. That would be a tool marketers simply couldn't get enough of.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter is the new TV.&lt;/strong&gt; It's where you tune in to see what's going on around the world (and with your friends). And in exchange, there is limited commercial interruption. And on the whole, that interruption is fine for users and lucrative for publishers.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/how-big-twitter-can-be-2011-9"&gt;We previously estimated Twitter's revenue opportunity at $2 billion&lt;/a&gt;, using low revenue-per-user estimates compared to Twitter's peers. This might prove to be the low end.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-business-and-opportunity-2011-10"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't Miss Our Special Report On Twitter's Business And Valuation&amp;nbsp;&amp;rarr;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are we missing? Email comments and questions to pegobry@businessinsider.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This note was published as part of BI Research, a new industry intelligence service from Business Insider. The service is currently in beta and is free. To learn more and sign up, please&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/sign-up-for-business-insider-research" target="_blank" title="Business Insider Research Sign-Up"&gt;&lt;span&gt;click here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please follow &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/research"&gt;BI Research&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/BIR_Internet"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://facebook.com/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-is-quietly-building-a-huge-business-2011-11#comments"&gt;Join the conversation about this story &amp;#187;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;See Also:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/imminent-threat-2011-11"&gt;Returning To America After A Long Time Abroad, The Changes Hit You In The Head Like A Baseball Bat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/my-views-on-corporations-and-taxes-2011-11"&gt;MARK CUBAN: There's Only One Reason Why CEOs Want Lower Taxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/must-watch-citis-willem-buiter-says-europe-might-just-have-days-before-a-financial-catastrophe-2011-11"&gt;MUST-READ: Citi's Willem Buiter Says Europe Could Just Have Days Before A Financial Catastrophe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br clear="both" style="clear: both;"/&gt; &lt;br clear="both" style="clear: both;"/&gt; &lt;a href="http://ads.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=8578e22ddc5819af75d455bbd60976b3&amp;p=1"&gt;&lt;img alt="" style="border: 0;" border="0" src="http://ads.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=8578e22ddc5819af75d455bbd60976b3&amp;p=1"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt="" height="0" width="0" border="0" style="display:none" src="http://segment-pixel.invitemedia.com/pixel?code=Business&amp;partnerID=167&amp;key=segment"/&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="0" width="0" border="0" style="display:none" src="http://insight.adsrvr.org/track/evnt/?ct=0:ef7jeah&amp;adv=wouzn4v&amp;fmt=3"/&gt;&lt;div class="feedflare"&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?a=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:yIl2AUoC8zA"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?a=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:F7zBnMyn0Lo"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?i=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?a=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:V_sGLiPBpWU"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?i=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?a=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:qj6IDK7rITs"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?a=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:gIN9vFwOqvQ"&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/businessinsider?i=JUt-Id69LpU:REyQVm3gfCA:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/businessinsider/~4/JUt-Id69LpU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-is-quietly-building-a-huge-business-2011-11?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+businessinsider+%28Business+Insider%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.businessinsider.com/twitter-is-quietly-building-a-huge-business-2011-11?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+businessinsider+%28Business+Insider%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Windows Phone the Best Mobile Platform You&#8217;re Not Using?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; In the world of smartphones, Windows Phone 7 is barely a blip. It has, by some estimates less than 6% market share. Android now owns half the market and iOS about 26%. This isn&#8217;t right. You see the Windows Phone 7 is a good -- possibly great -- mobile platform. It&#8217;s better, in my opinion, than Android and nibbling at the heels of my favorite, iOS and the iPhone.</description>
      <link>http://news.yahoo.com/windows-phone-best-mobile-platform-youre-not-using-163226145.html</link>
      <guid>http://news.yahoo.com/windows-phone-best-mobile-platform-youre-not-using-163226145.html</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
