<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Google+ Events: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Google Introduces Google+ Events: Google+ Events are &#8220;for all the moments that matter&#8212;before, during and after.&#8221; Google+ Events will sync with Calendar integration. You can also share photos in real time with Party Mode, and after the event you can see everyone&#8217;s pictures in one place in chronological order and with comments.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=si9Li4ehv74New Apple Podcasts App Available: The Podcasts app is the easiest way to discover, subscribe to and play your favorite podcasts on Apple mobile devices.Explore free audio and video podcasts from the Podcasts Catalog, and play the most popular podcasts, organized for you by topic, with the new Top Stations feature.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:What&#8217;s your favorite Facebook app?Can podcasting grow your business?What do you think about Facebook&#8217;s recent integration with WordPress blogs?Google +1 Recommendations Launch Across the Web: Google+ is &#8220;rolling out a new feature of the +1 button in platform preview: when users hover over a +1 button, they will see recommendations for other great content on your site.&#8221;"See related apps and recommendations from friends."It&#8217;s Easier for Facebook Admins to Change Page URLs: Facebook page admins used to have to submit a request to change their Facebook page username (http://www.facebook.com/username), but page admins can now change usernames themselves.It's easy to change your Facebook page username now.Hookflash Brings Video Calling to Your LinkedIn Network: Hookflash for iPad is integrated with LinkedIn. &#8220;Hookflash helps professionals communicate effectively with their peers and colleagues with video, voice and messaging on the iPad.&#8221;"Simply tap the LinkedIn contact you want to reach on Hookflash and instantly chat with them (video, voice and text)."Here are a couple of useful social media tools worth noting:Gripevine: a simple platform where annoyed customers can post their gripes on the site.An automated system immediately informs the targeted company that a gripe exists to offer them a chance to solve the problem.Wishpond Social Offers: a self-serve application that puts businesses in total control of their own limited-time offers on Facebook and their website.YYoga used Wishpond Social Offers and generated 1000 participants in their offer in less than 48 hours.And don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-events-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/google-events-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Social Media Day 2012 [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Today we celebrate the digital revolution happening right before our eyes. From finding jobs through Twitter to rekindling old friendships on Facebook, social media impacts many of our lives. It empowers people everywhere to have their voices be heard and connect from miles apart &#8212; and that&#8217;s something worth celebrating. Mashable launched Social Media Day in 2010, and both the event and social media use have grown tremendously in that time. The event has been declared official by 17 cities worldwide and three U.S. states. This year, we have tens of thousands of people participating throughout the world. Meetups are ranging from small community gatherings discussing social media and local businesses to huge events featuring speakers and performances. You can follow by tracking the #smday hashtag on Twitter, Google+, Instagram and Flickr, and by connecting with fellow social media fans at a Social Media Day Meetup near you. How has social media affected you? What digital communities and connections have changed your life? Tell us in the comments below. Now celebrate your online communities by getting offline at a Social Media Day event!</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/mashable-social-media-day-2012/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/mashable-social-media-day-2012/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Relationship: College Students and Their Smartphones [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>College students aren't just concerned with getting good grades and finding the best parties. More than ever, they're using their smartphones to navigate life on campus. On the bus, waiting in line, in bed, on the treadmill and even while driving, college students can't seem to put their phones down. Fifty-two percent say they often check their phones before getting out of bed in the morning, according to one study. Nearly half do so while in bed at night before they fall asleep. Thirty-five percent say they sometimes use their phones while driving but stopped at a red light, and nearly 20% say they sometimes use them while the wheels are even moving. But it's not all addiction and d&#8230; Continue reading... More About: smartphones</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/smartphones-college-students-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/smartphones-college-students-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Relationship: College Students and Their Smartphones [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>College students aren't just concerned with getting good grades and finding the best parties. More than ever, they're using their smartphones to navigate life on campus. On the bus, waiting in line, in bed, on the treadmill and even while driving, college students can't seem to put their phones down. Fifty-two percent say they often check their phones before getting out of bed in the morning, according to one study. Nearly half do so while in bed at night before they fall asleep. Thirty-five percent say they sometimes use their phones while driving but stopped at a red light, and nearly 20% say they sometimes use them while the wheels are even moving. But it's not all addiction and d&#8230; Continue reading... More About: smartphones</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/smartphones-college-students-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/smartphones-college-students-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Hashtag History Gets a Musical Tribute [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>Here's a funky little piece of weekend edutainment: the history of the Twitter hashtag as performed by horn player and YouTube music video maker Paul the Trombonist. Raps interspersed with jazzy trombone interludes tell how the now-ubiquitous number sign followed by letters went from a random nothing on the social network to something tweeters today rely on to spread important news, tell jokes and tell they world they're #winning. We haven't vigorously vetted Paul's history lesson, but it checks out against a quick web search. If Paul the Trombonist looks familiar to you, it's because he's also the man behind "Playing With Your Phone While Sitting on the Toilet," a viral hit from&#8230; Continue reading... More About: Twitter, Video, viral videos</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/twitter-hashtag-history/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/twitter-hashtag-history/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch the Entire Google I/O Day One Keynote [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>If you've missed out on some of the action from the first day of Google's I/O conference, here's a chance to relive it: Google has made available the video of the entire 2-hour opening keynote. And what a keynote it was! Google has arguably outdone even Apple with an action-packed event, showcasing a bunch of exciting new products, including Android Jelly Bean, Nexus 7 and Nexus Q. Even with all these new products, the highlight of the event was definitely Sergey Brin's bit, who showed the attendants a spectacular demo of Project Glass. See the entire keynote in the video above and tell us what you think in the comments. More About: Google, I/O, keynote, Video</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/google-io-day-one-keynote-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/google-io-day-one-keynote-video/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is AWS and How Did It Bring Down Instagram?</title>
      <description>Instagram has been insta-tripping since Friday night and here's why: A powerful storm in northern Virginia that took out the servers it runs on. Maybe you're wondering how a storm on the East Coast killed access to your favorite photo sharing app, which is based in San Francisco. That's because Instagram, like many major web companies, uses an even bigger web company -- Amazon -- to host its traffic and data. An enterprise cloud-computing product called Amazon Web Services (AWS) powers businesses in 190 countries worldwide -- "hundreds of thousands" of startups and mature companies, all told, according Amazon's website. Pinterest, Netflix and Heroku are among the notable sites and se&#8230; Continue reading... More About: amazon web services, instagram</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/aws-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/30/aws-instagram/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Drops LinkedIn Partnership</title>
      <description>LinkedIn announced via a blog post on Friday that Twitter would no longer be partnering with the business-networking site to sync updates from one site to the other. This ends a partnership that began in 2009. LinkedIn users can still create updates on the site and click a button to share to Twitter as well, but the the reverse is no longer possible. The LinkedIn post by Ryan Roslansky, head of content products at LinkedIn, pointed to Twitter's own Friday blog post about "delivering a consistent experience on Twitter." Perhaps Twitter wants to separate itself from the business networking company after the recent password breach in which 6 million LinkedIn passwords were stolen. Li&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Drops LinkedIn Partnership</title>
      <description>LinkedIn announced via a blog post on Friday that Twitter would no longer be partnering with the business-networking site to sync updates from one site to the other. This ends a partnership that began in 2009. LinkedIn users can still create updates on the site and click a button to share to Twitter as well, but the the reverse is no longer possible. The LinkedIn post by Ryan Roslansky, head of content products at LinkedIn, pointed to Twitter's own Friday blog post about "delivering a consistent experience on Twitter." Perhaps Twitter wants to separate itself from the business networking company after the recent password breach in which 6 million LinkedIn passwords were stolen. Li&#8230; Continue reading... More About: linkedin, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/twitter-drops-linkedin-partnership/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone: The 5-Year-Old That Changed the World [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Love or hate Apple products, there's no denying the iPhone's indelible mark on technology, culture and business. Five years ago, the first iteration was unleashed on throngs of early adopters, who ogled its touchscreen interface and poked at little icons. Today, the smartphone concept is no longer the bastion of tech nerds and fan girls. It has become standard issue, thanks in large part to the iPhone's overwhelming success and iconic design. The device revolutionized Apple itself. iPhone sales were a tiny slice of Apple pie in 2007. In 2012, it accounts for 58% of the company's revenue (which, overall, has skyrocketed, thanks to a culture of iTunes and apps propagated by the iPhone). SEE ALSO: Apple by the Numbers [INFOGRAPHIC] Sales of the iPhone (and its related services and accessories) even trump the revenue of entire companies like Microsoft and Disney. It's no wonder that Apple is consistently a front-runner for the most valuable company in the world by market cap. Our friends at Statista have compiled relevant data about the iPhone's ascendance. Check out the graphic below and tell us about your first iPhone experience in the comments. For more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/iphone-5-anniversary-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/29/iphone-5-anniversary-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fapple+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Apple+News%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Integrates With WordPress: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Integrates With WordPress: WordPress publishers can now &#8220;easily integrate Facebook features, such as social publishing and mentions, through the new Facebook for WordPress plugin.&#8221; Publishers can use social plugins as WordPress widgets to share the Facebook Activity Feed, Recommendations, Comments Box and Customizable Like, Subscribe and Send buttons."Once the plugin is installed, you can cross-post content published to WordPress to your Facebook Timeline and the Facebook Pages you manage. You can also mention the names of Pages and friends as you post to further distribute your content."Twitter Rolls Out Tailored Trends: &#8220;In order to show emerging topics that matter more to you,&#8221; Twitter is improving their algorithms to &#8220;tailor Trends based on your location and who you follow on Twitter.&#8221; This new feature will impact how marketers can use Twitter.If you don't wish to see tailored Trends, but instead want to see a more general list of Trends, just change your location on Twitter.com.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:What kind of traffic is Pinterest driving to your site?What do you think of the new Facebook integration for WordPress?What&#8217;s your &#8220;feeling&#8221; about Facebook?Experience More Expanded Tweets: &#8220;When you expand Tweets containing links to partner websites, you can now see content previews, view images, play videos and more.&#8221;More companies like the the New York Times are partnering with Twitter to deliver rich content inside tweets.Facebook Opens the App Center: The App Center is a &#8220;place for people to find great social apps on the web and mobile.&#8221;The App Center helps high-quality apps grow by promoting those that people enjoy most.Bitly Shares Keyboard Shortcuts: Bitly users can &#8220;pick up some speed while performing some of the most common actions&#8221; with these shortcuts.Keyboard shortcuts for Bitly ninjas.Klout&#8217;s iPhone App Gets a Big Update: There are several new features. Users can now enter any Twitter handle and quickly find that user&#8217;s Klout score.With this new upgrade, users can endorse anyone's influence by swiping a finger across one of their Topics.Facebook Announces a New Ad Exchange: &#8220;Facebook announced a new &#8216;real-time bidding&#8217; ad exchange system for buying ads on the network.&#8221;Here are some social media tools worth noting:Konekt.me: An online platform that makes it extremely simple to build and curate a portfolio of your best work online.Konekt.me features include an easy-to-use, content-specific uploader, customizable collections and an interactive CV/resume feature that help you link your content and experience.Likester: A Facebook advertising tool to help Facebook users, companies and advertisers organize and explore over half a billion Facebook Likes.Check out the other pages your Facebook fans also like.Learnist: Essentially Pinterest with a focus on education. All learning boards are created by users and feature educational material.Unlike Pinterest, you are not limited to posting images on Learnist. You can also post articles, websites and videos.Chill: A video sharing site that allows you and your friends to watch videos together on your own computers while interacting in real time through Facebook."Chill is designed to make video sharing beautiful, simple and contextual."LoveIt: A visual sharing space that allows users to share their finished shopping excursion with the public, privately share the deals they got, and collaboratively plan their next shopping trip.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6FAOJXnPW3sAnd don&#8217;t miss this:Want to start a business blog? Starting July 10! Social Media Examiner presents Blogging Fundamentals for Business (an online business-building workshop). Join Michael Stelzner for Social Media Examiner&#8217;s online workshop! Go here to learn more.What do you think? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-integrates-with-wordpress-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-integrates-with-wordpress-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking for Developers? Try This Geeky Community</title>
      <description>The Spark of Genius Series highlights a unique feature of startups and is made possible by Microsoft BizSpark. If you would like to have your startup considered for inclusion, please see the details here. Name: Geeklist Quick Pitch: Geeklist is a community for geeks and developers. Genius Idea: A place for geeks to share their accomplishments and connect with great companies and other developers. While Christian Sanz worked at startups, he realized that there was a need for an effective way to recruit developers for jobs at top companies. &#8220;The only ways for developers to connect with companies were through recruiters and r&#233;sum&#233;s,&#8221; Sanz told Mashable. &#8220;I wanted to c&#8230; Continue reading... More About: bizspark, social networking</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/geeklist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/28/geeklist/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
