<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Just Changed Your Email Without Asking&#8212;Here's How to Fix It [Facebook]</title>
      <description>Hey, here's something really stupid and annoying: Facebook abruptly switched everyone's default email address to the @facebook.com account you've never used. Here's how to switch back Facebook's obnoxious overreach right now. So people can actually, you know, contact you. Remember long, long ago, when Facebook launched a Facebook email system and then nobody used it? That's fine&#8212;it was always just an option you were more than welcome to completely ignore. And we did, because we already had Gmail and work inboxes, and didn't need yet another. If our friends wanted to email us, they could just head to our profiles and have options. Not today! If you go to your profile (or anyone else's), you'll see the @facebook.com email account listed, and none of your others. They've all been hidden in a ham-handed attempt to make the Facebook inbox relevant. Luckily, it's easy to fix this foolish move. Go to your Timeline. Click about, under your contact info. Scroll down to "Contact Info" and hit edit. Switch all of the crossed out circle symbols to a full circle for each inbox you want visible on your profile. If you don't want @facebook.com to show up, switch it from a full circle to crossed out. Hit save. Facebook: don't do this again. [Forbes]</description>
      <link>http://gizmodo.com/5921085/facebook-just-changed-your-email-without-asking++heres-how-to-fix-it</link>
      <guid>http://gizmodo.com/5921085/facebook-just-changed-your-email-without-asking++heres-how-to-fix-it</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Pictures That Will Restore Your Faith In Humanity</title>
      <description>People aren't always awful. Sometimes, they're maybe even just a little bit wonderful. Here are 21 pictures to remind you of that fact. This picture of Chicago Christians who showed up at a gay pride parade to apologize for homophobia in the Church. and the reaction from the parade. This story about Japanese senior citizens who volunteered to tackle the nuclear crisis at Fukushima power station so that young people wouldn't have to subject themselves to radiation. This picture of two Norwegian guys rescuing a sheep from the ocean. View Entire List &#8250;</description>
      <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</link>
      <guid>http://www.buzzfeed.com/expresident/pictures-that-will-restore-your-faith-in-humanity</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megaupload Founder Kim Dotcom Returns to Twitter, Promotes 'Megabox'</title>
      <description>Kim Dotcom, the quixotic millionaire founder of file-sharing service Megaupload who&#8217;s wanted for extradition to the U.S., returned to Twitter this week to prove to the world he&#8217;s still creating new platforms despite his entanglements with law enforcement. Dotcom also used the new account to announce that &#8220;Megabox,&#8221; a new music discovery and sharing service, is still on its way despite his still being under arrest. He&#8217;s previously said that Megabox, which would compete with similar platforms such as Spotify, would let artists keep almost 90% of the profits made from their music. Dotcom, arrested in New Zealand after file-sharing service Megaupload was brought down on charges of computer piracy in January, has also been using the reactivated Twitter account (@kimdotcom) mostly to post photos and thank supporters during his ongoing extradition hearing. In true Dotcom style, he&#8217;s also been poking fun at his situation, tweeting jokes about the FBI and police. He&#8217;s also met with Apple founder Steve Wozniak, who visited him in New Zealand. Dotcom&#8217;s assets have been frozen and he remains under house arrest in New Zealand while a court weighs the American extradition request. U.S. law enforcement officials have accused Dotcom and his staff of being a part of the &#8220;Mega Conspiracy, a worldwide criminal organization whose members engaged in criminal copyright infringement and money laundering on a massive scale.&#8221; The fate of the data still stored on Megaupload&#8217;s servers is still unknown. The Electronic Frontier Foundation is suing the Federal Bureau of Investigation over the files, which the EFF argues that the site&#8217;s users have a right to access. What should happen to the Megaupload data? Share your opinion in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Megaupload Founder Kim Dotcom Returns to Twitter, Promotes 'Megabox'</title>
      <description>Kim Dotcom, the quixotic millionaire founder of file-sharing service Megaupload who&#8217;s wanted for extradition to the U.S., returned to Twitter this week to prove to the world he&#8217;s still creating new platforms despite his entanglements with law enforcement. Dotcom also used the new account to announce that &#8220;Megabox,&#8221; a new music discovery and sharing service, is still on its way despite his still being under arrest. He&#8217;s previously said that Megabox, which would compete with similar platforms such as Spotify, would let artists keep almost 90% of the profits made from their music. Dotcom, arrested in New Zealand after file-sharing service Megaupload was brought down on charges of computer piracy in January, has also been using the reactivated Twitter account (@kimdotcom) mostly to post photos and thank supporters during his ongoing extradition hearing. In true Dotcom style, he&#8217;s also been poking fun at his situation, tweeting jokes about the FBI and police. He&#8217;s also met with Apple founder Steve Wozniak, who visited him in New Zealand. Dotcom&#8217;s assets have been frozen and he remains under house arrest in New Zealand while a court weighs the American extradition request. U.S. law enforcement officials have accused Dotcom and his staff of being a part of the &#8220;Mega Conspiracy, a worldwide criminal organization whose members engaged in criminal copyright infringement and money laundering on a massive scale.&#8221; The fate of the data still stored on Megaupload&#8217;s servers is still unknown. The Electronic Frontier Foundation is suing the Federal Bureau of Investigation over the files, which the EFF argues that the site&#8217;s users have a right to access. What should happen to the Megaupload data? Share your opinion in the comments.</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/23/kim-dotcom-twitter/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>45% of Executives Think Social Media Has a Positive Impact on the Workplace</title>
      <description>More executives than employees think social media has a positive impact on workplace culture. While 45% of executives believe social media is good for their companies&#8217; culture, only 27% of employees agree, finds a recent survey by Deloitte. Executives think social media has a positive impact because it allows managers to be more transparent (38%), helps build and maintain relationships among colleagues (46%), helps build company culture (41%), and fosters a feeling of connection to the company and its leadership (37%). What factors do executives think are more important to culture building than social media? Some 65% say financial performance and 62% say compensation. However, employees disagree with their workplace superiors. Only 33% saying compensation and 24% saying financial performance have effects on company culture. Employees rank regular and candid communications (50%), employee recognition (49%) and access to management and leadership (47%) as having the largest impact. SEE ALSO: 6 Mobile Apps for Your Job Hunt The survey&#8217;s findings say that though some executives may use social media as a crutch to enhance workplace culture, it cannot replace solid leadership and communications. What&#8217;s your company&#8217;s relationship with social media? Should executives do more to encourage the use of social media or is online networking better left for our personal lives?</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/?p=1176429&amp;preview=true</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/?p=1176429&amp;preview=true</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FunnyJunk is threatening to file a federal lawsuit against me unless I pay $20,000 in damages</title>
      <description>FunnyJunk's lawyer sent me a letter stating that I owe him $20k in damages. View</description>
      <link>http://theoatmeal.com/blog/funnyjunk_letter</link>
      <guid>http://theoatmeal.com/blog/funnyjunk_letter</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Women Still Can&#8217;t Have It All | The Atlantic | Jun. 21, 2012 | 51 Minutes (12,949 words)</title>
      <description>A call for women and men to have a more honest conversation about work-life balance: "Today, however, women in power can and should change that environment, although change is not easy. When I became dean of the Woodrow Wilson School, in 2002, I decided that one of the advantages of being a woman in power was that I could help change the norms by deliberately talking about my children and my desire to have a balanced life. Thus, I would end faculty meetings at 6 p.m. by saying that I had to go home for dinner; I would also make clear to all student organizations that I would not come to dinner with them, because I needed to be home from six to eight, but that I would often be willing to come back after eight for a meeting. I also once told the Dean&#8217;s Advisory Committee that the associate dean would chair the next session so I could go to a parent-teacher conference. "After a few months of this, several female assistant professors showed up in my office quite agitated. 'You have to stop talking about your kids,' one said. 'You are not showing the gravitas that people expect from a dean, which is particularly damaging precisely because you are the first woman dean of the school.' I told them that I was doing it deliberately and continued my practice, but it is interesting that gravitas and parenthood don&#8217;t seem to go together."</description>
      <link>http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/07/why-women-still-can-8217-t-have-it-all/9020/?single_page=true</link>
      <guid>http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/07/why-women-still-can-8217-t-have-it-all/9020/?single_page=true</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friendshake: Facebook&#8217;s New Mobile Feature For Finding People Nearby (And A Highlight Killer?)</title>
      <description>Facebook has created a new feature that lets users find friends and potential friends nearby. Called &#8220;Friendshake&#8221; (for now), it&#8217;s another step in Facebook furthering its reach into mobile, and creating services to meet new people &#8212; rather than build more connections up with the ones you already know. And, in keeping with Facebook&#8217;s emphasis on being as ubiquitous as possible, it&#8217;s not in a native app, but via the mobile web. The feature follows a little under two months after Facebook announced the acquisition of Glancee, a mobile app that helps users discover people near them with similar interests, whose three founders have now joined Facebook and closed down their app. It is not clear if Friendshake has been created out of that acquisition, or if it has been developed along an altogether different thread &#8212; and how the functions of the two may eventually dovetail. We first heard about Friendshake from developer Roger Pincombe, who himself got the info from a Facebook developer at the Angelhack event going on this weekend: Facebook is a title sponsor, and at the San Francisco event (Angelhack&#8217;s taking place also in Seattle, Boston and NYC), and one of its engineers was on site showing off how the app worked with developers. The feature has not been officially launched, but it is live and visible for those seeking it out. &#8220;He specifically said I should tell other people about it,&#8221; he told me in an email. &#8220;I (semi-jokingly) asked &#8216;even TechCrunch?&#8217; and he said sure.&#8221; So here we are. For now, the app works like this. Users have to be logged into Facebook and also into the Friendshake URL, and then others who are near can pick each other up. You can see both your own friends, as well as those you may not know. For now it looks like the main purpose is to quickly add people who you meet at a specific event &#8212; like a hackathon, or a bar. As Pincombe points out, &#8220;Before you would need to tell them your name, probably spell it for them, and then depending on how common your name is, you&#8217;d have to tell them which of the results is actually you. This makes it 2 taps if you save a bookmark.&#8221; And there is, of course, the potential of how this basic service could be further developed: finding people who are friends of friends, or who have flagged similar interests in their social graphs; and it potentially could be something to incorporate as a push service, rather than one you have to be activate to use every time. All of these features could make Friendshake into a Highlight killer &#8212; which can already do all of the above &#8212; and a lot more like Glancee, too. And as with so many of these kinds of features, you have to wonder how and if it will be abused &#8212; random people you would like to shake off suddenly start asking you to friend them on Facebook, for example. However, it appears that, even if Friendshake is already publicly available, this is still a work in progress being tested out, and so we may see more controls getting put in place, in addition to the fact that you have to activate the service to use it. &#8220;To my knowledge, the few people here at AngelHack that the Facebook employee tested it with are the only people to know about it yet,&#8221; said Pincombe. Before this, Facebook already had an ambient location feature, but it worked somewhat less in real time, and it is more about friends you have rather than making new ones. Facebook&#8217;s Check-In feature, when enabled, lets users see contacts who have visited the same places they have, or who has checked-in to a Facebook event.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friendshake: Facebook&#8217;s New Mobile Feature For Finding People Nearby (And A Highlight Killer?)</title>
      <description>Facebook has created a new feature that lets users find friends and potential friends nearby. Called &#8220;Friendshake&#8221; (for now), it&#8217;s another step in Facebook furthering its reach into mobile, and creating services to meet new people &#8212; rather than build more connections up with the ones you already know. And, in keeping with Facebook&#8217;s emphasis on being as ubiquitous as possible, it&#8217;s not in a native app, but via the mobile web. The feature follows a little under two months after Facebook announced the acquisition of Glancee, a mobile app that helps users discover people near them with similar interests, whose three founders have now joined Facebook and closed down their app. It is not clear if Friendshake has been created out of that acquisition, or if it has been developed along an altogether different thread &#8212; and how the functions of the two may eventually dovetail. We first heard about Friendshake from developer Roger Pincombe, who himself got the info from a Facebook developer at the Angelhack event going on this weekend: Facebook is a title sponsor, and at the San Francisco event (Angelhack&#8217;s taking place also in Seattle, Boston and NYC), and one of its engineers was on site showing off how the app worked with developers. The feature has not been officially launched, but it is live and visible for those seeking it out. &#8220;He specifically said I should tell other people about it,&#8221; he told me in an email. &#8220;I (semi-jokingly) asked &#8216;even TechCrunch?&#8217; and he said sure.&#8221; So here we are. For now, the app works like this. Users have to be logged into Facebook and also into the Friendshake URL, and then others who are near can pick each other up. You can see both your own friends, as well as those you may not know. For now it looks like the main purpose is to quickly add people who you meet at a specific event &#8212; like a hackathon, or a bar. As Pincombe points out, &#8220;Before you would need to tell them your name, probably spell it for them, and then depending on how common your name is, you&#8217;d have to tell them which of the results is actually you. This makes it 2 taps if you save a bookmark.&#8221; And there is, of course, the potential of how this basic service could be further developed: finding people who are friends of friends, or who have flagged similar interests in their social graphs; and it potentially could be something to incorporate as a push service, rather than one you have to be activate to use every time. All of these features could make Friendshake into a Highlight killer &#8212; which can already do all of the above &#8212; and a lot more like Glancee, too. And as with so many of these kinds of features, you have to wonder how and if it will be abused &#8212; random people you would like to shake off suddenly start asking you to friend them on Facebook, for example. However, it appears that, even if Friendshake is already publicly available, this is still a work in progress being tested out, and so we may see more controls getting put in place, in addition to the fact that you have to activate the service to use it. &#8220;To my knowledge, the few people here at AngelHack that the Facebook employee tested it with are the only people to know about it yet,&#8221; said Pincombe. Before this, Facebook already had an ambient location feature, but it worked somewhat less in real time, and it is more about friends you have rather than making new ones. Facebook&#8217;s Check-In feature, when enabled, lets users see contacts who have visited the same places they have, or who has checked-in to a Facebook event.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/24/friendshake-facebooks-new-mobile-feature-for-finding-people-nearby-and-a-highlight-killer/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A DRAMATIC SURPRISE ON A QUIET SQUARE</title>
      <description>To launch the high quality TV channel TNT in Belgium we placed a big red push button on an average Flemish square of an average Flemish town. A sign with the...</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=316AzLYfAzw</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=316AzLYfAzw</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New York City&#8217;s Getting a Tech Upgrade</title>
      <description>New York City is looking to double down on its status as a technology-first metropolis as city officials announced this week five new initiatives with the goal of expanding New York's booming tech sector. The initiatives, introduced by Mayor Michael Bloomberg and City Council Speaker Christine Quinn and developed in partnership with the New York City Economic Development Corporation and the Department of Information Technology and Telecommunications, include a variety of plans to further develop broadband access and incorporate technology into the City's public policy: 1. ConnectNYC: Small and medium-sized companies in buildings with poor broadband wiring will compete with one another&#8230; Continue reading... More About: broadband, government, internet access, new york city, open data, open government, technology, US</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/new-york-city-upgrade/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/24/new-york-city-upgrade/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like Louis CK, the comedian. I also like Louis CK, the chap trying to do something different, making his own stuff and &lt;a href="https://buy.louisck.net/"&gt;distributing it straight to the audience&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s more, I especially like his message to people who might want to download his material illegally instead of paying the five dollars:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;To those who might wish to &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; this video: look, I don&amp;#8217;t really get the whole &amp;#8220;torrent&amp;#8221; thing. I don&amp;#8217;t know enough about it to judge either way. But I&amp;#8217;d just like you to consider this: I made this video extremely easy to use against well-informed advice. I was told that it would be easier to torrent the way I made it, but I chose to do it this way anyway, because I want it to be easy for people to watch and enjoy this video in any way they want without &amp;#8220;corporate&amp;#8221; restrictions. Please bear in mind that I am not a company or a corporation. I&amp;#8217;m just some guy. I paid for the production and posting of this video with my own money. I would like to be able to post more material to the fans in this way, which makes it cheaper for the buyer and more pleasant for me. So, please help me keep this being a good idea. I can&amp;#8217;t stop you from torrenting; all I can do is politely ask you to pay your five little dollars, enjoy the video, and let other people find it in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you like something, even if you can get it for free, do try and do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://writeforyourlife.net/louis-ck-live-at-the-beacon-theater" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent link to 'Louis CK: Live at the Beacon Theater'" class="glyph"&gt;Read this post on Write for Your Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WriteForYourLife/~4/xTjySALLr7Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
      <link>https://buy.louisck.net/</link>
      <guid>https://buy.louisck.net/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
