<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Social TV Finale Trends: Dancing With the Stars, American Idol, Glee</title>
      <description>Four hours of finale episodes from three primetime TV shows Tuesday night &#8212; Dancing With the Stars, American Idol and Glee &#8212; left viewers with much to discuss and debate on social networks. DWTS crowned its 14th champion, Idol finalists went head-to-head in the performance finale, and Glee said goodbye to graduating seniors. And although Glee roped in the least amount of viewers (7.64 million), it incited more people to check in on social entertainment platform GetGlue. SEE ALSO: Summer TV Guide &#8212; 20 Social Shows to See | SNL&#8217;s 100th Digital Short [VIDEO] Below, we&#8217;ve compiled GetGlue check-in stats, viewership numbers and the trends emerging from Twitter and GetGlue conversations. We&#8217;re also featuring some of the best tweets from Tuesday night and Wednesday. Dancing With the Stars GetGlue check-ins: 20,029 Overall viewers: 17.48 million, according to Nielsen Media Research data Comment trends: DWTS Green Bay Packers football player Donald Driver and dance partner Peta Murgatroyd took home the show&#8217;s coveted Mirror Ball Trophy, beating out celebrity finalists William Levy and Katherine Jenkins. Much of the post-show buzz online focused on him being the seventh athlete to win the show, which is in its 14th season. The Packers and fellow teammates even chimed in with tweets. &#8220;Completely floored, I guess all the football fans got it together to vote,&#8221; GetGlue user Kimberly Bagley posted Tuesday night. &#8220;Love football and all but I really thought it should have gone the other way.&#8221; Congratulations to Donald Driver! The new @DancingABC champion! RT this to show your support! &#8212; Green Bay Packers (@packers) May 23, 2012 With @Donald_Driver80, 7 past #DWTS champs are athletes, 4 are actors, and 3 are singers. #GMADancing &#8212; Good Morning America (@GMA) May 23, 2012 I know how hard @Donald_Driver80 works on the field so it&#8217;s no surprise he won #DWTS, I&#8217;m sure the work ethic just carried over to the floor &#8212; Ryan Grant (@RyanGrant25) May 23, 2012 Countless msgs of love and support! Thank you so much everyone. I&#8217;m reading them all and it makes me so thankful for this #DWTS experience! &#8212; Peta Murgatroyd (@PetaMurgatroyd) May 23, 2012 American Idol GetGlue check-ins: 20,335 Overall viewers: 14.39 million Comment trends: Powerhouse vocalist Jessica Sanchez and crooner Phillip Phillips gave their final three judged performances. But even though Phillips&#8217;s third performance garnered a standing ovation from the judges, critics are having a difficult time picking a clear winner. Both contestants ignited a flurry of tweets as viewers weighed in on their song choices, vocal abilities and potential to succeed in the music industry. &#8220;There are a ton of comments that feel very mixed,&#8221; GetGlue spokeswoman Claire Gendel told Mashable. &#8220;There are a lot of Jessica fans and a lot of Phillip fans.&#8221; Hmm. @latimes and @billboard polls both have @JSanchezAI11 winning by a lot; @EW has Phillip winning by a lot; Dial Idol slightly Phillip. &#8212; Jose m iniguez (@imJmi) May 23, 2012 #Idol Final 2 really picking wrong songs tonight. Phillip should have done &#8216;Still Raining&#8217; not &#8216;Moving Out.&#8217; &#8212; Jarett Wieselman (@JarettSays) May 23, 2012 Retweet for Jessica.. Favorite for Phillip.. #IdolFinale &#8212; Rhap Salazar (@RhapSalazar) May 23, 2012 @AmericanIdol It&#8217;s so interesting hearing Jessica and Phillip back to back. It&#8217;s vocal ability versus artistry at its best! #IdolFinale &#8212; Scott MacIntyre (@ScottDMacIntyre) May 23, 2012 Glee GetGlue check-ins: 41,447 Overall viewers: 7.64 million Comment Trends: Crying &#8212; and lots of it viewers during Glee&#8216;s graduation finale. The episode flashed back to several memorable scenes in the show&#8217;s three-year run, including one from the pilot episode and another from the episode in which Kurt performed Beyonce&#8217;s &#8220;Single Ladies&#8221; in a leotard. Viewers reacted significantly to learning the fate of the graduating seniors and their plans for the future. &#8220;A lot of people commented about how they might not have watched most of the season but tuned in for the finale and loved it,&#8221; Gendel says. &#8220;Many people commented about how touching the scene between Sue and Quinn was as well as watching Kurt&#8217;s dad do &#8216;Single Ladies.&#8217; There were also a lot of fans who said they were crying, or would write &#8216;sniff sniff&#8217; in the comments and definitely some who were shocked that Kurt didn&#8217;t get in to NYADA (New York Academy of the Dramatic Arts).&#8221; KURT AND BLAINE LOVE EACHOTHER SO MUCH! CRYING FOREVER #GLEE &#8212; Jeremy Cabalona(@JeremyCabalona) May 23, 2012 Glee could have functioned as a series finale tonight. Great ending to Rachel Berry&#8217;s high school career. #glee &#8212; Rolfe Norman (@rolfenorman) May 23, 2012 Still choked up from the #Gleefinale. Did not see that coming! @Msleamichele was perfection. &#8212; Kristin Dos Santos (@KristinDSantos) May 23, 2012 OMG. Burt doing &#8216;Single Ladies&#8217; *dies* #GLEE &#8212; Jason Scott&#8482; (@JasontheGleek) May 23, 2012 And on that note, we leave you with Burt&#8217;s performance of &#8220;Single Ladies.&#8221; Please don&#8217;t die. More About: american idol, celebrities, Dancing With The Stars, Entertainment, getglue, GLEE, Music, social tv, sports, Twitter</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/dwts-glee-idol-finales-twitter-getglue/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/dwts-glee-idol-finales-twitter-getglue/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HP to Cut 27,000 Jobs</title>
      <description>Hewlett-Packard said on Wednesday it was going to lay off 27,000 of its workers over the next year and half in a broad restructuring effort aimed at making the company leaner and more profitable. The news comes alongside HP&#8217;s quarterly results which showed profits down more than 30%. HP executives said in an earnings call that it expects to cut the jobs &#8212; about 8% of its workforce &#8212; by the end of the 2014 fiscal year. Some of the workers will be offered early retirement, HP says, and the proportion of jobs cut will vary by region. Once complete, the restructuring is expected to save HP $3 billion to $3.5 billion, the &#8220;vast majority&#8221; of which will be used to reinvest in the company. Research and development will factor highly as an area of reinvestement, along with expanding its cloud, security and information services. Enterprise storage is also expected to be an area of growth. &#8220;We&#8217;ve got to streamline our operating model,&#8221; CEO Meg Whitman said during the call. &#8220;We went business unit by business unit and said, &#8216;What do we want to focus on, and how many individuals do we need to deliver that service?&#8221; SEE ALSO: HP Merges PC and Printer Units in Major Restructuring Gross revenues for the company were $30.7 billion, down 3% from the previous quarter. Profits came in at $1.59 billion, down from $2.3 billion, a 31% reduction. HP&#8217;s job cuts and declining balance sheet follow a chaotic period that saw the company release and then discontinue its webOS mobile devices (including the HP TouchPad), flirt with selling off its consumer PC division, the fire its new CEO, Leo Apotheker, amid widespread criticism over his plan to reinvent HP as a software-and-services company. Since then HP appointed Whitman as CEO and has taken many steps to get the company back on track &#8212; today&#8217;s job cuts being the biggest yet. What do you think of HP&#8217;s plan to become more efficient through downsizing? Have your say in the comments. More About: Business, Hewlett-Packard, HP, layoffsFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/hp-cuts-27000-jobs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/hp-cuts-27000-jobs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fbusiness+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Business+and+Marketing%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook May Unfriend Nasdaq, Hook Up With NYSE [REPORT]</title>
      <description>If Facebook and Nasdaq were in a relationship, the status would likely read: &#8220;it&#8217;s complicated.&#8221; The relationship was on a rocky road from the start. The Nasdaq exchange, home to many tech stocks, had an unplanned 30-minute delay in offering Facebook stock on its IPO day, which may have contributed to the stock&#8217;s meager performance. Nasdaq declared itself &#8220;embarrassed&#8221; by the glitch, and earmarked $13 million to cover &#8220;bad trades&#8221; made by investors whose schedules were thrown off. But that face-saving gesture may not have been enough for Facebook. According to a Reuters source, the social network is mulling a breakup with Nasdaq &#8212; and a hook-up with the New York Stock Exchange. SEE ALSO: What Went Wrong With Facebook&#8217;s IPO? The report says Facebook sat through a pitch from the NYSE, and is mulling the option to switch its official listing exchange. In a statement to Bloomberg, a NYSE representative indicated reports it was in talks with are false. &#8220;There have been no discussions with Facebook regarding switching their listing in light of the events of the last week nor do we think a discussion along those lines would be appropriate at this time&#8221; No further comment was offered by Facebook or Nasdaq. Although unusual, such a move would not be entirely unprecedented. Viacom went in the other direction recently, switching from the NYSE to Nasdaq to save fees in November 2011. Should Facebook consider switching exchanges so early, or dance with the one who brung it for a while longer? Let us know your take in the comments. Image courtesy of iStockphoto, AUDINDesign More About: Facebook, nasdaqFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/facebook-unfriend-nasdaq-nyse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/facebook-unfriend-nasdaq-nyse/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Target and Shopkick Launch Nationwide Loyalty Gift Card Program</title>
      <description>Target is expanding its partnership with Shopkick, a mobile couponing app that allows shoppers to collect and exchange points for rewards. Beginning Wednesday, shoppers equipped with Shopkick on their iPhone or Android devices will be eligible to collect points, or &#8220;kicks,&#8221; as soon as they step foot in one of Target&#8217;s 1,764 stores. They can earn more points by scanning various products in the store using the app, and then redeem those points for items such as Target gift cards, Facebook credits, dining gift certificates, iTunes downloads, charitable donations, etc. So how much do you have to do for a reward? Five hundred kicks will get you a $2 Target gift card; 6,250 will get you a $25 one. Walking into a store merits 60 kicks on a normal day, and between 120 and 300 kicks on special promotional days. Scan every designated item in the store and you&#8217;ll earn 315 kicks. If that seems like a lot of work, remember, it&#8217;s designed as a bonus for repeat shoppers &#8212; not scavenger hunters. Target&#8217;s program is an expansion of one implemented at 242 of its stores in November 2010 and is the largest partnership Shopkick has announced to date. In November, the startup partnered with Visa to allow shoppers to collect points by making purchases from &#8212; rather than just visiting &#8212; retailers including Toys &#8220;R&#8221; Us, American Eagle Outfitters, Old Navy and Wet Seal. Shopkick, which claims 3 million members, has also worked with CW Television Network, offering kicks in exchange for watching and recording ads displayed on the network. Shopkick has more than 3 million registered users and has recorded 7 million verified walkins to partner stores since launching in June 2009, the company tells us. More About: retail, shopkick, TargetFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/target-shopkick/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/target-shopkick/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Social Media Marketing Really Work? [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>From Twitter to Facebook, to Google+, to YouTube, to Foursquare and more, social media use is the hottest thing in marketing. But does it really work? Brands and businesses are certainly making a stronger push than ever on social media, which makes sense &#8212; that&#8217;s where the people are. Figuring out just how much social media marketing returns on investments of time and money, however, is harder to do. Facebook marketing company Pagemodo recently pulled research from sources around the web to produce the infographic below, looking at just how much faith marketers have in social media. The aggregated data shows a sense of conservative optimism. 64% of business owners say social media marketing is a promising tactic and they believe it provides returns &#8212; but they aren&#8217;t willing to go all in with it just yet and favor a more cautious approach. 20% are more bullish on its potential, according to the same study, while just 6% are hardcore skeptics. How do marketers and entrepreneurs measure whether social media marketing pays off? Most do so by measuring the accumulation of friends, likes, followers and other online connections. 39% look at shares of brand content, while 35% measure actual leads from social media. Just 18% measure success by overall brand awareness and favorability as gauged by consumer surveys. Check out the infographic below for more on how much faith businesses put in social media as a marketing tool, and for tips on additional ways to maximize results and measure influence. Then let us know in the comments &#8212; do you think social media marketing provides real results? Thumbnail image via iStockphoto, courtneyk More About: infographics, Marketing, social media marketingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/social-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/social-marketing-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>See Muppets on Your Band-Aid With New AR App [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>This will help sooth your kids&#8217; booboos: Johnson &amp; Johnson has just introduced an augmented reality app that projects image of the Muppets on their Band-Aids. As the video above shows, the iOS-based app, co-developed by JWT, can prompt a song from Kermit the Frog, a red carpet entry by Miss Piggy or a &#8220;daring act of lunacy&#8221; from Gonzo. The free app is available for iPhone and iPad in the App Store [iTunes link]. More About: apps, Augmented Reality, Marketing, muppetsFor more Mobile coverage:Follow Mashable Mobile on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Mobile channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/muppets-band-aid-ar-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/muppets-band-aid-ar-app/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Fmobile+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Mobile+Feed%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginner&#8217;s Guide to LinkedIn</title>
      <description>LinkedIn is considered the non-sexy, sleeping giant of social networks. It keeps a low profile, perhaps due to the professional nature of its users. Nonetheless, LinkedIn continues to exert a powerful influence on connected job seekers, brands, recruiters and industries. Founded by Reid Hoffman in 2002, LinkedIn has grown to 161 million members in over 200 countries, making it the world&#8217;s largest professional network on the Internet (by comparison, Twitter has 500 million registered users, and Facebook has 900 million). Currently available in 17 languages, LinkedIn remains a relevant platform the world over. That being said, we doubt you spend 20 minutes on LinkedIn per day, like Facebook&#8217;s power users do. So, if you need a crash course on what LinkedIn has to offer, browse the network&#8217;s most prominent features below. Or send this to your recent grad as he or she prepares to enter today&#8217;s daunting job market. SEE ALSO: The Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Facebook Have you used LinkedIn to find a job, network with professionals or research hot topics in your industry? Please share your own tips in the comments below. 1. Profile Like most social networks, LinkedIn hosts your personal profile, a page on which you may list information like job experience and professional skills. However, unlike many other social networks, it&#8217;s important to complete your profile to the best of your ability &#8212; especially if you&#8217;re using LinkedIn for the job hunt. LinkedIn measures your &#8220;profile completeness&#8221; from 0-100%. The higher your profile completeness, the more likely you are to appear in search results. For instance, when you list skills like &#8220;Final Cut Pro&#8221; and &#8220;Photoshop,&#8221; potential employers may come across your profile when they perform an advanced search based on those keywords. Handy. To ensure that your profile is 100% complete, LinkedIn recommends including the following information. Industry and postal code A current position with description Two more positions Education At least five skills Profile photo At least 50 connections A summary For more information about optimizing your LinkedIn profile, see these additional resources: 6 Things on Your LinkedIn Profile That Shouldn&#8217;t Be on Your Resume 8 Job Search Tips From the Co-Founder of LinkedIn The 10 Most Overused LinkedIn Profile Buzzwords of 2011 2. Connections Of course, to get those &#8220;50 connections&#8221; mentioned above, you&#8217;ll have to expand your network on LinkedIn. Don&#8217;t worry &#8212; LinkedIn&#8217;s algorithms and data mining make it pretty easy. I recommend first performing a series of basic searches to find people you know by name. (See the search box at the top of each LinkedIn page.) Click the &#8220;Connect&#8221; button next to people&#8217;s names to add them to your network. You may send a custom message along with that invitation to make the connection more personalized. Once you have made several connections, head to the &#8220;People You May Know&#8221; page. LinkedIn&#8217;s algorithm will likely have begun determining additional suggestions based on your connections&#8217; networks. LinkedIn labels these connections by degree. People you&#8217;re already connected to are &#8220;1st degree&#8221; connections. People you&#8217;re not yet connected to, but who are linked to your 1st degree connections, are 2nd degree connections. And so on. You&#8217;ll see a blue icon that says &#8220;1st,&#8221; &#8220;2nd&#8221; or &#8220;3rd&#8221; next to their names. You may also choose to connect your email&#8217;s contact list to LinkedIn for the purpose of finding additional connections. Head to &#8220;Import Contacts&#8221; and allow access your contacts to pull up a list of potentials. Be aware, however, that this may generate a huge list of people, especially if email services like Gmail tend to save every address you&#8217;ve ever contacted. 3. Groups LinkedIn groups are spaces in which professionals and experts can share content, ask advice, post or search for jobs and network with others. Groups are tailored to brands, associations and societies, support groups, causes, publications and industries in general. That can mean anything from &#8220;On Startups &#8211; The Community for Entrepreneurs&#8221; to &#8220;Cal Alumni Association | UC Berkeley.&#8221; On the other hand, don&#8217;t confuse LinkedIn &#8220;groups&#8221; with &#8220;companies.&#8221; Coca-Cola has a &#8220;Coca-Cola Current &amp; Former Employees&#8221; group, but its business lives on &#8220;The Coca-Cola Company&#8221; company page. More on that later. With over 1.3 million groups to choose from, you&#8217;re likely to find at few that fit your field and interests. Keep in mind that many groups require authentication before the manager permits you to join. However, nearly one-third of groups don&#8217;t require review, and are labeled &#8220;open.&#8221; Once you&#8217;re familiar with group functions, you may choose to create your own group. That means you&#8217;re the group owner, but you may also appoint a group manager and moderator, who are responsible for supervising discussions, subgroups, settings, etc. To get the most out of your LinkedIn group, take a look at the following features: LinkedIn Rolls Out Polling for Groups LinkedIn Unveils Dashboard for Groups Statistics 4. Companies Just as you have a personal profile page, many companies choose to represent themselves on LinkedIn, too. Like Facebook brand pages, you may choose to follow the activity and updates of companies on LinkedIn. Company pages contain general information, such as a business overview, list of employees and press mentions. Many companies also choose to list job openings on their pages, and some even encourage applicants to apply through LinkedIn, a very handy tool of the network. Once you follow a company, you&#8217;ll see its updates appear on your LinkedIn homepage alongside those of your connections. Mashable, for instance, tends to post business-related articles on LinkedIn, since that seems to be the content most pertinent to the network&#8217;s audience. Businesses also use LinkedIn to post company announcements, such as acquisitions, new hires or updated policies. LinkedIn warns against update spam, however: &#8220;Businesses that post updates excessively are subject to review by LinkedIn and could risk having their page deleted.&#8221; If you&#8217;re interested in adding your own company to the network, LinkedIn advises you take the following steps. You&#8217;re a current company employee and your position is on your profile. A company email address (e.g. john@companyname.com) is one of the confirmed email addresses on your LinkedIn account. You associate your profile with the right company. You must click on a name from our company name dropdown list when you edit or add a position on your profile. Your company&#8217;s email domain is unique to the company. Your profile must be more than 50% complete. You must have several connections. If you&#8217;re interested in learning more about how companies can use LinkedIn, see the following resources: 9 Ways to Add LinkedIn to Your Company Website 5 Ways to Market Your Brand on LinkedIn Why Your Non-Profit Needs to Stop Ignoring LinkedIn 5. Jobs Job search and recruitment tools are among LinkedIn&#8217;s most valuable features. More and more companies are encouraging candidates to apply for jobs via LinkedIn, due to the social network&#8217;s credibility and ease-of-use. Head to the &#8220;Jobs&#8221; tab, where you&#8217;ll find options for applicants. Perform an advanced search for available jobs by keyword, title, location, company, salary and industry. (A search for &#8220;developer&#8221; within 50 miles of Manhattan turned up 488 results.) Save jobs to review later, and even save searches to check back later for updated results. As an employer, you may post an available job to LinkedIn for $295 for a 30-day period. (Bulk packages are available for better deals.) Once posted, these jobs will not only appear in search results, but also in the &#8220;Careers&#8221; tab on your company page. Finally, recruiters may &#8220;find talent&#8221; on LinkedIn, but they must upgrade to a premium subscription plan to search for potential hires. 6. Updates Unlike content shared on social networks like Facebook and Twitter, LinkedIn updates tend to be industry- and professionally-focused. Keep that in mind if you&#8217;re attempting to increase engagement. You can share updates from a number of different places, both on LinkedIn.com and from outside web properties. Post a status update from the LinkedIn homepage, and it will be shared as well as posted to your profile under the activity feed. Also, when you engage in discussions in LinkedIn groups, that activity counts as an update. Post updates from sites like The New York Times by clicking the LinkedIn social share button next to an article. Or add the LinkedIn sharing bookmarklet to your browser toolbar to quickly share most sites as an update. Finally, you may also connect your Twitter account to LinkedIn. This not only expands your network, but allows you to post tweets on LinkedIn as if they were status updates. Once tweets post to LinkedIn, users can interact with them as if from Twitter.com, by retweeting, replying and favoriting. Like updates, tweets post to the homepage and live in the activity feed on your profile. Just as LinkedIn advises brands to cool it on excessive updates, you should practice the same self-control. Users appreciate information, not excessive traffic on their feeds. That being said, you can mute certain connections, if you choose. Hover over a user&#8217;s update on the homepage and click the &#8220;hide&#8221; button to stop receiving updates from that user. 7. Applications Applications allow LinkedIn users to customize their profiles and share content in different ways. For example, you may choose to add the WordPress app so that your latest WordPress blog posts share with your LinkedIn network. Do the same for SlideShare presentations you or your company have created. Keep in mind that most apps require permissions to access some of your basic profile information, such as your name or job title. However, all applications must abide by LinkedIn&#8217;s privacy policy, which means they&#8217;re not allowed to reach any private information not easily accessible by browsing the site. Learn about some of the top LinkedIn apps here: 5 Essential LinkedIn Apps for Sales Teams 8. Mobile LinkedIn has mobile applications for iPhone, iPad, Android, BlackBerry and Palm devices. The app is useful for posting status updates and checking group updates on-the-go, but its inherent advantages lie in networking. Pull up the mobile app to find LinkedIn connections and exchange information at events. After meeting someone, you may choose to email that person a link to your profile, so he or she may connect with you later &#8212; no business cards needed. Or search for that person on your LinkedIn mobile app and add him as a connection then and there. You may also choose to download LinkedIn connections to your smartphone&#8217;s address book for later contact. For more information on LinkedIn&#8217;s mobile presence, see below: 5 Tips for Using LinkedIn&#8217;s Mobile Site LinkedIn Launches iPad App, Takes New Direction 9. Upgraded Account Once you&#8217;ve explored LinkedIn Free, you may choose to upgrade to a LinkedIn account with more features. Starting at $15.95 per month, LinkedIn has premium subscription plans for businesses, job seekers, recruiters and more. One of the distinguishing features of most upgraded accounts is the ability to send InMail to anyone. InMail is an internal LinkedIn message sent to a person with whom you are not connected. You can message people you are already connected with free-of-charge, but you can&#8217;t message non-connections; you must InMail them &#8212; and those InMails are limited. The Basic business premium account allows you three InMails per month, while the Business Plus plan allows 10, and the Executive 25 per month. So, choose your InMails wisely. Upgraded accounts also have access to more search results, which can be a huge bonus for LinkedIn recruiters. You also have access to additional tools for saving and organizing profiles, and you can view the full list of people who have viewed your LinkedIn profile. Image courtesy of Flickr, Coletivo Mambembe. More About: Business, features, jobs, linkedin, Social Media</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/linkedin-beginners/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/23/linkedin-beginners/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Smart Companies Using Tech For Good</title>
      <description>In our social entrepreneurship series, The World at Work, Mashable interviews the faces behind the startups and projects that are working to make a global impact. By harnessing the power of the web and digital technology, these organizations help children with autism communicate, match volunteers to their perfect charity and fund classrooms all over the country. While the companies are diverse, they are all on a mission to change our lives for the better and improve society. Here&#8217;s a roundup of featured projects from the last week, including exclusive video interviews with the founders of these innovative startups. To read more and watch the videos, click through to the full story, and follow the series to learn about more breakthrough companies. 1. Keepon Big Idea: Keepon is a little robot developed in Japan that is used to research childhood communication and interaction. The consumer version, MyKeepon, funds the construction and distribution of Keepons to labs around the globe. Why It&#8217;s Working: Keepon&#8217;s simple design and mannerisms make it an effective communication tool that doesn&#8217;t intimidate kids with autism. Also, its cuteness factor is nothing short of infectious. Read the full story here. 2. Donors Choose Big Idea: Donors Choose is an educational charity that allows donors to choose to fund a variety of classroom projects and materials. Why It&#8217;s Working: With more than $116 million raised and 6 million kids helped in classrooms all over the country, Donors Choose has been increasing its impact and surpassing funding records every year since it went live in 2003. Read the full story and see the video here. 3. Social Reality Big Idea: Social Reality is an app developer that integrates philanthropy and gaming into brands&#8217; social media strategies. Why It&#8217;s Working: The app network blends gaming and social good to create viral digital engagement programs as part of a brand&#8217;s social strategy. Its network of social apps reaches more than 300 million visitors each month. Read the full story here. 4. Idealist Big Idea: Idealist is a platform that helps connect non-profits and charities with volunteers, interns and employees. Why It&#8217;s Working: With more than one million registered users, Idealist is a conduit for those interested in working at non-profits or charities to find a job with purpose. It&#8217;s also a win for non-profits and charities, which benefit from visibility and resources found on Idealist&#8217;s website. Read the full story and see the video here. 5. Raspberry Pi Big Idea: Raspberry Pi is a small, lightweight computer that runs on Linux and costs next to nothing &#8212; the Model A retails at $35, while the forthcoming Model B will be priced at $25. Why It&#8217;s Working: By far the cheapest computer on the market, the creator of Raspberry Pi hopes to get the gadget in the hands of children all over the world. Read the full story here. What do you think of the efforts of these startups and foundations? Let us know in the comments below. More About: features, mashable, roundup, trending, World at Work</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/world-at-work-8/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/20/world-at-work-8/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Marketer Vitrue Has Been Bought By Oracle For $300 Million</title>
      <description>TechCrunch has discovered that software giant Oracle has bought social marketing platform Vitrue for $300 million. The acquisition will give Oracle a strong Facebook marketing platform to offer its enterprise clients. Vitrue had taken $33 million in funding over the years and grown to become one of the most popular solution for big companies trying to win Facebook fans and push out marketing messages to the news feed. TC understands there was a lot of interest. Several bidders approached the company but Oracle was the most aggressive. Oracle will combine it with their overall social cloud offering targeting enterprises. Vitrue is one of the biggest of the social media marketing companies that have emerged over the last few years. It also integrates Pinterest and Instagram into their offerings. More analysis to come.</description>
      <link>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/23/more/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</link>
      <guid>http://techcrunch.com/2012/05/23/more/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Techcrunch+%28TechCrunch%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Officially Acquires Motorola Mobility, Appoints New CEO</title>
      <description>Motorola Mobility is now officially part of Google. CEO Larry Page announced Tuesday the search giant had closed the deal to acquire the cellphone manufacturer, also revealing that Motorola CEO Sanjay Jha would be stepping down. In the blog post, Page said the new CEO is &#8220;longtime Googler&#8221; Dennis Woodside. Page says Woodside, an ironman triathlete, is largely responsible for building Google&#8217;s presence overseas, especially in the Middle East, Africa, Eastern Europe and Russia. He has served as Google&#8217;s president of the of the Americas for the past three years and played a role in increasing Google&#8217;s revenue from $10.8 billion to $17.5 billion over that period. More details to come&#8230; More About: Google, MotorolaFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/google-closes-motorola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/google-closes-motorola/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube</title>
      <description>Jeff Pidgeon: SKYFALL - Official Teaser Trailer: http://t.co/ejmqd0tU via @youtube &#9733; Like Siftlinks.com? Donate now.</description>
      <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</link>
      <guid>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xJ4dAY3DW4c&amp;feature=youtu.be</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Tests New Timeline Design [PICS]</title>
      <description>Facebook is testing a series of cosmetic changes to the top of users&#8217; Timelines, the company has confirmed. Screenshots of the new design were posted on Talking Points Memo Tuesday morning. The images (below) show a condensed version of Timeline, in which a user&#8217;s details (name, occupation, education, location) appear in reverse type on top of &#8212; rather than below &#8212; the cover photo. The carousel of thumbnail images highlighting friends, photos, places, likes, etc. has also been compressed. Images are now replaced by thumbnails. Next to these, a new &#8220;Summary&#8221; section appears, presumably to highlight key events on a user&#8217;s Timeline. The new version: The old (current) version: It&#8217;s not clear if the new design will give users greater control over the appearance of their Timelines. We&#8217;re curious to know, for instance, whether users will be able to modify the color of the type that appears on top of their cover photos. What do you think of the new design? Do you like the reverse type? Would you miss the thumbnail images if they were removed? BONUS: The Evolution of the Facebook Profile 2005 - The Facebook Back in the days when The Facebook was only available to select networks, the News Feed didn't exist. Users hopped between profiles like this one.Click here to view this gallery.Top image courtesy of iStockphoto, -Oxford- More About: Facebook, facebook timeline, trending</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/facebook-tests-new-timeline-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/22/facebook-tests-new-timeline-design/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
