<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Venus Cross the Sun, with Astronomers [LIVE VIDEO]</title>
      <description>The transit of Venus is well underway, and we&#8217;ve found the best way to watch &#8212; with astronomers and amateur stargazers, in a Google+ Hang&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/05/venus-transit-live/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/05/venus-transit-live/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch Venus Cross the Sun, with Astronomers [LIVE VIDEO]</title>
      <description>The transit of Venus is well underway, and we&#8217;ve found the best way to watch &#8212; with astronomers and amateur stargazers, in a Google+ Hang&#8230;</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/05/venus-transit-live/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/05/venus-transit-live/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+mashable%2Ftech+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Tech%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Definitive Guide to Qualifying a Link Prospect [with Video]</title>
      <description>Posted by Adria Saracino Link builders should look at a website differently than other people. However, through my years of training new link builders, I found that most struggle with this. If they are new, they have trouble letting go of their "consumer lenses," taking everything at face value and evaluating a site by arbitrary trustworthiness cues. If it's SEO Consultants trying to do some link building, they are often looking at the architecture and diving deeply into site metrics. Link builders, on the other hand, should be looking for cues that make a website a good potential partner. They look at metrics like a SEO, but also less tangible cues like engagement and trustworthiness. I thought I'd share the work I'd already done through years of training and create the definitive guide to qualifying a potential link partner. Hopefully it can be used as both a refresher and a tool for training new hires. What Am I Talking About Here I think it's easiest to start with what I'm not talking about. I'm not going through the prospecting process - there are many a guide for that. I'm also not talking about sweet new hacks to scale this through the use of apps, spreadsheets, APIs, etc., though there are some pretty sweet ideas out there and I am all for speeding up the process. While I think efficiency is incredibly important, I think everyone needs to know how to do this stuff manually in order to truly understand how to evaluate a website. What I am talking about is what to do with a list of prospects once you've found them; the steps to take when you click on the first possible site and need to determine whether or not you will contact them. Going after every site willy nilly with an equal amount of effort is going to be a serious waste of time and resources. Here's a road map of where I'll be going with this article to help you improve efficiency: Link building metrics Less tangible metrics Bucketing qualified prospects Improving efficiency + a VIDEO DEMO Link Building Metrics Will this link pass value, and if so, how much? That's the question we're really trying to figure out with link building metrics. And let's be real, there are A LOT of different metrics that could make a data junkie OD. So how do you filter out the noise? This is one of the main stumbling blocks for new or occasional link builders. Just the other day during our #AskDistilled video series, the very first question I came across was, "What metrics do you look at to validate potential link partners?" While all this data is well and fun, it won't make you a great link builder if you spend all day analyzing it. Great link builder = being able to get shit done. If you really want to stand out you need to know how to scale, not spend 10 hours getting one link. So really, there are only a very few metrics I'd say you need to look at to determine if a prospect is worth going after. This is probably the #1 metric I look at because it will help me determine a prospective site's value for all types of projects. If I'm asking for a guest post or promoting an infographic, the new page this piece of content will be put on won't have metrics like page authority and # of linking root domains. But it will have domain authority. Yes, there are other nifty metrics like domain MozRank and domain MozTrust, but to get a quick impression of the site's value directly on the SEOmoz toolbar, this is my go to metric. Obviously the higher the better, but if it's higher on a site I don't recognize I'll evaluate it against other less tangible metrics (below) to determine the accuracy of this. This is one of the best-correlated Moz metrics because SEOmoz's analysis shows that ULD is well correlated with rankings, so you want to look at this. Ideally, the site will have a good amount of ULDs to both the page in question and domain. You can get a general sense of how popular that page/domain is to external websites, and more ULDs could mean more If the number is high, upon first look it may be safe to say that the DA and PA metrics are statistically significant, and thus more likely to stay consistent (if in doubt, I'll look at the backlink profile to see if these ULDs are manipulated). What do I mean by this? If there are only a few ULDs, and 50% of them decide to remove the link, those metrics could drastically change over time. I glance at this when I'm on the home page, but overall I'll ignore this if promoting something for placement on, say, a blog post, since it will be a new page without any PA value yet. For static pages, I'll be really excited if this is a high number and has a good number of ULDs. Also, it's important to note that if I am doing outreach for placement on a subdomain &#8211; such as blog.DOMAIN.com, NAME.blogspot.com, NAME.wordpress.com, and so forth - I will look at the subdomain's PA, since the DA will be pretty irrelevant for these types of targets. By this, I mean link attributes like nofollowed vs. followed. I make sure that all of the nofollowed links are highlighted in the browser I'm using, by doing this on my SEOmoz toolbar: That way I can spot if all the links on the page are nofollowed. If so, I walk, as the chances of convincing someone to do otherwise are slim. Plus, I think it gets a bit too shady talking about that kind of stuff with potential partners &#8211; especially when it is very easy to avoid it otherwise. As I'm scrolling down the page, I always hover over the links and look at the URL in the bottom left of the browser (clicking through wastes time) to see 1) if the links are to external sites and 2) if so, are they clean URLs or are they redirected or have parameters attached to them (i.e. something that looks like this: http://www.domain.com/landing-page?affid=johndoe&amp;sid=campaign1). Ideally, I'd like clean links in order to get the most out of that site's passable link juice. If I really want to know, I'll look at the "Page Attributes" tab in the SEOmoz toolbar, but oftentimes I just do a quick visual skim to see how many links are on the page, looking for blog rolls or excessive lists of links on sidebars. The more links, the more any link juice on that page is going to be split among all of them (regardless if they are followed or nofollowed). Thus, I want pages that have less links. However, a lot of links isn't necessarily a deal breaker, depending on the project goals. What those links say and what they are directing to come into play at that point, which moves us into the less tangible metrics (more below). Those are pretty much the only hard metrics I look at when qualifying a potential link partner. There are other useful ones, like comparing PageRank vs MozRank to check if the site has been penalized (if PR is a lot lower than mR, this could be a sign of a problem). You can also compare MozRank to MozTrust, to see if the site chases PR (though know why PR isn't a great metric for qualifying a site). Depending on the circumstances and my gut feeling, I'll start playing around with other metrics if needed, such as viewing the site code for potential iframes (which, when links reside in them, don't pass value), checking the HTTP status code of specific pages, and using OSE to decipher its top pages or analyze its backlinks. However, like I said, you do not want to waste a ton of time evaluating a site the first time around, only to be ignored when you reach out, or worse, realize you were targeting the completely wrong niche in the first place. Save that type of effort for high value prospects. Less Tangible Metrics Will this site owner work with me, and if so, what would be the best-case scenario? Some of the tangible metrics above will help answer this question, but there are other less tangible hints that an epic link builder will learn to pick up on. Here are the ones I find the most important, all of which can really tell you a lot about the site. This will be the first thing you notice, before you even click through to the site. Get in the habit of looking at URLs and what they tell you. First, does the domain name tell you what the site is about or is it a brand name? Is it highly optimized? Is it so optimized that it doesn't even make sense? There is a difference between www.lawyers.com and www.injury-lawyers-malpractice-law.com. When dealing with highly optimized sites, be on the lookout for ranking manipulation. I also look at the rest of the URL to see what else it says about the site. If it has any /index.html&#8217;s or /p=?&#8217;s, I may be dealing with a website that isn't completely SEO savvy, which could be great for outreach purposes. I also, do a quick check to see if the site is canonicalized. If it isn't, it might again mean the site isn't on the top of its architectural game (though note, some big brands have scary URL structure, so this isn't an end-all-be-all metric). This is important for sites that produce consistent content, like blogs or publications. If I notice that the most recent post was six months ago, it most likely means the site was neglected and I can cross it off my list. I think I can count on one hand the number of times I've tried reaching out to a dead site and heard back with a, "Sure, your content is so good it took me out of my writing slump, thanks!" Pro Tip: If you notice a lot of linking root domains to that page, save it for a backlink analysis later. Reach out to the sites linking to that page and tell them they are linking to a dead site, but you have another resource they might be interested in linking to instead :) Again, this is for projects targeting articles and blog posts. Get in the habit of looking for bylines. First, are there any? If so, are they made up of names or generic terms like "staff?" Is it consistently the same name(s)? If yes, then you know whom to contact about editorial content. Also, if the articles are all hosted on the main page (aka not cut short with a more tag), as you scroll down the page look to see if there are bios. If so, these might very well be contributor pieces. If they are, it is very likely this site will work with you. These are really important to answering the "what would be the best-case scenario" question. The best-case scenario would be that the website would cover your piece and not only give you a link, but also leverage its community to push your content viral. These types of sites are what I like to call "influencers" and they can really help scale your link building efforts by helping your content essentially generate its own links simply by being put in front of the right eyeballs. So how do you know if you're looking at an influencer site? Look for clues that show the site has an engaged audience. These include things like: Number of comments Number of social shares Number of RSS feed and newsletter subscribers Number of social media followers People might ask why I say these are intangible. Well, unless you look at those comments or followers, you don't really know if they are real. Was the subscriber list scraped? Does the site owner accept spam comments? So I bucket this in the intangibles because prospecting isn't about sitting around all day analyzing the nitty gritty, but rather seeing the big picture. Another important part to answering the "will they link to me" question is determining if your company or the content you are pitching is relevant to the content the site hosts. Notice that I don&#8217;t look at a site&#8217;s content until later. This is because you could come across a site with amazing content, but if it has absolutely no valuable metrics you might not want to target it right away. Looking at the content does not mean you need to spend a ton of time reading the website. Rather try: Reading titles &#8211; article titles can tell you not only what the content is about, but the "voice" of the website (are they news headlines or are they bold statements with sometimes vulgar language?). Using the search feature &#8211; If I'm really unsure or think it's a stretch, I'll do a quick keyword search across the site to see if there is any reference to the topic. If so, this gives me great positioning power when contacting them because it lets them know that I know they cover this type of content. About page &#8211; If I am still in doubt, I'll take a quick gander at the site's about page to figure out the mission statement and see if my content fits. But really, this is a last resort and if I have to work this hard to make it work, I need to determine if it's worth the effort. Get in the habit of quickly glancing at navigation and footer links for clues like "contributors," "write for us," or "guest posts." If they have a page dedicated to getting content already, boom, there is my in for contacting them. Also, while you're busy browsing links, look for any red flag keywords that look like sponsored links with questionable anchor text (loans, Viagra, poker, etc.). These aren't generally desirable, so if it's bad enough I'll walk away. After looking at all of these metrics, I usually have a pretty good gut feeling of whether or not I should trust this site. If I'm still not sure and the site is of particular high value, I might use an outbound link checker to see if it's linking to any questionable sites. I may also look at its backlink profile to see if the majority of links coming in are from directories or pages titled "Free Link Exchange." Note, design can be somewhat arbitrary of a spam test because, in my experience, there are a lot of websites out there run by old men just doing it for fun, so they use templates to get some visibility in the online world. So don't always judge a book by its cover. If you're still stumped, here are some questions to ask yourself: Taking a cue from Panda, would I trust giving my credit card information to this site? Does this site offer good content? Is it of value to visitors? What percentage of its site is taken up by AdSense or external links? Does the content look like unique content, or is the site a syndication farm that scrapes articles from around the Internet? What types of content/links are on this site? Are there red flag keywords? Are the external links related to the site content? Does the content seem suspiciously optimized? Is the site transparent? Is there an about or contact section? Transparency is a huge one for me. When there is no contact information and no about section, it can mean the site owner doesn&#8217;t really care about offering good content and connecting with readers, but rather is using this site for SEO or advertising purposes. I do want to note that a lot of AdSense and external links aren&#8217;t necessarily bad. It is only a piece of the puzzle. I think the content and types of external links are more important, but sometimes a lot of AdSense can be an obvious indicator that a site owner is trying to drive traffic to the site in order to make money from click throughs. Bucketing Qualified Prospects As you're going through your prospects, you'll start making a long list of sites to contact. How do you prioritize these? If you think you don't need to, you are wrong. Bucketing your prospects is really important so you can determine how long you should spend on trying to convert them and in which order you should reach out. Not all prospects are created equally so you should not be treating them the same. You don't need to be really formal about this, bucketing them into separate lists or labeling them obsessively. But you definitely can if it helps. I've found that I have a pretty good memory and just know with a few quick sorts in Excel, but if this isn't you find a system of organization that works best for you. Here are the variables I tend to use for determining buckets: DA Influencer status Potential difficulty of getting a link Past relationship? First access play? That's pretty much it. All of the other metrics told me that the site was worth being on the list, but these are the ones needed to organize them. These are the buckets I use and what defines them (I know, ingenious titles): High Value Sites with a high DA (anywhere from 65+ depending on the project), extreme influencer power (will help my content go viral), and likely difficult to get a link on. Why the last metric? Because sites that are high enough value are worth the chase, and this metric will help determine how long you should wait before letting go. Medium Value Sites with a DA around 50 &#8211; 65, has some influencer status (might get a handful of comments and shares), and probably reasonably easy to get a link. Low Value DA below 45, barely any influencer status, easy to get a link on &#8211; probably has cues like "write for us" on site. So what do I do with these buckets? I prioritize using the last two metrics from the above list that I didn't mention yet. First access play helps figure out when to contact a prospect, and this is reserved for high value contacts. Why would you give a site with mediocre metrics first access to something? This is oftentimes effective on journalists, who are always hungry to break a story. The past relationship point also helps determine when you will contact a prospect. I usually give my existing contacts the courtesy of first dibs once a piece goes live not only out of respect, but also because the turnaround time will probably be quick and allow me to start raking in the wins. Plus, these contact attempts will be easiest because you don't need to butter them up, so get these out of the way. So what order do I do outreach in once I have my prospects in buckets? Why the back and forth? Because I never do outreach in a linear fashion. You could reach out to all your prospects in a particular bucket only to find out your contact approach was a fail. Link builders need to think on their feet and do some informal A/B testing to figure out what will work, because you can never 100% guarantee what responses will be like for outreach. So my advice would be not to put all your eggs in one basket, but do outreach in chunks and adjust if the approach doesn't work. Improving Efficiency This was a long article. I know. But just because it was long does not mean this process needs to take forever &#8211; but it will at first. Every new link builder gets caught up qualifying sites, and they will keep doing it until they gain the confidence to breeze through it. This comes with practice, so whether you are new yourself or hiring, please keep this in mind and adjust your expectations accordingly. Practice of course will improve speed. When looking at a site for all of the above metrics and clues, I take a minute or less. The only time it takes longer is when I am looking for a high value target's contact details. The qualifying process &#8211; being able to say "yes" or "no" to adding them to your list &#8211; should become second nature to you; so much that you no longer look at websites the same ever again, even as a consumer. To review, let me give you a quick video of what I look at when I am qualifying a potential prospect, putting all of these metrics into practice. My advice for becoming a speedier and more efficient link builder in general is: Be hyper organized &#8211; whether you use a tool like Buzzstream or spreadsheets, you need to stay on top of your game and be detailed so you don't have to keep going back to the site to remember why you put it on your list in the first place. You should be able to put it on your list and not have to go back to the website when you contact them. Here is an example of the information I collect on spreadsheets when prospecting: You'll see I have a dropdown list in place to explain the relationship stage. I color code these so when I have a long list and sort them, I can quickly browse. Flag date refers to the next time I want to remember to contact them. Notes is where I like to keep detailed information so I do not have to go back to the site before contacting. Have an efficient workflow &#8211; I prospect, outreach, repeat in chunks. I rarely do all my prospecting and then all my outreach because you could be targeting a niche that will fail or burn yourself out. Similarly, I don't prospect one site, contact it, prospect, repeat. Reaching out one by one is difficult to scale and speed through, so focus on one task and ship it, rather than waffling back and forth. After qualifying your prospects, you're ready to craft a pitch and contact the appropriate person for each site. Hopefully this will help qualifying become second nature, allowing you to speed through the process and focus on what really matters &#8211; building relationships and getting conversions. Sign up for The Moz Top 10, a semimonthly mailer updating you on the top ten hottest pieces of SEO news, tips, and rad links uncovered by the Moz team. Think of it as your exclusive digest of stuff you don't have time to hunt down but want to read!</description>
      <link>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/definitive-guide-to-qualifying-a-link-prospect-video?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.seomoz.org/blog/definitive-guide-to-qualifying-a-link-prospect-video?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+seomoz+%28SEOmoz+Daily+Blog%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Mean To Be Alarmist, But The TV Business May Be Starting To Collapse</title>
      <description>In the first decade of the commercial Internet--the 1990s and early 2000s--there were frequent murmurings that newspapers were screwed. The digital audience didn't read newspapers, people pointed out. They visited web sites. They read articles here and there. But they didn't put the stack of articles, photos, and ads known as a "newspaper" on their breakfast table and flip through the whole thing. What's more, the digital audience stopped using newspapers as a reference and source for commerce. They browsed on eBay and Craigslist instead of reading classifieds. They got their movie news from movie sites. They got real-estate listings from real-estate sites. They learned about "sales" and other events from email and coupon sites. And so on. In other words, the user behavior that had supported newspaper companies for a century began to change. But for almost a whole decade, the newspaper industry barely noticed. Subscriptions kept going up. Ads kept going up. Stocks kept going up. Those who said that newspapers were screwed were dismissed as clueless doom-mongers, at least by newspaper executives. Then this happened: And lots of newspaper companies went broke or almost went broke. And the stock of The New York Times Company, the country's premiere newspaper, fell from $50 to $6. (See: "The Incredible Shrinking New York Times") In other words, newspapers were screwed. It just took a while for changing user behavior to really hammer the business. The same is almost certainly true for television. In our household, as in many households, television consumption has changed massively over the past decade, especially over the past 5 years. We almost never watch television shows when they are broadcast anymore (with the very notable exception of live sports) We rarely watch shows with ads, even on a DVR We watch a lot of TV and movie content, but always on demand and almost never with ads (We're now so used to watching shows via Netflix or iTunes or HBO that ads now seem like bizarre intrusions) We get our news from the Internet, article by article, clip by clip. The only time we watch TV news live is when there's a crisis or huge event happening somewhere. (You still can't beat TV for that, but soon, news networks will also be streamed). We watch TV and movie content on 4 different screens, depending on which is convenient (TV, laptops, phones, iPad) If not for live sports, which are consumed by exactly one member of our household (me), there is no way we would be paying for cable TV or any other kind of traditional pay TV anymore. And even as a sports fan, I'm starting to find the fragmented multi-channel coverage of the few sports I watch--like tennis (Grand Slams), baseball (Yankees), and football (Jets/Giants)--so annoying that I may soon investigate just getting those via direct subscriptions. In other words, in our household, and in many other households like ours, the same thing has happened to the TV business that has happened to the newspaper business: The user behavior that supported the traditional all-in-one TV "packages"--networks and cable/satellite distributors--has changed. We still consume some TV content, but we consume it when and where we want it, and we consume it deliberately: In other words, we don't settle down in front of the TV and watch "what's on." And, again with the exception of live sports, we've gotten so used to watching shows and series without ads that ads now seem extraordinarily intrusive and annoying. Our kids see TV ads so rarely that they're actually curious about and confused by them: "What is that? A commercial?" For now, our type of household may still be in the minority, but we won't be for long. And our type of household is the type of household that many advertisers and TV networks want to reach. We're still in "the demo" (24-55), and we're still buying a lot of stuff. So, what are the key points of this shift in user behavior for the traditional TV business? "Networks" are completely meaningless. We don't know or care which network owns the rights to a show or where it was broadcast. The only question that's relevant is whether it's available on Netflix, Hulu, Amazon, or iTunes. This means that one of the key traditional "businesses" of TV--the network--is obsolete. The majority of what we pay our cable company is wasted. We get broadband Internet from our cable company, and we use that constantly. But we also get 500 channels that we almost never watch, along with a couple (HBO, Tennis Channel) that we pay extra for and do watch occasionally. We rarely watch TV ads, and when we do, we're usually doing something else at the same time--like typing. Also, the ads seem startlingly intrusive, because we're not used to them. More directly, what this means is this: The vast majority of money TV advertisers spend to reach our household (~$750 a year, ~$60/month) is wasted, because we rarely watch TV content with ads, and, when we do, we rarely watch the ads. The vast majority of money we pay our cable company for live TV (~$1,200 a year / ~$100/month) is wasted, because we almost never watch live TV and we can get most of what we want to watch from iTunes, Netflix, Hulu, and Amazon. This user behavior has been changing for a while, and, so far, it has had almost no impact on the TV business. On the contrary, the networks and cable companies are still fat and happy, and they're coining more and more money every year. But remember what happened in the newspaper business. When the Internet arrived, user behavior started to change. It took a decade for this change in behavior to hit the business. But when it hit the business, it hit it hard--and it destroyed it shockingly quickly. And the same thing seems likely to happen to the TV business. The only questions are: When will it happen? What will it do? Let's take the second first. What is the shift in user behavior likely to do to the TV business? The traditional "network" model is likely to break down and be replaced with far larger "libraries" of content and far more efficient content production, acquisition, and distribution. Some of the content produced by networks will still be consumed (and, therefore, produced), but the idea of getting "affiliate fees" and selling advertising for each of dozens of branded networks seems absurd. This change is already occurring, of course: Traditional networks are being replaced by Netflix, iTunes, and uber-networks like "NBC Universal" and "Time Warner." There is so much money in the network business right now that, initially, this shift won't mean much. Over time, however, it will. Unprofitable networks will be merged with profitable ones. Unprofitable shows and overpaid talent will be cut. Overpaid managers will get fired. Production costs, on aggregate, will drop. Sets, crews, newsgathering, etc. will be consolidated. The fat will get squeezed out of the system. The cost of traditional pay TV will have to drop--users will have to get more for less, or they'll stop paying for much at all. I might value the TV content we get through our cable company at $20 a month--about 1/5th of what we pay for it. Eventually, as soon as I can figure out ways to get the few sports I watch another way, we'll stop paying the $100. Ultimately, the distinction between "TV" and other forms of video content will disappear. We'll pay some distributors for bundles of that content, we'll buy some of it directly, and we'll get some of it for free. But a lot of the money that is currently being wasted by us and to reach us will be spent much more efficiently. Bottom line, as it has in newspapers, the TV business is going to have to get radically more efficient. It won't disappear--newspapers haven't disappeared--but the fat and happy days will have to end. As for the other question, "when," the answer may be "now." Cable TV ratings over the past year have dropped sharply, as this chart from Citi shows. A recent survey from Nielsen, meanwhile, included some startling statistics, including the following: The percent of people worldwide who watch TV at least once a month dropped from 90% to 83% over the past year. The percentage of people who watch video on a computer once a month--84%--is now higher than the percentage who watch TV. Needless to say, a decade ago, newspaper industry forecasters were not expecting newspaper advertising to do this: Similarly, TV forecasters are not expecting TV advertising or subscriptions to do that over the next 10 years. On the contrary, they're expecting TV advertising to just keep going up. But user behavior is changing fast. And at some point, that's going to hammer the business. SEE ALSO: UH OH: This New Nielsen Data Suggests People Aren't Watching TV Anymore Please follow SAI: Media on Twitter and Facebook.Join the conversation about this story &#187;</description>
      <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/tv-business-collapse-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.businessinsider.com/tv-business-collapse-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Zuckerberg Does Not Look Thrilled with Airtime</title>
      <description>The verdict is in on Sean Parker&#8216;s new random video chat startup Airtime: It&#8217;s ChatRoulette, albeit with Facebook connectivity and a slightly greater chance of running into celebrities. That much was driven home Tuesday, when a New York artist who styles himself &#8220;Ronen V.&#8221; tried the service &#8212; and immediately got one Mark Zuckerberg of Palo Alto, Calif. on the other side of his screen. Ronen was excited to meet Zuckerberg, and thanked him &#8220;for making Facebook.&#8221; Zuckerberg, by the looks of things in the screenshot above, was not quite as thrilled. &#8220;After like 30 seconds he NEXTed me,&#8221; Ronen told Betabeat in an email. Still, for Zuck&#8230; Continue reading...</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/05/mark-zuckerberg-does-not-look-thrilled-with-airtime/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/05/mark-zuckerberg-does-not-look-thrilled-with-airtime/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cats away! Artist turns his dead pet into flying helicopter after it is killed by a car - Daily Mail</title>
      <description>Many animal lovers find it hard to part with their pets when they die. So when cat Orville, named after the famous aviator Orville Wright, was run over by a car, his artist owner decided to turn him into a permanent piece of artwork as the ultimate tribute by transforming him into a flying helicopter. Dutch artist Bart Jansen first stuffed Orville before teaming up with radio control helicopter flyer Arjen Beltman to build a specially-designed flying mechanism to attach to the cat. The end result, named the Orvillecopter, is now on show at the Kunstrai art festival in Amsterdam where visitors can watch Orville flying for themselves. Jansen said the Orvillecopter is 'half cat, half machine', and part of a visual art project to pay tribute to his cat Orville. Jansen, part of the art cooperative Generaal Pardon, said: 'After a period of mourning he received his propellers posthumously.' He added that Orville will soon be 'flying with the birds' stating: 'Oh how he loved birds. He will receive more powerful engines and larger props for his birthday. So this hopping will soon change into steady flight.'</description>
      <link>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2154283/Cats-away-Artist-turns-dead-pet-flying-helicopter-killed-car.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2154283/Cats-away-Artist-turns-dead-pet-flying-helicopter-killed-car.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Relationship: Mobile Apps and the Cloud [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Mobile apps and the cloud are going all the way to the altar together. They&#8217;ve been in a relationship for several years and are now inseparable. True love can be hard to explain, but in this case the relationship is based on pragmatism. More and more people are buying, using and relying on smartphones in their everyday lives. Much of that use and reliance revolves around mobile apps. The more mobile apps people use, the more data their phones consume and the more space they need to store all that information. Enter the cloud. Just how ubiquitous are smartphones becoming? More than a billion such devices will be sold in the year 2014, according to a Credit Suisse estimate. By the same year, the market for cloud-based mobile apps will have increased by 90% compared to 2009. By 2016, analysts predict there will be 10 billion connected mobile devices in use globally, and smartphone traffic will be 50 times what it is today. Many of your favorite apps are cloud-based now &#8212; Instagram, Pinterest, Foursquare, Yelp, Groupon and LinkedIn, just to name a handful. Apps are moving to cloud for three primary reasons, according to a survey of IT executives: accessibility to data from multiple devices, lower cost and increased speed for businesses. And increased consumption is disrupting hiring patterns. By 2015, development projects centered around mobile apps are projected to outnumber PC-based projects by four to one. From 2010 to 2011, the IT job site Dice.com reported a 220% increase in job postings for iPhone-related developer positions and a 302% increase in postings for Android developers. Jobs site Elance.com, meanwhile, reported a 100% increase in overall mobile app developer postings. The platform-as-a-service company Engine Yard recently pulled all these stats and more together to create the infographic below. Check it out for a deeper dive and let us know what you think in the comments. Courtesy of: Engine Yard More About: cloud computing, infographics, Mobile, mobile apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/mobile-apps-cloud-infographi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/mobile-apps-cloud-infographi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google To One-Up Apple, Announce 3D Maps a Week Earlier [VIDEO]</title>
      <description>We&#8217;ve already seen a few leaks that suggest Apple will be announcing its own 3D mapping service on June 11 at WWDC, its developer&#8217;s conference. Now it looks like Google is trying to beat Apple to the punch by unveiling its own 3D maps a week earlier. At an event entitled &#8220;The Next Dimension of Google Maps&#8221; next Wednesday, Brian McClendon, vice president of Google Maps and Google Earth is slated to give event goers an inside look at what&#8217;s in the works for Google&#8217;s mapping service and &#8220;provide a sneak peek at upcoming features that will help people get where they want to go &#8211; both physically and virtually.&#8221; Apple has used Google Maps in the iPhone since its launch in 2007, the company is rumored to be removing Google&#8217;s mapping service completely from its phone with the release of iOS 6 and replacing it with its own Google Maps alternative. Reports earlier this year indicated that the company will be showing off its own 3D mapping solution at its Worldwide Developers Conference June 11. In recent months Apple has also acquired mapping experts C3 Technologies, Placebase, and Poly9 adding fuel to those rumors. Apple also recently removed Google Maps from the iPad version of iPhoto. Google&#8217;s timing on its announcement suggests that it is being done to directly compete with Apple, and perhaps show users what &#8211;potentially better &#8211; options might exist with Google Maps and Android versus what Apple will be offering with the iPhone and iOS 6. What do you think Apple and Google have in store? More importantly, are you interested in 3D mapping in the first place? Let us know your thoughts in the comments. More About: apple, Google, Google Maps, iOS 6, iphone, wwdc</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/google-3d-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/01/google-3d-maps/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Will Disappear by 2020, Says Analyst</title>
      <description>Facebook&#8216;s sliding stock price has at least one hedge fund manager predicting a dismal decade ahead for the social network. &#8220;In five to eight years they are going to disappear in the way that Yahoo has disappeared,&#8221; Ironfire Capital founder Eric Jackson told the CNBC show Squawk on the Street on Monday. &#8220;Yahoo is still making money, it&#8217;s still profitable, still has 13,000 employees working for it, but it&#8217;s 10% of the value that it was at the height of 2000,&#8221; Jackson added. &#8220;For all intents and purposes, it&#8217;s disappeared.&#8221; So how exactly does Jackson see Facebook&#8217;s power eroding by decade&#8217;s end? He says it will be the continued emergence of the mobile web &#8212; and Facebook&#8217;s struggle to adapt to that paradigm shift. &#8220;The world is moving faster, it&#8217;s getting more competitive, not less,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I think those who are dominant in their prior generation are really going to have a hard time moving into this newer generation. &#8220;Facebook can buy a bunch of mobile companies, but they are still a big, fat website and that&#8217;s different from a mobile app.&#8221; Facebook bought the wildly popular mobile photo-sharing app Instagram &#8212; which some saw as a potential rival &#8212; for $1 billion in April. Still, the company has acknowledged mobile as a potential stumbling block for sustained growth. In its required initial pre-IPO disclosure of 35 &#8220;risk factors&#8221; released in February, the company admitted that as mobile use of Facebook and the web in general continues to expand, its ad-free mobile platform will become more problematic. In an amended filing in May, the company underscored that challenge again. Facebook stock officially went on sale on May 18 at $38 per share. It closed Monday at $26.90. Jackson sees Facebook as a member of the second of three generations of modern Internet companies. The first generation, highlighted by businesses such as Google and Yahoo, served as portals that organized and aggregated the web&#8217;s wealth of information. The second generation, most notably Facebook, capitalized on an emerging social web. The third generation is made up of companies whose sole goal is leveraging and monetizing mobile users. &#8220;When you look over these three generations, no matter how successful you are in one generation, you don&#8217;t seem to be able to translate that into success in the second generation, no matter how much money you have in the bank, no matter how many smart PhDs you have working for you,&#8221; Jackson says. &#8220;Look at how Google has struggled moving into social, and I think Facebook is going to have the same kind of challenges moving into mobile.&#8221; What do you think Facebook&#8217;s status will be in five years? Share your predictions in the comments. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/analyst-facebook-disappear/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/analyst-facebook-disappear/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unemployed bussed in to steward river pageant</title>
      <description>Coachloads of jobless people brought in to work unpaid on river pageant as part of Work ProgrammeA group of long-term unemployed jobseekers were bussed into London to work as unpaid stewards during the diamond jubilee celebrations and told to sleep under London Bridge before working on the river pageant.Up to 30 jobseekers and another 50 people on apprentice wages were taken to London by coach from Bristol, Bath and Plymouth as part of the government's Work Programme.Two jobseekers, who did not want to be identified in case they lost their benefits, said they had to camp under London Bridge the night before the pageant. They told the Guardian they had to change into security gear in public, had no access to toilets for 24 hours, and were taken to a swampy campsite outside London after working a 14-hour shift in the pouring rain on the banks of the Thames on Sunday.One young worker said she was on duty between London Bridge and Tower Bridge during the &#163;12m river spectacle of a 1,000-boat flotilla and members of the Royal family sail by . She said that the security firm Close Protection UK, which won a stewarding contract for the jubilee events, gave her a plastic see-through poncho and a high-visibility jacket for protection against the rain.Close Protection UK confirmed that it was using up to 30 unpaid staff and 50 apprentices, who were paid &#163;2.80 an hour, for the three-day event in London. A spokesman said the unpaid work was a trial for paid roles at the Olympics, which it had also won a contract to staff. Unpaid staff were expected to work two days out of the three-day holiday.The firm said it had spent considerable resources on training and equipment that stewards could keep and that the experience was voluntary and did not affect jobseekers keeping their benefits.The woman said that people were picked up at Bristol at 11pm on Saturday and arrived in London at 3am on Sunday. "We all got off the coach and we were stranded on the side of the road for 20 minutes until they came back and told us all to follow them," she said. "We followed them under London Bridge and that's where they told us to camp out for the night &#8230; It was raining and freezing."A 30-year-old steward told the Guardian that the conditions under the bridge were "cold and wet and we were told to get our head down [to sleep]". He said that it was impossible to pitch a tent because of the concrete floor.The woman said they were woken at 5.30am and supplied with boots, combat trousers and polo shirts. She said: "They had told the ladies we were getting ready in a minibus around the corner and I went to the minibus and they had failed to open it so it was locked. I waited around to find someone to unlock it, and all of the other girls were coming down trying to get ready and no one was bothering to come down to unlock [it], so some of us, including me, were getting undressed in public in the freezing cold and rain." The men are understood to have changed under the bridge.The female steward said that after the royal pageant, the group travelled by tube to a campsite in Theydon Bois, Essex, where some had to pitch their tents in the dark.She said: "London was supposed to be a nice experience, but they left us in the rain. They couldn't give a crap &#8230; No one is supposed to be treated like that, [working] for free. I don't want to be treated where I have to sleep under a bridge and wait for food." The male steward said: "It was the worst experience I've ever had. I've had many a job, and many a bad job, but this one was the worst."Both stewards said they were originally told they would be paid. But when they got to the coach on Saturday night, they said, they were told that the work would be unpaid and that if they did not accept it they would not be considered for well-paid work at the Olympics.Molly Prince, managing director of Close Protection UK, said in a statement: "We take the welfare of our staff and apprentices very seriously indeed."The staff travelling to the jubilee are completing their training and being assessed on the job for NVQ Level 2 in spectator safety after having completed all the knowledge requirements in the classroom and some previous work experience. It is essential that they are assessed in a live work environment in order to complete their chosen qualifications."The nature of festival and event work is such that we often travel sleeping on coaches through the night with an early morning pre-event start &#8211; it is the nature of the business &#8230; It's hard work and not for the faint-hearted."We had staff travel from several locations and some arrived earlier than others at the meeting point, which I believe was London Bridge [pictured left], which was why some had to hang around. This is an unfortunate set of circumstances but not lack of care on the part of CPUK."The company said it had spent up to &#163;220 on sponsoring security training licences for each participant and that boots and combat trousers cost more than &#163;100.The charity Tomorrow's People, which set up the placements at Close Protection under the work programme, said it would review the situation, but stressed that unpaid work was valuable and made people more employable. Tomorrow's People is one of eight youth charities that were supported in the Guardian and Observer's Christmas appeal last year.Abi Levitt, director of development services at the charity, said: "We have been unable to verify the accuracy of the situation with either the people on work experience or the business concerned."We will undertake a review of the situation as matter of urgency. Tomorrow's People believes strongly in the value of work experience in helping people to build the skills, confidence and CV they need to get and keep a job and we have an exemplary record going back nearly 30 years for our work with the long-term unemployed."Queen's diamond jubileeUnemploymentJob huntingWork &amp; careersShiv Malikguardian.co.uk &#169; 2012 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our Terms &amp; Conditions | More Feeds</description>
      <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2012/jun/04/jubilee-pageant-unemployed</link>
      <guid>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2012/jun/04/jubilee-pageant-unemployed</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Will Disappear by 2020, Says Analyst</title>
      <description>Facebook&#8216;s sliding stock price has at least one hedge fund manager predicting a dismal decade ahead for the social network. &#8220;In five to eight years they are going to disappear in the way that Yahoo has disappeared,&#8221; Ironfire Capital founder Eric Jackson told the CNBC show Squawk on the Street on Monday. &#8220;Yahoo is still making money, it&#8217;s still profitable, still has 13,000 employees working for it, but it&#8217;s 10% of the value that it was at the height of 2000,&#8221; Jackson added. &#8220;For all intents and purposes, it&#8217;s disappeared.&#8221; So how exactly does Jackson see Facebook&#8217;s power eroding by decade&#8217;s end? He says it will be the continued emergence of the mobile web &#8212; and Facebook&#8217;s struggle to adapt to that paradigm shift. &#8220;The world is moving faster, it&#8217;s getting more competitive, not less,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I think those who are dominant in their prior generation are really going to have a hard time moving into this newer generation. &#8220;Facebook can buy a bunch of mobile companies, but they are still a big, fat website and that&#8217;s different from a mobile app.&#8221; Facebook bought the wildly popular mobile photo-sharing app Instagram &#8212; which some saw as a potential rival &#8212; for $1 billion in April. Still, the company has acknowledged mobile as a potential stumbling block for sustained growth. In its required initial pre-IPO disclosure of 35 &#8220;risk factors&#8221; released in February, the company admitted that as mobile use of Facebook and the web in general continues to expand, its ad-free mobile platform will become more problematic. In an amended filing in May, the company underscored that challenge again. Facebook stock officially went on sale on May 18 at $38 per share. It closed Monday at $26.90. Jackson sees Facebook as a member of the second of three generations of modern Internet companies. The first generation, highlighted by businesses such as Google and Yahoo, served as portals that organized and aggregated the web&#8217;s wealth of information. The second generation, most notably Facebook, capitalized on an emerging social web. The third generation is made up of companies whose sole goal is leveraging and monetizing mobile users. &#8220;When you look over these three generations, no matter how successful you are in one generation, you don&#8217;t seem to be able to translate that into success in the second generation, no matter how much money you have in the bank, no matter how many smart PhDs you have working for you,&#8221; Jackson says. &#8220;Look at how Google has struggled moving into social, and I think Facebook is going to have the same kind of challenges moving into mobile.&#8221; What do you think Facebook&#8217;s status will be in five years? Share your predictions in the comments. More About: Facebook, facebook ipo</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/analyst-facebook-disappear/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/04/analyst-facebook-disappear/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo Sharing App Picplz to Shut Down on July 3</title>
      <description>If you&#8217;re a fan of the iPhone and Android photo sharing app Picplz, you only have one more month to enjoy its pleasures. In a blog post and email late Friday, developer Mixed Media Labs announced the demise of the app: On July 3, 2012, picplz will shut down permanently and all photos and data will be deleted. We have provided download links for existing users to save their photos. Thank you for your support of picplz and we apologize for any inconvenience this may cause you. Login before July 3, 2012 to download your photos. Picplz was competitive with market leader Instagram when both were new, especially since Picplz was available on both the Android and iPhone platforms while Instagram was only available on the iPhone. In February, 2011, when both Picplz and Instagram launched their APIs, Picplz seemed to gain an edge when it added analytics for its users at the same time, as well as the ability to add Creative Commons licensing to photos. Both apps have the ability to add filters and edges to photos, and can share photos with their own networks as well as friends on Twitter, Flickr and Facebook. But Instagram gained all-important buzz, thus experiencing explosive network growth, making it more desirable than all its competitors. On Saturday, Picplz was no longer available on the Apple App Store. More About: apps, instagram, Mixed Media Labs, photo sharing, picplzFor more Startups coverage:Follow Mashable Startups on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Startups channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/picplz-shut-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/picplz-shut-down/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable%2FStartups+%28Mashable+%C2%BB+Startups%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
