<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>XYDO.COM: xydo network feed</title>
    <description>XYDO.COM: top articles for xydo.com</description>
    <link>http://www.xydo.com</link>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Mean To Be Alarmist, But The TV Business May Be Starting To Collapse</title>
      <description>In the first decade of the commercial Internet--the 1990s and early 2000s--there were frequent murmurings that newspapers were screwed. The digital audience didn't read newspapers, people pointed out. They visited web sites. They read articles here and there. But they didn't put the stack of articles, photos, and ads known as a "newspaper" on their breakfast table and flip through the whole thing. What's more, the digital audience stopped using newspapers as a reference and source for commerce. They browsed on eBay and Craigslist instead of reading classifieds. They got their movie news from movie sites. They got real-estate listings from real-estate sites. They learned about "sales" and other events from email and coupon sites. And so on. In other words, the user behavior that had supported newspaper companies for a century began to change. But for almost a whole decade, the newspaper industry barely noticed. Subscriptions kept going up. Ads kept going up. Stocks kept going up. Those who said that newspapers were screwed were dismissed as clueless doom-mongers, at least by newspaper executives. Then this happened: And lots of newspaper companies went broke or almost went broke. And the stock of The New York Times Company, the country's premiere newspaper, fell from $50 to $6. (See: "The Incredible Shrinking New York Times") In other words, newspapers were screwed. It just took a while for changing user behavior to really hammer the business. The same is almost certainly true for television. In our household, as in many households, television consumption has changed massively over the past decade, especially over the past 5 years. We almost never watch television shows when they are broadcast anymore (with the very notable exception of live sports) We rarely watch shows with ads, even on a DVR We watch a lot of TV and movie content, but always on demand and almost never with ads (We're now so used to watching shows via Netflix or iTunes or HBO that ads now seem like bizarre intrusions) We get our news from the Internet, article by article, clip by clip. The only time we watch TV news live is when there's a crisis or huge event happening somewhere. (You still can't beat TV for that, but soon, news networks will also be streamed). We watch TV and movie content on 4 different screens, depending on which is convenient (TV, laptops, phones, iPad) If not for live sports, which are consumed by exactly one member of our household (me), there is no way we would be paying for cable TV or any other kind of traditional pay TV anymore. And even as a sports fan, I'm starting to find the fragmented multi-channel coverage of the few sports I watch--like tennis (Grand Slams), baseball (Yankees), and football (Jets/Giants)--so annoying that I may soon investigate just getting those via direct subscriptions. In other words, in our household, and in many other households like ours, the same thing has happened to the TV business that has happened to the newspaper business: The user behavior that supported the traditional all-in-one TV "packages"--networks and cable/satellite distributors--has changed. We still consume some TV content, but we consume it when and where we want it, and we consume it deliberately: In other words, we don't settle down in front of the TV and watch "what's on." And, again with the exception of live sports, we've gotten so used to watching shows and series without ads that ads now seem extraordinarily intrusive and annoying. Our kids see TV ads so rarely that they're actually curious about and confused by them: "What is that? A commercial?" For now, our type of household may still be in the minority, but we won't be for long. And our type of household is the type of household that many advertisers and TV networks want to reach. We're still in "the demo" (24-55), and we're still buying a lot of stuff. So, what are the key points of this shift in user behavior for the traditional TV business? "Networks" are completely meaningless. We don't know or care which network owns the rights to a show or where it was broadcast. The only question that's relevant is whether it's available on Netflix, Hulu, Amazon, or iTunes. This means that one of the key traditional "businesses" of TV--the network--is obsolete. The majority of what we pay our cable company is wasted. We get broadband Internet from our cable company, and we use that constantly. But we also get 500 channels that we almost never watch, along with a couple (HBO, Tennis Channel) that we pay extra for and do watch occasionally. We rarely watch TV ads, and when we do, we're usually doing something else at the same time--like typing. Also, the ads seem startlingly intrusive, because we're not used to them. More directly, what this means is this: The vast majority of money TV advertisers spend to reach our household (~$750 a year, ~$60/month) is wasted, because we rarely watch TV content with ads, and, when we do, we rarely watch the ads. The vast majority of money we pay our cable company for live TV (~$1,200 a year / ~$100/month) is wasted, because we almost never watch live TV and we can get most of what we want to watch from iTunes, Netflix, Hulu, and Amazon. This user behavior has been changing for a while, and, so far, it has had almost no impact on the TV business. On the contrary, the networks and cable companies are still fat and happy, and they're coining more and more money every year. But remember what happened in the newspaper business. When the Internet arrived, user behavior started to change. It took a decade for this change in behavior to hit the business. But when it hit the business, it hit it hard--and it destroyed it shockingly quickly. And the same thing seems likely to happen to the TV business. The only questions are: When will it happen? What will it do? Let's take the second first. What is the shift in user behavior likely to do to the TV business? The traditional "network" model is likely to break down and be replaced with far larger "libraries" of content and far more efficient content production, acquisition, and distribution. Some of the content produced by networks will still be consumed (and, therefore, produced), but the idea of getting "affiliate fees" and selling advertising for each of dozens of branded networks seems absurd. This change is already occurring, of course: Traditional networks are being replaced by Netflix, iTunes, and uber-networks like "NBC Universal" and "Time Warner." There is so much money in the network business right now that, initially, this shift won't mean much. Over time, however, it will. Unprofitable networks will be merged with profitable ones. Unprofitable shows and overpaid talent will be cut. Overpaid managers will get fired. Production costs, on aggregate, will drop. Sets, crews, newsgathering, etc. will be consolidated. The fat will get squeezed out of the system. The cost of traditional pay TV will have to drop--users will have to get more for less, or they'll stop paying for much at all. I might value the TV content we get through our cable company at $20 a month--about 1/5th of what we pay for it. Eventually, as soon as I can figure out ways to get the few sports I watch another way, we'll stop paying the $100. Ultimately, the distinction between "TV" and other forms of video content will disappear. We'll pay some distributors for bundles of that content, we'll buy some of it directly, and we'll get some of it for free. But a lot of the money that is currently being wasted by us and to reach us will be spent much more efficiently. Bottom line, as it has in newspapers, the TV business is going to have to get radically more efficient. It won't disappear--newspapers haven't disappeared--but the fat and happy days will have to end. As for the other question, "when," the answer may be "now." Cable TV ratings over the past year have dropped sharply, as this chart from Citi shows. A recent survey from Nielsen, meanwhile, included some startling statistics, including the following: The percent of people worldwide who watch TV at least once a month dropped from 90% to 83% over the past year. The percentage of people who watch video on a computer once a month--84%--is now higher than the percentage who watch TV. Needless to say, a decade ago, newspaper industry forecasters were not expecting newspaper advertising to do this: Similarly, TV forecasters are not expecting TV advertising or subscriptions to do that over the next 10 years. On the contrary, they're expecting TV advertising to just keep going up. But user behavior is changing fast. And at some point, that's going to hammer the business. SEE ALSO: UH OH: This New Nielsen Data Suggests People Aren't Watching TV Anymore Please follow SAI: Media on Twitter and Facebook.Join the conversation about this story &#187;</description>
      <link>http://www.businessinsider.com/tv-business-collapse-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</link>
      <guid>http://www.businessinsider.com/tv-business-collapse-2012-6?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Falleyinsider%2Fsilicon_alley_insider+%28Silicon+Alley+Insider%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Social Media for Employee Referrals</title>
      <description>Kes Thygesen is the Co-Founder and Head of Product at RolePoint, a tool that allows recruitment managers to socially power their hiring to increase the volume and quality of employee referrals. Connect with him and RolePoint on LinkedIn and Twitter. The war for talent is more competitive than ever. Every company wants the best and the brightest on its team, but traditional candidate sourcing methods may not cut it anymore. As companies, we have to be bold, we have to put ourselves on the line and, most importantly, we have to sell our culture harder than in the past. That&#8217;s where you, the already-employed professional, come in. More than ever, recruiters and hiring managers are looking to their internal network to help them find the right fit. After all, the real cost of a hire can be around $100,000, when you factor in the non-direct costs, such as training and the productivity lost in finding a new employee and bringing him up to speed. Many workers are passive candidates, meaning that they are silently looking or waiting for an attractive offer. And, there&#8217;s a large chance your friends are lumped into this group. Pair that with the explosion of social networking and we have a recipe for talent acquisition success. Apart from a status update here and there, you can use social media to help your friends find jobs and earn anywhere between $1,000 to $15,000 as a referral bonus from your company. Check out these tips to get the most out of your friend circle. 1. Look Beyond Your First Degree of Connections No matter what industry you&#8217;re in, you probably have tons of connections through your social networks. However, it may be in your company&#8217;s best interest to go past the base-level when you&#8217;re trying to help your friends find jobs. The right fit may lie beyond your direct connections, but you&#8217;d never know this if you just skim the surface. Many social networks allow you to see beyond your primary network. For example, Facebook &#8220;suggests&#8221; friends while LinkedIn not only shows second and third degrees, but it also may bring you to the right candidate based on their employment history. This tactic allows you to reach thousands of potential candidates, which is probably a lot more efficient than scouring your friends or contacts list. 2. Find a Perfectly Catered Match Do you think that all you need to do is tweet out a job listing to your friends? There&#8217;s actually more to it. Social media also comes with access to deeper technology and analytical insights, so take advantage of it. You can easily search for the right connections on your social networks by looking for specific keywords. For instance, say your company is looking for a candidate with an extensive design background who knows Photoshop and is located in San Francisco. You can search for these job-specific keywords on your social networks to find a more catered match. Once you&#8217;ve found these matches, you can then, of course, check out their profiles and job history to ensure they are the perfect candidate to be your new co-worker. Show Off Your Company Culture You know your workplace better than anyone else. So, use social media to show why your organization and company culture is inviting and forward-thinking and how it helped progress the careers of its employees. For instance many companies are using video testimonials to give a better insight into the journey a candidate takes within the company. This video could then, in turn, be posted on your social networks and blog. The aim here is to bring the organization down to a &#8220;human&#8221; level, free of typical corporate jargon. It makes it easier for your contacts to realize what your company is all about, and why they should consider the particular position. In a similar vein, recruitment videos, such as the one Twitter recently made, have been extremely successful in reaching potential candidates and giving them a better idea of what it&#8217;s like to work at a company. Share the Bonuses Most companies have a significant referral bonus if the contacts you suggest get hired, and the best way to reach beyond your direct contacts could be to pay it forward. If there&#8217;s a $5,000 referral bonus at your company, pick some of your well connected contacts and offer them half the bonus if they know anyone that might be a good fit &#8212; you&#8217;ll be surprised how many people are connected to talented people looking for new opportunities. In addition, you can make the process easier and help your friends out by using job matching platforms. Many of these actually allow you to analyze what kind of worker someone may be based on their social network value and work experience. By using these platforms, you gain something that keyword searching can&#8217;t give you: thorough insight and background information based on the networks your friends are using on an everyday basis. After all, you can learn a lot about a person by what they&#8217;re saying on Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn. If it matches what your company is saying, you may be on your way to finding the perfect colleague. Conclusion The combination of all of these gives your organization access to the highly sought-after professionals who&#8217;ll likely stick around for the long haul. Plus, you have the opportunity to help a friend who may be able to bring real value to your company, which is the ultimate goal for anyone looking to fill a coveted spot. It&#8217;s a win-win. What do you think? What are some other ways you can use social media to help your friends get jobs? Social Media Job Listings Every week we post a list of social media and web job opportunities. While we publish a huge range of job listings, we&#8217;ve selected some of the top social media job opportunities from the past two weeks to get you started. Happy hunting! Web Producer at Random House in New York City Director, Digital Business Development at the Washington Post in Washington, D.C. Software Engineer II at Matheson in Sacramento, Calif. Image courtesy wilhei, Flickr. More About: features, hiring, job search series, Recruiting, social networkingFor more Business coverage:Follow Mashable Business on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Business channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/social-media-friends-jobs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/social-media-friends-jobs/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Fascinating Things We Learned From Reddit This Week</title>
      <description>1. The White House Makes Beer NPR interviewed Michelle Obama this week about gardening, but Reddit users were more interested in the mention of the White House's home-brewed beer. White House Honey Ale is the first homemade beer to have been made in the White House. As one commenter mentioned, there are now two additional styles being brewed: White House Honey Blonde Ale and White House Honey Porter. Click here to view this gallery.Some of the most interesting things on Reddit are also the most unexpected. For instance, a post that&#8217;s just supposed to make people laugh might leave users learning something new. Or maybe an interesting interview with a celebrity includes a moment that&#8217;s fascinating, but has nothing to do with the original topic of discussion. Those are some of the most valuable moments on Reddit. For example, this week users got a biology lesson in the comments of a funny bird photo. They also learned that the White House makes beer, which came up when Michelle Obama told NPR about gardening. SEE ALSO: Reddit 101: Co-Founders Explain the Community [VIDEO] Ironically, the book that&#8217;s famous for making you look really hard for something small, &#8220;Where&#8217;s Waldo?&#8221; is also part of this week&#8217;s interesting facts. Seeking more odd facts? Check out last week&#8217;s roundup here. More About: fact, features, reddit</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/reddit-roundup-6-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/reddit-roundup-6-3/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Travel Tools for Planning Your Family Adventure</title>
      <description>1. Trippy As you can tell by the screenshot, Trippy looks very similar to Pinterest. At first, that's almost precisely how Trippy functioned, too. Recently, Trippy incorporated vacation planning into its otherwise simple "pinboard" functionality. Trippy's new map tool locates all the photos you've posted to your boards and pins them to a world map, so you can localize your travel wish list. Furthermore, Trippy has added Facebook Timeline integration, so consider connecting the social network to share your travel plans with friends. Click here to view this gallery.When it comes to planning an inexpensive, convenient vacation, you can never have enough travel tools in your arsenal. Whether you&#8217;re simply in the wish-list phase or well past the hotel-booking stage, digital and online resources can help. We&#8217;ve collected seven of our favorite travel tools that will inspire you, as well as help you organize and share your next holiday. Learn more about Thailand from user-curated sites like Wanderfly, or set up travel deal notifications on sites like TripTwit. SEE ALSO: 10 Free Must-Have Travel Apps for Android What tools do you find most helpful for planning vacations? Share advice for fellow travelers in the comments below. More About: apps, features, lifestyle, Social Media, travel</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/travel-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/travel-tools/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Adds Admin Roles: This Week in Social Media</title>
      <description>Welcome to our weekly edition of what&#8217;s hot in social media news. To help you stay up-to-date with social media, here are some of the news items that caught our attention.What&#8217;s New This Week?Facebook Gives Granularity to Page Admin Roles: Businesses with Facebook Pages can now set five different roles for their admins: Manager, Content Creator, Moderator, Advertiser and Insights Analyst. This is a useful tool for Facebook managers.Businesses on Facebook can now grant page admins varying degrees of permissions, depending on their role.Facebook Adds Post Scheduling: You can now schedule posts directly on your Facebook Page. &#8221;You can prepare a post and schedule it to appear later by adding a date and time in the future before you post it.&#8221;"You can schedule a post up to 6 months in advance in 15-minute intervals," and you can also "choose a date in the past" and your post will appear at the appropriate place on your Page's Timeline.Discussion From Our Networking Clubs: Thousands of social media marketers and small business owners are asking questions and helping others in our free Networking Clubs. Here are a few interesting discussions worth highlighting:How will the switch to Google+ Local impact your business?Has anyone tried the new Facebook Promoted Posts?Share your comments on ghost writing for blogs.Facebook Rolls Out Promoted Posts for Facebook Pages: &#8220;Promoted posts are a simple way to reach more of the people who like your Page and their friends.&#8221; Promoted Posts give your updates more exposure on Facebook.To promote a post, select the Promote button after creating an update on your Page.Google+ Local Replaces Google Places: &#8220;Each place you see in Google+ Local will now be scored using Zagat&#8217;s 30-point scale, which tells you all about the various aspects of a place so you can make the best decisions.&#8221; Google Place pages have been automatically converted into Google+ Local pages. This is Google&#8217;s first step beyond Google Places.Google+ users can see the different scores others give this restaurant.Bit.ly Gets New Look: The new design features &#8220;make it easier and faster to find and share interesting stuff.&#8221; Things have moved around a bit, so if you&#8217;re looking for something specific, check their Knowledge Base for directions.Check out Bit.ly's new bookmarking feature, the Bitmark.Pinterest Rival Fancy Brings Social Commerce to iPhone: The Fancy iPhone app allows people to browse the cool products shared on Fancy and also purchase items directly through their mobile devices.Fancy has nearly one million users who press the Fancy button 3 million times every week.Enhancer Adds Music to Vimeo Videos: Vimeo&#8217;s new Enhancer tool makes it easy for users to find and add music to their videos. The music catalog &#8220;has tracks in tons of genres, with lots for free.&#8221; Here are a couple of social media tools worth noting:Network Updater: A free social network alert service that sends you email alerts for any changes or updates from the Twitter and Facebook friends you select.Network Updater ensures you don't miss the news from the people who matter most to you.Curalate: A paid monitoring and analytics Pinterest tool for both the activity on your Pinterest account and all of the pinning activity from your own website.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X8iVa5gq2lIWhat social media news caught your interest this week? Please share your comments below. Tweet</description>
      <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-adds-admin-roles-this-week-in-social-media/</link>
      <guid>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/facebook-adds-admin-roles-this-week-in-social-media/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-way Ticket to Mars, Please: Startup Plans Space Colony in 2023</title>
      <description>NASA&#8217;s road map for getting to Mars may be in flux, and SpaceX pioneer Elon Musk has only a vague intention to point his rockets at the Red Planet. But that doesn&#8217;t mean nobody is making definitive plans to set up shop on the fourth rock from the Sun. Stepping into the vacuum Friday: a brand new private space venture from the Netherlands called Mars One, which aims to send four astronauts on a one-way journey to Mars in just 11 years time. Founded by Dutch entrepreneur and researcher Bas Landsdorp, who previously headed up an alternative energy company, the new venture doesn&#8217;t have a lot of the polish of other private space companies, many of which were started by billionaires such as Musk, Paul Allen or Jeff Bezos. Watch that video above and you&#8217;ll get a distinct sense of the earnest amateur. For all its letters of intent from component suppliers and support from Nobel prize-winners, there doesn&#8217;t seem to be a lot of money behind this venture &#8212; yet. But here&#8217;s what Mars One does have going for it: a definite and achievable to-do list. SEE ALSO: This $20 Trillion Rock Could Turn a Startup into Earth&#8217;s Richest Company Step one: send a communications satellite to Mars in 2016. Step two: follow up with a Red Planet rover in 2018, which will trawl the dusty landscape, scoping out some of the best spots to found a colony. Step three, in 2020: send infrastructure for the colonists to live in, including solar panels and machines that will convert the Martian elements into water and oxygen. Only then, on the surprisingly specific date of September 14, 2022, will Mars One launch its first four astronauts. Their journey to the new colony will take ten months, though they will have been preparing for a decade. Most of that prep time, we hope, will be spent figuring out how not to kill someone when you have to live in extremely close quarters for the better part of a year and none of you can take a shower. Landsdorp plans to send another couple of adventurous astronauts to join the colony every two years, but the idea is that no one gets a return journey. This is a permanent base, a Plymouth Rock in an entirely new world that will begin the long, slow and painstaking process of terraforming it. And how will this all be funded? Landsdorp has two words for you: &#8220;media spectacle.&#8221; We&#8217;re not sure what that means, exactly &#8212; selling broadcast rights to the landing? Sponsorships from large corporations eager to advertise on the mission? Will Coke be the first soda on Mars? Whatever it is, we can&#8217;t wait to find out. If Mars One is selling subscriptions to this spectacle, sign us up. Would you pay to watch humans travel to Mars? Let us know in the comments. More About: elon musk, Mars, space, SpaceXFor more Tech coverage:Follow Mashable Tech on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Tech channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/mars-one/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/mars-one/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MTV Movie Awards Go Social With Live Voting, Facebook Tracker and More</title>
      <description>MTV&#8217;s extensive social and digital tactics for the MTV Movie Awards offer viewers new ways to engage before, during and after the June 3 live broadcast. Building off its social success with the VMAs, MTV is looking to deeply integrate social elements into its other major awards show, the MTV Movie Awards. For the first time, movie fans can vote using Twitter hashtags. The live social voting works only for the new &#8220;Best Hero&#8221; category, which already has attracted more than 60,000 votes since Tuesday. Registered MTV.com users, however, can still vote in other categories on the show&#8217;s website. Vying for the &#8220;Best Hero&#8221; title are Harry Potter (#votepotter), Katniss Everdeen (from Hunger Games, #votekatniss), Thor (#votethor), Captain America (#votecaptain) and Jenko (from 21 Jump Street, #votejenko). MTV told us that it knows from past live-voting initiatives that fans love to get the word out to promote their favorite stars and franchises. &#8220;They love to game the system and we look forward to helping them do just that,&#8221; MTV told us. As a result, expect a showdown for &#8220;Best Hero&#8221; between fans of The Hunger Games and Harry Potter to continue until Sunday night. MTV also has these digital elements on tap for the awards show hosted by comedian Russell Brand: Twitter Tracker: Like MTV did during the Video Music Awards in August, it will dissect Twitter conversations in a visualization that displays popular moments and celebrities. The feature will allow users to view how many tweets per minute any moment is garnering and share photos of certain moments across social networks. What&#8217;s different about this year&#8217;s implementation is that MTV will be providing context around what happens at the moment of a tweet. So instead of just seeing &#8220;Beyonce&#8221; as a trending topic, fans can see a clip or image from the show that correlates with the social activity taking place online. Facebook Tracker: MTV will introduce a Facebook Tracker to keep tabs on the level of Likes and shares of Movie Awards moments shared on its Facebook page. All Access Live: The show&#8217;s second-screen experience for desktops and mobile devices will give viewers six camera angles (red carpet, dressing room, paparazzi, audience, balcony and MTV cut), sharing capabilities, a place to chat with fellow viewers and animated GIFs from celebrities on the red carpet. The GIFs will be posted on MTV&#8217;s Tumblr blog. Shazam: The ceremony will be Shazam-enabled, meaning viewers can use the app during the broadcast to buy performers&#8217; music and watch social media interactions. Post-Show Features: MTV will have a red carpet galleries and interviews, backstage video highlights and editorial coverage of the show and winners. A Launchpad for the Future Some of the features that MTV is launching for the MTV Movie Awards might just find their way into the big show &#8212; the VMAs &#8212; later this summer. In this way, the Movie Awards are a testbed of sorts for the future initiatives for the VMAs. &#8220;It just so happened that the Movie Awards are first,&#8221; MTV told us, noting that it plans to refine the most successful initiatives into its flagship awards show. Understanding that virility is a major component to award shows, MTV wants to make it as easy as possible for fans to tag and share the best moments of the show across mobile and the desktop in as close to real-time as possible. The net result &#8212; as last year&#8217;s VMA ratings proved &#8212; is that socially engaged audiences tend to watch more. To pump up the shareability factor even more, MTV will air exclusive footage of The Dark Knight Rises with director Christopher Nolan and actors Christian Bale, Joseph Gordon-Levitt and Gary Oldman on hand for the occasion at Gibson Amphitheatre in Universal City, California. Christina Warren contributed to the reporting in this article. More About: celebrities, Entertainment, Facebook, Film, GIFs, Movies, mtv, mtv movie awards, shazam, social tv, tumblr, TV, TwitterFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/mtv-movie-awards-social-tv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/30/mtv-movie-awards-social-tv/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Users React to Potential &#8216;Zombie Apocalypse&#8217;</title>
      <description>Several reports of alleged cannibalism circulated throughout the news this week, leading to online chatter about a &#8220;zombie apocalypse.&#8221; The buzz carried from Twitter to YouTube &#8212; pranksters VitalyzedTV dressed a guy in full zombie makeup and filmed him roaming the streets of Miami. Watch above as the public reacts in real life to a &#8220;zombie attack.&#8221; The Center for Disease Control came out with a zombie preparedness guide in January, which was originally a light-hearted way to prepare for natural disasters. &#8220;If you are generally well equipped to deal with a zombie apocalypse you will be prepared for a hurricane, pandemic, earthquake, or terrorist attack,&#8221; notes Dr. Ali Khan CDC&#8217;s director for the office of public health preparedness and response. After Twitter users quickly pointed to the guide this week, which fueled more buzz about an apocaplypse, the CDC officially claimed that zombies do not exist. Here&#8217;s what Twitter users had to say about a potential zombie apocalypse. Many incorporate cultural references such as video games, Michael Jackson&#8217;s &#8220;Thriller,&#8221; Shaun of the Dead and The Walking Dead. Why do you think these concurring reports of alleged cannibalism have led to a zombie apocalypse scare on Twitter? 1. Time Time, which recently received a lot of buzz for its controversial cover, suggested a zombie apocalypse in a headline about the Baltimore man who admitted to killing and consuming parts of his housemate. Click here to view this gallery. Image courtesy of Flickr, Mark Lobo More About: Twitter, viral, YouTube, zombies</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/zombie-apocalypse-2/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/03/zombie-apocalypse-2/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Instagram Is Taking Over Major League Baseball</title>
      <description>Instagram and baseball have a few things in common &#8212; they both invite reflection and facilitate nostalgia, for example. Now it seems they go together like 7th Inning and stretch. The photo sharing network is completely dominating in Major League ballparks this season. A month into the 2012 season, there has already been a 400% increase in Instagram photos posted from big league parks compared to the entire 2011 season. In total, more than 40,000 photos of ballparks have been posted to Instagram. Which teams lead the charge? It&#8217;s no big surprise that the San Francisco Giants&#8216; hometown AT&amp;T Park is the biggest filtered photo magnet, with almost 6,000 posts so far this year. The Giants are extremely active in social media, play in a gorgeous stadium and are located in the heart of the American tech scene. In fact, Instagram grew into a billion dollar company not far from AT&amp;T Park. Yankee Stadium, Atlanta&#8217;s Turner Field, Chicago&#8217;s Wrigley Field and Boston&#8217;s Fenway Park round out the top five. The social media tool VenueSeen compiled these stats and more from publicly posted Instagram photos to create the infographic below. The company even broke down some of major league baseball&#8217;s primary rivalries to see which teams own Instagram bragging rights so far this season. SEE ALSO: Baseball Home Openers: Social Media&#8217;s Best Shots [PICS] In the Battle of the Bay, the league-leading Giants dominate the Oakland Athletics by a tally of about 6,000 Instagram posts to about 1,400. The Yankees-Red Sox America League East rivalry, meanwhile, goes to the Yankees at a score of approximately 2,200 to 2,000. Chicago&#8217;s Red Line Series has the Cubs dominating the White Sox, and the Philadelphia Phillies trounce the Pittsburgh Pirates for bragging rights in Pennsylvania. Check out the infographic below for the fuller picture, and let us know in the comments &#8212; what&#8217;s your favorite ballpark filter? Thumbnail image courtesy Poppy Wright, Flickr. More About: infographic, instagram, Major League Baseball, sportsFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/instagram-baseball-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/instagram-baseball-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a Relationship: Mobile Apps and the Cloud [INFOGRAPHIC]</title>
      <description>Mobile apps and the cloud are going all the way to the altar together. They&#8217;ve been in a relationship for several years and are now inseparable. True love can be hard to explain, but in this case the relationship is based on pragmatism. More and more people are buying, using and relying on smartphones in their everyday lives. Much of that use and reliance revolves around mobile apps. The more mobile apps people use, the more data their phones consume and the more space they need to store all that information. Enter the cloud. Just how ubiquitous are smartphones becoming? More than a billion such devices will be sold in the year 2014, according to a Credit Suisse estimate. By the same year, the market for cloud-based mobile apps will have increased by 90% compared to 2009. By 2016, analysts predict there will be 10 billion connected mobile devices in use globally, and smartphone traffic will be 50 times what it is today. Many of your favorite apps are cloud-based now &#8212; Instagram, Pinterest, Foursquare, Yelp, Groupon and LinkedIn, just to name a handful. Apps are moving to cloud for three primary reasons, according to a survey of IT executives: accessibility to data from multiple devices, lower cost and increased speed for businesses. And increased consumption is disrupting hiring patterns. By 2015, development projects centered around mobile apps are projected to outnumber PC-based projects by four to one. From 2010 to 2011, the IT job site Dice.com reported a 220% increase in job postings for iPhone-related developer positions and a 302% increase in postings for Android developers. Jobs site Elance.com, meanwhile, reported a 100% increase in overall mobile app developer postings. The platform-as-a-service company Engine Yard recently pulled all these stats and more together to create the infographic below. Check it out for a deeper dive and let us know what you think in the comments. Courtesy of: Engine Yard More About: cloud computing, infographics, Mobile, mobile apps</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/mobile-apps-cloud-infographi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/mobile-apps-cloud-infographi/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Instagram Is Taking Over Major League Baseball</title>
      <description>Instagram and baseball have a few things in common &#8212; they both invite reflection and facilitate nostalgia, for example. Now it seems they go together like 7th Inning and stretch. The photo sharing network is completely dominating in Major League ballparks this season. A month into the 2012 season, there has already been a 400% increase in Instagram photos posted from big league parks compared to the entire 2011 season. In total, more than 40,000 photos of ballparks have been posted to Instagram. Which teams lead the charge? It&#8217;s no big surprise that the San Francisco Giants&#8216; hometown AT&amp;T Park is the biggest filtered photo magnet, with almost 6,000 posts so far this year. The Giants are extremely active in social media, play in a gorgeous stadium and are located in the heart of the American tech scene. In fact, Instagram grew into a billion dollar company not far from AT&amp;T Park. Yankee Stadium, Atlanta&#8217;s Turner Field, Chicago&#8217;s Wrigley Field and Boston&#8217;s Fenway Park round out the top five. The social media tool VenueSeen compiled these stats and more from publicly posted Instagram photos to create the infographic below. The company even broke down some of major league baseball&#8217;s primary rivalries to see which teams own Instagram bragging rights so far this season. SEE ALSO: Baseball Home Openers: Social Media&#8217;s Best Shots [PICS] In the Battle of the Bay, the league-leading Giants dominate the Oakland Athletics by a tally of about 6,000 Instagram posts to about 1,400. The Yankees-Red Sox America League East rivalry, meanwhile, goes to the Yankees at a score of approximately 2,200 to 2,000. Chicago&#8217;s Red Line Series has the Cubs dominating the White Sox, and the Philadelphia Phillies trounce the Pittsburgh Pirates for bragging rights in Pennsylvania. Check out the infographic below for the fuller picture, and let us know in the comments &#8212; what&#8217;s your favorite ballpark filter? Thumbnail image courtesy Poppy Wright, Flickr. More About: infographic, instagram, Major League Baseball, sportsFor more Entertainment coverage:Follow Mashable Entertainment on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Entertainment channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/instagram-baseball-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/05/31/instagram-baseball-infographic/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest Rolls Out Curated Newsletter for Users</title>
      <description>Users on Pinterest usually have to seek interesting content for themselves, but a new feature quietly rolled out Saturday drives them to even more personalized content. Pinterest has become a hot social pinboard that drives more traffic than most major social networks &#8212; meaning there is more content on the site than ever. That&#8217;s why many users are sure to appreciate Pinterest&#8217;s new weekly email newsletter, making it easier to find even more great pins and helping them keep tabs on how their own pins are doing. Mimicking the website&#8217;s pinboard style, each pin or board in the email is linked to the website, but users are unable to re-pin or like a post directly from the newsletter. The newsletter lists a few popular boards, pins from friends that might be of interest and a useful feature for brands especially: your most popular pins of the week. SEE ALSO: Eyes On Pinterest: How People Look at Your Boards Pinterest also includes its own favorite post in the newsletter, which this week was a lip-dub marriage proposal that went viral on YouTube. Though Pinterest is stepping up its curation game, startups are seizing the opportunity to make Pinterest a more enjoyable experience for users. Earlier this month, a site launched that notifies users via email when their pinned items go on sale. The recent startup Pinerly offers basic analytics about pin performance and scheduling pins. There&#8217;s also WP Pinner, which is a plug-in that lets WordPress users share, track and schedule material on Pinterest. What features would you like to see added to Pinterest&#8217;s email newsletter? Share your thoughts in the comments. More About: content curation, email, newsletters, pinterest, Social MediaFor more Social Media coverage:Follow Mashable Social Media on TwitterBecome a Fan on FacebookSubscribe to the Social Media channelDownload our free apps for Android, Mac, iPhone and iPad</description>
      <link>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/pinterest-curated-newsletter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</link>
      <guid>http://mashable.com/2012/06/02/pinterest-curated-newsletter/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+Mashable+%28Mashable%29</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
