<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
<channel>
<title>Topsy - Top 100 </title>
<link>http://topsy.com/top100</link>
<description>Top Links generated by Topsy.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>6</sy:updateFrequency>
<ttl>40</ttl>

    <item>
        <title>AdGenesis Aims To Be The Match.com of Video Advertising, Pair Brands With The Right Viewer</title>
        <description><![CDATA[AdGenesis Aims To Be The Match.com of Video Advertising, Pair Brands With The Right Viewer http://tcrn.ch/kLnYbw by @ripemp]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[AdGenesis Aims To Be The Match.com of Video Advertising, Pair Brands With The Right Viewer http://tcrn.ch/kLnYbw by @ripemp
            As online video advertising continues to grow, and expands to mobile, brands are looking for ways to get more bang for their advertising buck, and viewers continue to yearn for and expect video advertising that is more personalized, targeted, and relevant. And obviously the same is true for brands and advertisers -- they, too, want to be able to customize their ad experience to reach consumers that they know will care about their products. So, as technology and the web tools we use on a daily basis continue to get smarter, so should advertising, right?

AdGenesis, a New York-based video advertising startup, wants use the dating, or match-making game, to make the serving of video advertising a more intelligent arrangement. It hopes that its service will bring consumers and brands together for a rewarding, lifetime relationship of loyalty and happiness -- not just in a marriage of convenience. In other words, the startup is a white label video advertising platform that partners with publishers to match branded content to a large network of eager, opt-in customers.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/adgenesis-aims-to-be-the-match-com-of-video-advertising-pair-brands-with-the-right-viewer/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/adgenesis-aims-to-be-the-match-com-of-video-advertising-pair-brands-with-the-right-viewer/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 02:26:50 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/adgenesis-aims-to-be-the-match-com-of-video-advertising-pair-brands-with-the-right-viewer/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/adgenesis-aims-to-be-the-match-com-of-video-advertising-pair-brands-with-the-right-viewer/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Evernote-Rival SpringPad Now Supports Honeycomb And Offers Offline Access Via Chrome Web App</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Evernote-Rival SpringPad Now Supports Honeycomb And Offers Offline Access Via Chrome Web App http://tcrn.ch/ioKEOL by @leenarao]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Evernote-Rival SpringPad Now Supports Honeycomb And Offers Offline Access Via Chrome Web App http://tcrn.ch/ioKEOL by @leenarao
            Evernote rival Springpad is announcing support for Android Honeycomb tablets and is also debuting offline access via its popular chrome web app. 

Similar to Evernote, Springpad  serves as a multi-platform digital notebook. The service allows you to jot down notes, save websites, images and more. Springpad will then categorizes your saved content, and allows you to share your notes, set reminders and more. The app goes a step farther to analyze your content and then serve you alerts to relevant news, offers and deals. The app's semantic data technology allows you to save products, books, movies, recipes and more, and automatically get enhanced information, including price drops, local availability and coupons.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/evernote-rival-springpad-now-supports-honeycomb-and-offers-offline-access-via-chrome-web-app/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/evernote-rival-springpad-now-supports-honeycomb-and-offers-offline-access-via-chrome-web-app/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 02:26:50 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/evernote-rival-springpad-now-supports-honeycomb-and-offers-offline-access-via-chrome-web-app/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/evernote-rival-springpad-now-supports-honeycomb-and-offers-offline-access-via-chrome-web-app/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Google to Unveil Online Music Service - WSJ.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Google music http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703730804576313862695045964.html]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Google music http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703730804576313862695045964.html
            Google is preparing to unveil a new online music service similar to a service recently launched by Amazon.com, a move that escalates the battle to create the next generation of Internet businesses for storing and listening to music.
            <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703730804576313862695045964.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703730804576313862695045964.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 02:00:14 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703730804576313862695045964.html</guid>
        <link>http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703730804576313862695045964.html</link>
        <dc:creator>wsj.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Emergency Alert System Expected for Cellphones - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Emergency Alert System Expected for Cellphones - http://is.gd/zO5qNE - #us]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Emergency Alert System Expected for Cellphones - http://is.gd/zO5qNE - #us
            By the end of the year, some cellphone users in New York City and Washington will be able to receive alerts by text message about national and regional emergencies.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/us/10safety.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/us/10safety.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 01:43:14 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/us/10safety.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/us/10safety.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Gillmor Gang 5.9.11 (TCTV)</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Gillmor Gang 5.9.11 (TCTV) http://tcrn.ch/lFv45X by @stevegillmor]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Gillmor Gang 5.9.11 (TCTV) http://tcrn.ch/lFv45X by @stevegillmor
            The Gillmor Gang — John Borthwick, Robert Scoble, John Taschek, and Steve Gillmor — inaugurated a new kind of Gillmor Gang. To the undisclosed, it looks the same: silly chat, mangled technology disruptions, and dead air. To the more clueful, who recognize we're entering a new age of social media, the intersection of social monitoring and proactive brand creation tools spells big trouble for old media and their thin-skinned attacks on the realtime enterprise.

As @scobleizer describes Rackspace's move to Chatter, you get the idea that social media is not just the province of the Ashton's and Lady Gaga's, but a million personal clouds that resonate with accumulated authority and credibility. Mainstream media can play a role here; @jborthwick describes the velocity with which a New York Times reporter validated the Bin Laden story as it broke on Twitter. @jtaschek reminisces about the speeds and feeds days of recognizable software giving way to micro-authority and pushrank.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gillmor-gang-5-9-11-tctv/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gillmor-gang-5-9-11-tctv/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:22:48 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gillmor-gang-5-9-11-tctv/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gillmor-gang-5-9-11-tctv/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Twitter and Facebook Kill RSS – Jeffrey Zeldman Presents The Daily Report</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Twitter and Facebook Kill RSS http://bit.ly/lKu3vI]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Twitter and Facebook Kill RSS http://bit.ly/lKu3vI
            It seems Twitter has completely removed the ability to consume their feeds via the open standard of RSS in favor of their more proprietary API formats. At the same time, Facebook seems to have done the same.
            <a href="http://www.zeldman.com/2011/05/09/twitter-and-facebook-kill-rss/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.zeldman.com/2011/05/09/twitter-and-facebook-kill-rss/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:22:27 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.zeldman.com/2011/05/09/twitter-and-facebook-kill-rss/</guid>
        <link>http://www.zeldman.com/2011/05/09/twitter-and-facebook-kill-rss/</link>
        <dc:creator>zeldman.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>TechCrunch TV Goes HD</title>
        <description><![CDATA[TechCrunch TV Goes HD http://tcrn.ch/mlueOu by @jonorlin]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[TechCrunch TV Goes HD http://tcrn.ch/mlueOu by @jonorlin
            If you have been watching TechCrunch TV interviews lately, you may have noticed the videos are much sharper, crisper and much higher quality.  The reason: we've gone HD.  We are now using a new workflow with HD cameras and HD video switcher. Our shows from New York (Fly or Die and Founder Stories) have always been produced in HD at AOL Studios.  But, now our San Francisco studio has gotten the upgrade. 

You might be saying,
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/techcrunch-tv-goes-hd/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/techcrunch-tv-goes-hd/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:16:25 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/techcrunch-tv-goes-hd/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/techcrunch-tv-goes-hd/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Apple Employees Tell the Secrets Behind Steve Jobs’ ‘Magic’ | Gadget Lab | Wired.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Apple Employees Tell the Secrets Behind Steve Jobs’ ‘Magic’ http://bit.ly/kwJzqe]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Apple Employees Tell the Secrets Behind Steve Jobs’ ‘Magic’ http://bit.ly/kwJzqe
            Revealing how Steve Jobs runs Apple is like exposing the secrets behind a magician's tricks. And several of the magician's assistants just broke their
            <a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/05/steve-jobs-magic/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/05/steve-jobs-magic/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 23:30:29 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/05/steve-jobs-magic/</guid>
        <link>http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2011/05/steve-jobs-magic/</link>
        <dc:creator>wired.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Starbuck And Starbuck In Starbucks: Pics, Videos, Links, News</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Starbuck And Starbuck In Starbucks: (Head explodes.) Old and new and coffee shop Starbucks, together at last. (Via Pa... http://su.pr/9jQ8bW]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Starbuck And Starbuck In Starbucks: (Head explodes.) Old and new and coffee shop Starbucks, together at last. (Via Pa... http://su.pr/9jQ8bW
            Starbuck And Starbuck In Starbucks: (Head explodes.) Old and new and coffee shop Starbucks, together at last. (Via Patrick Haney )..
            <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/scott/starbuck-and-starbuck-in-starbucks">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.buzzfeed.com/scott/starbuck-and-starbuck-in-starbucks">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 23:22:07 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.buzzfeed.com/scott/starbuck-and-starbuck-in-starbucks</guid>
        <link>http://www.buzzfeed.com/scott/starbuck-and-starbuck-in-starbucks</link>
        <dc:creator>buzzfeed.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>YouTube - kitten vs a scary thing (котенок против страшной неведомой хрени)</title>
        <description><![CDATA[#subscribe http://youtu.be/_MqHN-4okZ4]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[#subscribe http://youtu.be/_MqHN-4okZ4
            http://supavid.com - more funny vids how i did the sync/sound for example - http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cIkc3eGPeRk
            <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_MqHN-4okZ4">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D_MqHN-4okZ4">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 23:15:01 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D_MqHN-4okZ4</guid>
        <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_MqHN-4okZ4</link>
        <dc:creator>youtube.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>LevelUp Now Lets You Swipe Your AmEx Card To Redeem Deals, No Print-Outs Required</title>
        <description><![CDATA[LevelUp Now Lets You Swipe Your AmEx Card To Redeem Deals, No Print-Outs Required http://tcrn.ch/mcsjnS by @jasonkincaid]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[LevelUp Now Lets You Swipe Your AmEx Card To Redeem Deals, No Print-Outs Required http://tcrn.ch/mcsjnS by @jasonkincaid
            Back in March location-based game SCVNGR launched a spinoff venture called LevelUp — a direct competitor to Groupon, Living Social, and other daily deal sites. LevelUp's key twist is that it has a heavy focus on generating repeat visitors, as opposed to customers who only stop by a venue once to redeem their deal. And today it has some significant news: it's partnered with American Express to start allowing LevelUp users to redeem their coupons simply by swiping their credit cards — a feat that they say is the first in the daily deal space.

To use the new feature, users connect their AmEx cards with their LevelUp account (a process that you only need to do once). Then, once they purchase a deal from a merchant that accepts American Express, they'll see a button that prompts them to 'load' their card with the deal. When the card is swiped at the merchant, the user receives an immediate push notification and email notification informing them that the coupon was applied successfully, and they don't have to bother pulling out a printout or showing their phone to an employee.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/levelup-now-lets-you-swipe-your-amex-card-to-redeem-deals-no-print-outs-required/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/levelup-now-lets-you-swipe-your-amex-card-to-redeem-deals-no-print-outs-required/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:50:58 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/levelup-now-lets-you-swipe-your-amex-card-to-redeem-deals-no-print-outs-required/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/levelup-now-lets-you-swipe-your-amex-card-to-redeem-deals-no-print-outs-required/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The iPad in Your Hand: As Fast as a Supercomputer of Yore - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The iPad in Your Hand: As Fast as a Supercomputer of Yore - http://is.gd/N7LKdL - #technology]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The iPad in Your Hand: As Fast as a Supercomputer of Yore - http://is.gd/N7LKdL - #technology
            A computer scientist who tracks the mathematical capabilities of computers has found that the iPad 2 is as fast as a supercomputer from years ago.
            <a href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/the-ipad-in-your-hand-as-fast-as-a-supercomputer-of-yore/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/the-ipad-in-your-hand-as-fast-as-a-supercomputer-of-yore/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:44:07 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/the-ipad-in-your-hand-as-fast-as-a-supercomputer-of-yore/</guid>
        <link>http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/the-ipad-in-your-hand-as-fast-as-a-supercomputer-of-yore/</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Google APIs Discovery Service: one API to find them all - The official Google Code blog</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The API of APIs is here - welcome Google APIs Discovery Service. http://goo.gl/eLzCX #googleapis #io2011 ^sk]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The API of APIs is here - welcome Google APIs Discovery Service. http://goo.gl/eLzCX #googleapis #io2011 ^sk
            data:blog.pageName
            <a href="http://googlecode.blogspot.com/2011/05/google-apis-discovery-service-one-api.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/googlecode.blogspot.com/2011/05/google-apis-discovery-service-one-api.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:33:04 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/googlecode.blogspot.com/2011/05/google-apis-discovery-service-one-api.html</guid>
        <link>http://googlecode.blogspot.com/2011/05/google-apis-discovery-service-one-api.html</link>
        <dc:creator>googlecode.blogspot.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Apple’s Massive New Data Center Set To Host Nuance Tech; Partnership Announcement Due At WWDC</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Apple&#39;s Massive New Data Center Set To Host Nuance Tech; Partnership Announcement Due At WWDC http://tcrn.ch/mRnyRx by @parislemon]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Apple&#39;s Massive New Data Center Set To Host Nuance Tech; Partnership Announcement Due At WWDC http://tcrn.ch/mRnyRx by @parislemon
            Last Friday, we posted about the negotiations between Apple and voice recognition company Nuance. While these talks have been going on for months, sources told us that it wasn't yet entirely clear what the outcome would be — either a broad strategic partnership or, less likely, an acquisition. Things are looking a bit more clear now.

In digging into the information about the relationship between the two companies, we had heard that Apple might actually already be using Nuance technology in their new (but yet to be officially opened) massive data center in North Carolina. Since then, we've gotten multiple independent confirmations that this is indeed the case. And yes, this is said to be the keystone of a partnership that Apple is likely to announce with Nuance at WWDC next month.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/apple-nuance-data-center-deal/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/apple-nuance-data-center-deal/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:28:43 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/apple-nuance-data-center-deal/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/apple-nuance-data-center-deal/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Google Partners With Sony Pictures, Universal And Warner Brothers For YouTube Movies</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Google Partners With Sony Pictures, NBC Universal And Warner Brothers For YouTube Movies http://tcrn.ch/kMemBO by @alexia]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Google Partners With Sony Pictures, NBC Universal And Warner Brothers For YouTube Movies http://tcrn.ch/kMemBO by @alexia
            Google confirmed the existence of its YouTube Movies service earlier today and has just released more details on which studios and movies will provide the 3,000 titles in its repertoire. YouTube has partnered up with Universal, Sony Pictures and Warner Bros and others to offer full length feature films on YouTube.com/movies.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-partners-with-sony-pictures-nbc-universal-and-warner-brothers-for-youtube-movies/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-partners-with-sony-pictures-nbc-universal-and-warner-brothers-for-youtube-movies/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:22:22 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-partners-with-sony-pictures-nbc-universal-and-warner-brothers-for-youtube-movies/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-partners-with-sony-pictures-nbc-universal-and-warner-brothers-for-youtube-movies/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>DreamIt Ventures Announces Its First Batch Of NYC Startups</title>
        <description><![CDATA[DreamIt Ventures Announces Its First Batch Of NYC Startups http://tcrn.ch/m685On by @ripemp]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[DreamIt Ventures Announces Its First Batch Of NYC Startups http://tcrn.ch/m685On by @ripemp
            In January of this year, DreamIt Ventures, a Philadelphia-based VC firm and startup accelerator, announced that it would be expanding to the Big Apple, creating a startup accelerator program based in New York City. 

The program offers $25,000 in seed funding to its portfolio companies, along with coaching, exclusive speaking engagements, a chance to pitch at a Demo Day to affiliated angel and venture investors, and a collaborative workspace. 

After reviewing hundreds of applications over the first quarter of this year, today DreamIt is officially announcing its final NYC roster. The program will include 15 startups that hail from all over the U.S. The selected companies include students and alumni from Harvard Business School, Wharton, Yale, and Carnegie Mellon, and its founders boast prior experience at companies including Yahoo!, Microsoft, American Express, and McKinsey. Like DreamIt's Philly program, 5 of the 15 startups are digital education businesses and were selected in partnership with Startl -- a social enterprise dedicated to accelerating digital innovations for learning.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/dreamit-ventures-announces-its-first-batch-of-nyc-startups/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/dreamit-ventures-announces-its-first-batch-of-nyc-startups/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:20:29 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/dreamit-ventures-announces-its-first-batch-of-nyc-startups/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/dreamit-ventures-announces-its-first-batch-of-nyc-startups/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Foursquare Teams With Google For NFC Check-Ins Via Posters At Google I/O</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Foursquare Teams With Google For NFC Check-Ins Via Posters At Google I/O http://tcrn.ch/jS5E9c by @parislemon]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Foursquare Teams With Google For NFC Check-Ins Via Posters At Google I/O http://tcrn.ch/jS5E9c by @parislemon
            Google's annual I/O conference kicks off tomorrow and it will likely bring a range of big announcements. But one of the cooler things that will be on display at the event was actually pre-announced today by Foursquare: NFC-based check-ins at the event.

Google and Foursquare are teaming up to make this a reality at the conference over the next few days. Around the conference center, you'll see Foursquare posters that will actually have NFC chips embedded in them. This means you simply need to bring your phone close to these posters in order to check in via Foursquare. Very cool.

And when you do, you'll get a Google I/O Foursquare badge, naturally.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-foursquare-nfc-check-ins/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-foursquare-nfc-check-ins/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:17:19 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-foursquare-nfc-check-ins/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/google-foursquare-nfc-check-ins/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Foregoing The Bump, Hashable Adds NFC Contact Swaps On Android</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Foregoing The Bump, Hashable Adds NFC Contact Swaps On Android http://tcrn.ch/mA0LSA by @erickschonfeld]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Foregoing The Bump, Hashable Adds NFC Contact Swaps On Android http://tcrn.ch/mA0LSA by @erickschonfeld
            When people talk about near-field communications (NFC) chips in phones, they usually bring up mobile payments.  But NFC chips, which are already in some Android phones, can be used by other apps besides payments (which won't take off as quickly as people expect anyway).  

At Google I/O this week, NFC apps will be highlighted.  Foursquare will allow Android users to check in by swiping their phones near posters with NFC chips.  Also just in time for I/O, Hashable's Android app now supports NFC features as well.  Android users can swap contact info via NFC, and also check into the same activity with someone, like #dinner or #drinks.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/hashable-nfc-android/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/hashable-nfc-android/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:17:13 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/hashable-nfc-android/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/hashable-nfc-android/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The Marvel comic edition of the Situation Room Osama photo</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Marvel comic edition of the Situation Room Osama photo http://yfrog.com/gzlctaoj]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Marvel comic edition of the Situation Room Osama photo http://yfrog.com/gzlctaoj
            yfrog free image and video hosting on your social networks
            <a href="http://yfrog.com/gzlctaoj">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/yfrog.com/gzlctaoj">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:11:53 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/yfrog.com/gzlctaoj</guid>
        <link>http://yfrog.com/gzlctaoj</link>
        <dc:creator>yfrog.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Crunching the numbers: How many people have ever lived? | 1000Memories</title>
        <description><![CDATA[What percentage of people are alive today?:  http://bit.ly/m6uKxI]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[What percentage of people are alive today?:  http://bit.ly/m6uKxI
            What percentage of people who have ever lived are alive today? We know that sometime this year the world population …
            <a href="http://1000memories.com/blog/75-number-of-people-who-have-ever-lived">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/1000memories.com/blog/75-number-of-people-who-have-ever-lived">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 22:01:21 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/1000memories.com/blog/75-number-of-people-who-have-ever-lived</guid>
        <link>http://1000memories.com/blog/75-number-of-people-who-have-ever-lived</link>
        <dc:creator>1000memories.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Prime Minister Is Defiant as Pakistan Outs C.I.A. Agent - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Pakistan Premier Defends Spy Agency, as Covert U.S. Agent Is Named - http://nyti.ms/iIa3TC]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Pakistan Premier Defends Spy Agency, as Covert U.S. Agent Is Named - http://nyti.ms/iIa3TC
            Prime Minister Yousaf Gilani defended Pakistan’s spy agency Monday, as the agency appeared to have told a newspaper the name of the C.I.A. station chief in Islamabad.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/world/asia/10pakistan.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/world/asia/10pakistan.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 21:10:50 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/world/asia/10pakistan.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/world/asia/10pakistan.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Shoefitr: You Know, For Shoes</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Shoefitr: You Know, For Shoes http://tcrn.ch/jvFVdU by @johnbiggs]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Shoefitr: You Know, For Shoes http://tcrn.ch/jvFVdU by @johnbiggs
            Shoefitr allows you to find a shoe that is similar in size and shape to a pair of shoes you already own. For example, say you're into Nike Free Runs but they discontinued the model you like. You tell Shoefittr and using the site's 3D scanning system it finds a pair that matches the size and shape of the shoe you like. The 3D scanning system is based on the same systems used to scan feet for orthotics.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/shoefitr-you-know-for-shoes/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/shoefitr-you-know-for-shoes/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 21:03:02 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/shoefitr-you-know-for-shoes/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/shoefitr-you-know-for-shoes/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Hillary Clinton, Audrey Tomason go missing in Situation Room photo in Der Tzitung newspaper - BlogPost - The Washington Post</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton, Audrey Tomason go missing in Situation Room photo in Der Tzitung newspaper - http://wapo.st/k3wpTl]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton, Audrey Tomason go missing in Situation Room photo in Der Tzitung newspaper - http://wapo.st/k3wpTl
            A Hasidic newspaper changes the iconic Situation Room photograph.
            <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/blogpost/post/hillary-clinton-audrey-tomason-go-missing-in-situation-room-photo-in-der-tzitung-newspaper/2011/05/09/AFfJbVYG_blog.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/blogpost/post/hillary-clinton-audrey-tomason-go-missing-in-situation-room-photo-in-der-tzitung-newspaper/2011/05/09/AFfJbVYG_blog.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 20:53:44 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/blogpost/post/hillary-clinton-audrey-tomason-go-missing-in-situation-room-photo-in-der-tzitung-newspaper/2011/05/09/AFfJbVYG_blog.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/blogpost/post/hillary-clinton-audrey-tomason-go-missing-in-situation-room-photo-in-der-tzitung-newspaper/2011/05/09/AFfJbVYG_blog.html</link>
        <dc:creator>washingtonpost.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>YouTube - Lady Gaga - The Edge Of Glory (Audio)</title>
        <description><![CDATA[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S08KonZiew4&amp;feature=feedu &lt; Edge of Glory!!1]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S08KonZiew4&amp;feature=feedu &lt; Edge of Glory!!1
            Lady Gaga "The Edge Of Glory" (Audio). Get it on iTunes now: http://bit.ly/lA5ID4 © 2011 Interscope Records
            <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S08KonZiew4">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DS08KonZiew4">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 20:27:54 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DS08KonZiew4</guid>
        <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S08KonZiew4</link>
        <dc:creator>youtube.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Stephen Hawking Speaks - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Life and the Cosmos, Word by Painstaking Word - NYT http://nyti.ms/mOEBEn]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Life and the Cosmos, Word by Painstaking Word - NYT http://nyti.ms/mOEBEn
            In a rare interview, Stephen Hawking discusses his work, aliens and living with A.L.S.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/science/10hawking.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/science/10hawking.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 20:00:19 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/science/10hawking.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/10/science/10hawking.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>YouTube Hints At Major Studio Deals, Adding 3,000 New Movies For Rent</title>
        <description><![CDATA[YouTube Hints At Major Studio Deals, Adding 3,000 New Movies For Rent http://tcrn.ch/m161wy by @jasonkincaid]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[YouTube Hints At Major Studio Deals, Adding 3,000 New Movies For Rent http://tcrn.ch/m161wy by @jasonkincaid
            YouTube chief Salar Kamangar has just written a post on the YouTube blog titled
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/youtube-hints-at-major-studio-deals-adding-3000-new-movies-for-rent/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/youtube-hints-at-major-studio-deals-adding-3000-new-movies-for-rent/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 19:16:18 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/youtube-hints-at-major-studio-deals-adding-3000-new-movies-for-rent/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/youtube-hints-at-major-studio-deals-adding-3000-new-movies-for-rent/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Osama bin Laden’s Abbottabad Hideout Now Has a Playable Counter-Strike Map | Geekosystem</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Osama bin Laden’s Abbottabad Hideout Now Has a Playable Counter-Strike Map http://t.co/2bMqrwX]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Osama bin Laden’s Abbottabad Hideout Now Has a Playable Counter-Strike Map http://t.co/2bMqrwX
            The line between video games and reality continues to blur: A week after President Obama told Americans in an emergency broadcast that Al-Qaeda leader Osama bin Laden had been killed by Navy SEALs in a compound in Abbottabad, Pakistan, there's now a playable map in first-person shooter Counter-Strike: Source modeled after that very compound. The map is available for download at GameBanana, and may be used as a base for a bomb or hostage map at a later stage, according to its description. The map's creator writes: What alot of people don't seem to understand is that the only thing this map has in common with Osama is location. I can see how people would think it is in bad taste, but honestly if that's your opinion you may as well protest the whole game (as well as many others). (GameBanana via GamePron via Slashdot, Kotaku)
            <a href="http://www.geekosystem.com/abbottabad-counterstrike-osama-bin-laden/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.geekosystem.com/abbottabad-counterstrike-osama-bin-laden/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 18:53:52 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.geekosystem.com/abbottabad-counterstrike-osama-bin-laden/</guid>
        <link>http://www.geekosystem.com/abbottabad-counterstrike-osama-bin-laden/</link>
        <dc:creator>geekosystem.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The web designer’s guide to a happier life | Webdesigner Depot</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The web designer’s guide to a happier life http://ff.im/-CYM58]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The web designer’s guide to a happier life http://ff.im/-CYM58
            Life as a web designer can be insanely busy. We have multiple clients, each making numerous demands on our time. We work in a fast-moving sector in which we
            <a href="http://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/the-web-designer%E2%80%99s-guide-to-a-happier-life/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/the-web-designer%E2%80%99s-guide-to-a-happier-life/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 18:53:35 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/the-web-designer%E2%80%99s-guide-to-a-happier-life/</guid>
        <link>http://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/the-web-designer%E2%80%99s-guide-to-a-happier-life/</link>
        <dc:creator>webdesignerdepot.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Tumblr Launches ‘Share On Tumblr’ Button For Publishers</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Tumblr Launches &#39;Share On Tumblr&#39; Button For Publishers http://tcrn.ch/jmGGTx by @alexia]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Tumblr Launches &#39;Share On Tumblr&#39; Button For Publishers http://tcrn.ch/jmGGTx by @alexia
            Following in the footsteps of Facebook, Twitter, Digg and even Google, blogging platform Tumblr has released its 'Share On Tumblr' button, which allows publishers to add a button encouraging users to share their content on Tumblr (just paste the javascript tag into your source code).

The basic behavior of the button is simple enough, but the advanced features are where the 'Share on Tumblr' button sets itself apart from other social engagement buttons out there.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/tumblr-launches-share-on-tumblr-button-for-publishers/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/tumblr-launches-share-on-tumblr-button-for-publishers/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 18:48:23 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/tumblr-launches-share-on-tumblr-button-for-publishers/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/tumblr-launches-share-on-tumblr-button-for-publishers/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The Pirate Bay: “The Battle of Internets is About to Begin” | TorrentFreak</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Pirate Bay: “The Battle of Internets is About to Begin” http://bit.ly/mPzqpK]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Pirate Bay: “The Battle of Internets is About to Begin” http://bit.ly/mPzqpK
            The Pirate Bay: “The Battle of Internets is About to Begin”
            <a href="http://torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-the-battle-of-internets-is-about-to-begin-110509/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-the-battle-of-internets-is-about-to-begin-110509/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 18:29:45 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-the-battle-of-internets-is-about-to-begin-110509/</guid>
        <link>http://torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-the-battle-of-internets-is-about-to-begin-110509/</link>
        <dc:creator>torrentfreak.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Zynga Acqhires Contributors To iPhone Games Framework Cocos2D</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Zynga Acqhires Contributors To iPhone Games Framework Cocos2D http://tcrn.ch/meMa4O by @leenarao]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Zynga Acqhires Contributors To iPhone Games Framework Cocos2D http://tcrn.ch/meMa4O by @leenarao
            Zynga has made yet another 'acqhire' today. The company is announcing that Ricardo Quesada and Rolando Abarca, key contributors to the cocos2d for iPhone open source project, are joining the gaming giant. This is Zynga’s 13th announced acquisition in 12 months 

The cocos2d for iPhone open source project is widely used by developers globally, including large players like Atari, ngmoco, Gamevil and Zynga, in the development of leading mobile games for iPhone, iPod Touch, iPad and Mac. Abarca and Quesada, who will be working on Zynga's mobile products, will continue to support and contribute to cocos2d for iPhone while in their new roles at Zynga.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/zynga-acqhires-contributors-to-iphone-games-framework-cocos2d/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/zynga-acqhires-contributors-to-iphone-games-framework-cocos2d/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 18:13:26 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/zynga-acqhires-contributors-to-iphone-games-framework-cocos2d/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/zynga-acqhires-contributors-to-iphone-games-framework-cocos2d/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Keen On… Ze Frank: Why the Future of Play is a “Hot Thing” (TCTV)</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Keen On... Ze Frank: Why the Future of Play is a &quot;Hot Thing&quot; (TCTV) http://tcrn.ch/k5us6G by @ajkeen]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Keen On... Ze Frank: Why the Future of Play is a &quot;Hot Thing&quot; (TCTV) http://tcrn.ch/k5us6G by @ajkeen
            Ze Frank thinks that the future of play is a “hot thing.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/keen-on-ze-frank-why-the-future-of-play-is-a-hot-thing-tctv/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/keen-on-ze-frank-why-the-future-of-play-is-a-hot-thing-tctv/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 18:08:23 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/keen-on-ze-frank-why-the-future-of-play-is-a-hot-thing-tctv/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/keen-on-ze-frank-why-the-future-of-play-is-a-hot-thing-tctv/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>How To Survive The Coming Appization Of Just About Everything</title>
        <description><![CDATA[How To Survive The Coming Appization Of Just About Everything http://tcrn.ch/kcuXi1 by @johnbiggs]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[How To Survive The Coming Appization Of Just About Everything http://tcrn.ch/kcuXi1 by @johnbiggs
            If smartphone app sales (namely iPhone app sales) have taught manufacturers anything it's that there's ready money to be made in the parting of the people from their pennies. For the past few years we've seen very little uptake in the general, non-mobile app sales market as Apple - and now, to a lesser degree - Android had that world sewn up. 

Now, however, I fear that appization - meaning the creation of cloud-based stores that sell small widgets, pieces of content, or streams and that eschew physical media entirely - is coming to just about everything including desktops (Mac App Store and the Windows App Store), publishing (Conde Nast et al), and now TVs. Books will be appized. Magazines will be appized. Cable TV will be appized. Heck, even OSes are appized.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/how-to-survive-the-coming-appization-of-just-about-everything/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/how-to-survive-the-coming-appization-of-just-about-everything/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 17:38:19 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/how-to-survive-the-coming-appization-of-just-about-everything/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/how-to-survive-the-coming-appization-of-just-about-everything/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Social network users have twice as many friends online as in real life | Media | The Guardian</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Social network users have twice as many friends online as in real life: Research finds that one in 10 people has... http://bit.ly/kNTjaM]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Social network users have twice as many friends online as in real life: Research finds that one in 10 people has... http://bit.ly/kNTjaM
            Research finds that one in 10 people has either met their best friend online or believes they will meet good friends on web
            <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/09/social-network-users-friends-online">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/09/social-network-users-friends-online">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 17:31:51 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/09/social-network-users-friends-online</guid>
        <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/09/social-network-users-friends-online</link>
        <dc:creator>guardian.co.uk</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>How To Set Smart Daily Goals :: Tips :: The 99 Percent</title>
        <description><![CDATA[How To Set Smart Daily Goals: To achieve great things, we must constantly question how we spend our time and ene... http://bit.ly/iwl2wk]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[How To Set Smart Daily Goals: To achieve great things, we must constantly question how we spend our time and ene... http://bit.ly/iwl2wk
            To achieve great things, we must constantly question how we spend our time and energy. Get started by asking yourself these six questions right now.
            <a href="http://the99percent.com/tips/7023/How-To-Set-Smart-Daily-Goals">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/the99percent.com/tips/7023/How-To-Set-Smart-Daily-Goals">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 17:07:23 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/the99percent.com/tips/7023/How-To-Set-Smart-Daily-Goals</guid>
        <link>http://the99percent.com/tips/7023/How-To-Set-Smart-Daily-Goals</link>
        <dc:creator>the99percent.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Spreading the News in Europe, in English - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Spreading the News in #Europe, in English http://goo.gl/fb/A3zwF #business #biznews #newsdealersandnewsstands #newsandnewsmedia]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Spreading the News in #Europe, in English http://goo.gl/fb/A3zwF #business #biznews #newsdealersandnewsstands #newsandnewsmedia
            Journalists, entrepreneurs and even government bodies are filling the gaps left by the disappearance of foreign news bureaus.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/business/media/09englishnews.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/business/media/09englishnews.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 16:36:52 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/business/media/09englishnews.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/business/media/09englishnews.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Budget Mix-Up Provides Nation's Schools With Enough Money To Properly Educate Students | The Onion - America's Finest News Source</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Budget Mix-Up Provides Nation&#39;s Schools With Enough Money To Properly Educate Students http://onion.com/m1L36x]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Budget Mix-Up Provides Nation&#39;s Schools With Enough Money To Properly Educate Students http://onion.com/m1L36x
            WASHINGTON—According to bewildered and contrite legislators, a major budgetary mix-up this week inadvertently provided the nation's public schools with enough funding and resources to properly educate students.

Sources in the Congressional Budget O...
            <a href="http://www.theonion.com/articles/budget-mixup-provides-nations-schools-with-enough,20350/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.theonion.com/articles/budget-mixup-provides-nations-schools-with-enough,20350/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 16:36:00 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.theonion.com/articles/budget-mixup-provides-nations-schools-with-enough,20350/</guid>
        <link>http://www.theonion.com/articles/budget-mixup-provides-nations-schools-with-enough,20350/</link>
        <dc:creator>theonion.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>With New App, Ustream Aims To Take Live Streaming On Facebook “To A New Level”</title>
        <description><![CDATA[With New App, Ustream Aims To Take Live Streaming On Facebook &quot;To A New Level&quot; http://tcrn.ch/kqn1yN by @robinwauters]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[With New App, Ustream Aims To Take Live Streaming On Facebook &quot;To A New Level&quot; http://tcrn.ch/kqn1yN by @robinwauters
            Exclusive - Ustream is today launching a new and improved Facebook application that it says will take live streaming within the hugely popular social networking site
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/ustream-live-facebook-app/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/ustream-live-facebook-app/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 16:10:04 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/ustream-live-facebook-app/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/ustream-live-facebook-app/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Your Essential Guide to Twitter Marketing | Copyblogger</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Wow, this is the best organized Twitter resource I&#39;ve ever seen http://bit.ly/mjZBYH]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Wow, this is the best organized Twitter resource I&#39;ve ever seen http://bit.ly/mjZBYH
            And in an attempt to find the best way to go forward with my own marketing efforts on Twitter, I recently realized that I’d collected a fairly valuable list of killer resources along the way.
            <a href="http://www.copyblogger.com/ultimate-twitter/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.copyblogger.com/ultimate-twitter/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 15:53:12 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.copyblogger.com/ultimate-twitter/</guid>
        <link>http://www.copyblogger.com/ultimate-twitter/</link>
        <dc:creator>copyblogger.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Russian Search Giant Yandex Prices $1.2B IPO At $20 To $22 Per Share</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Russian Search Giant Yandex Prices IPO At $20 To $22 Per Share http://tcrn.ch/moKk0Q by @leenarao]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Russian Search Giant Yandex Prices IPO At $20 To $22 Per Share http://tcrn.ch/moKk0Q by @leenarao
            As we wrote last week, Yandex, one of the leading Internet companies in Russia, filed for a public offering on NASDAQ under the symbol
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/russian-search-giant-yandex-prices-ipo-at-20-to-22-per-share/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/russian-search-giant-yandex-prices-ipo-at-20-to-22-per-share/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 15:51:23 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/russian-search-giant-yandex-prices-ipo-at-20-to-22-per-share/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/russian-search-giant-yandex-prices-ipo-at-20-to-22-per-share/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>After Delicious, YouTube Founders Acquire Business Intelligence Platform Tap11</title>
        <description><![CDATA[After Delicious, YouTube Founders Acquire Business Intelligence Platform Tap11 http://tcrn.ch/lgxMsz by @robinwauters]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[After Delicious, YouTube Founders Acquire Business Intelligence Platform Tap11 http://tcrn.ch/lgxMsz by @robinwauters
            AVOS, the new company formed by YouTube founders Chad Hurley and Steve Chen, has acquired Tap11, a real-time business intelligence platform. The company's platform integrates social publishing and analytics into a single dashboard to allow marketers to monitor, engage, and measure the impact of their campaigns. According to the press release, Tap11 works with over 500 major brands, media companies, and agencies. The company had raised funding from US Venture Partners, Alloy Ventures and Palomar Ventures. The acquisition closely follows AVOS' recent acquisition of social bookmarking service Delicious.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/after-delicious-youtube-founders-acquire-business-intelligence-platform-tap11/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/after-delicious-youtube-founders-acquire-business-intelligence-platform-tap11/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 15:18:44 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/after-delicious-youtube-founders-acquire-business-intelligence-platform-tap11/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/after-delicious-youtube-founders-acquire-business-intelligence-platform-tap11/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Can Brands Maintain Engagement on Facebook? - eMarketer</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Can Brands Maintain Engagement on Facebook? - eMarketer http://j.mp/lyDfPK via @AddToAny]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Can Brands Maintain Engagement on Facebook? - eMarketer http://j.mp/lyDfPK via @AddToAny
            “Likes” can go down as fan bases increase. Growing a base of Facebook fans is often a major objective for social media marketers. Whether through special offers available only to fans, the promise of
            <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article.aspx?R=1008377">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.emarketer.com%2FArticle.aspx%3FR%3D1008377">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 15:14:39 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.emarketer.com%2FArticle.aspx%3FR%3D1008377</guid>
        <link>http://www.emarketer.com/Article.aspx?R=1008377</link>
        <dc:creator>emarketer.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Apple overtakes Google to become the world's most valuable brand</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Apple overtakes Google to become the world&#39;s most valuable brand  http://tnw.co/jYT99u by @m4tt]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Apple overtakes Google to become the world&#39;s most valuable brand  http://tnw.co/jYT99u by @m4tt
            Apple pushes ahead of Google to become the world's most valuable brand, according to a new study by global brands agency Millward Brown.
            <a href="http://thenextweb.com/apple/2011/05/09/apple-overtakes-google-to-become-the-worlds-most-valuable-brand/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/thenextweb.com/apple/2011/05/09/apple-overtakes-google-to-become-the-worlds-most-valuable-brand/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 14:44:28 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/thenextweb.com/apple/2011/05/09/apple-overtakes-google-to-become-the-worlds-most-valuable-brand/</guid>
        <link>http://thenextweb.com/apple/2011/05/09/apple-overtakes-google-to-become-the-worlds-most-valuable-brand/</link>
        <dc:creator>thenextweb.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Gaming Industry Vets Raise $3 Million For New Social Games Development Studio</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Gaming Industry Vets Raise $3 Million For New Social Games Development Studio http://tcrn.ch/lX4eCA by @robinwauters]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Gaming Industry Vets Raise $3 Million For New Social Games Development Studio http://tcrn.ch/lX4eCA by @robinwauters
            Row Sham Bow, a new game development studio founded by gaming industry veterans and focused on creating games for social networks and direct-to-consumer platforms, has raised $3 million in funding from early-stage VC firm Intersouth Partners.

Founded earlier this year by president & CEO Philip Holt (former VP and GM of EA Tiburon) and CTO Nick Gonzalez (former Chief Software Architect at EA Tiburon and former CTO of video game technology company Massive), Row Sham Bow is based in Orlando, Florida.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gaming-industry-vets-raise-3-million-for-new-social-games-development-studio/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gaming-industry-vets-raise-3-million-for-new-social-games-development-studio/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 14:42:31 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gaming-industry-vets-raise-3-million-for-new-social-games-development-studio/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/gaming-industry-vets-raise-3-million-for-new-social-games-development-studio/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Limelight Buys Web And Application Acceleration Technology Startup AcceloWeb</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Limelight Buys Web And Application Acceleration Technology Startup AcceloWeb: 

NASDAQ-listed Limelight Network... http://tcrn.ch/izCc22]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Limelight Buys Web And Application Acceleration Technology Startup AcceloWeb: 

NASDAQ-listed Limelight Network... http://tcrn.ch/izCc22
            NASDAQ-listed Limelight Networks this morning announced the acquisition of AcceloWeb, a Tel Aviv-based provider of technology that helps speed the presentation of websites and applications. We wrote about the company back in July 2009 when it was still called FasterWeb.

Terms of the acquisition were not disclosed, but we've learned that the transaction was completed with a combination of Limelight Networks common stock and cash. Founded in 2008, AcceloWeb is headquartered in Israel with US offices in Boston. 
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/limelight-buys-web-and-application-acceleration-technology-startup-acceloweb/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/limelight-buys-web-and-application-acceleration-technology-startup-acceloweb/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 14:42:30 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/limelight-buys-web-and-application-acceleration-technology-startup-acceloweb/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/limelight-buys-web-and-application-acceleration-technology-startup-acceloweb/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>musiXmatch, An IMDB For Legal Song Lyrics, Raises $3.7 Million To Expand Globally</title>
        <description><![CDATA[musiXmatch, An IMDB For Legal Song Lyrics, Raises $3.7 Million To Expand Globally http://tcrn.ch/io6jtp by @ripemp]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[musiXmatch, An IMDB For Legal Song Lyrics, Raises $3.7 Million To Expand Globally http://tcrn.ch/io6jtp by @ripemp
            European music startup musiXmatch will be announcing today at the MusicTech Summit in San Francisco that it has closed a $3.7 million series A funding round for its digital lyrics platform. The round was led by Italian investor Francesco Micheli Associates. musiXmatch adds to the prior $700K it has raised in seed funding from both Francesco Micheli and a former Dada executive.

Lyrics are one of the most searched for terms on Google, and I think many of us have found ourselves looking to Google and one of the many lyric sites to either help us win an argument, or clean up the lyrics of a favorite old song playing our heads. There are, of course, tons of song lyric sites floating around the Web, but the large majority of them are unofficial, or don't have the rights to be broadcasting free song lyrics to the public.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/musixmatch-an-imdb-for-legal-song-lyrics-raises-3-7-million-to-expand-globally/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/musixmatch-an-imdb-for-legal-song-lyrics-raises-3-7-million-to-expand-globally/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:47:54 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/musixmatch-an-imdb-for-legal-song-lyrics-raises-3-7-million-to-expand-globally/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/09/musixmatch-an-imdb-for-legal-song-lyrics-raises-3-7-million-to-expand-globally/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>That's why bin Laden had no chance to escape</title>
        <description><![CDATA[That&#39;s why bin Laden had no chance to escape http://i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[That&#39;s why bin Laden had no chance to escape http://i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg
            That&#39;s why bin Laden had no chance to escape http://i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg
            <a href="http://i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:43:04 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg</guid>
        <link>http://i.imgur.com/VWuwQ.jpg</link>
        <dc:creator>imgur.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The Unwisdom of Elites - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Unwisdom of Elites - NYT http://nyti.ms/lSKHDu]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Unwisdom of Elites - NYT http://nyti.ms/lSKHDu
            The anatomy of a top-down disaster.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/opinion/09krugman.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/opinion/09krugman.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:39:53 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/opinion/09krugman.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/09/opinion/09krugman.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Use Twitter to Connect With Local Customers | Social Media Examiner</title>
        <description><![CDATA[5 Ways to Use Twitter to Connect With Local Customers http://bit.ly/kUo4Cd]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[5 Ways to Use Twitter to Connect With Local Customers http://bit.ly/kUo4Cd
            Local marketing: how to locate people who live or tweet in your city or neighborhood to create a Twitter strategy relevant to your business.
            <a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-ways-to-use-twitter-to-connect-with-local-customers/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-ways-to-use-twitter-to-connect-with-local-customers/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:31:22 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-ways-to-use-twitter-to-connect-with-local-customers/</guid>
        <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/5-ways-to-use-twitter-to-connect-with-local-customers/</link>
        <dc:creator>socialmediaexaminer.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Osama bin Laden’s hideout recreated in CS:S « GamePron</title>
        <description><![CDATA[GamePron: Osama bin Laden&#39;s hideout recreated in CS:S http://bit.ly/lfSq8q]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[GamePron: Osama bin Laden&#39;s hideout recreated in CS:S http://bit.ly/lfSq8q
            Osama bin Laden’s hideout recreated in CS:S «  GamePron - All the gaming news with just a touch of GamePron
            <a href="http://www.gamepron.com/news/2011/05/08/osama-bin-ladens-hideout-recreated-in-css/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.gamepron.com/news/2011/05/08/osama-bin-ladens-hideout-recreated-in-css/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 13:06:35 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.gamepron.com/news/2011/05/08/osama-bin-ladens-hideout-recreated-in-css/</guid>
        <link>http://www.gamepron.com/news/2011/05/08/osama-bin-ladens-hideout-recreated-in-css/</link>
        <dc:creator>gamepron.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

</channel>
</rss> 

