<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
<channel>
<title>Topsy - Top 100 </title>
<link>http://topsy.com/top100</link>
<description>Top Links generated by Topsy.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>6</sy:updateFrequency>
<ttl>40</ttl>

    <item>
        <title>The Tech Press: Screw Them All</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The Tech Press: Screw Them All http://tcrn.ch/lvfK9n by @arrington]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Tech Press: Screw Them All http://tcrn.ch/lvfK9n by @arrington
            Last week I wrote a post about my current investment policy at TechCrunch, and pointing out already disclosed financial conflicts of interest. Our primary duty to readers, as I've said many times, is transparency. To that end we will (as we always have) be extremely careful in disclosing any investments I've made in startups or in venture funds. And these interests will be disclosed even when other TechCrunch writers are covering these companies.

In that post I said that there would be a lot of criticism headed our way from our competitors. And that's exactly what happened. AllThingsD calls me
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/tech-press-screw-them-all/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/tech-press-screw-them-all/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 02:22:36 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/tech-press-screw-them-all/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/tech-press-screw-them-all/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>“Inside Apple” Reveals Steve Jobs Anecdotes, Apple’s Little Known Facts</title>
        <description><![CDATA[&quot;Inside Apple&quot; Reveals Steve Jobs Anecdotes, Apple&#39;s Little Known Facts http://mcstr.net/jG3LC6]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[&quot;Inside Apple&quot; Reveals Steve Jobs Anecdotes, Apple&#39;s Little Known Facts http://mcstr.net/jG3LC6
            + Footprints Lets You Share Your Location, Track Your Friends and Family + Twitterrific for Mac 4.1: Autocomplete, Visual Tweaks, and Better than Ever + AirServer Brings AirPlay For Everything to OS X + Listary for iPhone Creates Lists, Syncs with Simplenote + FlickAddress Enhances Your iPhone’s Address Book with Gestures
            <a href="http://www.macstories.net/news/inside-apple-reveals-steve-jobs-anecdotes-apples-little-known-facts/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.macstories.net/news/inside-apple-reveals-steve-jobs-anecdotes-apples-little-known-facts/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 01:27:09 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.macstories.net/news/inside-apple-reveals-steve-jobs-anecdotes-apples-little-known-facts/</guid>
        <link>http://www.macstories.net/news/inside-apple-reveals-steve-jobs-anecdotes-apples-little-known-facts/</link>
        <dc:creator>macstories.net</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>OMG/JK: Can Google Correct Last Year’s Big I/O Flops This Year?</title>
        <description><![CDATA[OMG/JK: Can Google Correct Last Year&#39;s Big I/O Flops This Year? http://tcrn.ch/iUPzRm by @parislemon]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[OMG/JK: Can Google Correct Last Year&#39;s Big I/O Flops This Year? http://tcrn.ch/iUPzRm by @parislemon
            It's just about that time again. Google I/O is happening next week and just as in year's past, the company is expected to announce some big things on stage during their two keynotes on Tuesday and Wednesday morning. But what will those things be? Jason and I delve into some predictions for the event, which we'll both be covering.

But first we take some time to look back at last year's I/O which made a big splash at the time — and can now probably be best described as a big flop. Google TV, Google Music, Chrome OS. Etc, etc, etc... Will this year's be more of the same, or will Google's mouth actually be able to write checks that their body can cash this time around? Stay tuned...
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/omgjk-google-io/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/omgjk-google-io/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:57:03 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/omgjk-google-io/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/omgjk-google-io/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Amazon Cloud Player Quietly Begins Working On iOS Devices!</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Amazon Cloud Player Quietly Begins Working On iOS Devices! http://tcrn.ch/ishfV7 by @parislemon]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Amazon Cloud Player Quietly Begins Working On iOS Devices! http://tcrn.ch/ishfV7 by @parislemon
            Back in March, alongside the roll out of Amazon's new cloud-based music upload/player service, we noted one glaring problem: it didn't work on iOS devices. You might think this had to due with Flash or another technology that iOS wasn't compatible with, but it wasn't. It looked like something else was simply blocking it from working. Well, good news. That's no longer the case.

If you visit Amazon's Cloud Player through the Safari web browser on an iOS device, you'll see that it does in fact now work. You'll first hit a warning page telling you that your browser is not supported, but just ignore that. Click into the music in your drive and it will begin playing. It works flawlessly — even to the point where if you get a Push Notification or incoming call, the music will be paused.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/amazon-cloud-player-quietly-begins-working-on-ios-devices/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/amazon-cloud-player-quietly-begins-working-on-ios-devices/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 23:48:59 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/amazon-cloud-player-quietly-begins-working-on-ios-devices/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/amazon-cloud-player-quietly-begins-working-on-ios-devices/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Does anyone else have a feeling that Pakistan knows where the Hamburglar is?</title>
        <description><![CDATA[RT @ConanOBrien: Does anyone else have a feeling that Pakistan knows where the Hamburglar is?]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[RT @ConanOBrien: Does anyone else have a feeling that Pakistan knows where the Hamburglar is?
            Does anyone else have a feeling that Pakistan knows where the Hamburglar is?
            <a href="http://twitter.com/conanobrien/status/66966457472385024">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/twitter.com/conanobrien/status/66966457472385024">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 23:12:07 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/twitter.com/conanobrien/status/66966457472385024</guid>
        <link>http://twitter.com/conanobrien/status/66966457472385024</link>
        <dc:creator>twitter.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Did /dev/fort Just Hand Over Astronaut Listening Data To The WWW?</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Did /dev/fort Just Hand Over Astronaut Listening Data To The WWW? http://tcrn.ch/kS7kdx by @paulcarr]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Did /dev/fort Just Hand Over Astronaut Listening Data To The WWW? http://tcrn.ch/kS7kdx by @paulcarr
            Everyone is rightly very excited about the upcoming mega-hackathon at Disrupt New York. At last count, the event will host around four hundred billion hackers, working on some eighty five trillion projects. Luckily, as at all TechCrunch events, there'll be rock-solid wifi and wired Internet for all those billions of people to use.

And yet... on the other side of the Atlantic, a merry band of hackers is providing that you don't need to attend a record-breakingly-large hackthon to produce a seriously cool app. In fact, you don't even need Internet access.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/did-devfort-just-hand-over-astronaut-listening-data-to-the-www/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/did-devfort-just-hand-over-astronaut-listening-data-to-the-www/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 22:57:33 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/did-devfort-just-hand-over-astronaut-listening-data-to-the-www/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/did-devfort-just-hand-over-astronaut-listening-data-to-the-www/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>URGENT - Pakistan-Bin-Laden-Intelligence - CNN.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[URGENT - Pakistan-Bin-Laden-Intelligence: Intelligence officials on Saturday unveiled five different videos of O... http://bit.ly/m2fD02]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[URGENT - Pakistan-Bin-Laden-Intelligence: Intelligence officials on Saturday unveiled five different videos of O... http://bit.ly/m2fD02
            Intelligence officials on Saturday unveiled five different videos of Osama bin Laden that were confiscated from the deadly raid at his Pakistan compound, further adding to the Obama administration's confirmation that the al Qaeda leader was among the five killed at the site.
            <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/asiapcf/05/07/pakistan.bin.laden.intelligence/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/asiapcf/05/07/pakistan.bin.laden.intelligence/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 22:12:38 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/asiapcf/05/07/pakistan.bin.laden.intelligence/</guid>
        <link>http://www.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/asiapcf/05/07/pakistan.bin.laden.intelligence/</link>
        <dc:creator>cnn.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Soon, AOL’s AIM Won’t Require A Separate Login To Chat With Contacts In Gmail</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Soon, AOL&#39;s AIM Won&#39;t Require A Separate Login To Chat With Contacts In Gmail http://tcrn.ch/lQo6Rz by @leenarao]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Soon, AOL&#39;s AIM Won&#39;t Require A Separate Login To Chat With Contacts In Gmail http://tcrn.ch/lQo6Rz by @leenarao
            Since 2007, you've been able to sign in to your AOL Instant Messenger (AIM) account to chat with your AIM contacts directly from Gmail. You simply login with your AIM account in Gmail and your contacts will populate your gChat list, allowing you to chat with them just like you would your Google Talk contatcs. 

From this notice, it looks like changes may be afoot to this feature. From AIM's notice,  In the next few days, Google and AOL are working together to change the way you connect to AIM buddies within Gmail. After this change, Gmail and AIM users can talk directly to each other without having to log into both services (you will no longer be able to log into AIM within Gmail's
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/soon-aols-aim-wont-require-a-separate-login-to-chat-with-contacts-in-gmail/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/soon-aols-aim-wont-require-a-separate-login-to-chat-with-contacts-in-gmail/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 20:00:38 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/soon-aols-aim-wont-require-a-separate-login-to-chat-with-contacts-in-gmail/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/soon-aols-aim-wont-require-a-separate-login-to-chat-with-contacts-in-gmail/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Group: 2 Muslim men pulled from plane bound for North Carolina - CNN.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Group: 2 Muslim men pulled from plane bound for North Carolina: Two Muslim men were  removed from a plane headed... http://bit.ly/kl7O3g]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Group: 2 Muslim men pulled from plane bound for North Carolina: Two Muslim men were  removed from a plane headed... http://bit.ly/kl7O3g
            Two Muslim men were  removed from a plane headed to North Carolina because passengers were uncomfortable, the  Council on American-Islamic Relations said.
            <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/TRAVEL/05/07/muslims.kicked.off.plane/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.cnn.com/2011/TRAVEL/05/07/muslims.kicked.off.plane/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 19:19:31 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.cnn.com/2011/TRAVEL/05/07/muslims.kicked.off.plane/</guid>
        <link>http://www.cnn.com/2011/TRAVEL/05/07/muslims.kicked.off.plane/</link>
        <dc:creator>cnn.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Why The New Guy Can’t Code</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Why The New Guy Can&#39;t Code http://tcrn.ch/jEA09X by @rezendi]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Why The New Guy Can&#39;t Code http://tcrn.ch/jEA09X by @rezendi
            We've all lived the nightmare. A new developer shows up at work, and you try to be welcoming, but he1 can't seem to get up to speed; the questions he asks reveal basic ignorance; and his work, when it finally emerges, is so kludgey that it ultimately must be rewritten from scratch by more competent people. And yet his interviewers—and/or the HR department, if your company has been infested by that bureaucratic parasite—swear that they only hire above-average/A-level/top-1% people.

It's a big problem, especially now. There's a boom on. I get harassing emails from recruiters every day. Everyone's desperate to hire developers…but developers are not fungible. A great coder can easily be 50 times more productive than a mediocre one, while bad ones ultimately have negative productivity. Hiring a mediocre or bad developer is a terrible mistake for any organization; for a startup, it can be a catastrophic company-killer. So how can it happen so often?

Like many of the hangovers that haunt modern software engineering, this is ultimately mostly Microsoft's fault.2
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/why-the-new-guy-cant-code/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/why-the-new-guy-cant-code/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 18:46:31 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/why-the-new-guy-cant-code/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/why-the-new-guy-cant-code/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The ‘Facebook Class’ Built Apps, and Fortunes - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[The ‘Facebook Class’ Built Apps, and Fortunes http://dlvr.it/QyBqR #facebook]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[The ‘Facebook Class’ Built Apps, and Fortunes http://dlvr.it/QyBqR #facebook
            In 2007, the “Facebook Class” at Stanford created free apps for millions of users. But it also fired up the careers of many students and pioneered a new model of entrepreneurship.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/technology/08class.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/technology/08class.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 18:22:46 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/technology/08class.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/technology/08class.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>10 fantastic social media campaign videos you shouldn’t miss - TNW Social Media</title>
        <description><![CDATA[10 fantastic social media campaign videos you shouldn&#39;t miss http://tnw.to/189XV by @SimplyZesty]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[10 fantastic social media campaign videos you shouldn&#39;t miss http://tnw.to/189XV by @SimplyZesty
            tweb&via=tnwsocialmedia&text=10 fantastic social media campaign videos you shouldn%E2%80%99t miss
            <a href="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/07/10-fantastic-social-media-campaign-videos-you-shouldnt-miss/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/07/10-fantastic-social-media-campaign-videos-you-shouldnt-miss/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 16:43:02 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/07/10-fantastic-social-media-campaign-videos-you-shouldnt-miss/</guid>
        <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/07/10-fantastic-social-media-campaign-videos-you-shouldnt-miss/</link>
        <dc:creator>thenextweb.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>A New Era Of Search Is About The Answers, Not Just The Links</title>
        <description><![CDATA[A New Era Of Search Is About The Answers, Not Just The Links http://tcrn.ch/klAIIF]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[A New Era Of Search Is About The Answers, Not Just The Links http://tcrn.ch/klAIIF
            Search is about to change quite radically. For more than a decade, search has been stagnant: the core product has not changed much. Users have changed radically in that time frame. Even though the kind of content users consume is different, search engines are still focused mostly on web pages. Users have become less patient and have less time on hand, while search engines still require users to dig through and extract information from the web pages to find what they’re looking for. In addition, users are spending more and more time on their mobile phones and other connected devices, which require a completely different kind of user experience for search.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/search-answers-not-just-links/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/search-answers-not-just-links/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 16:31:59 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/search-answers-not-just-links/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/search-answers-not-just-links/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>A Lesson in Twitter Etiquette</title>
        <description><![CDATA[It’s Not That Kind of Place: A Lesson in Twitter Etiquette http://tnw.to/189AX by @uglynewyorker]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[It’s Not That Kind of Place: A Lesson in Twitter Etiquette http://tnw.to/189AX by @uglynewyorker
            lated=thenextweb&via=tnwsocialmedia&text=It%E2%80%99s Not That Kind of Place: A Lesson in Twitter Etiquette
            <a href="http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/06/it%E2%80%99s-not-that-kind-of-place-a-lesson-in-twitter-etiquette/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/06/it%E2%80%99s-not-that-kind-of-place-a-lesson-in-twitter-etiquette/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 15:58:28 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/06/it%E2%80%99s-not-that-kind-of-place-a-lesson-in-twitter-etiquette/</guid>
        <link>http://thenextweb.com/socialmedia/2011/05/06/it%E2%80%99s-not-that-kind-of-place-a-lesson-in-twitter-etiquette/</link>
        <dc:creator>thenextweb.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>TechCrunch Giveaway: Free Ticket To Disrupt In NYC #TechCrunch</title>
        <description><![CDATA[TechCrunch Giveaway: Free Ticket To Disrupt In NYC #TechCrunch http://tcrn.ch/j5qoAl by @elinblesener]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[TechCrunch Giveaway: Free Ticket To Disrupt In NYC #TechCrunch http://tcrn.ch/j5qoAl by @elinblesener
            Here is another chance for you to win a free ticket to this year's Disrupt in NYC. Early bird tickets are no longer available, so this ticket is valued at around $3,000. This is one giveaway you don't want to miss!

We have been announcing new guest speakers week after week. Arianna Huffington, Marissa Mayer, Ron Conway, Dennis Crowley, Charlie Rose and many, many more will be joining us. You can read the full list of speakers as of now here. We still have surprises to announce, so be sure to be on the lookout for those.

Disrupt NYC is from May 23rd to May 25th and this ticket is good for the entire conference, as well as the after parties. Want it? Just follow the steps below to enter.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/techcrunch-giveaway-free-ticket-to-disrupt-in-nyc-techcrunch/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/techcrunch-giveaway-free-ticket-to-disrupt-in-nyc-techcrunch/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 14:16:54 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/techcrunch-giveaway-free-ticket-to-disrupt-in-nyc-techcrunch/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/techcrunch-giveaway-free-ticket-to-disrupt-in-nyc-techcrunch/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Hybrid Motoryacht Design Powered By Diesel And Electric Jet Skis</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Hybrid Motoryacht Design Powered By Diesel And Electric Jet Skis http://tcrn.ch/lAYQcy by @matylda]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Hybrid Motoryacht Design Powered By Diesel And Electric Jet Skis http://tcrn.ch/lAYQcy by @matylda
            Hybrid cars have been around for a while, but one German grad student is taking the concept to the water. A new hybrid propulsion motorboat designed by Stefanie Behringer, would reduce drag thanks to its three-hull, or trimaran, form.

A jet ski attaches to either side of the main hull, helping stabilize the boat. While the jet skis are electric-powered, the 49-foot long watercraft is also powered by two diesel engines that use Audi's turbo-charged injection technology. Audi's Concept Design team in Munich worked with Behringer on the project.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/hybrid-motoryacht-design-powered-by-diesel-and-electric-jet-skis/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/hybrid-motoryacht-design-powered-by-diesel-and-electric-jet-skis/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 13:26:59 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/hybrid-motoryacht-design-powered-by-diesel-and-electric-jet-skis/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/07/hybrid-motoryacht-design-powered-by-diesel-and-electric-jet-skis/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Trying to Game Google on ‘Mother’s Day Flowers’ - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Trying to Corner the Search Market for &#39;Mother&#39;s Day Flowers&#39;: Anyone who clicks on those backlinks, as they are... http://bit.ly/lNEfvS]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Trying to Corner the Search Market for &#39;Mother&#39;s Day Flowers&#39;: Anyone who clicks on those backlinks, as they are... http://bit.ly/lNEfvS
            Experts say that Teleflora, FTD, 1800Flowers.com and ProFlowers are violating guidelines in their quest to rise in online search results.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/business/07flowers.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/business/07flowers.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 13:03:59 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/business/07flowers.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/business/07flowers.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Seve Ballesteros, 54, Dashing Golf Champion - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Seve Ballesteros, Dashing Golf Champion, Dies at 54 - http://is.gd/oK5i4Y - #sports]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Seve Ballesteros, Dashing Golf Champion, Dies at 54 - http://is.gd/oK5i4Y - #sports
            Mr. Ballesteros won five major titles and helped propel Europe’s rise in the Ryder Cup competition with the United States.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/sports/golf/08ballesteros.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/sports/golf/08ballesteros.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 12:48:08 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/sports/golf/08ballesteros.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/sports/golf/08ballesteros.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Death of Osama bin Laden: Phone call pointed U.S. to compound — and to ‘the pacer’ - The Washington Post</title>
        <description><![CDATA[A phone call between old friends becomes the key moment in the decades-long search for Osama bin Laden. http://wapo.st/jtYiaF]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[A phone call between old friends becomes the key moment in the decades-long search for Osama bin Laden. http://wapo.st/jtYiaF
            The key phone exchange and several other pieces of information gave President Obama the confidence to launch a the risky mission.
            <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_story.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_story.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 12:19:57 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_story.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_story.html</link>
        <dc:creator>washingtonpost.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Iraqi Child in Acclaimed War Photo Tries to Move On - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Face That Screamed War’s Pain Looks Back, 6 Hard Years Later http://goo.gl/fb/x89xY #iraqwar2003 #hondroschris]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Face That Screamed War’s Pain Looks Back, 6 Hard Years Later http://goo.gl/fb/x89xY #iraqwar2003 #hondroschris
            At 5 years old, photographs of Samar Hassan, screaming and splattered in blood, illuminated the horror of civilian casualties in Iraq.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/middleeast/07photo.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/middleeast/07photo.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 12:12:52 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/middleeast/07photo.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/middleeast/07photo.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Easily distracted people may have too much brain - health - 06 May 2011 - New Scientist</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Sorry, I drifted off. What was that again? Easily distracted people have too much brain http://bit.ly/kX6rXv]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Sorry, I drifted off. What was that again? Easily distracted people have too much brain http://bit.ly/kX6rXv
            People who often find their mind wandering have a larger volume of grey matter in a part of the brain called the left superior parietal lobe
            <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn20453-easily-distracted-people-may-have-too-much-brain.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.newscientist.com/article/dn20453-easily-distracted-people-may-have-too-much-brain.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 11:52:48 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.newscientist.com/article/dn20453-easily-distracted-people-may-have-too-much-brain.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn20453-easily-distracted-people-may-have-too-much-brain.html</link>
        <dc:creator>newscientist.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Seth's Blog: How long is your long run?</title>
        <description><![CDATA[How long is your long run?: The bank robber may have a long run of just thirty minutes. Stealing money today app... http://bit.ly/mhianP]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[How long is your long run?: The bank robber may have a long run of just thirty minutes. Stealing money today app... http://bit.ly/mhianP
            The bank robber may have a long run of just thirty minutes. Stealing money today appears worth it because tomorrow is just too far away to consider. There are organizations and nations that have been around for hundreds of years...
            <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/05/how-long-is-your-long-ru.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/05/how-long-is-your-long-ru.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 10:07:34 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/05/how-long-is-your-long-ru.html</guid>
        <link>http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/05/how-long-is-your-long-ru.html</link>
        <dc:creator>sethgodin.typepad.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Afghanistan, April 2011 - The Big Picture - Boston.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Afghanistan, April 2011 http://bo.st/mow7zD]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Afghanistan, April 2011 http://bo.st/mow7zD
            Life expectancy in Afghanistan is but 45 years.  It has the world's second-highest infant mortality rate.  Only 12% of Afghan women are literate.   It is the world's largest producer of opium.  Soon it will have been occupied by foreign militaries for ten years, which followed years of Taliban rule, which followed years of civil war, which followed years of Soviet military occupation.  Widespread corruption mutes hopes for the immediate future.  The death of Osama bin Laden further clouds future American involvement in the country.  Gathered here in our monthly collection of photographs from Afghanistan are images of the U.S. military mission, the toll of violence on civilians, and daily life in the country of just under 30 million. -- Lane Turner
            <a href="http://www.boston.com/bigpicture/2011/05/afghanistan_april_2011.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.boston.com/bigpicture/2011/05/afghanistan_april_2011.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 09:22:01 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.boston.com/bigpicture/2011/05/afghanistan_april_2011.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.boston.com/bigpicture/2011/05/afghanistan_april_2011.html</link>
        <dc:creator>boston.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>42 Fresh Facts About Twitter &amp;amp; Facebook… | Bit Rebels</title>
        <description><![CDATA[42 Fresh Facts About Twitter &amp; Facebook [Infographic]: The infographics business has really taken off in the pas... http://bit.ly/jxbWcz]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[42 Fresh Facts About Twitter &amp; Facebook [Infographic]: The infographics business has really taken off in the pas... http://bit.ly/jxbWcz
            The infographics business has really taken off in the past year or so. We see new agencies spring up pretty much every day, and the infographics get more and
            <a href="http://www.bitrebels.com/social/42-fresh-facts-about-twitter-facebook-infographic/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.bitrebels.com/social/42-fresh-facts-about-twitter-facebook-infographic/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 07:54:25 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.bitrebels.com/social/42-fresh-facts-about-twitter-facebook-infographic/</guid>
        <link>http://www.bitrebels.com/social/42-fresh-facts-about-twitter-facebook-infographic/</link>
        <dc:creator>bitrebels.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Death of Osama bin Laden: Phone call pointed U.S. to compound — and to ‘the pacer’ - The Washington Post</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Bob Woodward: &quot;This is where you start the movie about the hunt for bin Laden&quot;
http://dlvr.it/Qv7YK #obl]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Bob Woodward: &quot;This is where you start the movie about the hunt for bin Laden&quot;
http://dlvr.it/Qv7YK #obl
            Death of Osama bin Laden: Phone call pointed U.S. to compound — and to ‘the
            <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_print.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_print.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 07:43:36 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_print.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/death-of-osama-bin-laden-phone-call-pointed-us-to-compound--and-to-the-pacer/2011/05/06/AFnSVaCG_print.html</link>
        <dc:creator>washingtonpost.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>PCC seeks to regulate press Twitter feeds | Media | guardian.co.uk</title>
        <description><![CDATA[PCC seeks to regulate press Twitter feeds: Watchdog to consult on how tweets can be brought under its remit, ask... http://bit.ly/kGKEuu]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[PCC seeks to regulate press Twitter feeds: Watchdog to consult on how tweets can be brought under its remit, ask... http://bit.ly/kGKEuu
            Watchdog to consult on how tweets can be brought under its remit, asking each newspaper to draw up a 'Twitter policy'. By Dan Sabbagh
            <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/06/pcc-press-twitter-feeds">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/06/pcc-press-twitter-feeds">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 07:09:06 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/06/pcc-press-twitter-feeds</guid>
        <link>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2011/may/06/pcc-press-twitter-feeds</link>
        <dc:creator>guardian.co.uk</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>You Think Pitching Your Startup Idea Is Hard? Watch These Kids Do It</title>
        <description><![CDATA[You Think Pitching Your Startup Idea Is Hard? Watch These Kids Do It http://tcrn.ch/intduW by @alexia]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[You Think Pitching Your Startup Idea Is Hard? Watch These Kids Do It http://tcrn.ch/intduW by @alexia
            Around eighty entrepreneur hopefuls gathered at NASA AMES last week to pitch their ideas for breakthrough technological products, with the hopes of gaining the funding to make their dreams a reality. But this wasn't part of the application process for a new fangled startup accelerator program, and the teams weren't comprised of Valley visionairies in their 20s and 30s but rather high school kids between the ages of 14-18.

To compete in the Conrad Foundation's Spirit of Innovation Awards, each team of high schoolers had to create a business plan, technical report, graphical representation and elevator pitch for their product, presenting their invention to a panel of judges for 10 minutes. All in all 27 finalists competed in the Aerospace, Clean Energy and Cyber security categories to win $5,000 and the community support and mentorship to develop their product commercially.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/you-think-pitching-your-startup-idea-is-hard-watch-these-kids-do-it/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/you-think-pitching-your-startup-idea-is-hard-watch-these-kids-do-it/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 06:35:01 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/you-think-pitching-your-startup-idea-is-hard-watch-these-kids-do-it/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/you-think-pitching-your-startup-idea-is-hard-watch-these-kids-do-it/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Love is like an Ewok: cute from a distance but up close; smelly, difficult to understand and likely to beat you to death with sticks.</title>
        <description><![CDATA[RT @DeathStarPR: Love is like an Ewok: cute from a distance but up close; smelly, difficult to understand and likely to beat you to deat ...]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[RT @DeathStarPR: Love is like an Ewok: cute from a distance but up close; smelly, difficult to understand and likely to beat you to deat ...
            Love is like an Ewok: cute from a distance but up close; smelly, difficult to understand and likely to beat you to death with sticks.
            <a href="http://twitter.com/deathstarpr/status/66668143845720064">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/twitter.com/deathstarpr/status/66668143845720064">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 06:33:01 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/twitter.com/deathstarpr/status/66668143845720064</guid>
        <link>http://twitter.com/deathstarpr/status/66668143845720064</link>
        <dc:creator>twitter.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Facebook Quietly Fixes its Original Privacy Problem, 5 Years Later</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Facebook Quietly Fixes its Original Privacy Problem, 5 Years Later http://rww.to/iJehOD]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Facebook Quietly Fixes its Original Privacy Problem, 5 Years Later http://rww.to/iJehOD
            Facebook has quietly enabled a new privacy feature that allows users to hide certain types of updates from their walls and from the newsfeeds of friends. Make a new friend? Planning on going to an event? Now you can do those things on Facebook but be discrete about it, thanks to the new Hide All These button. That type of posting will never show up on your wall - or in your friends' newsfeeds - again. This is exactly the kind of option that would have likely satisfied critics of the newsfeed when it launched to huge protests 5 years...
            <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/facebook_quietly_fixes_its_original_privacy_proble.php">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.readwriteweb.com/archives/facebook_quietly_fixes_its_original_privacy_proble.php">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 05:15:37 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.readwriteweb.com/archives/facebook_quietly_fixes_its_original_privacy_proble.php</guid>
        <link>http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/facebook_quietly_fixes_its_original_privacy_proble.php</link>
        <dc:creator>readwriteweb.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Gov. Bobby Jindal releases his birth certificate | NOLA.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Errrr. Gov. Bobby Jindal releases his birth certificate http://bit.ly/mzsUun What do you expect from a guy who names himself after a Brady?]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Errrr. Gov. Bobby Jindal releases his birth certificate http://bit.ly/mzsUun What do you expect from a guy who names himself after a Brady?
            He knows his own status will certainly be examined in the event he ends up on a presidential ticket
            <a href="http://www.nola.com/politics/index.ssf/2011/05/gov_bobby_jindal_releases_his.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nola.com/politics/index.ssf/2011/05/gov_bobby_jindal_releases_his.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 03:57:40 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nola.com/politics/index.ssf/2011/05/gov_bobby_jindal_releases_his.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nola.com/politics/index.ssf/2011/05/gov_bobby_jindal_releases_his.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nola.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Apple May Not Have Bought Nuance But…</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Apple May Not Have Bought Nuance But... http://tcrn.ch/mMH4JX by @parislemon]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Apple May Not Have Bought Nuance But... http://tcrn.ch/mMH4JX by @parislemon
            This past November, the blogosphere was briefly set on fire when a comment Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak made in passing stated that Apple had acquired the voice recognition company Nuance. Wozniak quickly came out and corrected that comment, and most believed that he had simply confused Nuance with the company he mentioned right afterwards, Siri — a company that Apple actually did acquire in April 2010. But as it turns out, Wozniak's comment, whether he knew it or not at the time, may not have been as off as it seemed.

Apple has been negotiating a deal with Nuance in recent months, we've heard from multiple sources. What does that mean? Well, it could mean an acquisition, but that is looking fairly unlikely at this point, we hear. More likely, it means a partnership that will be vital to both companies and could shape the future of iOS.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/apple-nuance-ios-siri/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/apple-nuance-ios-siri/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 03:33:55 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/apple-nuance-ios-siri/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/apple-nuance-ios-siri/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>U.S. Demands More From Pakistan as Details of Bin Laden’s Movements Emerge - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[U.S. Demands More From Pakistan as Details of Bin Laden’s Movements Emerge - http://is.gd/UCzPs6 - #world]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[U.S. Demands More From Pakistan as Details of Bin Laden’s Movements Emerge - http://is.gd/UCzPs6 - #world
            Tensions have increased between Pakistani officials and the Obama administration along with suspicions that Pakistan’s secret intelligence agency protected Bin Laden’s location.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/asia/07policy.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/asia/07policy.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 03:28:58 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/asia/07policy.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/07/world/asia/07policy.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Why We Need Firefox - Open Enterprise</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Why We Need #Firefox - http://bit.ly/kaqWxL just in case anyone had forgotten #openweb #freedom]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Why We Need #Firefox - http://bit.ly/kaqWxL just in case anyone had forgotten #openweb #freedom
            Earlier this week, I reported on my travails with Firefox, and how I teetered on the brink of switching to Google's Chromium. Actually, I wasn't too seriously tempted, and thanks to the kind efforts of Mozilla, the problem has been...
            <a href="http://blogs.computerworlduk.com/open-enterprise/2011/05/why-we-need-firefox/index.htm">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/blogs.computerworlduk.com/open-enterprise/2011/05/why-we-need-firefox/index.htm">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 03:07:36 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/blogs.computerworlduk.com/open-enterprise/2011/05/why-we-need-firefox/index.htm</guid>
        <link>http://blogs.computerworlduk.com/open-enterprise/2011/05/why-we-need-firefox/index.htm</link>
        <dc:creator>computerworlduk.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Joe Hewitt</title>
        <description><![CDATA[I&#39;m an indie developer now. New blog post: http://t.co/6zvJ3ep]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[I&#39;m an indie developer now. New blog post: http://t.co/6zvJ3ep
            Today was my last day at Facebook. Normally when I leave a job I go out cursing the management and wishing I had left much sooner. In the case of Facebook, I sent heartfelt emails to all of my managers thanking them for the privilege of letting me work there, and I genuinely meant it. Facebook was the longest I ever worked at one company, and the best employer I've ever had.
            <a href="http://joehewitt.com/post/creative-tools/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/joehewitt.com/post/creative-tools/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 02:04:11 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/joehewitt.com/post/creative-tools/</guid>
        <link>http://joehewitt.com/post/creative-tools/</link>
        <dc:creator>joehewitt.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Advanced commenting systems for WordPress | Webdesigner Depot</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Advanced commenting systems for WordPress  http://tiny.ly/ptL5]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Advanced commenting systems for WordPress  http://tiny.ly/ptL5
            WordPress has a perfectly adequate commenting system built-in. But it can quickly grow unwieldy and commenting can take up a lot of system resources if you
            <a href="http://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/advanced-commenting-systems-for-wordpress/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/advanced-commenting-systems-for-wordpress/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 01:25:02 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/advanced-commenting-systems-for-wordpress/</guid>
        <link>http://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/05/advanced-commenting-systems-for-wordpress/</link>
        <dc:creator>webdesignerdepot.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Esteemed Mobile Developer Joe Hewitt Leaves Facebook</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Mobile Developer Joe Hewitt Leaves Facebook http://tcrn.ch/jsC189 by @alexia]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Mobile Developer Joe Hewitt Leaves Facebook http://tcrn.ch/jsC189 by @alexia
            Notable mobile developer Joe Hewitt has left Facebook to pursue independent projects related to HTML 5 development.

From his blog:
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/mobile-developer-joe-hewitt-leaves-facebook/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/mobile-developer-joe-hewitt-leaves-facebook/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 01:06:46 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/mobile-developer-joe-hewitt-leaves-facebook/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/mobile-developer-joe-hewitt-leaves-facebook/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Google Appears To Be Testing A Sparse, Ugly New Results Page</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Google Appears To Be Testing A Sparse, Ugly New Results Page http://tcrn.ch/kR0WoV by @parislemon]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Google Appears To Be Testing A Sparse, Ugly New Results Page http://tcrn.ch/kR0WoV by @parislemon
            Whoa there tipsters, slow down. We've just been bombarded with tips coming our way that Google has rolled out a new-look search results page. Scanning Twitter, it looks like there are in fact a lot of people seeing this. And boy is it ugly.

I mean, it's great that Google appears to be trying to clean up the look of the results page, which has gotten pretty cluttered over the years as they add more and more types of information and snippets. But the new design is too sparse. And the colors are too soft. It looks like Bing on a bad day.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/google-new-results-page/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/google-new-results-page/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:23:32 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/google-new-results-page/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/google-new-results-page/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>The 2011 Toyota Corolla</title>
        <description><![CDATA[アメリカンなミクｗ　http://bit.ly/mEuhVx]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[アメリカンなミクｗ　http://bit.ly/mEuhVx
            The 2011 Toyota Corolla - Features And Prices For All Car Models: Corolla, LE And S. See The 2011 Manufacturer's Suggested Retail Price, Photos, Features, Options, And Much More.
            <a href="http://www.toyota.com/corollamiku/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.toyota.com/corollamiku/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2011 00:02:42 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.toyota.com/corollamiku/</guid>
        <link>http://www.toyota.com/corollamiku/</link>
        <dc:creator>toyota.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>YouTube - OSAMA MARILAC</title>
        <description><![CDATA[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRjx6RlRqzc&amp;feature=youtube_gdata UHAUHSAUHISUHIADSADUHISADUHISADUHISADUHISHADS]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRjx6RlRqzc&amp;feature=youtube_gdata UHAUHSAUHISUHIADSADUHISADUHISADUHISADUHISHADS
            Paródia de Marcelo Adnet para o programa Adnet Ao Vivo da MTV Brasil. http://www.mtv.com.br/adnetaovivo Adnet ao Vivo toda quinta-feira 22h00 na MTV. Vídeo o...
            <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRjx6RlRqzc">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DxRjx6RlRqzc">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 23:46:10 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/trackback?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DxRjx6RlRqzc</guid>
        <link>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRjx6RlRqzc</link>
        <dc:creator>youtube.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Poll: Given Choice Between Palin and Trump, Most Voters Choose Suicide « Borowitz Report</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Poll: Given Choice Between Palin and Trump, Most Voters Choose Suicide http://bit.ly/mMYBoT]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Poll: Given Choice Between Palin and Trump, Most Voters Choose Suicide http://bit.ly/mMYBoT
            NEW YORK (The Borowitz Report) – A new survey of likely voters indicates that in a hypothetical match-up between former Alaska Governor Sarah Palin and billionaire Donald Trump, a majority would choose suicide over either candidate.
            <a href="http://www.borowitzreport.com/2011/05/06/poll-given-choice-between-palin-and-trump-most-voters-choose-suicide/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.borowitzreport.com/2011/05/06/poll-given-choice-between-palin-and-trump-most-voters-choose-suicide/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 23:07:19 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.borowitzreport.com/2011/05/06/poll-given-choice-between-palin-and-trump-most-voters-choose-suicide/</guid>
        <link>http://www.borowitzreport.com/2011/05/06/poll-given-choice-between-palin-and-trump-most-voters-choose-suicide/</link>
        <dc:creator>borowitzreport.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Organizing Offline: Zenergo Launches Social Network For Real World Activities</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Organizing Offline: Zenergo Launches Social Network For Real World Activities http://tcrn.ch/jlON63 by @ripemp]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Organizing Offline: Zenergo Launches Social Network For Real World Activities http://tcrn.ch/jlON63 by @ripemp
            Who needs another social network? Maybe you, friend. Admittedly, the social networking space is packed with so many players, it makes the mind reel. Across the Web, it seems like a new social network is born (and dies) every day. There are niche social networking sites for everything you can imagine. The knitting and crochet community has one, as do gamers, pet-lovers, and bowlers. 

Some of these specialized networks have significant traffic, and while Facebook Groups continues to evolve, it seems that there may still be room for social networks that revolve around shared interests, and specific groups and activities. It's also true that more and more companies are becoming interested in leveraging online activity and interaction to create meaningful connections, relationships, and services offline. The examples are endless.

It's for these reasons that Zenergo, an activity-based social network that launches today, still believes there's room to succeed.
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/organizing-offline-zenergo-launches-social-network-for-real-world-activities/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/organizing-offline-zenergo-launches-social-network-for-real-world-activities/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 23:00:18 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/organizing-offline-zenergo-launches-social-network-for-real-world-activities/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/organizing-offline-zenergo-launches-social-network-for-real-world-activities/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Skype bug gives attackers root access to Mac OS X • The Register</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Skype bug gives attackers root access to Mac OS X: &#39;Extremely wormable and dangerous&#39;. Mac users running Skype are v… http://reg.cx/1NZw]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Skype bug gives attackers root access to Mac OS X: &#39;Extremely wormable and dangerous&#39;. Mac users running Skype are v… http://reg.cx/1NZw
            Mac users running Skype are vulnerable to self-propagating exploits that allow an attacker to gain unfettered system access by sending a specially manipulated attachment in an instant message, a hacker said.
            <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/05/06/skype_for_mac_critical_vulnerability/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/05/06/skype_for_mac_critical_vulnerability/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 22:42:57 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.theregister.co.uk/2011/05/06/skype_for_mac_critical_vulnerability/</guid>
        <link>http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/05/06/skype_for_mac_critical_vulnerability/</link>
        <dc:creator>theregister.co.uk</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Selling Books by Day, Writing Them by Night - NYTimes.com</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Selling Books by Day, Writing Them by Night. Nice essay in @nytimesbooks, featuring @emmastraub, @jamiattenberg http://tinyurl.com/3rxaj2t]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Selling Books by Day, Writing Them by Night. Nice essay in @nytimesbooks, featuring @emmastraub, @jamiattenberg http://tinyurl.com/3rxaj2t
            Once a bookseller, always a bookseller, say some published authors who haven’t quit their day jobs.
            <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/books/review/selling-books-by-day-writing-them-by-night.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/books/review/selling-books-by-day-writing-them-by-night.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 22:41:35 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/books/review/selling-books-by-day-writing-them-by-night.html</guid>
        <link>http://www.nytimes.com/2011/05/08/books/review/selling-books-by-day-writing-them-by-night.html</link>
        <dc:creator>nytimes.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>How Mashable Evolved Into a Major Media Company | Social Media Examiner</title>
        <description><![CDATA[How Mashable Evolved Into a Major Media Company http://bit.ly/kigYAG #socialmediaexaminer]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[How Mashable Evolved Into a Major Media Company http://bit.ly/kigYAG #socialmediaexaminer
            Adam Ostrow talks about Mashable, how blogging has transformed the world of media and shares some of the social media trends you need to follow.
            <a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-mashable-evolved-into-a-major-media-company/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-mashable-evolved-into-a-major-media-company/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 20:47:18 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-mashable-evolved-into-a-major-media-company/</guid>
        <link>http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-mashable-evolved-into-a-major-media-company/</link>
        <dc:creator>socialmediaexaminer.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>How Social Media Creates a Rough Draft of History: Tech News and Analysis «</title>
        <description><![CDATA[How Social Media Creates a Rough Draft of History http://dlvr.it/Qsg8K]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[How Social Media Creates a Rough Draft of History http://dlvr.it/Qsg8K
            Washington Post publisher Philip Graham called journalism the "first rough draft of history," but as a new research paper from the Reuters Institute for the Study of Journalism notes, that role is increasingly being played by social media such as Twitter, Flickr, YouTube and Facebook.
            <a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/05/06/how-social-media-creates-a-rough-draft-of-history/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/gigaom.com/2011/05/06/how-social-media-creates-a-rough-draft-of-history/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 20:19:46 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/gigaom.com/2011/05/06/how-social-media-creates-a-rough-draft-of-history/</guid>
        <link>http://gigaom.com/2011/05/06/how-social-media-creates-a-rough-draft-of-history/</link>
        <dc:creator>gigaom.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Official Google Webmaster Central Blog: More guidance on building high-quality sites</title>
        <description><![CDATA[... and because common sense is not so common, Google wants to give us more guidance on building a high quality website: http://ow.ly/4OZze]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[... and because common sense is not so common, Google wants to give us more guidance on building a high quality website: http://ow.ly/4OZze
            In recent months we’ve been especially focused on helping people find high-quality sites in Google’s search results. The “Panda” algorithm change has improved rankings for a large number of high-quality websites, so most of you reading have nothing to be concerned about.
            <a href="http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2011/05/more-guidance-on-building-high-quality.html">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2011/05/more-guidance-on-building-high-quality.html">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 20:16:32 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2011/05/more-guidance-on-building-high-quality.html</guid>
        <link>http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2011/05/more-guidance-on-building-high-quality.html</link>
        <dc:creator>googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Five Social Media Mistakes That Suck</title>
        <description><![CDATA[By @jggube Five Social Media Mistakes That Suck http://bit.ly/m8YPo0]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[By @jggube Five Social Media Mistakes That Suck http://bit.ly/m8YPo0
            Social media has become an integral part of organizations big and small. With this mass adoption, comes poor choices. Here are five common mistakes.
            <a href="http://sixrevisions.com/content-strategy/five-social-media-mistakes-that-suck/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/sixrevisions.com/content-strategy/five-social-media-mistakes-that-suck/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 20:05:03 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/sixrevisions.com/content-strategy/five-social-media-mistakes-that-suck/</guid>
        <link>http://sixrevisions.com/content-strategy/five-social-media-mistakes-that-suck/</link>
        <dc:creator>sixrevisions.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Who’s In? U.S. Solar Industry Bands Together To Cut Costs, Make Panels Better</title>
        <description><![CDATA[Who&#39;s In? U.S. Solar Industry Bands Together To Cut Costs, Make Panels Better http://tcrn.ch/iXSZ3q by @lorakolodny]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[Who&#39;s In? U.S. Solar Industry Bands Together To Cut Costs, Make Panels Better http://tcrn.ch/iXSZ3q by @lorakolodny
            The U.S. solar industry is banding together to fend off an onslaught of global competition, and to lower the cost of manufacturing solar technology domestically. To make it happen, the newly formed U.S. Photovoltaic Manufacturing Consortium (PVMC) secured a $57.5 million federal grant from the Department of Energy Sunshot Initiative, along with financial commitments totaling $400 million from various state and corporate entities.

Today, the PVMC revealed (in an exclusive to TechCrunch) who its earliest members are, including cleantech businesses more often seen as competitors, not collaborators...
            <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/pvmc-solar-collaboration/">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/pvmc-solar-collaboration/">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 19:37:56 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/pvmc-solar-collaboration/</guid>
        <link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/06/pvmc-solar-collaboration/</link>
        <dc:creator>techcrunch.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>SocialFlow Company Blog - Breaking Bin Laden: visualizing the power of a single tweet</title>
        <description><![CDATA[How did @keithurbahn spark the network effect around the #OBL rumor prior to the announcement? http://sirmc.me/lZIIWU]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[How did @keithurbahn spark the network effect around the #OBL rumor prior to the announcement? http://sirmc.me/lZIIWU
            Breaking Bin Laden: visualizing the power of a single tweet A full hour before the formal announcement of Bin-Laden’s death, Keith Urbahn posted his speculation on the emergency presidential address....
            <a href="http://blog.socialflow.com/post/5246404319/breaking-bin-laden-visualizing-the-power-of-a-single">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/blog.socialflow.com/post/5246404319/breaking-bin-laden-visualizing-the-power-of-a-single">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 18:56:00 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/blog.socialflow.com/post/5246404319/breaking-bin-laden-visualizing-the-power-of-a-single</guid>
        <link>http://blog.socialflow.com/post/5246404319/breaking-bin-laden-visualizing-the-power-of-a-single</link>
        <dc:creator>socialflow.com</dc:creator>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>BBC News - Flexible phone made from electronic paper to debut</title>
        <description><![CDATA[i♡♫ Flexible phone made from electronic paper to debut - BBC http://dlvr.it/Qq0Qf #B #Sound]]></description>    
        <content:encoded><![CDATA[i♡♫ Flexible phone made from electronic paper to debut - BBC http://dlvr.it/Qq0Qf #B #Sound
            A prototype flexible smart phone made of electronic paper has been created by Canadian researchers.
            <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-13308452">Link</a> - <a href="http://topsy.com/www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-13308452">Trackbacks</a>]]>
        </content:encoded>    
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 18:33:11 PDT</pubDate>
        <guid>http://topsy.com/www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-13308452</guid>
        <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-13308452</link>
        <dc:creator>bbc.co.uk</dc:creator>
    </item>

</channel>
</rss> 

